<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0120.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exceptions and special requirements; agencies.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DIVISION OF ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Division as a party.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), a hearing in which the division is a party may not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division. An attorney assigned by the Administration Commission shall be the hearing officer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Workers’ compensation.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.52(1), a judge of compensation claims, in adjudicating matters under chapter 440, is not an agency or part of an agency for purposes of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND CONSUMER SERVICES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marketing orders under chapter 527, chapter 573, or chapter 601 are not rules.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings held by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services pursuant to chapter 601 need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFICE OF FINANCIAL REGULATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.60(1), in proceedings for the issuance, denial, renewal, or amendment of a license or approval of a merger pursuant to title XXXVIII:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Financial Regulation of the Financial Services Commission shall have published in the Florida Administrative Weekly notice of the application within 21 days after receipt.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 21 days after publication of notice, any person may request a hearing. Failure to request a hearing within 21 days after notice constitutes a waiver of any right to a hearing. The Office of Financial Regulation or an applicant may request a hearing at any time prior to the issuance of a final order. Hearings shall be conducted pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57, except that the Financial Services Commission shall by rule provide for participation by the general public.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should a hearing be requested as provided by sub-subparagraph 1.b., the applicant or licensee shall publish at its own cost a notice of the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the area affected by the application. The Financial Services Commission may by rule specify the format and size of the notice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.60(1), and except as provided in subparagraph 4., every application for license for a new bank, new trust company, new credit union, or new savings and loan association shall be approved or denied within 180 days after receipt of the original application or receipt of the timely requested additional information or correction of errors or omissions. Any application for such a license or for acquisition of such control which is not approved or denied within the 180-day period or within 30 days after conclusion of a public hearing on the application, whichever is later, shall be deemed approved subject to the satisfactory completion of conditions required by statute as a prerequisite to license and approval of insurance of accounts for a new bank, a new savings and loan association, or a new credit union by the appropriate insurer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of every application for license to establish a new bank, trust company, or capital stock savings association in which a foreign national proposes to own or control 10 percent or more of any class of voting securities, and in the case of every application by a foreign national for approval to acquire control of a bank, trust company, or capital stock savings association, the Office of Financial Regulation shall request that a public hearing be conducted pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57. Notice of such hearing shall be published by the applicant as provided in subparagraph 2. The failure of any such foreign national to appear personally at the hearing shall be grounds for denial of the application. Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.60(1) and subparagraph 3., every application involving a foreign national shall be approved or denied within 1 year after receipt of the original application or any timely requested additional information or the correction of any errors or omissions, or within 30 days after the conclusion of the public hearing on the application, whichever is later.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any application for a license or merger pursuant to title XXXVIII which is referred by the agency to the division for hearing, the administrative law judge shall complete and submit to the agency and to all parties a written report consisting of findings of fact and rulings on evidentiary matters. The agency shall allow each party at least 10 days in which to submit written exceptions to the report.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS AND PROFESSIONAL REGULATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Business regulation.</Font><EmDash />The Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering is exempt from the hearing and notice requirements of ss. 120.569 and 120.57(1)(a), but only for stewards, judges, and boards of judges when the hearing is to be held for the purpose of the imposition of fines or suspensions as provided by rules of the Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering, but not for revocations, and only upon violations of subparagraphs 1.-6. The Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering shall adopt rules establishing alternative procedures, including a hearing upon reasonable notice, for the following violations:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Horse riding, harness riding, greyhound interference, and jai alai game actions in violation of chapter 550.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application and usage of drugs and medication to horses, greyhounds, and jai alai players in violation of chapter 550.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining or possessing any device which could be used for the injection or other infusion of a prohibited drug to horses, greyhounds, and jai alai players in violation of chapter 550.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspensions under reciprocity agreements between the Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering and regulatory agencies of other states.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assault or other crimes of violence on premises licensed for pari-mutuel wagering.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prearranging the outcome of any race or game.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Professional regulation.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), formal hearings may not be conducted by the Secretary of Business and Professional Regulation or a board or member of a board within the Department of Business and Professional Regulation for matters relating to the regulation of professions, as defined by chapter 455.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA LAND AND WATER ADJUDICATORY COMMISSION.<EmDash />Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.57(1)(a), when the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission receives a notice of appeal pursuant to s. 380.07, the commission shall notify the division within 60 days after receipt of the notice of appeal if the commission elects to request the assignment of an administrative law judge.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF LAW ENFORCEMENT.<EmDash />Law enforcement policies and procedures of the Department of Law Enforcement which relate to the following are not rules as defined by this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The collection, management, and dissemination of active criminal intelligence information and active criminal investigative information; management of criminal investigations; and management of undercover investigations and the selection, assignment, and fictitious identity of undercover personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recruitment, management, identity, and remuneration of confidential informants or sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surveillance techniques, the selection of surveillance personnel, and electronic surveillance, including court-ordered and consensual interceptions of communication conducted pursuant to chapter 934.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safety and release of hostages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of security and protection to public figures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The protection of witnesses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF CHILDREN AND FAMILY SERVICES.<EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings conducted within the Department of Children and Family Services in the execution of those social and economic programs administered by the former Division of Family Services of the former Department of Health and Rehabilitative Services prior to the reorganization effected by chapter 75-48, Laws of Florida, need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAY SAFETY AND MOTOR VEHICLES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Drivers’ licenses.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings regarding drivers’ licensing pursuant to chapter 322 need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.60(5), cancellation, suspension, or revocation of a driver’s license shall be by personal delivery to the licensee or by first-class mail as provided in s. 322.251.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Wrecker operators.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings held by the Division of the Florida Highway Patrol of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to deny, suspend, or remove a wrecker operator from participating in the wrecker rotation system established by s. 321.051 need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division. These hearings shall be held by a hearing officer appointed by the director of the Division of the Florida Highway Patrol.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFICE OF INSURANCE REGULATION.<EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.60(1), every application for a certificate of authority as required by s. 624.401 shall be approved or denied within 180 days after receipt of the original application. Any application for a certificate of authority which is not approved or denied within the 180-day period, or within 30 days after conclusion of a public hearing held on the application, shall be deemed approved, subject to the satisfactory completion of conditions required by statute as a prerequisite to licensure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF ECONOMIC OPPORTUNITY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.54, the rulemaking provisions of this chapter do not apply to reemployment assistance appeals referees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.54(5), the uniform rules of procedure do not apply to appeal proceedings conducted under chapter 443 by the Reemployment Assistance Appeals Commission, special deputies, or reemployment assistance appeals referees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings under chapter 443 may not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division, but instead shall be conducted by the Reemployment Assistance Appeals Commission in reemployment assistance appeals, reemployment assistance appeals referees, and the Department of Economic Opportunity or its special deputies under s. 443.141.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NATIONAL GUARD.<EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.52(16), the enlistment, organization, administration, equipment, maintenance, training, and discipline of the militia, National Guard, organized militia, and unorganized militia, as provided by s. 2, Art. X of the State Constitution, are not rules as defined by this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PUBLIC EMPLOYEES RELATIONS COMMISSION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings within the jurisdiction of the Public Employees Relations Commission need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 120.60 does not apply to certification of employee organizations pursuant to s. 447.307.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agency statements that relate to cost-recovery clauses, factors, or mechanisms implemented pursuant to chapter 366, relating to public utilities, are exempt from the provisions of s. 120.54(1)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 120.569 and 120.57, a hearing on an objection to proposed action of the Florida Public Service Commission may only address the issues in dispute. Issues in the proposed action which are not in dispute are deemed stipulated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Public Service Commission is exempt from the time limitations in s. 120.60(1) when issuing a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, in implementing the Telecommunications Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-104, the Public Service Commission is authorized to employ procedures consistent with that act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, s. 350.128, or s. 364.381, appellate jurisdiction for Public Service Commission decisions that implement the Telecommunications Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-104, shall be consistent with the provisions of that act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter, all public utilities and companies regulated by the Public Service Commission shall be entitled to proceed under the interim rate provisions of chapter 364 or the procedures for interim rates contained in chapter 74-195, Laws of Florida, or as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Assessments.</Font><EmDash />An assessment of tax, penalty, or interest by the Department of Revenue is not a final order as defined by this chapter. Assessments by the Department of Revenue shall be deemed final as provided in the statutes and rules governing the assessment and collection of taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Taxpayer contest proceedings.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any administrative proceeding brought pursuant to this chapter as authorized by s. 72.011(1), the taxpayer shall be designated the “petitioner” and the Department of Revenue shall be designated the “respondent,” except that for actions contesting an assessment or denial of refund under chapter 207, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall be designated the “respondent,” and for actions contesting an assessment or denial of refund under chapters 210, 550, 561, 562, 563, 564, and 565, the Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall be designated the “respondent.”</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any such administrative proceeding, the applicable department’s burden of proof, except as otherwise specifically provided by general law, shall be limited to a showing that an assessment has been made against the taxpayer and the factual and legal grounds upon which the applicable department made the assessment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to filing a petition under this chapter, the taxpayer shall pay to the applicable department the amount of taxes, penalties, and accrued interest assessed by that department which are not being contested by the taxpayer. Failure to pay the uncontested amount shall result in the dismissal of the action and imposition of an additional penalty of 25 percent of the amount taxed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 72.011(2) and (3)(a) are jurisdictional for any action under this chapter to contest an assessment or denial of refund by the Department of Revenue, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, or the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 220.719, further collection and enforcement of the contested amount of an assessment for nonpayment or underpayment of any tax, interest, or penalty shall be stayed beginning on the date a petition is filed. Upon entry of a final order, an agency may resume collection and enforcement action.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing party, in a proceeding under ss. 120.569 and 120.57 authorized by s. 72.011(1), may recover all legal costs incurred in such proceeding, including reasonable attorney’s fees, if the losing party fails to raise a justiciable issue of law or fact in its petition or response.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon review pursuant to s. 120.68 of final agency action concerning an assessment of tax, penalty, or interest with respect to a tax imposed under chapter 212, or the denial of a refund of any tax imposed under chapter 212, if the court finds that the Department of Revenue improperly rejected or modified a conclusion of law, the court may award reasonable attorney’s fees and reasonable costs of the appeal to the prevailing appellant.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Proceedings to establish paternity or paternity and child support; orders to appear for genetic testing; proceedings for administrative support orders.</Font><EmDash />In proceedings to establish paternity or paternity and child support pursuant to s. 409.256 and proceedings for the establishment of administrative support orders pursuant to s. 409.2563, final orders in cases referred by the Department of Revenue to the Division of Administrative Hearings shall be entered by the division’s administrative law judge and transmitted to the Department of Revenue for filing and rendering. The Department of Revenue has the right to seek judicial review under s. 120.68 of a final order entered by an administrative law judge. The Department of Revenue or the person ordered to appear for genetic testing may seek immediate judicial review under s. 120.68 of an order issued by an administrative law judge pursuant to s. 409.256(5)(b). Final orders that adjudicate paternity or paternity and child support pursuant to s. 409.256 and administrative support orders rendered pursuant to s. 409.2563 may be enforced pursuant to s. 120.69 or, alternatively, by any method prescribed by law for the enforcement of judicial support orders, except contempt. Hearings held by the Division of Administrative Hearings pursuant to ss. 409.256, 409.2563, and 409.25635 shall be held in the judicial circuit where the person receiving services under Title IV-D resides or, if the person receiving services under Title IV-D does not reside in this state, in the judicial circuit where the respondent resides. If the department and the respondent agree, the hearing may be held in another location. If ordered by the administrative law judge, the hearing may be conducted telephonically or by videoconference.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH.<EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), formal hearings may not be conducted by the State Surgeon General, the Secretary of Health Care Administration, or a board or member of a board within the Department of Health or the Agency for Health Care Administration for matters relating to the regulation of professions, as defined by chapter 456. Notwithstanding s. 120.57(1)(a), hearings conducted within the Department of Health in execution of the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children; Child Care Food Program; Children’s Medical Services Program; the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Program; and the exemption from disqualification reviews for certified nurse assistants program need not be conducted by an administrative law judge assigned by the division. The Department of Health may contract with the Department of Children and Family Services for a hearing officer in these matters.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA BUILDING COMMISSION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.542, the Florida Building Commission may not accept a petition for waiver or variance and may not grant any waiver or variance from the requirements of the Florida Building Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Building Commission shall adopt within the Florida Building Code criteria and procedures for alternative means of compliance with the code or local amendments thereto, for enforcement by local governments, local enforcement districts, or other entities authorized by law to enforce the Florida Building Code. Appeals from the denial of the use of alternative means shall be heard by the local board, if one exists, and may be appealed to the Florida Building Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 120.565, 120.569, and 120.57, the Florida Building Commission and hearing officer panels appointed by the commission in accordance with s. 553.775(3)(c)1. may conduct proceedings to review decisions of local building code officials in accordance with s. 553.775(3)(c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 120.541(3) does not apply to the adoption of amendments and the triennial update to the Florida Building Code expressly authorized by s. 553.73.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATE FIRE MARSHAL.<EmDash />Section 120.541(3) does not apply to the adoption of amendments and the triennial update to the Florida Fire Prevention Code expressly authorized by s. 633.0215.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION.<EmDash />Sections 120.54(3)(b) and 120.541 do not apply to the adjustment of tolls pursuant to s. 338.165(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 96-159; s. 13, ch. 98-166; s. 10, ch. 99-8; s. 4, ch. 99-397; s. 1, ch. 2000-141; s. 17, ch. 2000-151; s. 2, ch. 2000-160; s. 11, ch. 2000-304; s. 4, ch. 2000-305; ss. 2, 11, ch. 2000-312; s. 4, ch. 2000-355; s. 3, ch. 2000-367; s. 18, ch. 2001-158; s. 2, ch. 2001-279; s. 8, ch. 2002-173; s. 1, ch. 2002-239; s. 3, ch. 2003-36; s. 139, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2004-52; s. 7, ch. 2004-334; ss. 12, 13, ch. 2005-39; s. 1, ch. 2005-96; s. 13, ch. 2005-147; s. 1, ch. 2005-209; s. 5, ch. 2006-45; s. 9, ch. 2008-6; s. 16, ch. 2008-104; s. 5, ch. 2009-187; s. 1, ch. 2011-64; s. 50, ch. 2011-142; s. 8, ch. 2011-225; s. 43, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>