<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0120.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agency review, revision, and report.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency shall review and revise its rules as often as necessary to ensure that its rules are correct and comply with statutory requirements. Additionally, each agency shall perform a formal review of its rules every 2 years. In the review, each agency must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and correct deficiencies in its rules;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clarify and simplify its rules;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delete obsolete or unnecessary rules;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delete rules that are redundant of statutes;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek to improve efficiency, reduce paperwork, or decrease costs to government and the private sector;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contact agencies that have concurrent or overlapping jurisdiction to determine whether their rules can be coordinated to promote efficiency, reduce paperwork, or decrease costs to government and the private sector; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine whether the rules should be continued without change or should be amended or repealed to reduce the impact on small business while meeting the stated objectives of the proposed rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning October 1, 1997, and by October 1 of every other year thereafter, the head of each agency shall file a report with the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the committee, with a copy to each appropriate standing committee of the Legislature, which certifies that the agency has complied with the requirements of this section. The report must specify any changes made to its rules as a result of the review and, when appropriate, recommend statutory changes that will promote efficiency, reduce paperwork, or decrease costs to government and the private sector. The report must specifically address the economic impact of the rules on small business. The report must identify the types of cases or disputes in which the agency is involved which should be conducted under the summary hearing process described in s. 120.574.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in 2012, and no later than July 1 of each year, each agency shall file with the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the committee a regulatory plan identifying and describing each rule the agency proposes to adopt for the 12-month period beginning on the July 1 reporting date and ending on the subsequent June 30, excluding emergency rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the year 2011, the certification required in subsection (2) may omit any information included in the reports provided under s. 120.745. Reporting under subsections (1) and (2) shall be suspended for the year 2013, but required reporting under those subsections shall resume in 2015 and biennially thereafter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 96-399; s. 16, ch. 97-176; s. 9, ch. 2006-82; s. 15, ch. 2008-104; s. 8, ch. 2008-149; s. 4, ch. 2011-225.</History>
</Section>