<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0120.536" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rulemaking authority; repeal; challenge.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A grant of rulemaking authority is necessary but not sufficient to allow an agency to adopt a rule; a specific law to be implemented is also required. An agency may adopt only rules that implement or interpret the specific powers and duties granted by the enabling statute. No agency shall have authority to adopt a rule only because it is reasonably related to the purpose of the enabling legislation and is not arbitrary and capricious or is within the agency’s class of powers and duties, nor shall an agency have the authority to implement statutory provisions setting forth general legislative intent or policy. Statutory language granting rulemaking authority or generally describing the powers and functions of an agency shall be construed to extend no further than implementing or interpreting the specific powers and duties conferred by the enabling statute.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise expressly provided by law:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repeal of one or more provisions of law implemented by a rule that on its face implements only the provision or provisions repealed and no other provision of law nullifies the rule. Whenever notice of the nullification of a rule under this subsection is received from the committee or otherwise, the Department of State shall remove the rule from the Florida Administrative Code as of the effective date of the law effecting the nullification and update the historical notes for the code to show the rule repealed by operation of law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repeal of one or more provisions of law implemented by a rule that on its face implements the provision or provisions repealed and one or more other provisions of law nullifies the rule or applicable portion of the rule to the extent that it implements the repealed law. The agency having authority to repeal or amend the rule shall, within 180 days after the effective date of the repealing law, publish a notice of rule development identifying all portions of rules affected by the repealing law, and if no notice is timely published the operation of each rule implementing a repealed provision of law shall be suspended until such notice is published.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repeal of one or more provisions of law that, other than as provided in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), causes a rule or portion of a rule to be of uncertain enforceability requires the Department of State to treat the rule as provided by s. 120.555. A rule shall be considered to be of uncertain enforceability under this paragraph if the division notifies the Department of State that a rule or a portion of the rule has been invalidated in a division proceeding based upon a repeal of law, or the committee gives written notification to the Department of State and the agency having power to amend or repeal the rule that a law has been repealed creating doubt about whether the rule is still in full force and effect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administrative Procedures Committee or any substantially affected person may petition an agency to repeal any rule, or portion thereof, because it exceeds the rulemaking authority permitted by this section. Not later than 30 days after the date of filing the petition if the agency is headed by an individual, or not later than 45 days if the agency is headed by a collegial body, the agency shall initiate rulemaking proceedings to repeal the rule, or portion thereof, or deny the petition, giving a written statement of its reasons for the denial.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to change the legal status of a rule that has otherwise been judicially or administratively determined to be invalid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 96-159; s. 3, ch. 99-379; s. 15, ch. 2000-151; s. 15, ch. 2005-2; s. 4, ch. 2008-104; s. 1, ch. 2012-31.</History>
</Section>