<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0120.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a license application, an agency shall examine the application and, within 30 days after such receipt, notify the applicant of any apparent errors or omissions and request any additional information the agency is permitted by law to require. An agency may not deny a license for failure to correct an error or omission or to supply additional information unless the agency timely notified the applicant within this 30-day period. The agency may establish by rule the time period for submitting any additional information requested by the agency. For good cause shown, the agency shall grant a request for an extension of time for submitting the additional information. If the applicant believes the agency’s request for additional information is not authorized by law or rule, the agency, at the applicant’s request, shall proceed to process the application. An application is complete upon receipt of all requested information and correction of any error or omission for which the applicant was timely notified or when the time for such notification has expired. An application for a license must be approved or denied within 90 days after receipt of a completed application unless a shorter period of time for agency action is provided by law. The 90-day time period is tolled by the initiation of a proceeding under ss. 120.569 and 120.57. Any application for a license which is not approved or denied within the 90-day or shorter time period, within 15 days after conclusion of a public hearing held on the application, or within 45 days after a recommended order is submitted to the agency and the parties, whichever action and timeframe is latest and applicable, is considered approved unless the recommended order recommends that the agency deny the license. Subject to the satisfactory completion of an examination if required as a prerequisite to licensure, any license that is considered approved shall be issued and may include such reasonable conditions as are authorized by law. Any applicant for licensure seeking to claim licensure by default under this subsection shall notify the agency clerk of the licensing agency, in writing, of the intent to rely upon the default license provision of this subsection, and may not take any action based upon the default license until after receipt of such notice by the agency clerk.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant seeks a license for an activity that is exempt from licensure, the agency shall notify the applicant and return any tendered application fee within 30 days after receipt of the original application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant shall be given written notice, personally or by mail, that the agency intends to grant or deny, or has granted or denied, the application for license. The notice must state with particularity the grounds or basis for the issuance or denial of the license, except when issuance is a ministerial act. Unless waived, a copy of the notice shall be delivered or mailed to each party’s attorney of record and to each person who has made a written request for notice of agency action. Each notice must inform the recipient of the basis for the agency decision, inform the recipient of any administrative hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57 or judicial review pursuant to s. 120.68 which may be available, indicate the procedure that must be followed, and state the applicable time limits. The issuing agency shall certify the date the notice was mailed or delivered, and the notice and the certification must be filed with the agency clerk.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a licensee has made timely and sufficient application for the renewal of a license which does not automatically expire by statute, the existing license shall not expire until the application for renewal has been finally acted upon by the agency or, in case the application is denied or the terms of the license are limited, until the last day for seeking review of the agency order or a later date fixed by order of the reviewing court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No revocation, suspension, annulment, or withdrawal of any license is lawful unless, prior to the entry of a final order, the agency has served, by personal service or certified mail, an administrative complaint which affords reasonable notice to the licensee of facts or conduct which warrant the intended action and unless the licensee has been given an adequate opportunity to request a proceeding pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57. When personal service cannot be made and the certified mail notice is returned undelivered, the agency shall cause a short, plain notice to the licensee to be published once each week for 4 consecutive weeks in a newspaper published in the county of the licensee’s last known address as it appears on the records of the agency. If no newspaper is published in that county, the notice may be published in a newspaper of general circulation in that county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency finds that immediate serious danger to the public health, safety, or welfare requires emergency suspension, restriction, or limitation of a license, the agency may take such action by any procedure that is fair under the circumstances if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure provides at least the same procedural protection as is given by other statutes, the State Constitution, or the United States Constitution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency takes only that action necessary to protect the public interest under the emergency procedure; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency states in writing at the time of, or prior to, its action the specific facts and reasons for finding an immediate danger to the public health, safety, or welfare and its reasons for concluding that the procedure used is fair under the circumstances. The agency’s findings of immediate danger, necessity, and procedural fairness are judicially reviewable. Summary suspension, restriction, or limitation may be ordered, but a suspension or revocation proceeding pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57 shall also be promptly instituted and acted upon.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No agency shall include as a condition of approval of any license any provision that is based upon a statement, policy, or guideline of another agency unless the statement, policy, or guideline is within the jurisdiction of the other agency. The other agency shall identify for the licensing agency the specific legal authority for each such statement, policy, or guideline. The licensing agency must provide the licensee with an opportunity to challenge the condition as invalid. If the licensing agency bases a condition of approval or denial of the license upon the statement, policy, or guideline of the other agency, any party to an administrative proceeding that arises from the approval with conditions or denial of the license may require the other agency to join as a party in determining the validity of the condition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-310; s. 10, ch. 76-131; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 6, 9, ch. 77-453; s. 57, ch. 78-95; s. 8, ch. 78-425; s. 1, ch. 79-142; s. 6, ch. 79-299; s. 2, ch. 81-180; s. 6, ch. 84-203; s. 2, ch. 84-265; s. 1, ch. 85-82; s. 14, ch. 90-51; s. 762, ch. 95-147; s. 26, ch. 96-159; s. 326, ch. 96-410; s. 12, ch. 97-176; s. 7, ch. 2003-94; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-279; HJR 9-A, 2010 Special Session A; s. 10, ch. 2012-212.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text></Note></Section>