<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0682.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proceedings to compel and to stay arbitration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party to an agreement or provision for arbitration subject to this law claiming the neglect or refusal of another party thereto to comply therewith may make application to the court for an order directing the parties to proceed with arbitration in accordance with the terms thereof. If the court is satisfied that no substantial issue exists as to the making of the agreement or provision, it shall grant the application. If the court shall find that a substantial issue is raised as to the making of the agreement or provision, it shall summarily hear and determine the issue and, according to its determination, shall grant or deny the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an issue referable to arbitration under an agreement or provision for arbitration subject to this law becomes involved in an action or proceeding pending in a court having jurisdiction to hear an application under subsection (1), such application shall be made in said court. Otherwise and subject to s. 682.19, such application may be made in any court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action or proceeding involving an issue subject to arbitration under this law shall be stayed if an order for arbitration or an application therefor has been made under this section or, if the issue is severable, the stay may be with respect thereto only. When the application is made in such action or proceeding, the order for arbitration shall include such stay.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On application the court may stay an arbitration proceeding commenced or about to be commenced, if it shall find that no agreement or provision for arbitration subject to this law exists between the party making the application and the party causing the arbitration to be had. The court shall summarily hear and determine the issue of the making of the agreement or provision and, according to its determination, shall grant or deny the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order for arbitration shall not be refused on the ground that the claim in issue lacks merit or bona fides or because any fault or grounds for the claim sought to be arbitrated have not been shown.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 57-402; s. 12, ch. 67-254.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 57.12.</Text></Note></Section>