<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0682.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vacating an award.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application of a party, the court shall vacate an award when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The award was procured by corruption, fraud or other undue means.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There was evident partiality by an arbitrator appointed as a neutral or corruption in any of the arbitrators or umpire or misconduct prejudicing the rights of any party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The arbitrators or the umpire in the course of her or his jurisdiction exceeded their powers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The arbitrators or the umpire in the course of her or his jurisdiction refused to postpone the hearing upon sufficient cause being shown therefor or refused to hear evidence material to the controversy or otherwise so conducted the hearing, contrary to the provisions of s. 682.06, as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There was no agreement or provision for arbitration subject to this law, unless the matter was determined in proceedings under s. 682.03 and unless the party participated in the arbitration hearing without raising the objection.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">But the fact that the relief was such that it could not or would not be granted by a court of law or equity is not ground for vacating or refusing to confirm the award.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application under this section shall be made within 90 days after delivery of a copy of the award to the applicant, except that, if predicated upon corruption, fraud or other undue means, it shall be made within 90 days after such grounds are known or should have been known.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In vacating the award on grounds other than those stated in paragraph (1)(e), the court may order a rehearing before new arbitrators chosen as provided in the agreement or provision for arbitration or by the court in accordance with s. 682.04, or, if the award is vacated on grounds set forth in paragraphs (1)(c) and (d), the court may order a rehearing before the arbitrators or umpire who made the award or their successors appointed in accordance with s. 682.04. The time within which the agreement or provision for arbitration requires the award to be made is applicable to the rehearing and commences from the date of the order therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the application to vacate is denied and no motion to modify or correct the award is pending, the court shall confirm the award.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 57-402; s. 12, ch. 67-254; s. 729, ch. 97-102.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 57.22.</Text></Note></Section>