<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0718.618" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Converter reserve accounts; warranties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When existing improvements are converted to ownership as a residential condominium, the developer shall establish converter reserve accounts for capital expenditures and deferred maintenance, or give warranties as provided by subsection (6), or post a surety bond as provided by subsection (7). The developer shall fund the converter reserve accounts in amounts calculated as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the existing improvements include an air-conditioning system serving more than one unit or property which the association is responsible to repair, maintain, or replace, the developer shall fund an air-conditioning reserve account. The amount of the reserve account shall be the product of the estimated current replacement cost of the system, as disclosed and substantiated pursuant to s. 718.616(3)(b), multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the lesser of the age of the system in years or 9, and the denominator of which shall be 10. When such air-conditioning system is within 1,000 yards of the seacoast, the numerator shall be the lesser of the age of the system in years or 3, and the denominator shall be 4.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall fund a plumbing reserve account. The amount of the funding shall be the product of the estimated current replacement cost of the plumbing component, as disclosed and substantiated pursuant to s. 718.616(3)(b), multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the lesser of the age of the plumbing in years or 36, and the denominator of which shall be 40.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall fund a roof reserve account. The amount of the funding shall be the product of the estimated current replacement cost of the roofing component, as disclosed and substantiated pursuant to s. 718.616(3)(b), multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the lesser of the age of the roof in years or the numerator listed in the following table. The denominator of the fraction shall be determined based on the roof type, as follows:</Text>
					<Table Width="100" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">
						<ColumnDefinitions>
							<Column Width="5" />
							<Column Width="45" />
							<Column Width="25" />
							<Column Width="25" />
						</ColumnDefinitions>
						<CellPadding Bottom="4"/>
						<Header>
							<Row>
								<Cell></Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Roof Type</Font></Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Numerator</Font></Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Denominator</Font></Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
						</Header>
						<Body>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">a.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Built-up roof without insulation</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">4</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">5</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">b.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Built-up roof with insulation</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">4</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">5</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">c.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Cement tile roof</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">45</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">50</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">d.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Asphalt shingle roof</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">14</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">15</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">e.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Copper roof</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center"></Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center"></Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">f.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Wood shingle roof</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">9</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">10</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">g.</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell>
									<Text xml:space="preserve">All other types</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">18</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Center">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">20</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
						</Body>
					</Table>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The age of any component or structure for which the developer is required to fund a reserve account shall be measured in years, rounded to the nearest whole year. The amount of converter reserves to be funded by the developer for each structure or component shall be based on the age of the structure or component as disclosed in the inspection report. The architect or engineer shall determine the age of the component from the later of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date when the component or structure was replaced or substantially renewed, if the replacement or renewal of the component at least met the requirements of the then-applicable building code; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date when the installation or construction of the existing component or structure was completed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the age of a component or structure is to be measured from the date of replacement or renewal, the developer shall provide the division with a certificate, under the seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state, verifying:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the replacement or renewal; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the replacement or renewal at least met the requirements of the then-applicable building code.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to establishing the reserve accounts specified above, the developer shall establish those other reserve accounts required by s. 718.112(2)(f), and shall fund those accounts in accordance with the formula provided therein. The vote to waive or reduce the funding or reserves required by s. 718.112(2)(f) does not affect or negate the obligations arising under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall fund the reserve account required by subsection (1), on a pro rata basis upon the sale of each unit. The developer shall deposit in the reserve account not less than a percentage of the total amount to be deposited in the reserve account equal to the percentage of ownership of the common elements allocable to the unit sold. When a developer deposits amounts in excess of the minimum reserve account funding, later deposits may be reduced to the extent of the excess funding. For the purposes of this subsection, a unit is considered sold when a fee interest in the unit is transferred to a third party or the unit is leased for a period in excess of 5 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an association makes an expenditure of converter reserve account funds before the developer has sold all units, the developer shall make a deposit in the reserve account. Such deposit shall be at least equal to that portion of the expenditure which would be charged against the reserve account deposit that would have been made for any such unit had the unit been sold. Such deposit may be reduced to the extent the developer has funded the reserve account in excess of the minimum reserve account funding required by this subsection. This paragraph applies only when the developer has funded reserve accounts as provided by paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of reserve account funds, as provided in this section, is limited as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve account funds may be spent prior to the assumption of control of the association by unit owners other than the developer; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve account funds may be expended only for repair or replacement of the specific components for which the funds were deposited, unless, after assumption of control of the association by unit owners other than the developer, it is determined by three-fourths of the voting interests in the condominium to expend the funds for other purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall establish the reserve account, as provided in this section, in the name of the association at a bank, savings and loan association, or trust company located in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer may establish and fund additional converter reserve accounts. The amount of funding shall be the product of the estimated current replacement cost of a component, as disclosed and substantiated pursuant to s. 718.616(3)(b), multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is the age of the component in years and the denominator of which is the total estimated life of the component in years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer makes no implied warranties when existing improvements are converted to ownership as a residential condominium and reserve accounts are funded in accordance with this section. As an alternative to establishing such reserve accounts, or when a developer fails to establish the reserve accounts in accordance with this section, the developer shall be deemed to have granted to the purchaser of each unit an implied warranty of fitness and merchantability for the purposes or uses intended. The warranty shall be for a period beginning with the notice of intended conversion and continuing for 3 years thereafter, or the recording of the declaration to condominium and continuing for 3 years thereafter, or 1 year after owners other than the developer obtain control of the association, whichever occurs last, but in no event more than 5 years.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The warranty provided for in this section is conditioned upon routine maintenance being performed, unless the maintenance is an obligation of the developer or a developer-controlled association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The warranty shall inure to the benefit of each owner and successor owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing improvements converted to residential condominium may be covered by an insured warranty program underwritten by an insurance company authorized to do business in this state, if such warranty program meets the minimum requirements of this chapter. To the degree that the warranty program does not meet the minimum requirements of this chapter, such requirements shall apply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a developer desires to post a surety bond, the developer shall, after notification to the buyer, acquire a surety bond issued by a company licensed to do business in this state, if such a bond is readily available in the open market, in an amount which would be equal to the total amount of all reserve accounts required under subsection (1), payable to the association.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amended provisions of this section do not affect a conversion of existing improvements when a developer has filed a notice of intended conversion and the documents required by s. 718.503 or s. 718.504, as applicable, with the division prior to the effective date of this law, provided:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The documents are proper for filing purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer, not later than 6 months after such filing:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records a declaration for such filing in accordance with part I.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gives a notice of intended conversion.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only to the conversion of existing improvements where construction of the improvement was commenced prior to its designation by the developer as a condominium. In such circumstances, s. 718.203 does not apply.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer who sells a condominium parcel that is subject to this part shall disclose in conspicuous type in the contract of sale whether the developer has established converter reserve accounts, provided a warranty of fitness and merchantability, or posted a surety bond for purposes of complying with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-3; s. 23, ch. 84-368; s. 20, ch. 90-151; s. 22, ch. 91-103; s. 5, ch. 91-426; s. 15, ch. 94-350; s. 2, ch. 2006-145; s. 10, ch. 2007-80.</History>
</Section>