<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0718.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of association control; claims of defect by association.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If unit owners other than the developer own 15 percent or more of the units in a condominium that will be operated ultimately by an association, the unit owners other than the developer are entitled to elect at least one-third of the members of the board of administration of the association. Unit owners other than the developer are entitled to elect at least a majority of the members of the board of administration of an association:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years after 50 percent of the units that will be operated ultimately by the association have been conveyed to purchasers;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three months after 90 percent of the units that will be operated ultimately by the association have been conveyed to purchasers;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When all the units that will be operated ultimately by the association have been completed, some of them have been conveyed to purchasers, and none of the others are being offered for sale by the developer in the ordinary course of business;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When some of the units have been conveyed to purchasers and none of the others are being constructed or offered for sale by the developer in the ordinary course of business;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the developer files a petition seeking protection in bankruptcy;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a receiver for the developer is appointed by a circuit court and is not discharged within 30 days after such appointment, unless the court determines within 30 days after appointment of the receiver that transfer of control would be detrimental to the association or its members; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seven years after recordation of the declaration of condominium; or, in the case of an association that may ultimately operate more than one condominium, 7 years after recordation of the declaration for the first condominium it operates; or, in the case of an association operating a phase condominium created pursuant to s. 718.403, 7 years after recordation of the declaration creating the initial phase,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">whichever occurs first. The developer is entitled to elect at least one member of the board of administration of an association as long as the developer holds for sale in the ordinary course of business at least 5 percent, in condominiums with fewer than 500 units, and 2 percent, in condominiums with more than 500 units, of the units in a condominium operated by the association. After the developer relinquishes control of the association, the developer may exercise the right to vote any developer-owned units in the same manner as any other unit owner except for purposes of reacquiring control of the association or selecting the majority members of the board of administration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 75 days after the unit owners other than the developer are entitled to elect a member or members of the board of administration of an association, the association shall call, and give not less than 60 days’ notice of an election for the members of the board of administration. The election shall proceed as provided in s. 718.112(2)(d). The notice may be given by any unit owner if the association fails to do so. Upon election of the first unit owner other than the developer to the board of administration, the developer shall forward to the division the name and mailing address of the unit owner board member.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a developer holds units for sale in the ordinary course of business, none of the following actions may be taken without approval in writing by the developer:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessment of the developer as a unit owner for capital improvements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action by the association that would be detrimental to the sales of units by the developer. However, an increase in assessments for common expenses without discrimination against the developer shall not be deemed to be detrimental to the sales of units.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time that unit owners other than the developer elect a majority of the members of the board of administration of an association, the developer shall relinquish control of the association, and the unit owners shall accept control. Simultaneously, or for the purposes of paragraph (c) not more than 90 days thereafter, the developer shall deliver to the association, at the developer’s expense, all property of the unit owners and of the association which is held or controlled by the developer, including, but not limited to, the following items, if applicable, as to each condominium operated by the association:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original or a photocopy of the recorded declaration of condominium and all amendments thereto. If a photocopy is provided, it shall be certified by affidavit of the developer or an officer or agent of the developer as being a complete copy of the actual recorded declaration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the articles of incorporation of the association or, if the association was created prior to the effective date of this act and it is not incorporated, copies of the documents creating the association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the bylaws.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minute books, including all minutes, and other books and records of the association, if any.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any house rules and regulations which have been promulgated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resignations of officers and members of the board of administration who are required to resign because the developer is required to relinquish control of the association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial records, including financial statements of the association, and source documents from the incorporation of the association through the date of turnover. The records shall be audited for the period from the incorporation of the association or from the period covered by the last audit, if an audit has been performed for each fiscal year since incorporation, by an independent certified public accountant. All financial statements shall be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and shall be audited in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards, as prescribed by the Florida Board of Accountancy, pursuant to chapter 473. The accountant performing the audit shall examine to the extent necessary supporting documents and records, including the cash disbursements and related paid invoices to determine if expenditures were for association purposes and the billings, cash receipts, and related records to determine that the developer was charged and paid the proper amounts of assessments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Association funds or control thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All tangible personal property that is property of the association, which is represented by the developer to be part of the common elements or which is ostensibly part of the common elements, and an inventory of that property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the plans and specifications utilized in the construction or remodeling of improvements and the supplying of equipment to the condominium and in the construction and installation of all mechanical components serving the improvements and the site with a certificate in affidavit form of the developer or the developer’s agent or an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state that such plans and specifications represent, to the best of his or her knowledge and belief, the actual plans and specifications utilized in the construction and improvement of the condominium property and for the construction and installation of the mechanical components serving the improvements. If the condominium property has been declared a condominium more than 3 years after the completion of construction or remodeling of the improvements, the requirements of this paragraph do not apply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of the names and addresses, of which the developer had knowledge at any time in the development of the condominium, of all contractors, subcontractors, and suppliers utilized in the construction or remodeling of the improvements and in the landscaping of the condominium or association property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance policies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of any certificates of occupancy which may have been issued for the condominium property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other permits applicable to the condominium property which have been issued by governmental bodies and are in force or were issued within 1 year prior to the date the unit owners other than the developer take control of the association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All written warranties of the contractor, subcontractors, suppliers, and manufacturers, if any, that are still effective.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A roster of unit owners and their addresses and telephone numbers, if known, as shown on the developer’s records.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leases of the common elements and other leases to which the association is a party.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment contracts or service contracts in which the association is one of the contracting parties or service contracts in which the association or the unit owners have an obligation or responsibility, directly or indirectly, to pay some or all of the fee or charge of the person or persons performing the service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other contracts to which the association is a party.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report included in the official records, under seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state, attesting to required maintenance, useful life, and replacement costs of the following applicable common elements comprising a turnover inspection report:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Roof.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Structure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fireproofing and fire protection systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Elevators.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heating and cooling systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plumbing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electrical systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Swimming pool or spa and equipment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seawalls.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pavement and parking areas.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drainage systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Painting.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Irrigation systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the period prior to the time that the developer relinquishes control of the association pursuant to subsection (4), any provision of the Condominium Act or any rule promulgated thereunder is violated by the association, the developer is responsible for such violation and is subject to the administrative action provided in this chapter for such violation or violations and is liable for such violation or violations to third parties. This subsection is intended to clarify existing law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the developer relinquishing control of the association pursuant to subsection (4), actions taken by members of the board of administration designated by the developer are considered actions taken by the developer, and the developer is responsible to the association and its members for all such actions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any claim against a developer by an association alleging a defect in design, structural elements, construction, or any mechanical, electrical, fire protection, plumbing, or other element that requires a licensed professional for design or installation under chapter 455, chapter 471, chapter 481, chapter 489, or chapter 633, such defect must be examined and certified by an appropriately licensed Florida engineer, design professional, contractor, or otherwise licensed Florida individual or entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division has authority to adopt rules pursuant to the Administrative Procedure Act to ensure the efficient and effective transition from developer control of a condominium to the establishment of a unit-owner controlled association.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-222; s. 7, ch. 77-221; s. 10, ch. 79-314; s. 264, ch. 79-400; s. 4, ch. 81-185; s. 10, ch. 84-368; s. 3, ch. 88-148; s. 15, ch. 90-151; s. 12, ch. 91-103; s. 5, ch. 91-426; s. 9, ch. 92-49; s. 862, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 98-195; s. 1, ch. 2005-192; s. 17, ch. 2008-28; s. 15, ch. 2010-174.</History>
</Section>