<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Condominium parcels; appurtenances; possession and enjoyment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A condominium parcel created by the declaration is a separate parcel of real property, even though the condominium is created on a leasehold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall pass with a unit, as appurtenances thereto:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An undivided share in the common elements and common surplus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusive right to use such portion of the common elements as may be provided by the declaration, including the right to transfer such right to other units or unit owners to the extent authorized by the declaration as originally recorded, or amendments to the declaration adopted pursuant to the provisions contained therein. Amendments to declarations of condominium providing for the transfer of use rights with respect to limited common elements are not amendments that materially modify unit appurtenances as described in s. 718.110(4). However, in order to be effective, the transfer of use rights with respect to limited common elements must be effectuated in conformity with the procedures set forth in the declaration as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein. This section is intended to clarify existing law and applies to associations existing on the effective date of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An exclusive easement for the use of the airspace occupied by the unit as it exists at any particular time and as the unit may lawfully be altered or reconstructed from time to time. An easement in airspace which is vacated shall be terminated automatically.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership in the association designated in the declaration, with the full voting rights appertaining thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other appurtenances as may be provided in the declaration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit owner is entitled to the exclusive possession of his or her unit, subject to the provisions of s. 718.111(5). He or she is entitled to use the common elements in accordance with the purposes for which they are intended, but no use may hinder or encroach upon the lawful rights of other unit owners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a unit is leased, a tenant shall have all use rights in the association property and those common elements otherwise readily available for use generally by unit owners and the unit owner shall not have such rights except as a guest, unless such rights are waived in writing by the tenant. Nothing in this subsection shall interfere with the access rights of the unit owner as a landlord pursuant to chapter 83. The association shall have the right to adopt rules to prohibit dual usage by a unit owner and a tenant of association property and common elements otherwise readily available for use generally by unit owners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may not adopt an ordinance or regulation that prohibits condominium unit owners or their guests, licensees, or invitees from pedestrian access to a public beach contiguous to a condominium property, except where necessary to protect public health, safety, or natural resources. This subsection does not prohibit a governmental entity from enacting regulations governing activities taking place on the beach.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-222; s. 3, ch. 84-368; s. 4, ch. 90-151; s. 5, ch. 94-350; s. 853, ch. 97-102; s. 50, ch. 2000-302; s. 6, ch. 2002-27; s. 2, ch. 2007-173.</History></Section>