<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of administration; transfer of control.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, at the time the bulk assignee acquires title to the units and receives an assignment of developer rights, the developer has not relinquished control of the board of administration, for purposes of determining the timing for transfer of control of the board of administration of the association, a condominium parcel acquired by the bulk assignee is not deemed to be conveyed to a purchaser, or owned by an owner other than the developer, until the condominium parcel is conveyed to an owner who is not a bulk assignee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless control of the board of administration of the association has already been relinquished pursuant to s. 718.301(1), the bulk assignee must relinquish control of the association pursuant to s. 718.301 and this part, as if the bulk assignee were the developer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a bulk assignee relinquishes control of the board of administration as set forth in s. 718.301, the bulk assignee must deliver all of those items required by s. 718.301(4). However, the bulk assignee is not required to deliver items and documents not in the possession of the bulk assignee if some items were or should have been in existence before the bulk assignee’s acquisition of the units. In conjunction with the acquisition of units, a bulk assignee shall undertake a good faith effort to obtain the documents and materials that must be provided to the association pursuant to s. 718.301(4). If the bulk assignee is not able to obtain such documents and materials, the bulk assignee must certify in writing to the association the names or descriptions of the documents and materials that were not obtainable by the bulk assignee. Delivery of the certificate relieves the bulk assignee of responsibility for delivering the documents and materials referenced in the certificate as otherwise required under ss. 718.112 and 718.301 and this part. The responsibility of the bulk assignee for the audit required by s. 718.301(4) commences as of the date on which the bulk assignee elected or appointed a majority of the members of the board of administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a conflict arises between the provisions or application of this section and s. 718.301, this section prevails.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a bulk assignee or bulk buyer to substantially comply with all the requirements in this part results in the loss of any and all protections or exemptions provided under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2010-174; s. 11, ch. 2011-196.</History></Section>