<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maintenance; limitation upon improvement; display of flag; hurricane shutters; display of religious decorations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of the common elements is the responsibility of the association. The declaration may provide that certain limited common elements shall be maintained by those entitled to use the limited common elements or that the association shall provide the maintenance, either as a common expense or with the cost shared only by those entitled to use the limited common elements. If the maintenance is to be by the association at the expense of only those entitled to use the limited common elements, the declaration shall describe in detail the method of apportioning such costs among those entitled to use the limited common elements, and the association may use the provisions of s. 718.116 to enforce payment of the shares of such costs by the unit owners entitled to use the limited common elements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, there shall be no material alteration or substantial additions to the common elements or to real property which is association property, except in a manner provided in the declaration as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein. If the declaration as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein does not specify the procedure for approval of material alterations or substantial additions, 75 percent of the total voting interests of the association must approve the alterations or additions. This paragraph is intended to clarify existing law and applies to associations existing on October 1, 2008.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall not be any material alteration of, or substantial addition to, the common elements of any condominium operated by a multicondominium association unless approved in the manner provided in the declaration of the affected condominium or condominiums as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein. If a declaration as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein does not specify a procedure for approving such an alteration or addition, the approval of 75 percent of the total voting interests of each affected condominium is required. This subsection does not prohibit a provision in any declaration, articles of incorporation, or bylaws as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein requiring the approval of unit owners in any condominium operated by the same association or requiring board approval before a material alteration or substantial addition to the common elements is permitted. This paragraph is intended to clarify existing law and applies to associations existing on the effective date of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall not be any material alteration or substantial addition made to association real property operated by a multicondominium association, except as provided in the declaration, articles of incorporation, or bylaws as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein. If the declaration, articles of incorporation, or bylaws as originally recorded or as amended under the procedures provided therein do not specify the procedure for approving an alteration or addition to association real property, the approval of 75 percent of the total voting interests of the association is required. This paragraph is intended to clarify existing law and applies to associations existing on the effective date of this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit owner shall not do anything within his or her unit or on the common elements which would adversely affect the safety or soundness of the common elements or any portion of the association property or condominium property which is to be maintained by the association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unit owner may display one portable, removable United States flag in a respectful way and, on Armed Forces Day, Memorial Day, Flag Day, Independence Day, and Veterans Day, may display in a respectful way portable, removable official flags, not larger than 4<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> feet by 6 feet, that represent the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard, regardless of any declaration rules or requirements dealing with flags or decorations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of administration shall adopt hurricane shutter specifications for each building within each condominium operated by the association which shall include color, style, and other factors deemed relevant by the board. All specifications adopted by the board must comply with the applicable building code.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, subject to the provisions of s. 718.3026, and the approval of a majority of voting interests of the condominium, install hurricane shutters, impact glass or other code-compliant windows, or hurricane protection that complies with or exceeds the applicable building code. However, a vote of the owners is not required if the maintenance, repair, and replacement of hurricane shutters, impact glass, or other code-compliant windows are the responsibility of the association pursuant to the declaration of condominium. If hurricane protection or laminated glass or window film architecturally designed to function as hurricane protection which complies with or exceeds the current applicable building code has been previously installed, the board may not install hurricane shutters, hurricane protection, or impact glass or other code-compliant windows except upon approval by a majority vote of the voting interests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association is responsible for the maintenance, repair, and replacement of the hurricane shutters or other hurricane protection authorized by this subsection if such hurricane shutters or other hurricane protection is the responsibility of the association pursuant to the declaration of condominium. If the hurricane shutters or other hurricane protection authorized by this subsection are the responsibility of the unit owners pursuant to the declaration of condominium, the maintenance, repair, and replacement of such items are the responsibility of the unit owner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may operate shutters installed pursuant to this subsection without permission of the unit owners only if such operation is necessary to preserve and protect the condominium property and association property. The installation, replacement, operation, repair, and maintenance of such shutters in accordance with the procedures set forth in this paragraph are not a material alteration to the common elements or association property within the meaning of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision in the condominium documents, if approval is required by the documents, a board may not refuse to approve the installation or replacement of hurricane shutters by a unit owner conforming to the specifications adopted by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An association may not refuse the request of a unit owner for a reasonable accommodation for the attachment on the mantel or frame of the door of the unit owner of a religious object not to exceed 3 inches wide, 6 inches high, and 1.5 inches deep.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section or the governing documents of a condominium or a multicondominium association, the board of administration may, without any requirement for approval of the unit owners, install upon or within the common elements or association property solar collectors, clotheslines, or other energy-efficient devices based on renewable resources for the benefit of the unit owners.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-222; s. 1, ch. 89-161; s. 8, ch. 90-151; s. 6, ch. 91-103; s. 5, ch. 91-426; s. 4, ch. 92-49; s. 8, ch. 94-350; s. 43, ch. 95-274; s. 855, ch. 97-102; s. 54, ch. 2000-302; s. 10, ch. 2002-27; s. 1, ch. 2003-28; s. 9, ch. 2008-28; s. 26, ch. 2008-191; s. 89, ch. 2009-21; s. 59, ch. 2010-176; s. 4, ch. 2011-196.</History></Section>