<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.5012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ombudsman; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ombudsman shall have the powers that are necessary to carry out the duties of his or her office, including the following specific powers:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have access to and use of all files and records of the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To employ professional and clerical staff as necessary for the efficient operation of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare and issue reports and recommendations to the Governor, the department, the division, the Advisory Council on Condominiums, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives on any matter or subject within the jurisdiction of the division. The ombudsman shall make recommendations he or she deems appropriate for legislation relative to division procedures, rules, jurisdiction, personnel, and functions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as liaison between the division, unit owners, boards of directors, board members, community association managers, and other affected parties. The ombudsman shall develop policies and procedures to assist unit owners, boards of directors, board members, community association managers, and other affected parties to understand their rights and responsibilities as set forth in this chapter and the condominium documents governing their respective association. The ombudsman shall coordinate and assist in the preparation and adoption of educational and reference material, and shall endeavor to coordinate with private or volunteer providers of these services, so that the availability of these resources is made known to the largest possible audience.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To monitor and review procedures and disputes concerning condominium elections or meetings, including, but not limited to, recommending that the division pursue enforcement action in any manner where there is reasonable cause to believe that election misconduct has occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make recommendations to the division for changes in rules and procedures for the filing, investigation, and resolution of complaints filed by unit owners, associations, and managers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide resources to assist members of boards of directors and officers of associations to carry out their powers and duties consistent with this chapter, division rules, and the condominium documents governing the association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To encourage and facilitate voluntary meetings with and between unit owners, boards of directors, board members, community association managers, and other affected parties when the meetings may assist in resolving a dispute within a community association before a person submits a dispute for a formal or administrative remedy. It is the intent of the Legislature that the ombudsman act as a neutral resource for both the rights and responsibilities of unit owners, associations, and board members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist with the resolution of disputes between unit owners and the association or between unit owners when the dispute is not within the jurisdiction of the division to resolve.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifteen percent of the total voting interests in a condominium association, or six unit owners, whichever is greater, may petition the ombudsman to appoint an election monitor to attend the annual meeting of the unit owners and conduct the election of directors. The ombudsman shall appoint a division employee, a person or persons specializing in condominium election monitoring, or an attorney licensed to practice in this state as the election monitor. All costs associated with the election monitoring process shall be paid by the association. The division shall adopt a rule establishing procedures for the appointment of election monitors and the scope and extent of the monitor’s role in the election process.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 36, ch. 2004-345; s. 22, ch. 2008-28.</History></Section>