<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.616" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure of condition of building and estimated replacement costs and notification of municipalities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each developer of a residential condominium created by converting existing, previously occupied improvements to such form of ownership shall prepare a report that discloses the condition of the improvements and the condition of certain components and their current estimated replacement costs as of the date of the report.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information shall be stated concerning the improvements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and type of construction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prior use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether there is termite damage or infestation and whether the termite damage or infestation, if any, has been properly treated. The statement shall be substantiated by including, as an exhibit, an inspection report by a certified pest control operator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure of condition shall be made for each of the following components that the existing improvements may include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Roof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Structure.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire protection systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Elevators.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heating and cooling systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plumbing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electrical systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Swimming pool.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seawalls, pilings, and docks.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pavement and concrete, including roadways, walkways, and parking areas.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drainage systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Irrigation systems.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each component, the following information shall be disclosed and substantiated by attaching a copy of a certificate under seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The age of the component as of the date of the report.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated remaining useful life of the component as of the date of the report.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated current replacement cost of the component as of the date of the report, expressed:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a total amount; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a per-unit amount, based upon each unit’s proportional share of the common expenses.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The structural and functional soundness of the component.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each unit owner and the association are third-party beneficiaries of the report.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A supplemental report shall be prepared for any structure or component that is renovated or repaired after completion of the original report and prior to the recording of the declaration of condominium. If the declaration is not recorded within 1 year after the date of the original report, the developer shall update the report annually prior to recording the declaration of condominium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report may not contain representations on behalf of the development concerning future improvements or repairs and must be limited to the current condition of the improvements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the proposed condominium is situated within a municipality, the disclosure shall include a letter from the municipality acknowledging that the municipality has been notified of the proposed creation of a residential condominium by conversion of existing, previously occupied improvements and, in any county, as defined in s. 125.011(1), acknowledging compliance with applicable zoning requirements as determined by the municipality.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-3; s. 22, ch. 84-368; s. 14, ch. 94-350; s. 40, ch. 95-274; s. 5, ch. 96-396; s. 7, ch. 97-301; s. 9, ch. 2007-80.</History></Section>