<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of first refusal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each tenant, who for the 180 days preceding a notice of intended conversion has been a residential tenant of the existing improvements, shall have the right of first refusal to purchase the unit in which he or she resides on the date of the notice, under the following terms and conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days following the written notice of the intended conversion, the developer shall deliver to the tenant the following purchase materials: an offer to sell stating the price and terms of purchase, the economic information required by s. 718.614, and the disclosure documents required by ss. 718.503 and 718.504. The failure by the developer to deliver such purchase materials within 90 days following the written notice of the intended conversion will automatically extend the rental agreement, any extension of the rental agreement provided for in s. 718.606, or any other extension of the rental agreement. The extension shall be for that number of days in excess of 90 days that has elapsed from the date of the written notice of the intended conversion to the date when the purchase materials are delivered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tenant shall have the right of first refusal to purchase the unit for a period of not less than 45 days after mailing or personal delivery of the purchase materials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after any right of first refusal has expired, the developer offers the unit at a price lower than that offered to the tenant, the developer shall in writing notify the tenant prior to the publication of the offer. The tenant shall have the right of first refusal at the lower price for a period of not less than an additional 10 days after the date of the notice. Thereafter, the tenant shall have no additional right of first refusal. As used in this paragraph, the term “offer” includes any solicitation to the general public by means of newspaper advertisement, radio, television, or written or printed sales literature or price list but does not include a transaction involving the sale of more than one unit to one purchaser.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to closing on the sale of the unit, a tenant alleging a developer’s violation of paragraph (1)(c) may bring an action for equitable or other relief, including specific performance. Subsequent to closing, the tenant’s sole remedy for such a violation will be damages. In addition to any damages otherwise recoverable by law, the tenant is entitled to an amount equal to the difference between the price last offered in writing to the tenant pursuant to this section and the price at which the unit was sold to a third party, plus court costs and attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is against the public policy of this state for any developer to seek to enforce any provision of any contract which purports to waive the right of a purchasing tenant to bring an action for specific performance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tenant’s right of first refusal terminates upon:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The termination of the rental agreement and all extensions thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waiver of the right in writing by the tenant, if the waiver is executed subsequent to the date of the notice of intended conversion. A tenant who waives the right of first refusal waives the right to receive the purchase materials; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The running of the tenant’s 45-day right of first refusal and the additional 10-day period provided for by paragraph (1)(c), if applicable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-3; s. 478, ch. 81-259; s. 21, ch. 84-368; s. 873, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>