<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multicondominiums; multicondominium associations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An association may operate more than one condominium. For multicondominiums created on or after July 1, 2000, the declaration for each condominium to be operated by that association must provide for participation in a multicondominium, in conformity with this section, and disclose or describe:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner or formula by which the assets, liabilities, common surplus, and common expenses of the association will be apportioned among the units within the condominiums operated by the association, in accordance with s. 718.104(4)(g) or (h), as applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether unit owners in any other condominium, or any other persons, will or may have the right to use recreational areas or any other facilities or amenities that are common elements of the condominium, and, if so, the specific formula by which the other users will share the common expenses related to those facilities or amenities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recreational and other commonly used facilities or amenities which the developer has committed to provide that will be owned, leased by, or dedicated by a recorded plat to the association but which are not included within any condominium operated by the association. The developer may reserve the right to add additional facilities or amenities if the declaration and prospectus for each condominium to be operated by the association contains the following statement in conspicuous type and in substantially the following form: RECREATIONAL FACILITIES MAY BE EXPANDED OR ADDED WITHOUT CONSENT OF UNIT OWNERS OR THE ASSOCIATION.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The voting rights of the unit owners in the election of directors and in other multicondominium association affairs when a vote of the owners is taken, including, but not limited to, a statement as to whether each unit owner will have a right to personally cast his or her own vote in all matters voted upon.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any declaration requires a developer to convey additional lands or facilities to a multicondominium association and the developer fails to do so within the time specified, or within a reasonable time if none is specified in the declaration, any unit owner or the association may enforce that obligation against the developer or bring an action against the developer for specific performance or for damages that result from the developer’s failure or refusal to convey the additional lands or facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The declaration for each condominium to be operated by a multicondominium association may not, at the time of the initial recording of the declaration, contain any provision with respect to allocation of the association’s assets, liabilities, common surplus, or common expenses which is inconsistent with this chapter or the provisions of a declaration for any other condominium then being operated by the multicondominium association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prevent or restrict the formation of a multicondominium by the merger or consolidation of two or more condominium associations. Mergers or consolidations of associations shall be accomplished in accordance with this chapter, the declarations of the condominiums being merged or consolidated, and chapter 617. Section 718.110(4) does not apply to amendments to declarations necessary to effect a merger or consolidation. This section is intended to clarify existing law and applies to associations existing on the effective date of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 59, ch. 2000-302; s. 13, ch. 2002-27.</History></Section>