<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.120" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Separate taxation of condominium parcels; survival of declaration after tax sale; assessment of timeshare estates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ad valorem taxes, benefit taxes, and special assessments by taxing authorities shall be assessed against the condominium parcels and not upon the condominium property as a whole. No ad valorem tax, benefit tax, or special assessment, including those made by special districts, drainage districts, or water management districts, may be separately assessed against recreational facilities or other common elements if such facilities or common elements are owned by the condominium association or are owned jointly by the owners of the condominium parcels. Each condominium parcel shall be separately assessed for ad valorem taxes and special assessments as a single parcel. The taxes and special assessments levied against each condominium parcel shall constitute a lien only upon the condominium parcel assessed and upon no other portion of the condominium property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of a declaration relating to a condominium parcel which has been sold for taxes or special assessments survive and are enforceable after the issuance of a tax deed or master’s deed, upon foreclosure of an assessment, a certificate or lien, a tax deed, tax certificate, or tax lien, to the same extent that they would be enforceable against a voluntary grantee of the title immediately prior to the delivery of the tax deed, master’s deed, or clerk’s certificate of title as provided in s. 197.573.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Condominium property divided into fee timeshare real property shall be assessed for purposes of ad valorem taxes and special assessments as provided in s. 192.037.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-222; s. 58, ch. 82-226; s. 1, ch. 84-261; s. 217, ch. 85-342; s. 4, ch. 91-116.</History></Section>