<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.606" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conversion of existing improvements to condominium; rental agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When existing improvements are converted to ownership as a residential condominium:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each residential tenant who has resided in the existing improvements for at least the 180 days preceding the date of the written notice of intended conversion shall have the right to extend an expiring rental agreement upon the same terms for a period that will expire no later than 270 days after the date of the notice. If the rental agreement expires more than 270 days after the date of the notice, the tenant may not unilaterally extend the rental agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each other residential tenant shall have the right to extend an expiring rental agreement upon the same terms for a period that will expire no later than 180 days after the date of the written notice of intended conversion. If the rental agreement expires more than 180 days after the date of the notice, the tenant may not unilaterally extend the rental agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to extend the rental agreement as provided in subsection (1), a tenant shall, within 45 days after the date of the written notice of intended conversion, give written notice to the developer of the intention to extend the rental agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rental agreement will expire within 45 days following the date of the notice, the tenant may remain in occupancy for the 45-day decision period upon the same terms by giving the developer written notice and paying rent on a pro rata basis from the expiration date of the rental agreement to the end of the 45-day period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tenant may extend the rental agreement for the full extension period or a part of the period.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the date of a notice of intended conversion, a tenant may terminate any rental agreement, or any extension period having an unexpired term of 180 days or less, upon 30 days’ written notice to the developer. However, unless the rental agreement was entered into, extended, or renewed after the effective date of this part, the tenant may not unilaterally terminate the rental agreement but may unilaterally terminate any extension period having an unexpired term of 180 days or less upon 30 days’ written notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer may elect to provide tenants who have been continuous residents of the existing improvements for at least 180 days preceding the date of the written notice of intended conversion and whose rental agreements expire within 180 days of the date of the written notice of intended conversion the option of receiving in cash a tenant relocation payment at least equal to 1 month’s rent in consideration for extending the rental agreement for not more than 180 days, rather than extending the rental agreement for up to 270 days.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rental agreement may provide for termination by the developer upon 60 days’ written notice if the rental agreement is entered into subsequent to the delivery of the written notice of intended conversion to all tenants and conspicuously states that the existing improvements are to be converted. No other provision in a rental agreement shall be enforceable to the extent that it purports to reduce the extension period provided by this section or otherwise would permit a developer to terminate a rental agreement in the event of a conversion. This subsection applies to rental agreements entered into, extended, or renewed after the effective date of this part; the termination provisions of all other rental agreements are governed by the provisions of s. 718.402(3), Florida Statutes 1979.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision of this section or of the rental agreement or other contract or agreement to the contrary notwithstanding, whenever a county, including a charter county, determines that there exists within the county a vacancy rate in rental housing of 3 percent or less, the county may adopt an ordinance or other measure extending the 270-day extension period described in paragraph (1)(a) and the 180-day extension described in paragraph (1)(b) for an additional 90 days, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such measure was duly adopted, after notice and public hearing, in accordance with all applicable provisions of the charter governing the county and any other applicable laws; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body has made and recited in such measure its findings establishing the existence in fact of a housing emergency so grave as to constitute a serious menace to the general public and that such controls are necessary and proper to eliminate such grave housing emergency.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A county ordinance or other measure adopting an additional 90-day extension under the provisions of this section is controlling throughout the entire county, including a charter county, where adopted, including all municipalities, unless a municipality votes not to have it apply within its boundaries.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-3; s. 20, ch. 84-368.</History></Section>