<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.50155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service of process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the methods of service provided for in the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure and the Florida Statutes, service may be made and shall be binding upon the defendant or respondent if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division, which is acting as the petitioner or plaintiff, immediately sends a copy of the process and of the pleading by certified mail to the defendant or respondent at his or her last known address; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division files an affidavit of compliance with this section on or before the return date of the process or within the time set by the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person, including any nonresident of this state, allegedly engages in conduct prohibited by this chapter, or any rule or order of the division, and has not filed a consent to service of process, and personal jurisdiction over him or her cannot otherwise be obtained in this state, the director shall be authorized to receive service of process in any noncriminal proceeding against that person or his or her successor which grows out of the conduct and which is brought by the division under this chapter or any rule or order of the division. The process shall have the same force and validity as if personally served. Notice shall be given as provided in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 67-229; s. 2, ch. 71-98; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 26, 30, 32, ch. 79-347; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 26, 33, 34, ch. 88-90; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 581, ch. 97-103; s. 37, ch. 2008-240.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 478.29; s. 498.057.</Text></Note></Section>