<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.703" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bulk assignee” means a person who is not a bulk buyer and who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquires more than seven condominium parcels in a single condominium as set forth in s. 718.707; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receives an assignment of any of the developer rights, other than or in addition to those rights described in subsection (2), as set forth in the declaration of condominium or this chapter:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a written instrument recorded as part of or as an exhibit to the deed;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a separate instrument recorded in the public records of the county in which the condominium is located; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to a final judgment or certificate of title issued in favor of a purchaser at a foreclosure sale.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A mortgagee or its assignee may not be deemed a bulk assignee or a developer by reason of the acquisition of condominium units and receipt of an assignment of some or all of a developer’s rights unless the mortgagee or its assignee exercises any of the developer rights other than those described in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bulk buyer” means a person who acquires more than seven condominium parcels in a single condominium as set forth in s. 718.707, but who does not receive an assignment of any developer rights, or receives only some or all of the following rights:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to conduct sales, leasing, and marketing activities within the condominium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to be exempt from the payment of working capital contributions to the condominium association arising out of, or in connection with, the bulk buyer’s acquisition of the units; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to be exempt from any rights of first refusal which may be held by the condominium association and would otherwise be applicable to subsequent transfers of title from the bulk buyer to a third party purchaser concerning one or more units.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2010-174; s. 9, ch. 2011-196.</History></Section>