<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.122" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unconscionability of certain leases; rebuttable presumption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lease pertaining to use by condominium unit owners of recreational or other common facilities, irrespective of the date on which such lease was entered into, is presumptively unconscionable if all of the following elements exist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease was executed by persons none of whom at the time of the execution of the lease were elected by condominium unit owners, other than the developer, to represent their interests;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease requires either the condominium association or the condominium unit owners to pay real estate taxes on the subject real property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease requires either the condominium association or the condominium unit owners to insure buildings or other facilities on the subject real property against fire or any other hazard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease requires either the condominium association or the condominium unit owners to perform some or all maintenance obligations pertaining to the subject real property or facilities located upon the subject real property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease requires either the condominium association or the condominium unit owners to pay rents to the lessor for a period of 21 years or more;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease provides that failure of the lessee to make payments of rents due under the lease either creates, establishes, or permits establishment of a lien upon individual condominium units of the condominium to secure claims for rent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease requires an annual rental which exceeds 25 percent of the appraised value of the leased property as improved, provided that, for purposes of this paragraph, “annual rental” means the amount due during the first 12 months of the lease for all units, regardless of whether such units were in fact occupied or sold during that period, and “appraised value” means the appraised value placed upon the leased property the first tax year after the sale of a unit in the condominium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease provides for a periodic rental increase; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease or other condominium documents require that every transferee of a condominium unit must assume obligations under the lease.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature expressly finds that many leases involving use of recreational or other common facilities by residents of condominiums were entered into by parties wholly representative of the interests of a condominium developer at a time when the condominium unit owners not only did not control the administration of their condominium, but also had little or no voice in such administration. Such leases often contain numerous obligations on the part of either or both a condominium association and condominium unit owners with relatively few obligations on the part of the lessor. Such leases may or may not be unconscionable in any given case. Nevertheless, the Legislature finds that a combination of certain onerous obligations and circumstances warrants the establishment of a rebuttable presumption of unconscionability of certain leases, as specified in subsection (1). The presumption may be rebutted by a lessor upon the showing of additional facts and circumstances to justify and validate what otherwise appears to be an unconscionable lease under this section. Failure of a lease to contain all the enumerated elements shall neither preclude a determination of unconscionability of the lease nor raise a presumption as to its conscionability. It is the intent of the Legislature that this section is remedial and does not create any new cause of action to invalidate any condominium lease, but shall operate as a statutory prescription on procedural matters in actions brought on one or more causes of action existing at the time of the execution of such lease.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision of the Florida Statutes to the contrary notwithstanding, neither the statute of limitations nor laches shall prohibit unit owners from maintaining a cause of action under the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 77-221; s. 11, ch. 94-350.</History></Section>