<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0718.4015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Condominium leases; escalation clauses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared that the public policy of this state prohibits the inclusion or enforcement of escalation clauses in land leases or other leases or agreements for recreational facilities, land, or other commonly used facilities serving residential condominiums, and such clauses are hereby declared void for public policy. For the purposes of this section, an escalation clause is any clause in a condominium lease or agreement which provides that the rental under the lease or agreement shall increase at the same percentage rate as any nationally recognized and conveniently available commodity or consumer price index.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This public policy prohibits the inclusion or enforcement of such escalation clauses in leases related to condominiums for which the declaration of condominium was recorded on or after June 4, 1975; it prohibits the enforcement of escalation clauses in leases related to condominiums for which the declaration of condominium was recorded prior to June 4, 1975, but which have been refused enforcement on the grounds that the parties agreed to be bound by subsequent amendments to the Florida Statutes or which have been found to be void because of a finding that such lease is unconscionable or which have been refused enforcement on the basis of the application of former s. 711.231 or former s. 718.401(8); and it prohibits any further escalation of rental fees after October 1, 1988, pursuant to escalation clauses in leases related to condominiums for which the declaration was recorded prior to June 4, 1975.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply if the lessor is the Government of the United States or this state or any political subdivision thereof or any agency of any political subdivision thereof.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 88-148; s. 2, ch. 88-225; s. 1, ch. 89-164.</History></Section>