<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0713.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Waiver or release of liens.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acceptance by the lienor of an unsecured note for all or any part of the amount of his or her demand shall not constitute a waiver of his or her lien therefor unless expressly so agreed in writing, nor shall it in any way affect the period for filing the notice under s. 713.06(2), or the claim of lien under s. 713.08.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A right to claim a lien may not be waived in advance. A lien right may be waived only to the extent of labor, services, or materials furnished. Any waiver of a right to claim a lien that is made in advance is unenforceable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may at any time waive, release, or satisfy any part of his or her lien under this part, either as to the amount due for labor, services, or materials furnished or for labor, services, or materials furnished through a certain date subject to exceptions specified at the time of release, or as to any part or parcel of the real property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a lienor is required to execute a waiver or release of lien in exchange for, or to induce payment of, a progress payment, the waiver or release may be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">WAIVER AND RELEASE OF LIEN<NewLine />UPON PROGRESS PAYMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The undersigned lienor, in consideration of the sum of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, hereby waives and releases its lien and right to claim a lien for labor, services, or materials furnished through <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert date)</Directions> to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of your customer)</Directions> on the job of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of the owner)</Directions> to the following property:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(description of property)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">This waiver and release does not cover any retention or labor, services, or materials furnished after the date specified.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">DATED on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.<FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Lienor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">By: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a lienor is required to execute a waiver or release of lien in exchange for, or to induce payment of, the final payment, the waiver and release may be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">WAIVER AND RELEASE OF LIEN<NewLine />UPON FINAL PAYMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The undersigned lienor, in consideration of the final payment in the amount of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, hereby waives and releases its lien and right to claim a lien for labor, services, or materials furnished to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of your customer)</Directions> on the job of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of the owner)</Directions> to the following described property:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(description of property)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">DATED on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.<FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Lienor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">By: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not require a lienor to furnish a lien waiver or release of lien that is different from the forms in subsection (4) or subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lienor who executes a lien waiver and release in exchange for a check may condition the waiver and release on payment of the check. However, in the absence of a payment bond protecting the owner, the owner may withhold from any payment to the contractor the amount of any such unpaid check until any such condition is satisfied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lien waiver or lien release that is not substantially similar to the forms in subsections (4) and (5) is enforceable in accordance with the terms of the lien waiver or lien release.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-135; s. 35, ch. 67-254; s. 5, ch. 88-397; s. 8, ch. 96-383; s. 1769, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 97-219; s. 30, ch. 99-6.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 84.202.</Text></Note></Section>