<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0713.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Demand for copy of contract and statements of account; form.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the contract of a lienor or owner and a statement of the amount due or to become due if fixed or ascertainable thereon must be furnished by any party thereto, upon written demand of an owner or a lienor contracting with or employed by the other party to such contract. If the owner or lienor refuses or neglects to furnish such copy of the contract or such statement, or willfully and falsely states the amount due or to become due if fixed or ascertainable under such contract, any person who suffers any detriment thereby has a cause of action against the person refusing or neglecting to furnish the same or willfully and falsely stating the amount due or to become due for his or her damages sustained thereby. The information contained in such copy or statement furnished pursuant to such written demand is binding upon the owner or lienor furnishing it unless actual notice of any modification is given to the person demanding the copy or statement before such person acts in good faith in reliance on it. The person demanding such documents must pay for the reproduction thereof; and, if such person fails or refuses to do so, he or she is entitled only to inspect such documents at reasonable times and places.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner may serve in writing a demand of any lienor for a written statement under oath of his or her account showing the nature of the labor or services performed and to be performed, if any, the materials furnished, the materials to be furnished, if known, the amount paid on account to date, the amount due, and the amount to become due, if known, as of the date of the statement by the lienor. Any such demand to a lienor must be served on the lienor at the address and to the attention of any person who is designated to receive the demand in the notice to owner served by such lienor and must include a description of the property and the names of the owner, the contractor, and the lienor’s customer, as set forth in the lienor’s notice to owner. The failure or refusal to furnish the statement does not deprive the lienor of his or her lien if the demand is not served at the address of the lienor or directed to the attention of the person designated to receive the demand in the notice to owner. The failure or refusal to furnish the statement under oath within 30 days after the demand, or the furnishing of a false or fraudulent statement, deprives the person so failing or refusing to furnish such statement of his or her lien. If the owner serves more than one demand for statement of account on a lienor and none of the information regarding the account has changed since the lienor’s last response to a demand, the failure or refusal to furnish such statement does not deprive the lienor of his or her lien. The negligent inclusion or omission of any information deprives the person of his or her lien to the extent the owner can demonstrate prejudice from such act or omission by the lienor. The failure to furnish a response to a demand for statement of account does not affect the validity of any claim of lien being enforced through a foreclosure case filed before the date the demand for statement is received by the lienor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request for sworn statement of account must be in substantially the following form:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">REQUEST FOR SWORN STATEMENT OF ACCOUNT</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">WARNING: YOUR FAILURE TO FURNISH THE REQUESTED STATEMENT, SIGNED UNDER OATH, WITHIN 30 DAYS OR THE FURNISHING OF A FALSE STATEMENT WILL RESULT IN THE LOSS OF YOUR LIEN.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">To: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Lienor’s name and address)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The undersigned hereby demands a written statement under oath of his or her account showing the nature of the labor or services performed and to be performed, if any, the materials furnished, the materials to be furnished, if known, the amount paid on account to date, the amount due, and the amount to become due, if known, as of the date of the statement for the improvement of real property identified as <Directions xml:space="preserve">(property description)</Directions>.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of contractor)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of the lienor’s customer, as set forth in the lienor’s Notice to Owner, if such notice has been served)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(signature and address of owner)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(date of request for sworn statement of account)</Directions></Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a contractor has furnished a payment bond pursuant to s. 713.23, he or she may, when an owner makes any payment to the contractor or directly to a lienor, serve a written demand on any other lienor for a written statement under oath of his or her account showing the nature of the labor or services performed and to be performed, if any, the materials furnished, the materials to be furnished, if known, the amount paid on account to date, the amount due, and the amount to become due, if known, as of the date of the statement by the lienor. Any such demand to a lienor must be served on the lienor at the address and to the attention of any person who is designated to receive the demand in the notice to contractor served by such lienor. The demand must include a description of the property and the names of the owner, the contractor, and the lienor’s customer, as set forth in the lienor’s notice to contractor. The failure or refusal to furnish the statement does not deprive the lienor of his or her rights under the bond if the demand is not served at the address of the lienor or directed to the attention of the person designated to receive the demand in the notice to contractor. The failure to furnish the statement within 30 days after the demand, or the furnishing of a false or fraudulent statement, deprives the person who fails to furnish the statement, or who furnishes the false or fraudulent statement, of his or her rights under the bond. If the contractor serves more than one demand for statement of account on a lienor and none of the information regarding the account has changed since the lienor’s last response to a demand, the failure or refusal to furnish such statement does not deprive the lienor of his or her rights under the bond. The negligent inclusion or omission of any information deprives the person of his or her rights under the bond to the extent the contractor can demonstrate prejudice from such act or omission by the lienor. The failure to furnish a response to a demand for statement of account does not affect the validity of any claim on the bond being enforced in a lawsuit filed prior to the date the demand for statement of account is received by the lienor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lienor who is perfecting a claim of lien may serve with the claim of lien or thereafter a written demand on the owner for a written statement under oath showing:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the direct contract under which the lien was recorded;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dates and amounts paid or to be paid by or on behalf of the owner for all improvements described in the direct contract;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonable estimated costs of completing the direct contract under which the lien was claimed pursuant to the scope of the direct contract; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If known, the actual cost of completion.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any owner who does not provide the statement within 30 days after demand, or who provides a false or fraudulent statement, is not a prevailing party for purposes of an award of attorney fees under s. 713.29. The written demand must include the following warning in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">WARNING: YOUR FAILURE TO FURNISH THE REQUESTED STATEMENT WITHIN 30 DAYS OR THE FURNISHING OF A FALSE STATEMENT WILL RESULT IN THE LOSS OF YOUR RIGHT TO RECOVER ATTORNEY FEES IN ANY ACTION TO ENFORCE THE CLAIM OF LIEN OF THE PERSON REQUESTING THIS STATEMENT.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any written demand served on the owner must include a description of the property and the names of the contractor and the lienor’s customer, as set forth in the lienor’s notice to owner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “information” means the nature and quantity of the labor, services, and materials furnished or to be furnished by a lienor and the amount paid, the amount due, and the amount to become due on the lienor’s account.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-135; s. 10, ch. 65-456; s. 35, ch. 67-254; s. 8, ch. 77-353; s. 10, ch. 90-109; s. 6, ch. 92-286; s. 319, ch. 94-119; s. 6, ch. 96-383; s. 1767, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 99-386; s. 10, ch. 2007-221; s. 8, ch. 2012-211.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 84.161.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>