<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0713.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of commencement and applicability of lien.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any person applies for a building permit, the authority issuing such permit shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Print on the face of each permit card in no less than 14-point, capitalized, boldfaced type: “WARNING TO OWNER: YOUR FAILURE TO RECORD A NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT MAY RESULT IN YOUR PAYING TWICE FOR IMPROVEMENTS TO YOUR PROPERTY. A NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT MUST BE RECORDED AND POSTED ON THE JOB SITE BEFORE THE FIRST INSPECTION. IF YOU INTEND TO OBTAIN FINANCING, CONSULT WITH YOUR LENDER OR AN ATTORNEY BEFORE RECORDING YOUR NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the applicant and the owner of the real property upon which improvements are to be constructed with a printed statement stating that the right, title, and interest of the person who has contracted for the improvement may be subject to attachment under the Construction Lien Law. The Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall furnish, for distribution, the statement described in this paragraph, and the statement must be a summary of the Construction Lien Law and must include an explanation of the provisions of the Construction Lien Law relating to the recording, and the posting of copies, of notices of commencement and a statement encouraging the owner to record a notice of commencement and post a copy of the notice of commencement in accordance with s. 713.13. The statement must also contain an explanation of the owner’s rights if a lienor fails to furnish the owner with a notice as provided in s. 713.06(2) and an explanation of the owner’s rights as provided in s. 713.22. The authority that issues the building permit must obtain from the Department of Business and Professional Regulation the statement required by this paragraph and must mail, deliver by electronic mail or other electronic format or facsimile, or personally deliver that statement to the owner or, in a case in which the owner is required to personally appear to obtain the permit, provide that statement to any owner making improvements to real property consisting of a single or multiple family dwelling up to and including four units. However, the failure by the authorities to provide the summary does not subject the issuing authority to liability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to providing the owner with the statement as required by paragraph (b), inform each applicant who is not the person whose right, title, and interest is subject to attachment that, as a condition to the issuance of a building permit, the applicant must promise in good faith that the statement will be delivered to the person whose property is subject to attachment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish to the applicant two or more copies of a form of notice of commencement conforming with s. 713.13. If the direct contract is greater than $2,500, the applicant shall file with the issuing authority prior to the first inspection either a certified copy of the recorded notice of commencement or a notarized statement that the notice of commencement has been filed for recording, along with a copy thereof. In the absence of the filing of a certified copy of the recorded notice of commencement, the issuing authority or a private provider performing inspection services may not perform or approve subsequent inspections until the applicant files by mail, facsimile, hand delivery, or any other means such certified copy with the issuing authority. The certified copy of the notice of commencement must contain the name and address of the owner, the name and address of the contractor, and the location or address of the property being improved. The issuing authority shall verify that the name and address of the owner, the name of the contractor, and the location or address of the property being improved which is contained in the certified copy of the notice of commencement is consistent with the information in the building permit application. The issuing authority shall provide the recording information on the certified copy of the recorded notice of commencement to any person upon request. This subsection does not require the recording of a notice of commencement prior to the issuance of a building permit. If a local government requires a separate permit or inspection for installation of temporary electrical service or other temporary utility service, land clearing, or other preliminary site work, such permits may be issued and such inspections may be conducted without providing the issuing authority with a certified copy of a recorded notice of commencement or a notarized statement regarding a recorded notice of commencement. This subsection does not apply to a direct contract to repair or replace an existing heating or air-conditioning system in an amount less than $7,500.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not require that a notice of commencement be recorded as a condition of the application for, or processing or issuance of, a building permit. However, this paragraph does not modify or waive the inspection requirements set forth in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An issuing authority under subsection (1) is not liable in any civil action for the failure of the person whose property is subject to attachment to receive or to be delivered a printed statement stating that the right, title, and interest of the person who has contracted for the improvement may be subject to attachment under the Construction Lien Law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An issuing authority under subsection (1) is not liable in any civil action for the failure to verify that a certified copy of the recorded notice of commencement has been filed in accordance with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The several boards of county commissioners, municipal councils, or other similar bodies may by ordinance or resolution establish reasonable fees for furnishing copies of the forms and the printed statement provided in paragraphs (1)(b) and (d) in an amount not to exceed $5 to be paid by the applicant for each permit in addition to all other costs of the permit; however, no forms or statement need be furnished, mailed, or otherwise provided to, nor may such additional fee be obtained from, applicants for permits in those cases in which the owner of a legal or equitable interest (including that of ownership of stock of a corporate landowner) of the real property to be improved is engaged in the business of construction of buildings for sale to others and intends to make the improvements authorized by the permit on the property and upon completion will offer the improved real property for sale.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other information required by the authority issuing the permit, each building permit application must contain:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner of the real property;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the contractor;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description sufficient to identify the real property to be improved; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number or identifying symbol assigned to the building permit by the issuing authority, which number or symbol must be affixed to the application by the issuing authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other information required by the authority issuing the permit, the building permit application must be in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true">Tax Folio No.<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">BUILDING PERMIT APPLICATION</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Owner’s Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Owner’s Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Fee Simple Titleholder’s Name (If other than owner)<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Fee Simple Titleholder’s Address (If other than owner)<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">City<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">State<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Zip<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Contractor’s Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Contractor’s Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">City<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">State<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Zip<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Job Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Job Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">City<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><FlushRight />County<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Legal Description<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Bonding Company<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Bonding Company Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">City<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> State<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Architect/Engineer’s Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Architect/Engineer’s Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Mortgage Lender’s Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Mortgage Lender’s Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Application is hereby made to obtain a permit to do the work and installations as indicated. I certify that no work or installation has commenced prior to the issuance of a permit and that all work will be performed to meet the standards of all laws regulating construction in this jurisdiction. I understand that a separate permit must be secured for ELECTRICAL WORK, PLUMBING, SIGNS, WELLS, POOLS, FURNACES, BOILERS, HEATERS, TANKS, and AIR CONDITIONERS, etc.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">OWNER’S AFFIDAVIT: I certify that all the foregoing information is accurate and that all work will be done in compliance with all applicable laws regulating construction and zoning.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">WARNING TO OWNER: YOUR FAILURE TO RECORD A NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT MAY RESULT IN YOUR PAYING TWICE FOR IMPROVEMENTS TO YOUR PROPERTY. A NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT MUST BE RECORDED AND POSTED ON THE JOB SITE BEFORE THE FIRST INSPECTION.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">IF YOU INTEND TO OBTAIN FINANCING, CONSULT WITH YOUR LENDER OR AN ATTORNEY BEFORE COMMENCING WORK OR RECORDING YOUR NOTICE OF COMMENCEMENT.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Owner or Agent)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(including contractor)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Contractor)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">(Certificate of Competency Holder)</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Contractor’s State Certification or Registration No.<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Contractor’s Certificate of Competency No.<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">APPLICATION APPROVED BY<NewLine /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />Permit Officer</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consistent with the requirements of paragraph (a), an authority responsible for issuing building permits under this section may accept a building permit application in an electronic format, as prescribed by the authority. Building permit applications submitted to the authority electronically must contain the following additional statement in lieu of the requirement in paragraph (a) that a signed, sworn, and notarized signature of the owner or agent and the contractor be part of the owner’s affidavit:</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">OWNER’S ELECTRONIC SUBMISSION STATEMENT: Under penalty of perjury, I declare that all the information contained in this building permit application is true and correct.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of implementing a “United States Department of Energy SunShot Initiative: Rooftop Solar Challenge” grant and the participation of county and municipal governments, including local permitting agencies under the jurisdiction of such county and municipal governments, an owner or contractor shall not be required to personally appear and provide a notarized signature when filing a building permit application, if such building permit application will be electronically submitted to the permitting authority, the application relates to a solar project, and the owner or contractor certifies the application, consistent with this paragraph, using the permitting authority’s electronic confirmation system. For purposes of this subsection, a “solar project” means installing, uninstalling, or replacing solar panels on single-family residential property, multifamily residential property, or commercial property.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authority responsible for issuing building permit applications which accepts building permit applications in an electronic format shall provide public Internet access to the electronic building permit applications in a searchable format.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authority responsible for issuing building permits which accepts building permit applications in an electronic format for solar projects, as defined in subparagraph (b)2., is not liable in any civil action for any inaccurate information submitted by an owner or contractor using the authority’s electronic confirmation system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to every municipality and county in the state which now has or hereafter may have a system of issuing building permits for the construction of improvements or for the alteration or repair of improvements on or to real property located within the geographic limits of the issuing authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 67-185; s. 2, ch. 78-397; s. 1, ch. 84-26; s. 1, ch. 86-247; s. 4, ch. 87-74; s. 8, ch. 90-109; s. 3, ch. 91-102; s. 2, ch. 93-99; s. 230, ch. 94-218; s. 5, ch. 96-383; s. 4, ch. 97-219; s. 15, ch. 98-246; s. 71, ch. 99-5; s. 5, ch. 99-386; s. 5, ch. 2003-177; s. 2, ch. 2006-187; s. 9, ch. 2007-221; s. 18, ch. 2012-13.</History>
</Section>