<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0713.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discharge of lien.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lien properly perfected under <Reference Number="1" />this chapter may be discharged by any of the following methods:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By entering satisfaction of the lien upon the margin of the record thereof in the clerk’s office when not otherwise prohibited by law. This satisfaction shall be signed by the lienor, the lienor’s agent or attorney and attested by said clerk. Any person who executes a claim of lien shall have authority to execute a satisfaction in the absence of actual notice of lack of authority to any person relying on the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the satisfaction of the lienor, duly acknowledged and recorded in the clerk’s office. Any person who executes a claim of lien shall have authority to execute a satisfaction in the absence of actual notice of lack of authority to any person relying on the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By failure to begin an action to enforce the lien within the time prescribed in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By an order of the circuit court of the county where the property is located, as provided in this subsection. Upon filing a complaint therefor by any interested party the clerk shall issue a summons to the lienor to show cause within 20 days why his or her lien should not be enforced by action or vacated and canceled of record. Upon failure of the lienor to show cause why his or her lien should not be enforced or the lienor’s failure to commence such action before the return date of the summons the court shall forthwith order cancellation of the lien.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By recording in the clerk’s office the original or a certified copy of a judgment or decree of a court of competent jurisdiction showing a final determination of the action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-135; s. 35, ch. 67-254; s. 810, ch. 97-102.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The language “this chapter” predates inclusion of this material in chapter 713 and, when initially included in this section’s text, referred to former chapter 84, Mechanics Liens. The Florida Uniform Federal Lien Registration Act was enacted without reference to statutory placement by ch. 92-25, Laws of Florida, and was added as part IV of chapter 713 by the Division of Statutory Revision.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 84.211.</Text></Note></Section>