<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0713.235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Waivers of right to claim against payment bond; forms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person is required to execute a waiver of his or her right to make a claim against a payment bond provided pursuant to s. 713.23 or s. 713.245, in exchange for, or to induce payment of, a progress payment, the waiver may be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">WAIVER OF RIGHT TO CLAIM<NewLine />AGAINST THE PAYMENT BOND<NewLine />(PROGRESS PAYMENT)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The undersigned, in consideration of the sum of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> hereby waives its right to claim against the payment bond for labor, services, or materials furnished through <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert date)</Directions>, to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of your customer)</Directions> on the job of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of the owner)</Directions>, for improvements to the following described project:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">(description of project)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">This waiver does not cover any retention or any labor, services, or materials furnished after the date specified.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">DATED on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Lienor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">By:<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person is required to execute a waiver of his or her right to make a claim against a payment bond provided pursuant to s. 713.23 or s. 713.245, in exchange for, or to induce payment of, the final payment, the waiver may be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">WAIVER OF RIGHT TO CLAIM<NewLine />AGAINST THE PAYMENT BOND<NewLine />(FINAL PAYMENT)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The undersigned, in consideration of the final payment in the amount of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, hereby waives its right to claim against the payment bond for labor, services, or materials furnished to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of your customer)</Directions> on the job of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(insert the name of the owner)</Directions>, for improvements to the following described project:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">(description of project)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">DATED on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Lienor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">By:<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not require a claimant to furnish a waiver that is different from the forms in subsections (1) and (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who executes a waiver in exchange for a check may condition the waiver on payment of the check.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A waiver that is not substantially similar to the forms in this section is enforceable in accordance with its terms.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 98-135.</History></Section>