<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0738.703" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfers from income to principal for depreciation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, “depreciation” means a reduction in value due to wear, tear, decay, corrosion, or gradual obsolescence of a fixed asset having a useful life of more than 1 year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiduciary may transfer to principal a reasonable amount of the net cash receipts from a principal asset that is subject to depreciation but may not transfer any amount for depreciation:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of that portion of real property used or available for use by a beneficiary as a residence or of tangible personal property held or made available for the personal use or enjoyment of a beneficiary;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the administration of a decedent’s estate; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under this section if the fiduciary is accounting under s. 738.403 for the business or activity in which the asset is used.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of depreciation taken for tax purposes with respect to an asset shall be presumed to be a reasonable amount of depreciation. An amount taken for depreciation shall not be considered unreasonable solely because it is greater or less than the amount taken for tax purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount transferred to principal need not be held as a separate fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-42; s. 29, ch. 2012-49.</History>
</Section>