<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0738.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distribution to residuary and remainder beneficiaries.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each beneficiary described in s. 738.201(4) is entitled to receive a portion of the net income remaining after the application of s. 738.201(1)-(3), which is equal to the beneficiary’s fractional interest in undistributed principal assets, using carrying values as of the distribution date. If a fiduciary makes more than one distribution of assets to beneficiaries to whom this section applies, each beneficiary, including one who does not receive part of the distribution, is entitled, as of each distribution date, to the net income the fiduciary received after the date of death or terminating event or earlier distribution date but has not distributed as of the current distribution date.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining a beneficiary’s share of net income, the following applies:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary is entitled to receive a portion of the net income equal to the beneficiary’s fractional interest in the carrying value of the undistributed principal assets immediately before the distribution date, excluding the amount of unpaid liabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary’s fractional interest in the undistributed principal assets shall be calculated:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the interest began and adjusted for any disproportionate distributions since the interest began;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By excluding any liabilities of the estate or trust from the calculation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By also excluding property specifically given to a beneficiary and property required to pay pecuniary amounts not in trust; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the basis of the aggregate carrying value of those assets determined under subsection (1) as of the distribution date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a disproportionate distribution of principal is made to any beneficiary, the respective fractional interests of all beneficiaries in the remaining underlying assets shall be recomputed by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjusting the carrying value of the principal assets to their fair market value before the distribution;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reducing the fractional interest of the recipient of the disproportionate distribution in the remaining principal assets by the fair market value of the principal distribution; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recomputing the fractional interests of all beneficiaries in the remaining principal assets based upon the now restated carrying values.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a fiduciary does not distribute all of the collected but undistributed net income to each person as of a distribution date, the fiduciary shall maintain appropriate records showing the interest of each beneficiary in that net income.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiduciary may apply the provisions of this section, to the extent the fiduciary considers appropriate, to net gain or loss realized after the date of death or terminating event or earlier distribution date from the disposition of a principal asset if this section applies to the income from the asset.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The carrying value or fair market value of trust assets shall be determined on an asset-by-asset basis and is conclusive if reasonable and determined in good faith. Determinations of fair market value based on appraisals performed within 2 years before or after the valuation date are presumed reasonable. The values of trust assets are conclusively presumed to be reasonable and determined in good faith unless proven otherwise in a proceeding commenced by or on behalf of a person interested in the trust within the time provided in s. 736.1008.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All distributions to a beneficiary shall be valued based on their fair market value on the date of distribution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-42; s. 3, ch. 2003-43; s. 42, ch. 2006-217; s. 8, ch. 2012-49.</History>
</Section>