<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0738.604" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minerals, water, and other natural resources.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a fiduciary accounts for receipts from an interest in minerals or other natural resources pursuant to this section, the fiduciary shall allocate such receipts as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If received as nominal delay rental or nominal annual rent on a lease, a receipt shall be allocated to income.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If received from a production payment, a receipt shall be allocated to income if and to the extent the agreement creating the production payment provides a factor for interest or its equivalent. The balance shall be allocated to principal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an amount received as a royalty, shut-in-well payment, take-or-pay payment, bonus, or delay rental is more than nominal, 90 percent shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an amount is received from a working interest or any other interest not provided for in paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c), 90 percent of the net amount received shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount received on account of an interest in water that is renewable shall be allocated to income. If the water is not renewable, 90 percent of the amount shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter applies whether or not a decedent or donor was extracting minerals, water, or other natural resources before the interest became subject to the trust or estate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a trust or estate owns an interest in minerals, water, or other natural resources on January 1, 2003, the fiduciary may allocate receipts from the interest as provided in this chapter or in the manner used by the fiduciary before January 1, 2003. If the trust or estate acquires an interest in minerals, water, or other natural resources after January 1, 2003, the fiduciary shall allocate receipts from the interest as provided in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-42; s. 22, ch. 2012-49.</History>
</Section>