<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0727.112" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proof of claim.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All claims other than claims of creditors with liens on assets of the estate, whether contingent, liquidated, unliquidated, or disputed, which arose prior to the filing date, must be filed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, and any such claim not so filed is barred from any further recovery against the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims shall be filed by delivering the claim to the assignee within 120 days from the filing date unless for cause shown.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims shall be in written form entitled “proof of claim,” setting forth the name and address of the creditor and the nature and amount of the claim, and executed by the creditor or the creditor’s authorized agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a claim or an interest in property of the assignor securing the claim is based on a writing, the original or a copy of such writing shall be filed with the proof of claim, together with evidence of perfection of any security interest, if applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proof of claim, executed and delivered in accordance with this section, shall constitute prima facie evidence of the validity and amount of the claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a claim for damages results from the assignee’s rejection of a lease of real property, the claim shall be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rent reserved by such lease, without acceleration, for the greater of 1 year or 15 percent of the remaining term of the lease, following the earlier of the date of assignment or the date on which the lessor repossessed, or the lessee surrendered, the leased property; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unpaid rent due under the lease, without acceleration, on the earlier of the dates specified in paragraph (a);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable attorney’s fees and costs incurred by the lessor in connection with the lease; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lessor’s reasonable costs incurred in reletting the premises previously leased by the assignor.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a claim for damages results from the termination of an employment contract, the claim shall be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The compensation provided by the contract, without acceleration, for 1 year following the earlier of the date of assignment or the date on which the assignor or assignee, as applicable, directed the employee to terminate, or such employee terminated, performance under the contract; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unpaid compensation due under the contract, without acceleration, on the earlier of the dates specified in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 87-174; s. 10, ch. 2007-185.</History></Section>