<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0727.110" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Actions by assignee and other parties in interest.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All matters requiring court authorization under this chapter shall be brought by motion, except for the following matters, which shall be brought by supplemental proceeding, as provided in subsection (2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action by the assignee to recover money or other assets of the estate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action by the assignee to determine the validity, priority, or extent of a lien or other interest in property or to subordinate or avoid an unperfected security interest under s. 727.109(8)(b); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action by the assignee to avoid any conveyance or transfer void or voidable by law under s. 727.109(8)(c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A supplemental proceeding is an action of the type designated in paragraphs (1)(a), (b), and (c) and shall be brought as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Rules of Civil Procedure shall apply to supplemental proceedings, except where inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the court shall docket a supplemental proceeding under both the same case number assigned to the original petition filed by the assignee pursuant to s. 727.104 and a separate supplemental proceeding number, and shall assign such supplemental proceeding to the same division and judge assigned to the main case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All pleadings and other papers filed in a supplemental proceeding shall contain a separate subcaption and the supplemental proceeding number in addition to the caption and case number applicable to the main case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 87-174; s. 8, ch. 2007-185.</History></Section>