<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0727.113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Objections to claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time prior to the entry of an order approving the assignee’s final report, the assignee or any party in interest, including another creditor of the assignor, may file with the court an objection to a claim, which objection must be in writing and set forth the nature of the objection. A copy of the objection, together with notice of hearing thereon, shall be mailed to the creditor at least 20 days prior to the hearing. All claims properly filed with the assignee and not disallowed by the court constitute all claims entitled to distribution from the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following expiration of the claims bar date, the assignee shall create a register of all creditors that have filed claims against the assignor’s estate and shall make the register available upon request to any creditor or other party in interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assignee, as well as any creditor or any party in interest, has standing to challenge the validity, extent, or priority of any claim filed by a creditor against the assignor’s estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A creditor whose claim is secured by a lien against property of the estate has 60 days following the sale or disposition of the property securing his or her claim to file a claim for an unsecured deficiency, notwithstanding the passage of the last date in which a proof of claim may be served upon the assignee set forth in s. 727.112(2). If such a creditor fails to file with the assignee a deficiency claim within 10 days after the filing and service by mail of the assignee’s final report of all receipts and disbursements, the creditor’s deficiency claim shall be disallowed as untimely, and the creditor is not entitled to share in any distribution made to holders of unsecured claims under s. 727.114(1)(f) on account of its deficiency claim.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 87-174; s. 11, ch. 2007-185.</History></Section>