<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0727.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Priority of claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allowed claims shall receive distribution under this chapter in the following order of priority and, with the exception of paragraph (1)(a), on a pro rata basis:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creditors with liens on assets of the estate, which liens are duly perfected pursuant to applicable law, shall receive the proceeds from the disposition of their collateral, less the reasonable, necessary expenses of preserving or disposing of such collateral to the extent of any benefit to such creditors. If and to the extent that such proceeds are less than the amount of a creditor’s claim or a creditor’s lien is avoided pursuant to s. 727.109(8)(c), such a creditor shall be deemed to be an unsecured creditor for such deficiency pursuant to paragraph (f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses incurred during the administration of the estate, other than those expenses allowable under paragraph (a), including allowed fees and reimbursements of all expenses of the assignee and professional persons employed by the assignee under s. 727.108(7), and rent incurred by the assignee in occupying any premises in which the assets of the assignment estate are located or the business of the assignor is conducted, from and after the date of the assignment, through and until the earlier of the date on which the lease for such premises is rejected pursuant to an order of the court or the date of termination of such lease.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unsecured claims of governmental units for taxes that accrued within 3 years before the filing date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims for wages, salaries, or commissions, including vacation, severance, and sick leave pay, or contributions to an employee benefit plan earned by employees of the assignor within 180 days before the filing date or the cessation of the assignor’s business, whichever occurs first, but only to the extent of $10,000 per individual employee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allowed unsecured claims, to the extent of $2,225 for each individual, arising from the deposit with the assignor before the filing date of money in connection with the purchase, lease, or rental of property or the purchase of services for personal, family, or household use by such individuals that were not delivered or provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unsecured claims.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subordination agreement is enforceable under this chapter to the same extent that such agreement is enforceable under applicable law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of distributions under this chapter, a claim arising from rescission of a purchase or sale of a security of the assignor or of an affiliate of the assignor for damages arising from the purchase or sale of the security or for reimbursement or contribution allowed under this chapter on account of such a claim shall be subordinated to all claims or interests that are senior to or equal to the claim or interest represented by such security, except that if the security is common stock, the claim has the same priority as common stock.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If all claims subject to distribution under this section have been paid in full, any residue shall be paid to the assignor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 87-174; s. 12, ch. 2007-185; s. 21, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>