<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0284.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of premiums by each agency; handling of funds; payment of losses and expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums as calculated on all coverages shall be billed and charged to each state agency according to coverages obtained from the fund for their benefit, and such obligation shall be paid promptly by each agency from its operating budget upon presentation of a bill therefor. However, no state agency shall be liable for the cost of insurance protection under this section prior to July 1, 1971, if any obligation therefor would be incurred against unappropriated funds. After July 1, 1971, billings and the obligation to pay shall be based on coverage provided during each fiscal year and annually thereafter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All premiums paid into the fund and all moneys received by the fund from investment or any other source pursuant to said program shall be held by the Department of Financial Services and used for the purpose of paying losses, expenses incurred in adjustment of losses, premiums for reinsurance, and operating expenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Financial Services is authorized to employ a director of the fund and necessary administrative and clerical personnel, actuaries, consultants, and adjusters to maintain, operate, and administer the fund and to underwrite all certificates of insurance issued by the fund. All salaries and expenses of administration and operation shall be paid from the fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7294, 1917; s. 1, ch. 7902, 1919; RGS 1312; s. 1, ch. 8430, 1921; CGL 1991; s. 1, ch. 28092, 1953; s. 2, ch. 57-101; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 2, ch. 61-463; ss. 13, 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 70-272; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 309, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>