<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0284.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Salary indemnification costs of state agencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature, through the implementation of this section, to provide state agencies with an increased incentive to become actively involved in the prevention and management of workers’ compensation claims involving state employees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State agencies covered by the state risk management program established under this part shall be responsible for funding initial salary indemnification costs, for employees who are entitled to workers’ compensation benefits pursuant to chapter 440, from funds appropriated to pay salaries and benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “salary indemnification costs” means the payments made to employees for temporary total disability benefits. After an employee has been eligible for disability benefits for 10 weeks, salary indemnification costs shall be funded from the State Risk Management Trust Fund in accordance with the provisions of this part for those agencies insured by the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of administering this section, the Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services shall continue to pay all claims, but shall be periodically reimbursed from funds of state agencies for initial salary indemnification costs for which they are responsible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a state agency demonstrates to the Executive Office of the Governor and the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees that no funds are available to pay initial salary indemnification costs for a specific claim pursuant to this section without adversely impacting its ability to perform statutory responsibilities, the Executive Office of the Governor may direct the Division of Risk Management to fund all salary indemnification costs for that specific claim from the State Risk Management Trust Fund and waive the state agency reimbursement requirement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Risk Management shall prepare quarterly reports to the Executive Office of the Governor and the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees indicating for each state agency the total amount of salary indemnification benefits paid to claimants and the total amount of reimbursements from state agencies to the State Risk Management Trust Fund for initial costs for the previous quarter. These reports shall also include information for each state agency indicating the number of cases and amounts of initial salary indemnification costs for which reimbursement requirements were waived by the Executive Office of the Governor pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a state agency fails to pay casualty increase premiums or salary indemnification reimbursements within 30 days after being billed, the Division of Risk Management shall advise the Chief Financial Officer. After verifying the accuracy of the billing, the Chief Financial Officer shall transfer the appropriate amount from any available funds of the delinquent state agency to the State Risk Management Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 95-327; s. 16, ch. 2000-122; s. 328, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>