<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0199.232" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may audit the books and records of any person to determine whether a nonrecurring tax has been properly paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An audit is commenced by service in person or by certified mail of a written notice to the taxpayer of intent to audit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may inspect all records of the taxpayer which may be relevant to the audit, and the department may compel the testimony of the taxpayer under oath or affirmation. The department may also issue subpoenas to compel the testimony of third parties under oath or affirmation and the production of records and other evidence held by third parties, including corporations and brokers. Any duly authorized representative of the department may administer an oath or affirmation. If the taxpayer fails to give testimony or to produce any requested records, or if a third party fails to comply with a subpoena, any circuit court having jurisdiction over the taxpayer or third party may, upon application of the department, issue such orders as are necessary to secure compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With or without an audit, the department may assess any tax deficiency resulting from nonpayment or underpayment of the tax, as well as any applicable interest and penalties. The department shall assess on the basis of the best information available to it, including estimates based on the best information available to it if the taxpayer fails to permit inspection of the taxpayer’s records, files a grossly incorrect return, or files a false and fraudulent return.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following an assessment, the department shall collect the assessed amount from the taxpayer. The assessment is considered prima facie correct, and the taxpayer has the burden of showing any error in the assessment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall credit or refund any overpayment of tax that is revealed on an audit or for which a claim for refund is filed. A claim for refund may be filed within the period specified in s. 215.26(2). It must be filed by the taxpayer, or the taxpayer’s heirs, personal representatives, successors, or assigns, and must include the information required by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In its discretion, the department may, for reasonable cause, grant extensions of time not to exceed 3 months for paying any tax due, or for filing any return or report required, under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it appears, upon examination of an intangible tax return made under this chapter or upon proof submitted to the department by the taxpayer, that an amount of intangible personal property tax has been paid in excess of the amount due, the department shall refund the amount of the overpayment to the taxpayer by a warrant of the Chief Financial Officer. The department shall refund the overpayment without regard to whether the taxpayer has filed a written claim for a refund; however, the department may request that the taxpayer file a statement affirming that the taxpayer made the overpayment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), a refund of the intangible personal property tax may not be made nor is a taxpayer entitled to bring an action for a refund of the intangible personal property tax after the period specified in s. 215.26(2) has elapsed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a refund issued by the department under this section is found to exceed the amount of refund legally due to the taxpayer, the provisions of s. 199.282 concerning penalties and interest do not apply if the taxpayer reimburses the department for any overpayment within 60 days after the taxpayer is notified that the overpayment was made.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-134; s. 22, ch. 85-342; s. 5, ch. 86-152; s. 51, ch. 87-6; s. 7, ch. 94-314; ss. 5, 47, ch. 94-353; s. 177, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2006-312.</History></Section>