<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0199.303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Declaration of legislative intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase, or word of this chapter is for any reason held or declared to be unconstitutional, invalid, inoperative, ineffective, inapplicable, or void, such invalidity or unconstitutionality shall not affect the portions of this chapter not so held to be unconstitutional, void, invalid, or ineffective, or affect the application of this chapter to other circumstances not so held to be invalid, it being the express legislative intent that any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, inapplicable, or void portion or portions of this chapter did not induce its passage, and that without the inclusion of any such unconstitutional, illegal, invalid, ineffective, or void portions of this chapter, the Legislature would have enacted the valid and constitutional portions thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is hereby declared to be the specific legislative intent to tax all intangible personal property that may constitutionally be taxed subject only to the exemptions and credits allowed by law. However, if any application of these statutes is declared unconstitutional, the taxes imposed shall nevertheless remain in force, but only to the extent permitted by the constitutions of this state and of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is hereby declared to be the specific intent of the Legislature that all annual intangible personal property taxes imposed as provided by law for calendar years 2006 and prior shall remain in full force and effect during the period specified by s. 95.091 for the year in which the tax was due. It is further the intent of the Legislature that the department continue to assess and collect all taxes due to the state under such provisions for all periods available for assessment, as provided for the year in which tax was due by s. 95.091.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 92-319; s. 16, ch. 2006-312.</History></Section>