<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0199.145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corrective mortgages; assignments; assumptions; refinancing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any mortgage, deed of trust, or other lien given to replace a defective mortgage, deed of trust, or other lien, covering the identical real property as the original and securing the identical original note or obligation, may be recorded without payment of additional nonrecurring tax upon proof of payment of the tax upon the original recording. The clerk shall note the original payment on the new instrument.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No additional nonrecurring tax shall be due upon the assignment by the obligee of a note, bond, or other obligation for the payment of money upon which a nonrecurring tax has previously been paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No additional nonrecurring tax shall be due upon the assumption of a note, bond, or other obligation for the payment of money if a nonrecurring tax has previously been paid and the amount of the indebtedness remains the same, whether or not the original obligor is released from liability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a note, bond, or other obligation upon which a nonrecurring tax has previously been paid is refinanced with the original obligee or its assignee:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No additional nonrecurring tax is due if the principal balance of the new obligation is less than or equal to the unpaid principal balance of the original obligation, plus accrued but unpaid interest, as of the refinancing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional nonrecurring tax is due if the principal balance of the new obligation exceeds the principal balance of the original obligation, plus accrued but unpaid interest, as of the refinancing. If the original obligor is not liable to the obligee under the new obligation, the additional nonrecurring tax shall be computed on the entire principal balance of the new obligation; otherwise, the additional nonrecurring tax shall be computed on the excess of the principal balance of the new obligation over the principal balance of the original obligation, plus accrued but unpaid interest, as of the refinancing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 85-342.</History></Section>