<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0581.1843" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citrus nursery stock propagation and production and the establishment of regulated areas around citrus nurseries.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “commercial citrus grove” means a solid set planting of 40 or more citrus trees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 2007, it is unlawful for any person to propagate for sale or movement any citrus nursery stock that was not propagated or grown on a site and within a protective structure approved by the department and that is not at least 1 mile away from commercial citrus groves. A citrus nursery registered with the department prior to April 1, 2006, shall not be required to comply with the 1-mile setback from commercial citrus groves while continuously operating at the same location for which it was registered. However, the nursery shall be required to propagate citrus within a protective structure approved by the department. Effective January 1, 2008, it shall be unlawful to distribute any citrus nursery stock that was not produced in a protective structure approved by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 which set forth the conditions under which citrus nursery stock can be propagated, grown, sold, or moved and the specifications for the approved site and protective structure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the provisions of this chapter, the department shall adopt rules that are consistent with scientific findings and recommendations of the Citrus Budwood Technical Advisory Committee to regulate all genera of the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rutaceous</Font> subfamilies <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Aurantioideae</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rutoideae</Font>, and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Toddalioideae</Font> that pose a threat of introducing or spreading a citrus plant pest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish regulated areas around the perimeter of commercial citrus nurseries that were established on sites after April 1, 2006, not to exceed a radius of 1 mile. The planting of citrus in an established regulated area is prohibited. The planting of citrus within a 1-mile radius of commercial citrus nurseries that were established on sites prior to April 1, 2006, must be approved by the department. Citrus plants planted within a regulated area prior to the establishment of the regulated area may remain in the regulated area unless the department determines the citrus plants to be infected or infested with citrus canker or citrus greening. The department shall require the removal of infected or infested citrus, nonapproved planted citrus, and citrus that has sprouted by natural means in regulated areas. The property owner shall be responsible for the removal of citrus planted without proper approval. Notice of the removal of citrus trees, by immediate final order of the department, shall be provided to the owner of the property on which the trees are located. An immediate final order issued by the department under this section shall notify the property owner that the citrus trees, which are the subject of the immediate final order, must be removed and destroyed unless the property owner, no later than 10 days after delivery of the immediate final order, requests and obtains a stay of the immediate final order from the district court of appeal with jurisdiction to review such requests. The property owner shall not be required to seek a stay from the department of the immediate final order prior to seeking a stay from the district court of appeal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulation of the removal or destruction of citrus plants under this section is preempted to the state. No county, municipal, or other local ordinance or other regulation that would otherwise impose requirements, restrictions, or conditions upon the department or its contractors with respect to the removal or destruction of citrus trees under this section shall be enforceable against the department or its contractors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall relocate foundation source trees maintained by the Division of Plant Industry from various locations, including those in Dundee and Winter Haven, to protective structures at the Florida Forest Service nursery in Chiefland or to other protective sites located a minimum of 10 miles from any commercial citrus grove.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2006-45; s. 22, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>