<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0581.145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Aquatic plant nursery registration; special permit requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nursery or nursery stock dealer shall not engage in any business involving the importation, transportation, cultivation, collection, sale, or possession of any aquatic plant species unless a certification of registration has been issued by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any nursery or nursery stock dealer to import, transport, cultivate, collect, sell, or possess any noxious aquatic plant listed on the prohibited aquatic plant list established by the Department of Environmental Protection in s. 369.25(3)(b) without a special permit issued by the department.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No special permit shall be issued until the department determines that the proposed activity poses no threat or danger to the waters, wildlife, natural resources, agriculture, or environment of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a special permit with respect to a prohibited aquatic plant species if the Department of Environmental Protection prohibits the importation, transportation, cultivation, collection, sale, or possession of the species.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of state or federal law, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall issue, by request, a permit to the aquaculture producer to engage in the business of transporting and selling water hyacinths (<Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Eichhornia spp.</Font>) only to other states or countries that permit such transportation and sale when such aquaculture activities have been certified by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. In accordance with any appropriate state or federal law or United States treaty, a Florida aquaculture producer may not ship water hyacinths to other states or countries under such a permit for the purpose of importing water hyacinths back into Florida. This subsection does not restrict or interfere with the efforts of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, or the efforts of any other agency or local government with responsibilities for the management of noxious aquatic plants, to control or eradicate noxious nonnursery aquatic plants, including water hyacinths. This subsection may not be considered in the approval or the release of biological control agents for water hyacinths or any other noxious aquatic plants.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 92-147; s. 52, ch. 93-169; s. 464, ch. 94-356; s. 73, ch. 95-144; s. 22, ch. 96-247; s. 9, ch. 99-390; s. 34, ch. 2012-190.</History>
</Section>