<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0581.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of registration or of inspection; revocation and suspension; fines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVOCATION AND SUSPENSION.<EmDash />If it is determined by the department that any nurseryman, stock dealer, agent, or plant broker is selling or offering for sale, or is distributing or offering to distribute, nursery stock in violation of the provisions of this chapter and the rules adopted under this chapter, or has aided or abetted in such violation, the department may revoke or suspend her or his certificate of registration or the use of any certificates, permits, or agreements issued by the division. Further, the department may refuse or suspend the certification of any nursery stock or plant product when it is determined that plant pests exist on the stock or product or that the nursery or site is in such condition with regard to growth and cultivation that an efficient inspection for plant pests cannot be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FINES; PROBATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, after notice and hearing, impose a fine not exceeding $5,000 or probation not exceeding 12 months, or both, for the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or the rules adopted under this chapter upon any person, nurseryman, stock dealer, agent, or plant broker. The fine, when paid, shall be deposited in the Plant Industry Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The imposition of a fine or probation pursuant to this subsection may be in addition to or in lieu of the suspension or revocation of a certificate of registration or certificate of inspection.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any administrative order has been made and entered by the department imposing a fine upon any person pursuant to this subsection, the order shall specify the amount of the fine and the time limit for payment, which shall not exceed 15 days. Upon failure to pay the fine within such time, the certificate of registration or certificate of inspection of the person may be suspended or revoked without further hearing; and a fine of $100 per day may be imposed for each day the violation continues.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 29767, 1955; s. 14, ch. 59-261; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-39; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 5, ch. 80-41; s. 2, ch. 84-60; s. 5, ch. 84-355; s. 4, ch. 85-283; s. 50, ch. 93-169; s. 920, ch. 97-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 581.082.</Text></Note></Section>