<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0581.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties for violations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates any provision of this chapter or the rules adopted under this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forges, counterfeits, removes, destroys, disguises, or wrongfully or improperly uses any tag, certificate, permit, compliance agreement, or other written agreement provided for in this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interferes with or obstructs any director or authorized representative of the department in the performance of her or his duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully refuses to identify the origin and source of any plant, plant product, or other thing likely to carry plant pests, noxious weeds, or arthropods; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has in her or his possession unauthorized imported plants or plant products,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who imports from other states, territories, or countries, without a special permit from the Division of Plant Industry, plants or propagative plant parts of the subfamily Aurantioideae (after Swingle and Reese which includes all species of citrus) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other provision of law, the department may, after notice and hearing, impose an administrative fine not exceeding $5,000 for each violation of this chapter, upon any person, nurseryman, stock dealer, agent or plant broker. The fine, when paid, shall be deposited in the Plant Industry Trust Fund. In addition, the department may place the violator on probation for up to 1 year, with conditions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The imposition of a fine or probation pursuant to this subsection may be in addition to or in lieu of the suspension or revocation of a certificate of registration or certificate of inspection.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any administrative order has been entered by the department imposing a fine or probation upon any person pursuant to this subsection, the order shall specify the conditions and time limit for probation, and the amount of the fine and time limit for payment which shall not exceed 15 days. If the person fails to meet the conditions of probation or to pay the fine within the established time, the person’s certificate of registration or certificate of inspection may be suspended or revoked, and a fine of $100 per day imposed for each day the violation continues.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 12291, 1927; CGL 7854; s. 21, ch. 59-261; s. 600, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 76-95; s. 4, ch. 78-72; s. 10, ch. 79-158; s. 6, ch. 80-41; s. 6, ch. 84-355; s. 4, ch. 85-153; s. 5, ch. 88-31; s. 150, ch. 91-224; s. 7, ch. 92-147; s. 61, ch. 93-169; s. 923, ch. 97-103; s. 32, ch. 2001-279.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 581.09.</Text></Note></Section>