<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0581.142" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Viable nursery stock; requirements for sale.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful to sell or offer for sale any plant or nursery stock unless the plant or nursery stock is viable and meets the basic requirements of a viable plant or viable nursery stock, at the time and place of sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The basic requirements of viable nursery stock or a viable plant are as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must be capable of living and accomplishing the purpose for which it is grown, whether foliage, flowers, fruit, or special use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must be free of physiological and pathological defects to the extent that all essential parts function normally.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The root system must have adequate roots or the ability to produce them to support normal performance of the plant. The root system must be adequately protected to prevent excessive loss of moisture while in storage and transit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trunk and branches must be capable of transporting fluids throughout the plant and be free from any infirmity of a permanent nature which would interfere with this function. Any damaged branches must be capable of being pruned without seriously deterring growth of the plant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leaves must be capable of performing essential manufacturing functions, such as photosynthesis. Deciduous plants, when void of leaves, must have the ability to put out new leaves capable of functioning normally.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 63-260; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 599, ch. 71-136; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 11, ch. 79-158; s. 51, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>