<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0194.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Circuit court to have original jurisdiction in tax cases.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit courts have original jurisdiction at law of all matters relating to property taxation. Venue is in the county where the property is located, except that venue shall be in Leon County when the property is assessed pursuant to s. 193.085(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action shall be brought to contest a tax assessment after 60 days from the date the assessment being contested is certified for collection under s. 193.122(2), or after 60 days from the date a decision is rendered concerning such assessment by the value adjustment board if a petition contesting the assessment had not received final action by the value adjustment board prior to extension of the roll under s. 197.323.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before an action to contest a tax assessment may be brought, the taxpayer shall pay to the collector not less than the amount of the tax which the taxpayer admits in good faith to be owing. The collector shall issue a receipt for the payment, and the receipt shall be filed with the complaint. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 197, payment of the taxes the taxpayer admits to be due and owing and the timely filing of an action pursuant to this section shall suspend all procedures for the collection of taxes prior to final disposition of the action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of a tax shall not be deemed an admission that the tax was due and shall not prejudice the right to bring a timely action as provided in subsection (2) to challenge such tax and seek a refund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action to contest a tax assessment may be maintained, and any such action shall be dismissed, unless all taxes on the property assessed in years after the action is brought, which the taxpayer in good faith admits to be owing, are paid before they become delinquent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of subsections (2), (3), and (5) are jurisdictional. No court shall have jurisdiction in such cases until after the requirements of both subsections (2) and (3) have been met. A court shall lose jurisdiction of a case when the taxpayer has failed to comply with the requirements of subsection (5).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 8586, 1921; CGL 1038; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 1, ch. 67-538; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 8, ch. 69-102; s. 6, ch. 69-140; ss. 30, 31, ch. 70-243; s. 1, ch. 72-239; s. 6, ch. 74-234; s. 17, ch. 82-226; s. 7, ch. 83-204; s. 56, ch. 83-217; s. 211, ch. 85-342; s. 3, ch. 88-146; s. 151, ch. 91-112; s. 32, ch. 94-353; s. 1470, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 192.21, 194.151, 196.01.</Text></Note></Section>