<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0194.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hearing purposes; timetable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value adjustment board shall meet not earlier than 30 days and not later than 60 days after the mailing of the notice provided in s. 194.011(1); however, no board hearing shall be held before approval of all or any part of the assessment rolls by the Department of Revenue. The board shall meet for the following purposes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearing petitions relating to assessments filed pursuant to s. 194.011(3).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearing complaints relating to homestead exemptions as provided for under s. 196.151.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearing appeals from exemptions denied, or disputes arising from exemptions granted, upon the filing of exemption applications under s. 196.011.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearing appeals concerning ad valorem tax deferrals and classifications.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a), the value adjustment board may meet prior to the approval of the assessment rolls by the Department of Revenue, but not earlier than July 1, to hear appeals pertaining to the denial by the property appraiser of exemptions, agricultural and high-water recharge classifications, classifications as historic property used for commercial or certain nonprofit purposes, and deferrals under subparagraphs (a)2., 3., and 4. In such event, however, the board may not certify any assessments under s. 193.122 until the Department of Revenue has approved the assessments in accordance with s. 193.1142 and all hearings have been held with respect to the particular parcel under appeal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event may a hearing be held pursuant to this subsection relative to valuation issues prior to completion of the hearings required under s. 200.065(2)(c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the governing body of the county shall prepare a schedule of appearances before the board based on petitions timely filed with him or her. The clerk shall notify each petitioner of the scheduled time of his or her appearance at least 25 calendar days before the day of the scheduled appearance. The notice shall indicate whether the petition has been scheduled to be heard at a particular time or during a block of time. If the petition has been scheduled to be heard within a block of time, the beginning and ending of that block of time shall be indicated on the notice; however, as provided in paragraph (b), a petitioner may not be required to wait for more than a reasonable time, not to exceed 2 hours, after the beginning of the block of time. If the petitioner checked the appropriate box on the petition form to request a copy of the property record card containing relevant information used in computing the current assessment, the clerk shall provide the copy of the card along with the notice. Upon receipt of the notice, the petitioner may reschedule the hearing a single time by submitting to the clerk a written request to reschedule, at least 5 calendar days before the day of the originally scheduled hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petitioner may not be required to wait for more than a reasonable time, not to exceed 2 hours, after the scheduled time for the hearing to commence. If the hearing is not commenced within that time, the petitioner may inform the chairperson of the meeting that he or she intends to leave. If the petitioner leaves, the clerk shall reschedule the hearing, and the rescheduling is not considered to be a request to reschedule as provided in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure on three occasions with respect to any single tax year to convene at the scheduled time of meetings of the board is grounds for removal from office by the Governor for neglect of duties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall remain in session from day to day until all petitions, complaints, appeals, and disputes are heard. If all or any part of an assessment roll has been disapproved by the department pursuant to s. 193.1142, the board shall reconvene to hear petitions, complaints, or appeals and disputes filed upon the finally approved roll or part of a roll.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 69-140; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 27, ch. 70-243; s. 12, ch. 73-172; s. 6, ch. 74-234; s. 7, ch. 76-133; s. 3, ch. 76-234; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 13, ch. 77-301; ss. 1, 9, 37, ch. 80-274; s. 5, ch. 81-308; ss. 14, 16, ch. 82-208; ss. 9, 11, 23, 26, 80, ch. 82-226; ss. 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, ch. 83-204; s. 146, ch. 91-112; s. 979, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 96-204; s. 4, ch. 97-117; s. 2, ch. 98-52; s. 3, ch. 2002-18; s. 2, ch. 2004-349; s. 11, ch. 2012-193.</History></Section>