<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0194.036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appeals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appeals of the decisions of the board shall be as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the property appraiser disagrees with the decision of the board, he or she may appeal the decision to the circuit court if one or more of the following criteria are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property appraiser determines and affirmatively asserts in any legal proceeding that there is a specific constitutional or statutory violation, or a specific violation of administrative rules, in the decision of the board, except that nothing herein shall authorize the property appraiser to institute any suit to challenge the validity of any portion of the constitution or of any duly enacted legislative act of this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a variance from the property appraiser’s assessed value in excess of the following: 15 percent variance from any assessment of $50,000 or less; 10 percent variance from any assessment in excess of $50,000 but not in excess of $500,000; 7.5 percent variance from any assessment in excess of $500,000 but not in excess of $1 million; or 5 percent variance from any assessment in excess of $1 million; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is an assertion by the property appraiser to the Department of Revenue that there exists a consistent and continuous violation of the intent of the law or administrative rules by the value adjustment board in its decisions. The property appraiser shall notify the department of those portions of the tax roll for which the assertion is made. The department shall thereupon notify the clerk of the board who shall, within 15 days of the notification by the department, send the written decisions of the board to the department. Within 30 days of the receipt of the decisions by the department, the department shall notify the property appraiser of its decision relative to further judicial proceedings. If the department finds upon investigation that a consistent and continuous violation of the intent of the law or administrative rules by the board has occurred, it shall so inform the property appraiser, who may thereupon bring suit in circuit court against the value adjustment board for injunctive relief to prohibit continuation of the violation of the law or administrative rules and for a mandatory injunction to restore the tax roll to its just value in such amount as determined by judicial proceeding. However, when a final judicial decision is rendered as a result of an appeal filed pursuant to this paragraph which alters or changes an assessment of a parcel of property of any taxpayer not a party to such procedure, such taxpayer shall have 60 days from the date of the final judicial decision to file an action to contest such altered or changed assessment pursuant to s. 194.171(1), and the provisions of s. 194.171(2) shall not bar such action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any taxpayer may bring an action to contest a tax assessment pursuant to s. 194.171.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court proceeding shall be de novo, and the burden of proof shall be upon the party initiating the action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 83-204; s. 149, ch. 91-112; s. 982, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>