<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0194.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Parties to a tax suit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff in any tax suit shall be:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxpayer or other person contesting the assessment of any tax, the payment of which he or she is responsible for under a statute or a person who is responsible for the entire tax payment pursuant to a contract and has the written consent of the property owner, or the condominium association, cooperative association, or homeowners’ association as defined in s. 723.075 which operates the units subject to the assessment; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property appraiser pursuant to s. 194.036.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case brought by the taxpayer or association contesting the assessment of any property, the county property appraiser shall be party defendant. In any case brought by the property appraiser pursuant to s. 194.036(1)(a) or (b), the taxpayer shall be party defendant. In any case brought by the property appraiser pursuant to s. 194.036(1)(c), the value adjustment board shall be party defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit involving the collection of any tax on property, as well as questions relating to tax certificates or applications for tax deeds, the tax collector charged under the law with collecting such tax shall be the defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit involving a tax other than an ad valorem tax on property, the tax collector charged under the law with collecting such tax shall be defendant. However, this section does not apply in any instance wherein general law provides for some other person to be the party defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit in which the assessment of any tax, or the collection of any tax, tax certificate, or tax deed is contested on the ground that it is contrary to the State Constitution, the official of the state government responsible for overall supervision of the assessment and collection of such tax shall be made a party defendant of such suit. Any such suit shall be brought in that county having venue under s. 194.171 or, when that section is inapplicable, in the Circuit Court of Leon County, and the attorney for the defendant county officer shall upon request represent the state official in any such suit or proceeding, for which he or she shall receive no additional compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit in which the validity of any statute or regulation found in, or issued pursuant to, chapters 192-197, inclusive, is contested, the public officer affected may be a party plaintiff.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 8586, 1921; CGL 1040; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 7, ch. 69-140; s. 32, ch. 70-243; s. 1, ch. 73-74; s. 9, ch. 76-133; s. 4, ch. 76-234; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 27, ch. 83-204; s. 4, ch. 88-146; s. 152, ch. 91-112; s. 983, ch. 95-147; s. 7, ch. 2004-349.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 196.03.</Text></Note></Section>