<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0194.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing fees for petitions; disposition; waiver.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If so required by resolution of the value adjustment board, a petition filed pursuant to s. 194.011 shall be accompanied by a filing fee to be paid to the clerk of the value adjustment board in an amount determined by the board not to exceed $15 for each separate parcel of property, real or personal, covered by the petition and subject to appeal. However, no such filing fee may be required with respect to an appeal from the disapproval of homestead exemption under s. 196.151 or from the denial of tax deferral under s. 197.2425. Only a single filing fee shall be charged under this section as to any particular parcel of property despite the existence of multiple issues and hearings pertaining to such parcel. For joint petitions filed pursuant to s. 194.011(3)(e) or (f), a single filing fee shall be charged. Such fee shall be calculated as the cost of the special magistrate for the time involved in hearing the joint petition and shall not exceed $5 per parcel. Said fee is to be proportionately paid by affected parcel owners.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value adjustment board shall waive the filing fee with respect to a petition filed by a taxpayer who demonstrates at the time of filing, by an appropriate certificate or other documentation issued by the Department of Children and Family Services and submitted with the petition, that the petitioner is then an eligible recipient of temporary assistance under chapter 414.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All filing fees imposed under this section shall be paid to the clerk of the value adjustment board at the time of filing. If such fees are not paid at that time, the petition shall be deemed invalid and shall be rejected.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All filing fees collected by the clerk shall be allocated and utilized to defray, to the extent possible, the costs incurred in connection with the administration and operation of the value adjustment board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 83-204; s. 210, ch. 85-342; s. 2, ch. 86-175; s. 4, ch. 86-300; s. 2, ch. 88-146; s. 144, ch. 91-112; s. 55, ch. 96-175; s. 18, ch. 99-8; s. 3, ch. 2000-262; s. 70, ch. 2004-11; s. 55, ch. 2011-151.</History>
</Section>