<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0447.501" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unfair labor practices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public employers or their agents or representatives are prohibited from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interfering with, restraining, or coercing public employees in the exercise of any rights guaranteed them under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encouraging or discouraging membership in any employee organization by discrimination in regard to hiring, tenure, or other conditions of employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to bargain collectively, failing to bargain collectively in good faith, or refusing to sign a final agreement agreed upon with the certified bargaining agent for the public employees in the bargaining unit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discharging or discriminating against a public employee because he or she has filed charges or given testimony under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dominating, interfering with, or assisting in the formation, existence, or administration of, any employee organization or contributing financial support to such an organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to discuss grievances in good faith pursuant to the terms of the collective bargaining agreement with either the certified bargaining agent for the public employee or the employee involved.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public employee organization or anyone acting in its behalf or its officers, representatives, agents, or members are prohibited from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interfering with, restraining, or coercing public employees in the exercise of any rights guaranteed them under this part or interfering with, restraining, or coercing managerial employees by reason of their performance of job duties or other activities undertaken in the interests of the public employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing or attempting to cause a public employer to discriminate against an employee because of the employee’s membership or nonmembership in an employee organization or attempting to cause the public employer to violate any of the provisions of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to bargain collectively or failing to bargain collectively in good faith with a public employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discriminating against an employee because he or she has signed or filed an affidavit, petition, or complaint or given any information or testimony in any proceedings provided for in this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participating in a strike against the public employer by instigating or supporting, in any positive manner, a strike. Any violation of this paragraph shall subject the violator to the penalties provided in this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instigating or advocating support, in any positive manner, for an employee organization’s activities from high school or grade school students or students in institutions of higher learning.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1) and (2), the parties’ rights of free speech shall not be infringed, and the expression of any arguments or opinions shall not constitute, or be evidence of, an unfair employment practice or of any other violation of this part, if such expression contains no promise of benefits or threat of reprisal or force.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 74-100; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 160, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>