<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0447.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public Employees Relations Commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Public Employees Relations Commission, hereinafter referred to as the “commission,” shall be composed of a chair and two part-time members to be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate, from persons representative of the public and known for their objective and independent judgment, who shall not be employed by, or hold any commission with, any governmental unit in the state or any employee organization, as defined in this part, while in such office. In no event shall more than one appointee be a person who, on account of previous vocation, employment, or affiliation, is, or has been, classified as a representative of employers; and in no event shall more than one such appointee be a person who, on account of previous vocation, employment, or affiliation, is, or has been, classified as a representative of employees or employee organizations. The chair of the commission shall devote full time to commission duties and shall not engage in any other business, vocation, or employment while in such office. The part-time members shall not engage in any business, vocation, or employment that conflicts with their duties while in such office. Beginning January 1, 1980, the chair shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, one commissioner for a term of 1 year, and one commissioner for a term of 2 years. Thereafter, every term of office shall be for 4 years; and each term of the office of chair shall commence on January 1 of the second year following each regularly scheduled general election at which a Governor is elected to a full term of office. In the event of a vacancy prior to the expiration of a term of office, an appointment shall be made for the unexpired term of that office. The chair shall be responsible for the administrative functions of the commission and shall have the authority to employ such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this part. Once appointed to the office of chair, the chair shall serve as chair for the duration of the term of office of chair. Nothing contained herein prohibits a chair or commissioner from serving multiple terms.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair and the other commissioners shall be paid annual salaries to be fixed by law. Such salaries shall be paid in equal monthly installments. All commissioners shall be reimbursed for expenses, as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission, in the performance of its powers and duties under this part, shall not be subject to control, supervision, or direction by the Department of Management Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property, personnel, and appropriations related to the commission’s specified authority, powers, duties, and responsibilities shall be provided to the commission by the Department of Management Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall make such expenditures, including expenditures for personal services and rent at the seat of government and elsewhere, for law books, books of reference, periodicals, furniture, equipment, and supplies, and for printing and binding, as may be necessary in exercising its authority and powers and carrying out its duties and responsibilities. All such expenditures of the commission shall be allowed and paid upon the presentation of itemized vouchers therefor approved by the chair.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may, in its discretion, charge for publications, subscriptions, and copies of records and documents. Such funds shall be deposited in a trust fund to be established by the commission and shall be used to help defray the cost of providing such publications, subscriptions, and copies of records and documents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall maintain and keep open during reasonable business hours an office, which shall be provided in the Capitol Center for the transaction of its business, at which its official records and papers shall be kept. The commission may hold sessions and conduct hearings at any place within the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall have a seal for authentication of its orders and proceedings, upon which shall be inscribed the words “State of Florida<EmDash/>Employees Relations Commission<EmDash/>and which shall be judicially noticed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is expressly authorized to provide by rule for, and to destroy, obsolete records of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The deliberations of the commission in any proceeding before it are closed and exempt from the provisions of s. 286.011. However, any hearing held or oral argument heard by the commission pursuant to chapter 120 or this chapter shall be open to the public. All draft orders developed in preparation for, or preliminary to, the issuance of a final written order are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any hearing held under this chapter shall be conducted according to the provisions of ss. 120.569 and 120.57 by the commission, a member of the commission, or a hearing officer designated by the commission who is an employee of the commission and a member of The Florida Bar.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may appoint an employee as elections supervisor to conduct elections in accordance with this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 74-100; s. 7, ch. 77-343; s. 40, ch. 79-7; s. 1, ch. 79-85; s. 189, ch. 79-400; s. 2, ch. 84-228; s. 1, ch. 91-151; s. 15, ch. 91-269; s. 299, ch. 96-406; s. 201, ch. 96-410; s. 1073, ch. 97-103; s. 36, ch. 2001-43; s. 1, ch. 2011-57.</History>
</Section>