<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0447.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following terms, when used in this chapter, shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “labor organization” means any organization of employees or local or subdivision thereof, having within its membership residents of the state, whether incorporated or not, organized for the purpose of dealing with employers concerning hours of employment, rate of pay, working conditions, or grievances of any kind relating to employment and recognized as a unit of bargaining by one or more employers doing business in this state, except that an “employee organization,” as defined in s. 447.203(11), shall be included in this definition at such time as it seeks to register pursuant to s. 447.305.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “business agent” means any person, without regard to title, who shall, for a pecuniary or financial consideration, act or attempt to act for any labor organization in:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance of membership or authorization cards, work permits, or any other evidence of rights granted or claimed in, or by, a labor organization; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting or receiving from any employer any right or privilege for employees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 21968, 1943; s. 1, ch. 65-396; s. 1, ch. 77-184; s. 35, ch. 79-7; s. 1, ch. 79-89; s. 188, ch. 79-400; s. 29, ch. 83-174; s. 19, ch. 95-345; s. 127, ch. 2000-165; s. 59, ch. 2002-194.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 481.02.</Text></Note></Section>