<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0020.155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Governors of the State University System.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GENERAL PROVISIONS.<EmDash />The Board of Governors of the State University System is established by the State Constitution under s. 7, Art. IX and, accordingly, is granted rights and privileges equal to those of departments established under this chapter while preserving the Board of Governors’ constitutional designation and title.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEAD OF THE BOARD.<EmDash />The head of the Board of Governors is the board with members appointed by the Governor as provided for in s. 7, Art. IX of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERSONNEL.<EmDash />The Board of Governors may appoint a Chancellor to aid the board in the implementation of its responsibilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS AND DUTIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors shall operate, regulate, control, and be responsible for the management of the whole State University System in accordance with s. 7, Art. IX of the State Constitution and law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors, in exercising its authority under the State Constitution and statutes, shall do so in a manner that supports, promotes, and enhances all of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affordable access to postsecondary educational opportunities for Florida residents.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articulation among state universities and with public schools and other postsecondary educational institutions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fiscal responsibility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accountability.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFICE OF INSPECTOR GENERAL.<EmDash />An Office of Inspector General shall be organized using existing resources and funds to promote accountability, efficiency, and effectiveness and to detect fraud and abuse within state universities. If the Board of Governors determines that a state university board of trustees is unwilling or unable to address substantiated allegations made by any person relating to waste, fraud, or financial mismanagement, the office shall conduct, coordinate, or request investigations into substantiated allegations made by any person relating to waste, fraud, or financial mismanagement within a state university. The office shall have access to all information and personnel necessary to perform its duties and shall have all of its current powers, duties, and responsibilities authorized in s. 20.055.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>