<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0020.057" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interagency agreements to delete duplication of inspections.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall direct any department, the head of which is an officer or board appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the Governor, to enter into an interagency agreement to eliminate duplication of inspections among departments that inspect the same type of facility or structure. Parties to the agreement may include departments headed by a Cabinet officer, the Governor and Cabinet, or a collegial body. The agreement shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize agents of one department to conduct inspections required to be performed by another department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify that agents of the department conducting the inspection have all powers relative to the inspection as the agents of the department on whose behalf the inspection is being conducted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that agents of the department conducting the inspection have sufficient knowledge of statutory and administrative inspection requirements to conduct a proper inspection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify that the departments entering into the agreement may not charge or accept funds with respect to duties performed under the agreement which are in excess of the direct costs of conducting the inspections.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before taking effect, an agreement entered into under this section must be approved by the Governor. Inspections conducted under an agreement are sufficient for enforcement purposes pursuant to the agreement or as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 91-429; s. 32, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>