<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0020.601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agency review; Department of Economic Opportunity.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not later than July 1, 2016, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall provide the Legislature with a report on the department and Enterprise Florida, Inc., which includes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance measures for each program and activity as defined in s. 216.011 and 3 years of data for each measure which provides actual results for the immediately preceding 2 years and projected results for the fiscal year that begins in the year that the agency report is scheduled to be submitted to the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of factors that have contributed to any failure to achieve the legislative standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The promptness and effectiveness with which the agency disposes of complaints concerning persons affected by the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the agency has encouraged participation by the public in making its rules and decisions as opposed to participation solely by those it regulates and the extent to which public participation has resulted in rules compatible with the objectives of the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the agency has complied with applicable requirements of state law and applicable rules regarding purchasing goals and programs for small and minority-owned businesses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of any statutory objectives intended for each program and activity, the problem or need that the program and activity were intended to address, and the extent to which these objectives have been achieved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the extent to which the jurisdiction of the agency and its programs overlap or duplicate those of other agencies and the extent to which the programs can be consolidated with those of other agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of less restrictive or alternative methods of providing services for which the agency is responsible which would reduce costs or improve performance while adequately protecting the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the extent to which the agency has corrected deficiencies and implemented recommendations contained in reports of the Auditor General, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, legislative interim studies, and federal audit entities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The process by which an agency actively measures quality and efficiency of services it provides to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the agency complies with public records and public meetings requirements under chapters 119 and 286 and s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which alternative program delivery options, such as privatization, outsourcing, or insourcing, have been considered to reduce costs or improve services to state residents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations to the Legislature for statutory, budgetary, or regulatory changes that would improve the quality and efficiency of services delivered to the public, reduce costs, or reduce duplication.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of federal intervention or loss of federal funds if the agency, program, or activity is abolished.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of all advisory committees, including those established in statute and those established by managerial initiative; their purpose, activities, composition, and related expenses; the extent to which their purposes have been achieved; and the rationale for continuing or eliminating each advisory committee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agency programs or functions that are performed without specific statutory authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other information requested by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information and data reported by the agency shall be validated by its agency head and inspector general before submission to the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall review the department and Enterprise Florida, Inc. The review shall include an examination of the cost of each program, an evaluation of best practices and alternatives that would result in the administration of the department in a more efficient or effective manner, an examination of the viability of privatization or a different state agency performing the functions, and an evaluation of the cost and consequences of discontinuing the agency. The review shall be comprehensive in scope and shall consider the information provided by the department report in addition to information deemed necessary by the office and the appropriate legislative committees. The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall include in the report recommendations for consideration by the Legislature and shall submit the report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives no later than December 31, 2016.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>