<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0020.165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The head of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation is the Secretary of Business and Professional Regulation. The secretary shall be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. The secretary shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following divisions of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation are established:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Certified Public Accounting.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the division shall be appointed by the secretary of the department, subject to approval by a majority of the Board of Accountancy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offices of the division shall be located in Gainesville.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Drugs, Devices, and Cosmetics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Hotels and Restaurants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Professions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Real Estate.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the division shall be appointed by the secretary of the department, subject to approval by a majority of the Florida Real Estate Commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offices of the division shall be located in Orlando.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Regulation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Technology.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Service Operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary shall appoint a director for each division established within this section. Each division director shall directly administer the division and shall be responsible to the secretary. The secretary may appoint deputy and assistant secretaries as necessary to aid the secretary in fulfilling the secretary’s statutory obligations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following boards and programs are established within the Division of Professions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Architecture and Interior Design, created under part I of chapter 481.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Board of Auctioneers, created under part VI of chapter 468.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Barbers’ Board, created under chapter 476.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board, created under part XII of chapter 468.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction Industry Licensing Board, created under part I of chapter 489.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Cosmetology, created under chapter 477.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electrical Contractors’ Licensing Board, created under part II of chapter 489.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Employee Leasing Companies, created under part XI of chapter 468.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Landscape Architecture, created under part II of chapter 481.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Pilot Commissioners, created under chapter 310.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Professional Engineers, created under chapter 471.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Professional Geologists, created under chapter 492.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board of Veterinary Medicine, created under chapter 474.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home inspection services licensing program, created under part XV of chapter 468.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mold-related services licensing program, created under part XVI of chapter 468.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following board and commission are established within the Division of Real Estate:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Real Estate Appraisal Board, created under part II of chapter 475.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Real Estate Commission, created under part I of chapter 475.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following board is established within the Division of Certified Public Accounting: Board of Accountancy, created under chapter 473.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of each board established pursuant to subsection (4) shall be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. Consumer members on the board shall be appointed pursuant to subsection (6). Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms, and such terms shall expire on October 31. However, a term of less than 4 years may be utilized to ensure that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than two members’ terms expire during the same calendar year for boards consisting of seven or eight members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 3 members’ terms expire during the same calendar year for boards consisting of 9 to 12 members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 5 members’ terms expire during the same calendar year for boards consisting of 13 or more members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A member whose term has expired shall continue to serve on the board until such time as a replacement is appointed. A vacancy on the board shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment. No member may serve for more than the remaining portion of a previous member’s unexpired term, plus two consecutive 4-year terms of the member’s own appointment thereafter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board with five or more members shall have at least two consumer members who are not, and have never been, members or practitioners of the profession regulated by such board or of any closely related profession. Each board with fewer than five members shall have at least one consumer member who is not, and has never been, a member or practitioner of the profession regulated by such board or of any closely related profession.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No board, with the exception of joint coordinatorships, shall be transferred from its present location unless authorized by the Legislature in the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the department is authorized to establish uniform application forms and certificates of licensure for use by the divisions within the department. Nothing in this subsection authorizes the department to vary any substantive requirements, duties, or eligibilities for licensure or certification as provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All employees authorized by the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco shall have access to, and shall have the right to inspect, premises licensed by the division, to collect taxes and remit them to the officers entitled to them, and to examine the books and records of all licensees. The authorized employees shall require of each licensee strict compliance with the laws of this state relating to the transaction of such business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee serving as a law enforcement officer for the division must meet the qualifications for employment or appointment as a law enforcement officer set forth under s. 943.13 and must be certified as a law enforcement officer by the Department of Law Enforcement under chapter 943. Upon certification, each law enforcement officer is subject to and has the same authority as provided for law enforcement officers generally in chapter 901 and has statewide jurisdiction. Each officer also has arrest authority as provided for state law enforcement officers in s. 901.15. Each officer possesses the full law enforcement powers granted to other peace officers of this state, including the authority to make arrests, carry firearms, serve court process, and seize contraband and the proceeds of illegal activities.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary responsibility of each officer appointed under this section is to investigate, enforce, and prosecute, throughout the state, violations and violators of parts I and II of chapter 210, part VII of chapter 559, and chapters 561-569, and the rules adopted thereunder, as well as other state laws that the division, all state law enforcement officers, or beverage enforcement agents are specifically authorized to enforce.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secondary responsibility of each officer appointed under this section is to enforce all other state laws, provided that the enforcement is incidental to exercising the officer’s primary responsibility as provided in subparagraph 1., and the officer exercises the powers of a deputy sheriff, only after consultation or coordination with the appropriate local sheriff’s office or municipal police department or when the division participates in the Florida Mutual Aid Plan during a declared state emergency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 93-220; s. 1, ch. 94-119; s. 2, ch. 94-218; s. 1, ch. 95-346; s. 9, ch. 96-403; s. 1, ch. 97-162; s. 9, ch. 99-254; s. 5, ch. 2004-17; s. 135, ch. 2004-301; s. 2, ch. 2006-1; s. 1, ch. 2006-222; s. 8, ch. 2008-240; s. 2, ch. 2009-66; s. 62, ch. 2009-195; s. 1, ch. 2010-106; s. 1, ch. 2012-143.</History>
</Section>