<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0020.331" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHTS AND PRIVILEGES.<EmDash />The Legislature, recognizing the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission as being specifically authorized by the State Constitution under s. 9, Art. IV, grants rights and privileges to the commission, as contemplated by s. 6, Art. IV of the State Constitution. These rights and privileges are equal to those of departments established under this chapter while preserving the commission’s constitutional designation and title.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEAD OF THE COMMISSION.<EmDash />The head of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is the commission, with commissioners appointed by the Governor as provided for in s. 9, Art. IV of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To aid the commission in the implementation of its constitutional and statutory responsibilities, the Legislature authorizes the commission to appoint and fix the salary of a person who is not a member of the commission to serve as the executive director and to remove such person at its pleasure. The executive director shall supervise, direct, coordinate, and administer all activities necessary to fulfill the commission’s constitutional and statutory responsibilities. The executive director shall be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses incurred in the discharge of official duties as provided in s. 112.061. The executive director shall maintain headquarters in and reside in Tallahassee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each executive director must be confirmed by the Senate during the regular legislative session immediately following his or her appointment by the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM AND RESEARCH SERVICES.<EmDash />Within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, the principal unit for program services is a “division” headed by a “director.” The principal subunit of the division is a “section” headed by a “leader.” The principal subunit of the section is a “subsection” headed by an “administrator.”</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following divisions and section are created within the commission:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Freshwater Fisheries Management.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Habitat and Species Conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Hunting and Game Management.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Law Enforcement. There is created within the division the Boating and Waterways Section with duties and responsibilities as provided in paragraph (7)(e).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Marine Fisheries Management.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal unit for research services within the commission is the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute, which shall be headed by a director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATIVE AND SUPPORT SERVICES.<EmDash />The principal unit for administrative and support services is the Office of Executive Direction and Administrative Support Services, headed by the executive director of the commission. Each office within this principal unit shall be headed by a “director”. The following administrative and support offices are created within the Office of Executive Direction and Administrative Support Services:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Finance and Budget.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Human Resources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information Technology.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspector General.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional Operations. Within the Regional Operations office, the executive director may establish regional offices for each of the administrative regions established by the commission. Each regional office shall be headed by a “director.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GENERAL PROVISIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section leader positions are classified at a level equal to bureau chiefs, and subsection administrator positions are classified at a level equal to section administrators, as established in s. 20.04. At the discretion of the executive director, director positions shall be classified at a level equal to division directors, bureau chiefs, or section administrators, as established in s. 20.04.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless specifically authorized by law, the commission may not reallocate duties and functions assigned by law to a specific unit of the commission. Functions assigned generally to the commission without specific designation to a unit of the commission may be allocated at the discretion of the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Divisions, sections, and offices created by this act may be abolished only by general law. Additional divisions in the commission may only be established by general law. New sections, subsections, and offices of the commission may be initiated by the commission and established as recommended by the Department of Management Services and approved by the Executive Office of the Governor, or may be established by general law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ASSIGNMENT OF DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES.<EmDash />The commission, and the Legislature as provided in s. 9, Art. IV of the State Constitution, shall assign to the:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fish and Wildlife Research Institute such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to accomplish its mission, which is to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as the primary source of research and technical information and expertise on the status of marine life, freshwater aquatic life, and wild animal life resources in this state;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor the status and health of marine life, freshwater aquatic life, and wild animal life species and their habitat;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop restoration and management techniques for habitat and enhancement of plant and animal populations;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Respond to and provide critical technical support for catastrophes including oil spills, ship groundings, major species die-offs, hazardous spills, and natural disasters;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and monitor harmful algal blooms including red tides, evaluate their impacts, and provide technical support concerning state and local public health concerns; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide state and local governments with technical information and research results concerning fish and wild animal life.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Freshwater Fisheries Management such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to facilitate the responsible and sustained use of freshwater aquatic life resources. The division shall provide expertise on freshwater fish populations or other aspects of freshwater fisheries needed for recreational and commercial use management decisions. The division also shall assess impacts of decisions made by others to ensure quality fisheries and fishing in lakes, fish management areas, rivers, and streams in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Habitat and Species Conservation such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to protect and conserve the state’s diverse and unique fish and wild animal life. Powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions of the division must be focused at the ecosystem or landscape level and must include the management of public lands, habitat restoration on public lands, development and implementation of nongame species management plans, development and implementation of imperiled species recovery plans, providing scientific support and assistance on habitat-related issues to public and private landowners, aquatic habitat restoration, habitat management assistance, land acquisition, and exotic species coordination focused on measures that prevent and control the introduction of exotic species. The division shall utilize scientific data to develop resource management plans that maintain stable or increasing populations of fish and wild animal life.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Hunting and Game Management such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to facilitate the responsible and sustained use of wild animal life resources. The division must develop scientifically based recommendations that support effective regulation and sound management of game wild animal life resources. The division must also coordinate the development and management of public hunting opportunities and provide hunter safety training and certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Law Enforcement such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to ensure enforcement of laws and rules governing the management, protection, conservation, improvement, and expansion of wild animal life, freshwater aquatic life, and marine life resources. In performance of their duties as sworn law enforcement officers for the State of Florida, the division’s officers also shall enforce all laws relating to boating, provide public safety services for citizens on lands and waters of the state particularly in remote areas, provide search-and-rescue and disaster response services when necessary, assist in the enforcement of all general laws, and coordinate with local, state, and federal entities on law enforcement issues.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Boating and Waterways Section such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to manage and promote the use of state waterways for safe and enjoyable boating. Duties and responsibilities of the section include oversight and coordination of waterway markers on state waters, providing boating education and boating safety programs, improving boating access, coordinating the removal of derelict vessels from state waters, implementing economic development initiatives to promote boating in the state, and coordinating the submission of state comments on marine events.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Division of Marine Fisheries Management such powers, duties, responsibilities, and functions as are necessary to facilitate the responsible and sustained use of marine life resources. The division shall develop recommendations for managing and enhancing commercial and recreational saltwater fisheries resources, implement marine fisheries management programs, and assist in the development and monitoring of artificial reefs in state waters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE AUTHORITY.<EmDash />The constitutional power granted to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission does not include any authority over marine life retained by the Legislature or vested in any agency other than the Marine Fisheries Commission on March 1, 1998, or any authority over marine aquaculture retained by the Legislature and vested in any other agency as of July 1, 1999.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADEQUATE DUE PROCESS PROCEDURES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt a rule establishing due process procedures to be accorded to any party, as defined in s. 120.52, whose substantial interests are affected by any action of the commission in the performance of its constitutional duties or responsibilities, and the adequate due process procedures adopted by rule shall be published in the Florida Administrative Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature encourages the commission to incorporate into its process the provisions of s. 120.54(3)(c) when adopting rules in the performance of its constitutional duties or responsibilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall follow the provisions of chapter 120 when adopting rules in the performance of its statutory duties or responsibilities. The commission’s statutory duties or responsibilities include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research and management responsibilities for marine species listed as endangered or threatened, including manatees and marine turtles.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment and enforcement of boating safety regulations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land acquisition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement and collection of fees for all commercial and recreational hunting or fishing licenses or permits.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aquatic plant removal using fish as a biological control agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of penalties for violations of commission rules and state laws, including, but not limited to, the seizure and forfeiture of vessels and other equipment used to commit those violations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of free fishing days.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulation of off-road vehicles on state lands.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment and coordination of a statewide hunter safety course.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of programs and activities to develop and distribute public education materials.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Police powers of sworn law enforcement officers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of citizen support organizations to provide assistance, funding, and promotional support for programs of the commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creation of the voluntary authorized hunter identification program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulation of required clothing of persons hunting deer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERMIT COMMENTING AUTHORITY.<EmDash />Comments submitted by the commission to a permitting agency regarding applications for permits, licenses, or authorizations affecting the commission’s jurisdiction must be based on credible, factual scientific data, and must be received by the permitting agency within the time specified by applicable statutes or rules, or within 30 days, whichever is sooner. Comments provided by the commission are not binding on any permitting agency. Comments by the commission shall be considered for consistency with the Florida Coastal Management Program and ss. 373.428 and 380.23. If the commission comments are used by a permitting agency as a condition of denial, approval, or modification of a proposed permit, license, or authorization, any party to an administrative proceeding involving such proposed action may require the commission to join as a party in determining the validity of the condition. In any action in which the commission is joined as a party, the commission shall bear only the actual cost of defending the validity of the credible, factual scientific data used as a basis for comments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LAND ACQUISITION AUTHORITY.<EmDash />The commission shall acquire, in the name of the state, lands and waters suitable for the protection, improvement, and restoration of the state’s wild animal life, freshwater aquatic life, and marine life resources. Lands may be acquired by purchase, lease, gift, or otherwise, using state, federal, or other sources of funding. Lands acquired under this section shall be managed for recreational and other multiple-use activities that do not impede the commission’s ability to perform its constitutional and statutory duties and responsibilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EMPLOYEE BONDS.<EmDash />The commission may require any commission employee to give a bond for the faithful performance of duties. The commission may determine the amount of the bond and must approve the bond. In determining the amount of the bond, the commission may consider the amount of money or property likely to be in the custody of the officer or employee at any one time. The premium for the bond must be paid out of the funds of the commission, and the bond must be payable to the Governor of the state and the Governor’s successors in office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-245; s. 4, ch. 2000-151; s. 3, ch. 2000-197; s. 7, ch. 2001-60; s. 2, ch. 2003-156; s. 1, ch. 2004-264; s. 1, ch. 2007-223; s. 1, ch. 2008-106.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 1, ch. 2012-88, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All powers, duties, functions, records, offices, personnel, property, pending issues and existing contracts, administrative authority, administrative rules, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds relating to the Division of Law Enforcement within the Department of Environmental Protection, excluding the Bureau of Emergency Response, are transferred by a type two transfer, as defined in s. 20.06(2), Florida Statutes, to the Division of Law Enforcement within the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The Bureau of Emergency Response within the Department of Environmental Protection is reassigned to the Secretary of Environmental Protection as the Office of Emergency Response within the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The Secretary of Environmental Protection shall transfer to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission the number of administrative, auditing, inspector general, attorney, and operational support positions, including any related powers, duties, functions, property, and funding, proportionate to the number of Division of Law Enforcement full-time equivalent and other personal services positions being transferred from the department to the commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) A memorandum of agreement shall be developed between the department and the commission detailing the responsibilities of the commission to the department, to include, at a minimum, the following:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Support and response for oil spills, hazardous spills, and natural disasters.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Law enforcement patrol and investigative services for all state-owned lands managed by the department.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Law enforcement services, including investigative services, for all criminal law violations of chapters 161, 258, 373, 376, and 403, Florida Statutes.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(d) Enforcement services for all civil violations of all department administrative rules related to the following program areas:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“1. Division of Recreation and Parks.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“2. Office of Coastal and Aquatic Managed Areas.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“3. Office of Greenways and Trails.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(e) Current and future funding for positions and property being transferred from the department to the commission that is funded through any trust fund.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 2, ch. 2012-88, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All powers, duties, functions, records, property, pending issues and existing contracts, administrative authority, administrative rules, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds relating to sworn positions funded by the Conservation and Recreation Lands Program and assigned to the Florida Forest Service within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services as of July 1, 2011, and the investigator responsible for the enforcement of aquaculture violations at the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services as of July 1, 2011, are transferred by a type two transfer, as defined in s. 20.06(2), Florida Statutes, to the Division of Law Enforcement within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) A memorandum of agreement shall be developed between the department and the commission detailing the responsibilities between the commission and the department, to include, at a minimum, the following:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Law enforcement patrol and investigative services for all state-owned forests managed by the department.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Current and future funding for positions and property assigned to the Conservation and Recreation Lands Program that are transferred from the department to the commission.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 3, ch. 2012-88, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Secretary of Environmental Protection and the Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall each appoint three staff members to a transition advisory working group to review and determine the following:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) The appropriate proportionate number of administrative, auditing, inspector general, attorney, and operational support positions and their related funding levels and sources and assigned property to be transferred from the Office of General Counsel, Office of Inspector General, and Division of Administrative Services or other relevant offices or divisions within the Department of Environmental Protection to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) The development of a recommended plan addressing the transfer or shared use of buildings, regional offices, and other facilities used or owned by the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Any operating budget adjustments as necessary to implement the requirements of this act. Adjustments made to the operating budgets of the department and the commission in the implementation of this act must be made in consultation with the appropriate substantive and fiscal committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives. The revisions to the approved operating budgets for the 2012-2013 fiscal year which are necessary to reflect the organizational changes made by this act shall be implemented pursuant to s. 216.292(4)(d), Florida Statutes, and subject to s. 216.177, Florida Statutes. Subsequent adjustments between agencies that are determined necessary by the department or commission and approved by the Executive Office of the Governor are authorized and subject to s. 216.177, Florida Statutes. The appropriate substantive committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives shall also be notified of the proposed revisions to ensure consistency with legislative policy and intent.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The Secretary of Environmental Protection, the Commissioner of Agriculture, and the Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall each appoint two staff members to a transition advisory working group to identify rules of the Department of Environmental Protection, the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, and the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission that need to be amended to reflect the changes made by this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>