<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0020.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The head of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services is the Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following divisions of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services are established:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agricultural Environmental Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Animal Industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aquaculture.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consumer Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food Safety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Forest Service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fruit and Vegetables.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marketing and Development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plant Industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food, Nutrition, and Wellness.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bureaus may be established as deemed necessary to promote efficient and effective operation of the department, pursuant to s. 20.04.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-309; s. 1, ch. 71-196; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 77-108; s. 9, ch. 81-259; s. 1, ch. 84-165; s. 1, ch. 92-291; s. 9, ch. 99-245; s. 49, ch. 2001-89; s. 3, ch. 2002-295; s. 1, ch. 2008-107; s. 1, ch. 2011-56; ss. 1, 65, ch. 2011-206; s. 1, ch. 2012-67; s. 1, ch. 2012-190.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 2, ch. 2012-88, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All powers, duties, functions, records, property, pending issues and existing contracts, administrative authority, administrative rules, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds relating to sworn positions funded by the Conservation and Recreation Lands Program and assigned to the Florida Forest Service within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services as of July 1, 2011, and the investigator responsible for the enforcement of aquaculture violations at the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services as of July 1, 2011, are transferred by a type two transfer, as defined in s. 20.06(2), Florida Statutes, to the Division of Law Enforcement within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) A memorandum of agreement shall be developed between the department and the commission detailing the responsibilities between the commission and the department, to include, at a minimum, the following:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Law enforcement patrol and investigative services for all state-owned forests managed by the department.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Current and future funding for positions and property assigned to the Conservation and Recreation Lands Program that are transferred from the department to the commission.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 3, ch. 2012-88, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Secretary of Environmental Protection and the Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall each appoint three staff members to a transition advisory working group to review and determine the following:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) The appropriate proportionate number of administrative, auditing, inspector general, attorney, and operational support positions and their related funding levels and sources and assigned property to be transferred from the Office of General Counsel, Office of Inspector General, and Division of Administrative Services or other relevant offices or divisions within the Department of Environmental Protection to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) The development of a recommended plan addressing the transfer or shared use of buildings, regional offices, and other facilities used or owned by the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Any operating budget adjustments as necessary to implement the requirements of this act. Adjustments made to the operating budgets of the department and the commission in the implementation of this act must be made in consultation with the appropriate substantive and fiscal committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives. The revisions to the approved operating budgets for the 2012-2013 fiscal year which are necessary to reflect the organizational changes made by this act shall be implemented pursuant to s. 216.292(4)(d), Florida Statutes, and subject to s. 216.177, Florida Statutes. Subsequent adjustments between agencies that are determined necessary by the department or commission and approved by the Executive Office of the Governor are authorized and subject to s. 216.177, Florida Statutes. The appropriate substantive committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives shall also be notified of the proposed revisions to ensure consistency with legislative policy and intent.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The Secretary of Environmental Protection, the Commissioner of Agriculture, and the Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall each appoint two staff members to a transition advisory working group to identify rules of the Department of Environmental Protection, the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, and the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission that need to be amended to reflect the changes made by this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>