<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0020.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Method of reorganization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive branch of state government shall be reorganized by transferring the specified agencies, programs, and functions to other specified departments, commissions, or offices. Such a transfer does not affect the validity of any judicial or administrative proceeding pending on the day of the transfer, and any agency or department to which are transferred the powers, duties, and functions relating to the pending proceeding must be substituted as a party in interest for the proceeding. The transfers provided herein are intended to supplement but not supplant the requirements of s. 6, Art. III of the State Constitution. The definitions provided in s. 20.03 apply to this section, and the types of transfers are defined as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TYPE ONE TRANSFER.<EmDash />A type one transfer is the transferring intact of an existing agency or department so that the agency or department becomes a unit of another agency or a department. Any agency or department transferred to another agency or department by a type one transfer will exercise its powers, duties, and functions as prescribed by law, subject to review and approval by, and under the direct supervision of, the head of the agency or department to which the transfer is made, unless otherwise provided by law. Any agency or department transferred by a type one transfer has all its statutory powers, duties, and functions, and its records, personnel, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds transferred to the agency or department to which it is transferred. The transfer of segregated funds must be made in such manner that the relation between program and revenue source as provided by law is retained. Unless otherwise provided by law, the administrative rules of any agency or department involved in the transfer which are in effect immediately before the transfer remain in effect until specifically changed in the manner provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TYPE TWO TRANSFER.<EmDash />A type two transfer is the merging into another agency or department of an existing agency or department or a program, activity, or function thereof or, if certain identifiable units or subunits, programs, activities, or functions are removed from the existing agency or department, or are abolished, it is the merging into an agency or department of the existing agency or department with the certain identifiable units or subunits, programs, activities, or functions removed therefrom or abolished.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agency or department or a program, activity, or function thereof transferred by a type two transfer has all its statutory powers, duties, and functions, and its records, personnel, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds, except those transferred elsewhere or abolished, transferred to the agency or department to which it is transferred, unless otherwise provided by law. The transfer of segregated funds must be made in such a manner that the relation between program and revenue source as provided by law is retained.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided by law, the head of the agency or department to which an existing agency or department or a program, activity, or function thereof is transferred is authorized to establish units or subunits to which the agency or department is assigned, and to assign administrative authority for identifiable programs, activities, or functions, to the extent authorized in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided by law, the administrative rules of any agency or department involved in the transfer which are in effect immediately before the transfer remain in effect until specifically changed in the manner provided by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 79-36; s. 12, ch. 94-235.</History></Section>