<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0020.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review of programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To achieve maximum efficiency and effectiveness of government as intended by s. 6, Art. IV of the State Constitution, and to promote quality management and accountability as required in s. 19, Art. III of the State Constitution, all programs, functions, and entities must be reviewed by the executive and the legislative branches. The review must identify and examine the purpose of each program, function, or entity to ensure that each program, function, or entity is administered in the most effective and efficient manner possible, and to assess the public benefit derived from the program, function, or entity. Reviews must determine whether the function, program, or entity:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serves an identifiable purpose that benefits the public and accomplishes the purpose for which it was created;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operates efficiently and effectively within its statutory framework, and whether there are any statutory changes that would likely increase the effectiveness and efficiency of the function, program, or entity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is necessary to the public health, safety, or welfare, and what would be the effect of its abolition;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serves a beneficial purpose to state agencies in improving the effectiveness and efficiency of the operations of the state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly increases or decreases the costs of any goods or services, and whether any identified increase in cost is more harmful to the state than any of the harm that could occur absent the function, program, or entity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is situated within an organizational structure that promotes its efficient and effective administration and does not duplicate activities conducted in other agencies of the state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Could be assigned to another state agency or to private enterprise, and if so, the most efficient way of doing so.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless other criteria are specifically provided by law, any review of a function, program, or entity scheduled for repeal by law must be conducted in accordance with the criteria specified in subsection (1). In conducting a review of a function, program, or entity scheduled for repeal, the presumption is in favor of the repeal. The need for or benefits derived from a program, function, or entity subject to repeal and prior review must be compelling as measured by these criteria for the function, program, or entity to be continued.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 94-235.</History></Section>