<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0020.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Revenue.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Department of Revenue.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The head of the Department of Revenue is the Governor and Cabinet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative responsibilities of the Department of Revenue are to plan, organize, and control the administrative support services for the department. Administrative functions include, but are not limited to, finance and accounting, revenue accounting, personnel, and office services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ad valorem tax responsibilities of the department are to carry out the relevant provisions of ad valorem tax law. Ad valorem tax functions include, but are not limited to, ad valorem administration, assessment standards and review, central property valuation, and field operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The audit responsibilities of the department are to plan, organize, administer, and control tax auditing activities. Audit functions include, but are not limited to, audit selection and standards development for those taxes collected by the department. The standards development function shall include development of standard audit criteria and provision of functional direction to field audit staff.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The collection and enforcement responsibilities of the department are to conduct tax collection and enforcement activities. Collection and enforcement functions include, but are not limited to, investigative services and central and field operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information systems and services responsibilities of the department are to develop, maintain, and manage all information systems for tax return processing and taxpayer registration activities. Information systems and services functions include, but are not limited to, automation of all information systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxpayer assistance responsibilities of the department are to render advice to department personnel and the public on tax matters. Taxpayer assistance functions include, but are not limited to, the preparation of departmental rules for all taxes, the rendition of opinions pursuant to s. 213.22, and the provision of informal assistance to the public on tax matters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax processing responsibilities of the department include, but are not limited to, receipts processing, tax returns processing, license registration, and taxpayer registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child support enforcement responsibilities of the department include the administration of the child support enforcement program established by Title IV-D of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. ss. 651 et seq.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The position of taxpayers’ rights advocate is created within the Department of Revenue. The taxpayers’ rights advocate shall be appointed by and report to the executive director of the department. The responsibilities of the taxpayers’ rights advocate include, but are not limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitating the resolution of taxpayer complaints and problems which have not been resolved through normal administrative channels within the department, including any taxpayer complaints regarding unsatisfactory treatment of taxpayers by employees of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuing a stay action on behalf of a taxpayer who has suffered or is about to suffer irreparable loss as a result of action by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Necessary legal services, pursuant to chapter 16, including litigation shall be provided to the Department of Revenue by the Department of Legal Affairs, except for the establishment of paternity or support obligations, and the modification, enforcement, and collection of support obligations, for which legal services may be provided under a contract entered into by the Department of Revenue as the Title IV-D agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law, the department may process taxes, fines, or license or regulatory fees for the benefit of any other state agency. Such processing may be done only pursuant to a written agreement between the department and the agency requesting this service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 110.123, relating to the state group insurance program, the department may pay, or participate in the payment of, premiums for health, accident, and life insurance for its full-time out-of-state employees, pursuant to such rules as it may adopt, and such payments shall be in addition to the regular salaries of such full-time out-of-state employees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-266; s. 1, ch. 75-211; s. 1, ch. 77-102; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-390; s. 3, ch. 79-10; s. 2, ch. 80-391; s. 1, ch. 81-50; s. 11, ch. 84-170; s. 1, ch. 86-124; s. 31, ch. 90-203; s. 1, ch. 91-112; s. 17, ch. 92-315; s. 4, ch. 94-124; ss. 2, 16, ch. 95-272; s. 2, ch. 97-287.</History></Section>