<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0020.317" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of the Lottery.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Department of the Lottery.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The head of the Department of the Lottery is the Secretary of the Department of the Lottery. The secretary shall be appointed by the Governor subject to the confirmation of the Senate. The secretary shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. The compensation of the secretary shall be set annually by executive order of the Governor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that, prior to appointing a secretary of the department, the Governor conduct a thorough search to find the most qualified appointee available. In conducting such search, the Governor shall emphasize such considerations as business management experience, marketing experience, computer experience, and lottery management experience.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, the secretary may create divisions and bureaus within the department and allocate the various functions of the department among such divisions and bureaus. However, in order to promote and protect the integrity of and the public confidence in the state lottery, there is created a Division of Security within the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The headquarters of the department shall be located in Tallahassee. However, the department may establish such regional offices throughout the state as the secretary deems necessary to the efficient operation of the state lottery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 87-65.</History></Section>