<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discharge.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCHARGE AT THE AGE OF MAJORITY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any residential client reaches his or her 18th birthday, the agency shall give the resident or legal guardian the option to continue residential services or to be discharged from residential services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resident appears to meet the criteria for involuntary admission to residential services, as defined in s. 393.11, the agency shall file a petition to determine the appropriateness of continued residential placement on an involuntary basis. The agency shall file the petition for involuntary admission in the county in which the client resides. If the resident was originally involuntarily admitted to residential services pursuant to s. 393.11, then the agency shall file the petition in the court having continuing jurisdiction over the case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall in any way limit or restrict the resident’s right to a writ of habeas corpus or the right of the agency to transfer a resident receiving residential care to a program of appropriate services provided by the agency when such program is the appropriate habilitative setting for the resident.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCHARGE AFTER CRIMINAL OR JUVENILE COMMITMENT.<EmDash />Any person with developmental disabilities committed to the custody of the agency pursuant to the provisions of the applicable criminal or juvenile court law shall be discharged in accordance with the requirements of the applicable criminal or juvenile court law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 7887, 1919; ss. 2, 3, ch. 10272, 1925; CGL 3669, 3674-3676; s. 1, ch. 61-426; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-343; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 7, ch. 73-308; s. 194, ch. 77-147; s. 3, ch. 77-335; s. 19, ch. 78-95; s. 9, ch. 88-398; s. 16, ch. 89-308; s. 702, ch. 95-148; s. 107, ch. 2004-267.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 393.05.</Text></Note></Section>