<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.066" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community services and treatment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall plan, develop, organize, and implement its programs of services and treatment for persons with developmental disabilities to allow clients to live as independently as possible in their own homes or communities and to achieve productive lives as close to normal as possible. All elements of community-based services shall be made available, and eligibility for these services shall be consistent across the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All services needed shall be purchased instead of provided directly by the agency, when such arrangement is more cost-efficient than having those services provided directly. All purchased services must be approved by the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community-based services that are medically necessary to prevent institutionalization shall, to the extent of available resources, include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult day training services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Family care services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guardian advocate referral services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical/dental services, except that medical services shall not be provided to clients with spina bifida except as specifically appropriated by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parent training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal care services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recreation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential facility services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Respite services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specialized therapies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supported employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supported living.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training, including behavioral analysis services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other habilitative and rehabilitative services as needed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall utilize the services of private businesses, not-for-profit organizations, and units of local government whenever such services are more cost-efficient than such services provided directly by the department, including arrangements for provision of residential facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to improve the potential for utilization of more cost-effective, community-based residential facilities, the agency shall promote the statewide development of day habilitation services for clients who live with a direct service provider in a community-based residential facility and who do not require 24-hour-a-day care in a hospital or other health care institution, but who may, in the absence of day habilitation services, require admission to a developmental disabilities center. Each day service facility shall provide a protective physical environment for clients, ensure that direct service providers meet minimum screening standards as required in s. 393.0655, make available to all day habilitation service participants at least one meal on each day of operation, provide facilities to enable participants to obtain needed rest while attending the program, as appropriate, and provide social and educational activities designed to stimulate interest and provide socialization skills.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote independence and productivity, the agency shall provide supports and services, within available resources, to assist clients enrolled in Medicaid waivers who choose to pursue gainful employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of making needed community-based residential facilities available at the least possible cost to the state, the agency is authorized to lease privately owned residential facilities under long-term rental agreements, if such rental agreements are projected to be less costly to the state over the useful life of the facility than state purchase or state construction of such a facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules providing definitions, eligibility criteria, and procedures for the purchase of services provided pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-335; s. 2, ch. 80-174; s. 43, ch. 83-218; s. 15, ch. 84-226; s. 6, ch. 85-54; s. 2, ch. 85-147; s. 10, ch. 86-220; s. 7, ch. 87-238; s. 11, ch. 89-308; s. 18, ch. 91-158; s. 4, ch. 92-174; ss. 2, 3, ch. 93-143; s. 9, ch. 93-200; s. 5, ch. 93-267; s. 9, ch. 94-154; s. 1, ch. 98-152; s. 83, ch. 99-8; s. 3, ch. 99-144; s. 74, ch. 2004-267; s. 18, ch. 2006-227; s. 6, ch. 2008-244.</History></Section>