<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.0673" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial, suspension, or revocation of license; moratorium on admissions; administrative fines; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may revoke or suspend a license or impose an administrative fine, not to exceed $1,000 per violation per day, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsely represented or omitted a material fact in its license application submitted under s. 393.067;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Had prior action taken against it under the Medicaid or Medicare program; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to comply with the applicable requirements of this chapter or rules applicable to the licensee; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services has verified that the licensee is responsible for the abuse, neglect, or abandonment of a child or the abuse, neglect, or exploitation of a vulnerable adult.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may deny an application for licensure submitted under s. 393.067 if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsely represented or omitted a material fact in its license application submitted under s. 393.067;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Had prior action taken against it under the Medicaid or Medicare program;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to comply with the applicable requirements of this chapter or rules applicable to the applicant; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Previously had a license to operate a residential facility revoked by the agency, the Department of Children and Family Services, or the Agency for Health Care Administration; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services has verified that the applicant is responsible for the abuse, neglect, or abandonment of a child or the abuse, neglect, or exploitation of a vulnerable adult.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All hearings shall be held within the county in which the licensee or applicant operates or applies for a license to operate a facility as defined herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, as a part of any final order issued by it under this chapter, may impose such fine as it deems proper, except that such fine may not exceed $1,000 for each violation. Each day a violation of this chapter occurs constitutes a separate violation and is subject to a separate fine, but in no event may the aggregate amount of any fine exceed $10,000. Fines paid by any facility licensee under the provisions of this subsection shall be deposited in the Health Care Trust Fund and expended as provided in s. 400.063.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may issue an order immediately suspending or revoking a license when it determines that any condition in the facility presents a danger to the health, safety, or welfare of the residents in the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may impose an immediate moratorium on admissions to any facility when the agency determines that any condition in the facility presents a threat to the health, safety, or welfare of the residents in the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish by rule criteria for evaluating the severity of violations and for determining the amount of fines imposed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-230; s. 8, ch. 85-54; s. 40, ch. 93-217; s. 85, ch. 99-8; s. 5, ch. 99-144; s. 102, ch. 2004-267; s. 20, ch. 2006-227; s. 7, ch. 2008-9; s. 7, ch. 2008-244.</History></Section>