<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.0641" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Program for the prevention and treatment of severe self-injurious behavior.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, there is created a diagnostic, treatment, training, and research program for clients exhibiting severe self-injurious behavior. As used in this section, the term “severe self-injurious behavior” means any chronic behavior that results in injury to the person’s own body, including, but not limited to, self-hitting, head banging, self-biting, scratching, and the ingestion of harmful or potentially harmful nutritive or nonnutritive substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a resource center for information, training, and program development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research the diagnosis and treatment of severe self-injurious behavior, and related disorders, and develop methods of prevention and treatment of self-injurious behavior.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify individuals in critical need.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop treatment programs which are meaningful to individuals with developmental disabilities, in critical need, while safeguarding and respecting the legal and human rights of the individuals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate research findings on the prevention and treatment of severe self-injurious behavior.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect data on the type, severity, incidence, and demographics of individuals with severe self-injurious behavior, and disseminate the data.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall adhere to the provisions of s. 393.13.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may contract for the provision of any portion or all of the services required by the program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may license this program and adopt rules to administer the program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 89-308; s. 8, ch. 93-200; s. 25, ch. 2001-62; s. 99, ch. 2004-267; s. 12, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>