<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Developmental disabilities centers; trust accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All receipts from the operation of canteens, vending machines, hobby shops, sheltered workshops, activity centers, farming projects, and other like activities operated in a developmental disabilities center, and moneys donated to the center, must be deposited in a trust account in any bank, credit union, or savings and loan association authorized by the State Treasury as a qualified depository to do business in this state, if the moneys are available on demand.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the trust account must be expended for the benefit, education, or welfare of clients. However, if specified, moneys that are donated to the center must be expended in accordance with the intentions of the donor. Trust account money may not be used for the benefit of agency employees or to pay the wages of such employees. The welfare of clients includes the expenditure of funds for the purchase of items for resale at canteens or vending machines, and for the establishment of, maintenance of, and operation of canteens, hobby shops, recreational or entertainment facilities, sheltered workshops, activity centers, farming projects, or other like facilities or programs established at the center for the benefit of clients.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center may invest, in the manner authorized by law for fiduciaries, any money in a trust account which is not necessary for immediate use. The interest earned and other increments derived from the investments of the money must be deposited into the trust account for the benefit of clients.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accounting system of the center must account separately for revenues and expenses for each activity. The center shall reconcile the trust account to the center’s accounting system and check registers and to the accounting system of the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All sales taxes collected by the center as a result of sales shall be deposited into the trust account and remitted to the Department of Revenue.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds shall be expended in accordance with requirements and guidelines established by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 2006-227; s. 99, ch. 2008-4; s. 10, ch. 2008-244; s. 3, ch. 2009-56.</History></Section>