<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.0695" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provision of in-home subsidies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may pay in-home subsidies to clients enrolled in the family care program or supported living when it is determined to be more cost-effective and in the best interest of the client to provide a cash supplement to the client’s income to enable the client to remain in the family home or the client’s own home. Payments may be made to the parent or guardian of the client or, if the client is competent, directly to the client.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In-home subsidies may be used to pay for basic living necessities including, but not limited to: rent, utilities, food, clothing, toiletries, household supplies, and other household items. In-home subsidies may not be used to pay a contractor for the provision of services and supports to the client or to pay for medical or dental services, medicines, medical supplies, or adaptive equipment or aids.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In-home subsidies must be based on an individual determination of need and must not exceed maximum amounts set by the agency and reassessed by the agency quarterly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payments may be made monthly and shall be considered a client service rather than a purchase of service. Chapter 287 does not apply to in-home subsidies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules to administer this section, including standards and procedures governing eligibility for services, selection of housing, selection of providers, planning for services, and requirements for ongoing monitoring.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 91-158; s. 77, ch. 2004-267; s. 25, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>