<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of medication.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A direct service provider who is not currently licensed to administer medication may supervise the self-administration of medication or may administer oral, transdermal, ophthalmic, otic, rectal, inhaled, enteral, or topical prescription medications to a client as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to supervise the self-administration of medication or to administer medications as provided in subsection (1), a direct service provider must satisfactorily complete a training course of not less than 4 hours in medication administration and be found competent to supervise the self-administration of medication by a client or to administer medication to a client in a safe and sanitary manner. Competency must be assessed and validated at least annually in an onsite setting and must include personally observing the direct service provider satisfactorily:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervising the self-administration of medication by a client; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administering medication to a client.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A direct service provider may supervise the self-administration of medication by a client or may administer medication to a client only if the client, or the client’s guardian or legal representative, has given his or her informed consent to self-administering medication under the supervision of an unlicensed direct service provider or to receiving medication administered by an unlicensed direct service provider. Such informed consent must be based on a description of the medication routes and procedures that the direct service provider is authorized to supervise or administer. Only a provider who has received appropriate training and has been validated as competent may supervise the self-administration of medication by a client or may administer medication to a client.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination of competency and annual validation required in this section shall be conducted by a registered nurse licensed pursuant to chapter 464 or a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish by rule standards and procedures that a direct service provider must follow when supervising the self-administration of medication by a client and when administering medication to a client. Such rules must, at a minimum, address requirements for labeling medication, documentation and recordkeeping, the storage and disposal of medication, instructions concerning the safe administration of medication or supervision of self-administered medication, informed-consent requirements and records, and the training curriculum and validation procedures.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-57; s. 113, ch. 2004-267; s. 1, ch. 2006-37; s. 16, ch. 2006-197; s. 11, ch. 2008-244.</History></Section>