<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General liability coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “children” means those persons under the age of 18 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services shall provide coverage through the agency to any person who owns or operates a foster care facility or group home facility solely for the agency, who cares for children placed by the agency, and who is licensed pursuant to s. 393.067 to provide such supervision and care in his or her place of residence. The coverage shall be provided from the general liability account of the State Risk Management Trust Fund. The coverage is limited to general liability claims arising from the provision of supervision and care of children in a foster care facility or group home facility pursuant to an agreement with the agency and pursuant to guidelines established through policy, rule, or statute. Coverage shall be subject to the limits provided in ss. 284.38 and 284.385, and the exclusions set forth therein, together with other exclusions as may be set forth in the certificate of coverage issued by the trust fund. A person covered under the general liability account pursuant to this subsection shall immediately notify the Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services of any potential or actual claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed as designating or not designating that a person who owns or operates a foster care facility or group home facility as described in this section or any other person is an employee or agent of the state. Nothing in this section amends, expands, or supersedes the provisions of s. 768.28.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-386; s. 701, ch. 95-148; s. 88, ch. 99-8; s. 21, ch. 2000-122; s. 413, ch. 2003-261; s. 106, ch. 2004-267; s. 26, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>