<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0393.0674" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any person willfully, knowingly, or intentionally to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail, by false statement, misrepresentation, impersonation, or other fraudulent means, to disclose in any application for voluntary or paid employment a material fact used in making a determination as to such person’s qualifications to be a direct service provider;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide or attempt to provide supports or services with direct service providers who are not in compliance with the background screening requirements in this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use information from the criminal records or central abuse hotline obtained under s. 393.0655, s. 393.066, or s. 393.067 for any purpose other than screening that person for employment as specified in those sections or release such information to any other person for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in those sections.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, for any person willfully, knowingly, or intentionally to use information from the juvenile records of a person obtained under s. 393.0655, s. 393.066, or s. 393.067 for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in those sections or to release information from such records to any other person for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in those sections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 85-54; s. 27, ch. 90-347; s. 11, ch. 94-154; s. 63, ch. 2000-349; s. 21, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>