<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0393.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hearing rights.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVIEW OF AGENCY DECISIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For Medicaid programs administered by the agency, any developmental services applicant or client, or his or her parent, guardian advocate, or authorized representative, may request a hearing in accordance with federal law and rules applicable to Medicaid cases and has the right to request an administrative hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57. These hearings shall be provided by the Department of Children and Family Services pursuant to s. 409.285 and shall follow procedures consistent with federal law and rules applicable to Medicaid cases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other developmental services applicant or client, or his or her parent, guardian, guardian advocate, or authorized representative, who has any substantial interest determined by the agency, has the right to request an administrative hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57, which shall be conducted pursuant to s. 120.57(1), (2), or (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the right to an administrative hearing shall be given, both verbally and in writing, to the applicant or client, and his or her parent, guardian, guardian advocate, or authorized representative, at the same time that the agency gives the applicant or client notice of the agency’s action. The notice shall be given, both verbally and in writing, in the language of the client or applicant and in English.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request for a hearing under this section shall be made to the agency, in writing, within 30 days after the applicant’s or client’s receipt of the notice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVIEW OF PROVIDER DECISIONS.<EmDash />The agency shall adopt rules to establish uniform guidelines for the agency and service providers relevant to termination, suspension, or reduction of client services by the service provider. The rules shall ensure the due process rights of service providers and clients.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 89-308; s. 703, ch. 95-148; s. 122, ch. 96-410; s. 109, ch. 2004-267; s. 3, ch. 2010-157.</History>
</Section>