<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0238.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reemployment after retirement; conditions and limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is retired under this chapter, except under the disability provisions of s. 238.07, may be employed by an employer that does not participate in a state-administered retirement system and may receive compensation from such employment without limiting or restricting in any way the retirement benefits payable to such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person retired under this chapter, except under the disability retirement provisions of s. 238.07, may be reemployed by any private or public employer after retirement and receive retirement benefits and compensation from his or her employer without limitation, except that no person may receive both a salary from reemployment with any agency participating in the Florida Retirement System and retirement benefits under this chapter for a period of 12 months immediately subsequent to the date of retirement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom the limitation in paragraph (a) applies who violates such reemployment limitation and who is reemployed with any agency participating in the Florida Retirement System before completion of the 12-month limitation period shall give timely notice of this fact in writing to his or her employer and to the Department of Management Services and shall have his or her retirement benefits suspended for the balance of the 12-month limitation period. Any person employed in violation of this paragraph and any employing agency which knowingly employs or appoints such person without notifying the department to suspend retirement benefits shall be jointly and severally liable for reimbursement to the retirement trust fund of any benefits paid during the reemployment limitation period. To avoid liability, such employing agency shall have a written statement from the retiree that he or she is not retired from a state-administered retirement system. Any retirement benefits received while reemployed during this reemployment limitation period shall be repaid to the retirement trust fund, and retirement benefits shall remain suspended until such repayment has been made. Benefits suspended beyond the reemployment limitation shall apply toward repayment of benefits received in violation of the reemployment limitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2003, after a retired member has been retired for 1 calendar month in accordance with s. 121.021(39), a district school board may reemploy such retired member as a substitute or hourly teacher on a noncontractual basis, or reemploy such retired member as instructional personnel, as defined in s. 1012.01(2)(a), on an annual contractual basis. Any other retired member who is reemployed within 1 calendar month after retirement shall void his or her application for retirement benefits. All retirees reemployed under this paragraph shall become renewed members of the Florida Retirement System under s. 121.122, and district school boards reemploying such retired members as described herein are subject to the contributions as provided for renewed membership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community college board of trustees may reemploy a retired member as an adjunct instructor, that is, an instructor who is noncontractual and part time, or as a participant in a phased retirement program within a community college, after he or she has been retired for 1 calendar month, in accordance with s. 121.021(39). Any retired member who is reemployed within 1 calendar month after retirement shall void his or her application for retirement benefits. Boards of trustees reemploying such instructors are subject to the retirement contribution required in paragraph (g). A retired member may be reemployed as an adjunct instructor for no more than 780 hours during the first 12 months of his or her retirement. Any retired member reemployed for more than 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall give timely notice in writing to his or her employer and to the department of the date he or she will exceed the limitation. The department shall suspend his or her retirement benefits for the remainder of his or her first 12 months of retirement. Any person employed in violation of this paragraph and any employing agency which knowingly employs or appoints such person without notifying the department to suspend retirement benefits shall be jointly and severally liable for reimbursement to the retirement trust fund of any benefits paid during the reemployment limitation period. To avoid liability, such employing agency shall have a written statement from the retiree that he or she is not retired from a state-administered retirement system. Any retirement benefits received by a retired member while reemployed in excess of 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall be repaid to the Retirement System Trust Fund, and retirement benefits shall remain suspended until repayment is made. Benefits suspended beyond the end of the retired member’s first 12 months of retirement shall apply toward repayment of benefits received in violation of the 780-hour reemployment limitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind may reemploy a retired member as a substitute teacher, substitute residential instructor, or substitute nurse on a noncontractual basis after he or she has been retired for 1 calendar month, in accordance with s. 121.021(39). Any retired member who is reemployed within 1 calendar month after retirement shall void his or her application for retirement benefits. The Board of Trustees of the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind reemploying such teachers, residential instructors, or nurses is subject to the retirement contribution required by paragraph (g). Reemployment of a retired member as a substitute teacher, substitute residential instructor, or substitute nurse is limited to 780 hours during the first 12 months of his or her retirement. Any retired member reemployed for more than 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall give timely notice in writing to his or her employer and to the department of the date he or she will exceed the limitation. The department shall suspend his or her retirement benefits for the remainder of his or her first 12 months of retirement. Any person employed in violation of this paragraph and any employing agency which knowingly employs or appoints such person without notifying the department to suspend retirement benefits shall be jointly and severally liable for reimbursement to the retirement trust fund of any benefits paid during the reemployment limitation period. To avoid liability, such employing agency shall have a written statement from the retiree that he or she is not retired from a state-administered retirement system. Any retirement benefits received by a retired member while reemployed in excess of 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall be repaid to the Retirement System Trust Fund, and his or her retirement benefits shall remain suspended until payment is made. Benefits suspended beyond the end of the retired member’s first 12 months of retirement shall apply toward repayment of benefits received in violation of the 780-hour reemployment limitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State University System may reemploy a retired member as an adjunct faculty member or as a participant in a phased retirement program within the State University System after the retired member has been retired for 1 calendar month, in accordance with s. 121.021(39). Any retired member who is reemployed within 1 calendar month after retirement shall void his or her application for retirement benefits. The State University System is subject to the retired contribution required in paragraph (g), as appropriate. A retired member may be reemployed as an adjunct faculty member or a participant in a phased retirement program for no more than 780 hours during the first 12 months of his or her retirement. Any retired member reemployed for more than 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall give timely notice in writing to his or her employer and to the department of the date he or she will exceed the limitation. The department shall suspend his or her retirement benefits for the remainder of his or her first 12 months of retirement. Any person employed in violation of this paragraph and any employing agency which knowingly employs or appoints such person without notifying the department to suspend retirement benefits shall be jointly and severally liable for reimbursement to the retirement trust fund of any benefits paid during the reemployment limitation period. To avoid liability, such employing agency shall have a written statement from the retiree that he or she is not retired from a state-administered retirement system. Any retirement benefits received by a retired member while reemployed in excess of 780 hours during his or her first 12 months of retirement shall be repaid to the Retirement System Trust Fund, and retirement benefits shall remain suspended until repayment is made. Benefits suspended beyond the end of the retired member’s first 12 months of retirement shall apply toward repayment of benefits received in violation of the 780-hour reemployment limitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment by an employer of any retiree of a state-administered retirement system shall have no effect on the average final compensation or years of creditable service of such retiree. Prior to July 1, 1991, upon employment of any person, other than an elected officer as provided in s. 121.053, who has been retired under any state-administered retirement program, the employer shall pay retirement contributions in an amount equal to the unfunded actuarial accrued liability portion of the employer contribution which would be required for a regular member of the Florida Retirement System. Effective July 1, 1991, contributions shall be made as provided in s. 121.122 for renewed membership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limitations of this subsection apply to reemployment in any capacity with an “employer” as defined in s. 121.021(10), irrespective of the category of funds from which the person is compensated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28110, 1953; s. 12, ch. 29942, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-189; s. 1, ch. 69-300; s. 1, ch. 72-215; s. 4, ch. 80-126; s. 9, ch. 81-307; s. 22, ch. 84-266; s. 5, ch. 85-220; s. 2, ch. 88-61; s. 21, ch. 90-274; s. 18, ch. 92-122; s. 23, ch. 95-148; s. 19, ch. 97-180; s. 86, ch. 99-255; s. 1, ch. 2004-355.</History></Section>