<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0238.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Regular benefits; survivor benefits.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any member retires and before his or her death fails to select one of the optional benefits set forth in s. 238.08, the member’s executors or administrators shall receive the excess of his or her accumulated contributions at retirement over the total of all annuity payments made to the member.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions for the retirement of a member are as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To retire at the age of 60 upon the basis of a standard of service of 35 years (this provision shall be known and referred to throughout this chapter as plan A); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To retire at the age of 55 upon the basis of a standard of service of 35 years (this provision shall be known and referred to throughout this chapter as plan B); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To retire at the age of 55 upon the basis of a standard of service of 30 years (this provision shall be known and referred to throughout this chapter as plan C); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To retire after 25 years of service upon the basis of a standard of service of 25 years provided the member has reached age 50; provided, further, however, that a member electing to retire under this provision shall not be eligible to receive the benefits allowed by subsection (8) and paragraph (11)(f) (this provision shall be known and referred to throughout this chapter as plan D); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To retire:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At normal retirement age which shall be age 60 for those persons whose membership date, or last renewal thereof, occurred prior to July 1, 1963, and age 62 for those persons whose membership date, or last renewal thereof, occurred on or after July 1, 1963; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to normal retirement age but at or subsequent to age 55, provided that upon such date the member has completed 10 years of creditable service, which shall be the early retirement age; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent to normal retirement age, which shall be the delayed retirement age; (this provision shall be known and referred to throughout this chapter as plan E); or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, effective January 1, 1993, the normal retirement age for a member under this chapter is attained upon the member’s completion of 30 years of creditable service in the aggregate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The manner and time of selecting a plan of retirement are set out elsewhere in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member who, prior to July 1, 1955, elected to retire under one of plans A, B, C, or D may elect, prior to retirement, to retire under plan E in accordance with the terms hereof. Any person who became a member on or after July 1, 1955, shall retire under plan E, except as provided for under s. 238.31. With respect to plans A, B, C, or D, any member shall have the right at any time to change to a plan of retirement requiring a lower rate of contribution. The Department of Management Services shall also notify the member of the rate of contribution such member must make from and after selecting such plan of retirement. Any member in service may retire upon reaching the age of retirement formerly selected by him or her, upon the member’s written application to the department setting forth at which time, not more than 90 days subsequent to the execution and filing of such application, it is his or her desire to retire notwithstanding that during such period of notification he or she may have separated from service. Upon receipt of such application for retirement, the department shall retire such member not more than 90 days thereafter. Before such member may retire he or she must file with the department his or her written selection of one of the optional benefits provided in s. 238.08.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon service retirement under plans A and B, a member shall receive a retirement allowance which shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of the member’s accumulated contributions at the time of his or her retirement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pension, in addition to this annuity, of one one-hundred-fortieth of the member’s average final compensation, multiplied by the number of his or her years of membership service since he or she last became a member; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member has a prior service certificate in full force and effect, an additional pension of one-seventieth of his or her average final compensation, multiplied by the number of years of service certified on his or her prior service certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon service retirement under plan C a member shall receive a service retirement allowance which shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of the member’s accumulated contributions at the time of his or her retirement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pension, in addition to the member’s annuity of one one-hundred-twentieth of his or her average final compensation, multiplied by the number of years of membership service since he or she last became a member; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member has a prior service certificate in full force and effect, an additional pension of one-sixtieth of his or her average final compensation, multiplied by the number of years of service certified on his or her prior service certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon service retirement under plan D, a member shall receive a service retirement allowance which shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of the member’s accumulated contributions at the time of his or her retirement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pension, in addition to the member’s annuity, of one one-hundredth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of his or her years of membership service since he or she last became a member; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member has a prior service certificate in full force and effect, an additional pension of one-fiftieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of service certified on his or her prior service certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon service retirement under plan E, a member shall receive a service retirement allowance which shall be determined as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At normal retirement age: Two percent of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of creditable service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At early retirement age: Two percent of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of creditable service and adjusted for actuarial equivalents based on completed months by which early retirement precedes normal retirement as provided in paragraph (2)(e).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At delayed retirement age: Two percent of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of creditable service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member who has heretofore, or who hereafter, retires after 30 years of creditable service shall receive a retirement allowance of not less than $100 per month, provided, however that with respect to plans A, B, or C, any person with less than 30 but with 10 or more years of service shall be entitled to a service retirement allowance which shall be computed on the basis of an average final compensation of $2,400 per year and shall receive a retirement allowance which shall be the equivalent of one-sixtieth of said average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of his or her creditable service; provided that in no event shall such a member receive a retirement allowance greater than $100 per month.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member who has taught, or who teaches in the public free schools of Florida for not less than an aggregate of 10 years and withdraws or has withdrawn from the system, may elect to leave his or her accumulated contributions in the system or to repay his or her withdrawn accumulations to the system, and upon reaching retirement age, the member shall receive a retirement allowance based on the number of years of service which he or she taught in the public schools of Florida before retirement, provided, that a person who has lost his or her membership and later returns to service shall be allowed the privilege of having credit restored for previous service if he or she returns to full-time teaching service and renders 3 additional years of continuous service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member in service, who has 10 or more years of creditable service, may upon the application of his or her employer or upon his or her own application, be retired by the department not less than 30 nor more than 90 days next following the date of filing such application, on a disability retirement allowance; provided that a physician licensed by this state examines and certifies that such member is mentally or physically incapacitated for the further performance of duty, that such incapacity is likely to be permanent, and that such member should be retired, and the department concurs. In making the determination, the department may require other evidence of disability as deemed appropriate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon retirement on account of disability, a member shall be paid his or her service retirement allowance if he or she is eligible for a service retirement allowance; otherwise, the member shall receive a retirement allowance which shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of his or her accumulated contributions at the time of retirement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is making contributions for retirement under plan A or B, he or she shall receive a pension which, together with his or her annuity shall provide a total retirement allowance equal to one-seventieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of service creditable to him or her at retirement, if such retirement allowance exceeds 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation; or if such retirement allowance does not exceed 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation, a pension shall be payable which, together with his or her annuity, shall provide a total retirement allowance of 25 percent of his or her average final compensation; provided, however that no retirement allowance shall exceed one-seventieth of his or her average final compensation, multiplied by the number of years of total service which would be credited to the member were his or her service continued to the minimum age for service retirement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is making contributions for retirement under plan C, he or she shall receive a pension which, together with his or her annuity, shall provide a total retirement allowance equal to one-sixtieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of service creditable to him or her at retirement, if such retirement allowance exceeds 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation; or if such retirement allowance does not exceed 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation, a pension shall be payable which, together with his or her annuity, shall provide a total retirement allowance of 25 percent of his or her average final compensation; provided, however that no retirement allowance shall exceed one-sixtieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of total service which would be credited to the member were his or her service continued to the minimum age for service retirement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is making contributions for retirement under plan D, he or she shall receive a pension, which together with his or her annuity shall provide a total retirement allowance equal to one-fiftieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of service creditable to him or her at retirement, if such retirement allowance exceeds 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation; or if such retirement allowance does not exceed 25 percent of the member’s average final compensation, a pension shall be payable which, together with his or her annuity, shall provide a total retirement allowance of 25 percent of his or her average final compensation, provided, however that no retirement allowance shall exceed one-fiftieth of his or her average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of total service which would be creditable to the member were his or her service continued to the minimum age of service retirement; provided, however that when a member has taught the standard number of years required for retirement under any of the several retirement plans provided by this section and elected by such member, and such member shall retire on account of disability prior to attainment of the minimum required age under the plan elected, then such member so retired shall receive the same benefits as if he or she had retired on service retirement under the plan elected.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is making contributions for retirement under plan E, he or she shall receive a retirement allowance which shall consist of 100 percent of the retirement allowance to which he or she would be entitled if his or her date of disability retirement were his or her otherwise normal retirement date; provided, however that the retirement allowance payable upon disability retirement shall not be less than the 25 percent of average final compensation nor, if disability retirement occurs prior to the date on which the member is first eligible for service retirement, shall it be greater than the service retirement allowance to which the member would be entitled if he or she continued in active service to such date at the same rate of compensation effective on the date of disability retirement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to plans A, B, or C, the average final compensation under this subsection shall be computed on the actual average final compensation, or upon the basis of an average final compensation of $2,400 per year, whichever is the greater.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the minimum disability retirement allowance set out in paragraphs (a) through (f), any member who retired prior to July 1, 1957, on account of disability, shall, on and after July 1, 1957, receive as a minimum disability retirement allowance $75 per month, or an annual sum equal to 40 multiplied by the number of years of his or her creditable service whichever is the greater, and any person who retires on and after July 1, 1957, shall, from the date of his or her retirement, receive as a minimum disability retirement allowance $75 per month, or an annual sum equal to 40 multiplied by the number of years of creditable service, whichever is the greater.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a member who has attained normal retirement age and is retiring on account of disability shall be eligible to receive a minimum of 25 percent of his or her average final compensation under Option 1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once each year during the first 5 years following the retirement of a member on a disability retirement allowance, and once in every 3-year period thereafter, the department may require any disability beneficiary who has not yet attained his or her minimum service retirement age to undergo a medical examination by a physician licensed by this state and to submit any other evidence of disability as required by the department. Should a disability beneficiary who has not yet attained his or her minimum service retirement age refuse to submit to any such medical examination, his or her retirement allowance shall be discontinued until his or her withdrawal of such refusal, and should such refusal continue for 1 year, all of the disability beneficiary’s rights in and to his or her pension shall be forfeited.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that a disability beneficiary is engaged in or is able to engage in a gainful occupation paying more than the difference between his or her disability retirement allowance and his or her average final compensation, the amount of the beneficiary’s pension shall be reduced to an amount which, together with his or her annuity and the amount earnable by him or her, shall equal the amount of his or her average final compensation. Should the beneficiary’s earning capacity later be changed, the amount of his or her pension may be further modified; provided that the pension so modified shall not exceed the amount of the pension allowable under subsection (11), at the time of retirement, nor an amount which, when added to the amount earnable by the beneficiary, together with his or her annuity, equals the amount of his or her average final compensation. A beneficiary restored to active service at a salary less than the average final compensation upon the basis of which he or she was retired shall not become a member of the retirement system at that time.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should a disability beneficiary under his or her minimum service retirement age be at any time in service at a salary equal to or greater than his or her average final compensation upon the basis of which he or she was retired, the beneficiary’s disability retirement allowance shall cease and he or she shall again become a member of the retirement system and shall contribute thereafter at the same rate at which he or she paid prior to disability. Any prior service certificate, on the basis of which his or her allowance was computed at the time of his or her disability retirement, shall be restored to full force and effect; and, in addition, upon his or her subsequent retirement he or she shall be credited with all his or her membership service on the basis of which his or her allowance was computed at the time of his or her disability retirement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should a member cease to be a teacher except by death or by retirement under the provisions of this chapter, the member shall be paid the amount of his or her accumulated contributions. Should a member die before retirement, the amount of his or her accumulated contributions shall be paid to such person, if any, as he or she shall have nominated by written designation duly executed and filed with the department; otherwise, to his or her executors or administrators.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member who retires on or after July 1, 1954, who at the time of his or her retirement has not served as a teacher in Florida for 10 years shall not be eligible to receive and shall not be paid any service retirement allowance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the Teachers’ Retirement System who has heretofore, or who hereafter, retires and who has passed his or her 65th birthday and whose retirement allowance is less than $150 shall have his or her retirement allowance redetermined and shall be entitled to a service retirement allowance which shall be computed on the basis of an average final compensation of $2,400 per year and shall receive a retirement allowance which shall be the equivalent of one-sixtieth of said average final compensation multiplied by the number of years of his or her creditable service; provided, that in no event shall such redetermination entitle the member to receive a retirement allowance greater than $150.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the Teachers’ Retirement System who has heretofore, or who hereafter, retires with no less than 10 years of creditable service and who has passed his or her 65th birthday, may, upon application to the department, have his or her retirement allowance redetermined and thereupon shall be entitled to a monthly service retirement allowance which shall be equal to $4 multiplied by the number of years of the member’s creditable service which shall be payable monthly during his or her retirement; provided, that the amount of retirement allowance as determined hereunder, shall be reduced by an amount equal to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any social security benefits received by the member, and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any social security benefits that the member is eligible to receive by reason of his or her own right or through his or her spouse.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No payment shall be made to a member of the Teachers’ Retirement System under this act, until the department has determined the social security status of such member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligibility of a member of the Teachers’ Retirement System shall be determined under the social security laws and regulations; provided, however, that a member shall be considered eligible if the member or the member’s spouse has reached 65 years of age and would draw social security if the member or the member’s spouse were not engaged in activity that results in the member or the member’s spouse receiving income that would make him or her ineligible to receive social security benefits. A member of the Teachers’ Retirement System shall be deemed to be eligible for social security benefits if the member has this eligibility in his or her own right or through his or her spouse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review, at least annually, the social security status of all members of the Teachers’ Retirement System receiving payment under this act and shall increase or decrease payments to such members as shall be necessary to carry out the intent of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No member of the Teachers’ Retirement System shall have his or her retirement allowance reduced or any of his or her rights impaired by reason of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall take effect on January 1, 1962.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member recovers from disability, has his or her disability benefit terminated, reenters covered employment, and is continuously employed for a minimum of 1 year of creditable service, he or she may claim as creditable service the months during which he or she was receiving a disability benefit, upon payment of the required contributions. Contributions shall equal the total required employee and employer contribution rate during the period the retiree received retirement benefits, multiplied times his or her rate of monthly compensation prior to the commencement of disability retirement for each month of the period claimed, plus 4 percent interest until July 1, 1975, and 6.5 percent interest thereafter on such contributions, compounded annually each June 30 to the date of payment. If the member does not claim credit for all of the months he or she received disability benefits, the months claimed must be his or her most recent months of retirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Definitions under survivor benefits are:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dependent is a child, widow, widower, or parent of the deceased member who was receiving not less than one-half of his or her support from the deceased member at the time of the death of such member.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child is a natural or legally adopted child of a member, who:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is under 18 years of age, or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is over 18 years of age but not over 22 years of age and is enrolled as a student in an accredited educational institution, or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older and is physically or mentally incapable of self-support, when such mental and physical incapacity occurred prior to such child obtaining the age of 18 years. Such person shall cease to be regarded as a child upon the termination of such physical or mental disability. The determination as to such physical or mental incapability shall be vested in the department.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">No person shall be considered a child who has married or, except as provided in sub-subparagraph 2.b. or as to a child who is physically or mentally incapable of self-support as hereinbefore set forth, has become 18 years of age.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent is a natural parent of a member and includes a lawful spouse of a natural parent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficiary is a person who is entitled to benefits under this subsection by reason of his or her relation to a deceased member during the lifetime of such member.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to all other benefits to which a member shall, subject to the conditions set out below, be entitled, the beneficiary of such member shall, upon the death of such member, receive the following benefits:</Text>
				<Table Width="100" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">
					<ColumnDefinitions><Column Width="34" />
						<Column Width="33" />
						<Column Width="33" />
					</ColumnDefinitions>
					<CellPadding Left="6" Right="0" Top="0" Bottom ="0"/>
					<Header>
						<Row>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Minimum period of paid service of member in Florida as regular full-time teacher</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Beneficiaries of deceased member</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Benefits</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
					</Header>
					<Body>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">1. One calendar day</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell>
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Widow or widower who has care of dependent child or children of deceased member.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$190 per month for one child. $250 per month if more than one child, maximum benefits $250 per month.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">2. One calendar day</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell>
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">One or more dependent children if there is no surviving widow or widower.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$190 per month per child; maximum benefits $250 per month if more than one child.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell>
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">3. One calendar day</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Dependent parents 65 years or older.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">For each parent, $100 per month for life.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">4. One calendar day</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Designated beneficiary and, if no designated beneficiary, then the executor or administrator of deceased member.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$500 lump-sum death benefits payable only once.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">5. One calendar day</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Dependent widow or widower 50 years of age and less than 65 years of age.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell>
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$150 per month for life.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">6. Ten years</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Widow or widower 65 years of age or older.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$175 per month for life.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
						<Row SpaceAbove="true">
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">7. Retired member</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">Designated beneficiary and if no designated beneficiary, then the executor or administrator of deceased retired member.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
							<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
								<Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="6.0">$500 lump-sum death benefits payable only once.</Font></Text>
							</Cell>
						</Row>
					</Body>
				</Table>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Beginning on July 1, 1971, the lump-sum death benefit, provided in item 7 above for the retired teacher, shall apply to all present and future retirees of the systems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of survivor benefits shall begin as of the month immediately following the death of the member except where the beneficiary has not reached the age required to receive benefits under paragraph (b), in which event the payment of survivor benefits shall begin as of the month immediately following the month in which the beneficiary reaches the required age. Provided that if death occurs during the first 3 years of employment, the payment of survivor benefits shall be reduced by the amount of monthly benefits the member’s survivors are entitled to receive under federal social security as either a survivor of the member or as a covered worker under federal social security.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on rights of beneficiary are:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person named as beneficiary in paragraph (b) shall, in no event, be entitled to receive the benefits set out in such paragraph unless the death of the member under whom such beneficiary claims occurs within the period of time after the member has served in Florida as follows:</Text>
					<Table Width="100" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">
						<ColumnDefinitions><Column Width="50" />
							<Column Width="50" />
						</ColumnDefinitions>
						<Header>
							<Row>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Minimum number of years<NewLine />of service in Florida</Text>
								</Cell>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Right">
									<Text xml:space="preserve">Period after serving in<NewLine />Florida in which<NewLine />death of member<NewLine />occurs</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
						</Header>
						<Body>
							<Row>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left" ColSpan="2">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"> 3 to 5<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />2 years</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left" ColSpan="2">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"> 6 to 9<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />5 years</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
							<Row>
								<Cell HorizontalAlign="Left" ColSpan="2">
									<Text xml:space="preserve"> 10 or more<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />10 years</Text>
								</Cell>
							</Row>
						</Body>
					</Table>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the death of a member, the department shall make a determination of the beneficiary or beneficiaries of the deceased member and shall pay survivor benefits to such beneficiary or beneficiaries beginning 1 month immediately following the death of the member except where the beneficiary has not reached the age required to receive benefits under paragraph (b), in which event the payment of survivor benefits shall begin as of the month immediately following the month in which the beneficiary reaches the required age. When required by the department, the beneficiary or beneficiaries shall file an application for survivor benefits upon forms prescribed by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiaries of a member to receive survivor benefits are fixed by this subsection, and a member may not buy or otherwise change such benefits. He or she may, however, designate the beneficiary to receive the $500 death benefits. If a member fails to make this designation, the $500 death benefits shall be paid to his or her executor or administrator.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary or beneficiaries of a member whose death occurs while he or she is in service or while he or she is receiving a disability allowance under subsection (11), shall receive survivor benefits under this subsection determined by the years of service in Florida of the deceased member as set out in paragraph (b). The requirement that the death of a member must occur within a certain period of time after service in Florida as set out in subparagraph (d)1. shall not apply to a member receiving a disability benefit at the time of his or her death.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who hereafter elects to receive retirement benefits under s. 112.05 shall not be entitled to the retirement benefits of this chapter except for the refund of his or her accumulated contributions as provided in subsection (13); likewise any person who elects to receive retirement benefits under this chapter shall thereby become ineligible to receive retirement benefits under s. 112.05.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 19014, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 892(162); s. 4, ch. 22693, 1945; s. 4, ch. 23864, 1947; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 4, ch. 25398, 1949; s. 1, ch. 28110, 1953; s. 3, ch. 28196, 1953; s. 6, ch. 29942, 1955; ss. 2, 4, 5, ch. 57-357; s. 2, ch. 61-301; ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 61-333; ss. 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 61-458; ss. 4, 5, 7, 12, ch. 63-554; ss. 1, 2, ch. 65-552; s. 1, ch. 67-557; ss. 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 69-189; s. 1, ch. 70-125; s. 1, ch. 70-998; s. 1, ch. 71-198; s. 2, ch. 71-260; s. 1, ch. 71-347; s. 1, ch. 72-343; s. 1, ch. 73-326; s. 1, ch. 76-225; s. 14, ch. 80-295; s. 6, ch. 86-180; s. 4, ch. 87-19; s. 17, ch. 92-122; s. 3, ch. 92-139; s. 10, ch. 95-148; s. 77, ch. 99-255; s. 35, ch. 2010-5.</History>
</Section>