<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of partnership agreement; nonwaivable provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), relations among partners and between partners and a partnership are governed by the partnership agreement. To the extent the partnership agreement does not otherwise provide, this act governs relations among partners and between partners and a partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partnership agreement may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the rights and duties under s. 620.8105 except to eliminate the duty to provide copies of statements to all of the partners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the law applicable to a limited liability partnership under s. 620.8106(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restrict the right of access to books and records under s. 620.8403(2) or to information under s. 620.8403(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate the duty of loyalty under s. 620.8404(2) or s. 620.8603(2)(c), but:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partnership agreement may identify specific types or categories of activities that do not violate the duty of loyalty, if not manifestly unreasonable; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the partners or a number or percentage specified in the partnership agreement may authorize or ratify, after full disclosure of all material facts, a specific act or transaction that otherwise would violate the duty of loyalty;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably reduce the duty of care under s. 620.8404(3) or s. 620.8603(2)(c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate the obligation of good faith and fair dealing under s. 620.8404(4), but the partnership agreement may prescribe the standards by which the performance of the obligation is to be measured if the standards are not manifestly unreasonable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the power to dissociate as a partner under s. 620.8602(1), except to require the notice under s. 620.8601(1) to be in writing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the right of a court to expel a partner under the events specified in s. 620.8601(5);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the requirement to wind up the partnership business in cases specified in s. 620.8801(4), (5), or (6); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrict rights of third parties under this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242; s. 2, ch. 99-285; s. 18, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>