<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability for contribution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner’s obligation to contribute money or other property or other benefit to, or to perform services for, a limited partnership shall be in a record signed by the partner, and such obligation shall not be excused by the partner’s death, disability, or other inability to perform personally.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a partner does not make a promised nonmonetary contribution, the partner is obligated at the option of the limited partnership to contribute money equal to that portion of the value, as stated in the required information, of the stated contribution which has not been made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligation of a partner to make a contribution or return money or other property paid or distributed in violation of this act may be compromised only by consent of all partners. A creditor of a limited partnership which extends credit or otherwise acts in reliance on an obligation described in subsection (1), without notice of any compromise under this subsection, may enforce the original obligation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership agreement may provide that the interest of any partner who fails to make any contribution that the partner is obligated to make shall be subject to specified penalties for, or specified consequences of, such failure. Such penalty or consequence may take the form of reducing the partner’s proportionate interest in the limited partnership, subordinating the partner’s partnership interests to that of nondefaulting partners, a forced sale, or the forfeiture of the partner’s interest in the limited partnership, the lending by other partners of the amount necessary to meet the partner’s commitment, a fixing of the value of the partner’s interest in the limited partnership by appraisal or by formula and redemption or sale of such interest at such value, or other penalty or consequence.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>