<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8911" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section and ss. 620.8912-620.8923:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Constituent partnership” means a constituent organization that is a partnership governed by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Constituent organization” means an organization that is party to a merger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Converted organization” means the organization into which a converting organization converts pursuant to ss. 620.8912-620.8915.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Converting partnership” means a converting organization that is a partnership governed by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Converting organization” means an organization that converts into another organization pursuant to s. 620.8912.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governing law” of an organization means the law that governs the organization’s internal affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Organization” means a corporation; general partnership, including a limited liability partnership; limited partnership, including a limited liability limited partnership; limited liability company; common law or business trust or association; real estate investment trust; or any other person organized under a governing law or other applicable law, provided such term shall not include an organization that is not organized for profit, unless the not-for-profit organization is the converted organization in a conversion or the surviving organization in a merger governed by this act. The term includes both domestic and foreign organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Organizational documents” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a domestic or foreign general partnership, its partnership agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership, its certificate of limited partnership and partnership agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a domestic or foreign limited liability company, its articles of organization and operating agreement, or comparable records as provided in its governing law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a business trust, its agreement of trust and declaration of trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a domestic or foreign corporation for profit, its articles of incorporation, bylaws, and other agreements among its shareholders which are authorized by its governing law, or comparable records as provided in its governing law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any other organization, the basic records that create the organization and determine its internal governance and the relations among the persons that own it, have an interest in it, or are members of it.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal liability” means personal liability for a debt, liability, or other obligation of an organization which is imposed on a person that coowns, has an interest in, or is a member of the organization:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the organization’s governing law solely by reason of the person’s coowning, having an interest in, or being a member of the organization; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the organization’s organizational documents under a provision of the organization’s governing law authorizing those documents to make one or more specified persons liable for all or specified debts, liabilities, and other obligations of the organization solely by reason of the person or persons’ coowning, having an interest in, or being a member of the organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surviving organization” means an organization into which one or more other organizations are merged. A surviving organization may preexist the merger or be created by the merger.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2005-267; s. 135, ch. 2007-5; s. 15, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>