<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8921" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability of a partner after conversion or merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conversion or merger under this act does not discharge any liability under ss. 620.8306 and 620.8703 of a person that was a partner in or dissociated as a partner from a converting or constituent partnership, but:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act pertaining to the collection or discharge of the liability continue to apply to the liability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of applying those provisions, the converted or surviving organization is deemed to be the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person is required to pay any amount under this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a right of contribution from each other person that was liable as a partner under s. 620.8306 when the obligation was incurred and has not been released from the obligation under s. 620.8703.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such rights of contribution and the relative amounts of contribution shall be determined and settled in the same manner as provided in s. 620.8807(3).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other liability provided by law:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that immediately before a conversion or merger became effective was a partner in a converting or constituent partnership that was not a limited liability partnership is personally liable on a transaction entered into by the converted or surviving organization with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if, at the time the third party enters into the transaction, the third party:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The converted or surviving business is the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The converting or constituent partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is a partner in the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that was dissociated as a partner from a converting or constituent partnership before the conversion or merger became effective is personally liable on a transaction entered into by the converted or surviving organization with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately before the conversion or merger became effective the converting or surviving partnership was not a limited liability partnership.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the third party enters into the transaction fewer than 2 years have passed since the person dissociated as a partner, and the third party:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the dissociation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that the converted or surviving organization is the converting or constituent partnership, the converting or constituent limited partnership is not a limited liability partnership, and the person is a partner in the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>