<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1607" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability to other persons of person dissociated as general partner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person’s dissociation as a general partner does not of itself discharge the person’s liability as a general partner for an obligation of the limited partnership incurred before dissociation. Except as otherwise provided in subsections (2) and (3), the person is not liable for a limited partnership’s obligation incurred after dissociation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose dissociation as a general partner resulted in a dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities is liable to the same extent as a general partner under s. 620.1404 on an obligation incurred by the limited partnership under s. 620.1804.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that has dissociated as a general partner but whose dissociation did not result in a dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities is liable on a transaction entered into by the limited partnership after the dissociation only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner would be liable on the transaction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the other party enters into the transaction:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Less than 2 years have passed since the dissociation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The other party does not have notice of the dissociation and reasonably believes that the person is a general partner.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By agreement with a creditor of a limited partnership and the limited partnership, a person dissociated as a general partner may be released from liability for an obligation of the limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person dissociated as a general partner is released from liability for an obligation of the limited partnership if the limited partnership’s creditor, with notice of the person’s dissociation as a general partner but without the person’s consent, agrees to a material alteration in the nature or time of payment of the obligation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>