<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8920" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restrictions on approval of conversions and mergers and on relinquishing limited liability partnership status.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a partner of a converting or constituent partnership will have personal liability with respect to a converted or surviving organization, approval and amendment of a plan of conversion or merger are ineffective without the consent of the partner, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partnership’s partnership agreement provides for the approval of the conversion or merger with the consent of fewer than all the partners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partner has consented to the provision of the partnership agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment to a statement of qualification of a limited liability partnership which revokes its status as such is ineffective without the consent of each general partner unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability partnership’s partnership agreement provides for the amendment with the consent of less than all its partners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each partner that does not consent to the amendment has consented to the provision of the partnership agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner does not give the consent required by subsection (1) or subsection (2) merely by consenting to a provision of the partnership agreement which permits the partnership agreement to be amended with the consent of fewer than all the partners.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>