<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8602" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Partner’s power to dissociate; wrongful dissociation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner has the power to dissociate at any time, rightfully or wrongfully, by express will pursuant to s. 620.8601(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner’s dissociation is wrongful only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in breach of an express provision of the partnership agreement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a partnership for a definite term or particular undertaking, before the expiration of the term or the completion of the undertaking:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partner withdraws by express will, unless the withdrawal follows within 90 days after another partner’s dissociation by death or otherwise under s. 620.8601(6)-(10) or wrongful dissociation under this subsection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partner is expelled by judicial determination under s. 620.8601(5);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partner is dissociated by becoming a debtor in bankruptcy; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a partner who is not an individual, trust other than a business trust, or estate, the partner is expelled or otherwise dissociated because the partner willfully dissolved or terminated.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner who wrongfully dissociates is liable to the partnership and to the other partners for damages caused by the dissociation. The liability is in addition to any other obligation of the partner to the partnership or to the other partners.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242.</History></Section>