<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Name.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of a limited partnership may contain the name of any partner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of a limited partnership that is not a limited liability limited partnership must contain the phrase “limited partnership” or “limited” or the abbreviation “L.P.” or “Ltd.” or the designation “LP,” and may not contain the phrase “limited liability limited partnership” or the abbreviation “L.L.L.P.” or the designation “LLLP.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of a limited liability limited partnership must contain the phrase “limited liability limited partnership” or the abbreviation “L.L.L.P.” or designation “LLLP,” except that a limited liability limited partnership organized prior to the effective date of this act that is using an abbreviation or designation permitted under prior law shall be entitled to continue using such abbreviation or designation until its dissolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of a limited partnership must be distinguishable in the records of the Department of State from the names of all other entities or filings, except fictitious name registrations pursuant to s. 865.09 organized, registered, or reserved under the laws of this state, the names of which are on file with the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to s. 620.1905, this section applies to any foreign limited partnership transacting business in this state, having a certificate of authority to transact business in this state, or applying for a certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267; s. 71, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>