<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of status.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State, upon request and payment of the requisite fee, shall furnish a certificate of status for a limited partnership if the records filed in the Department of State show that the Department of State has filed a certificate of limited partnership. A certificate of status must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited partnership’s name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the limited partnership was duly formed under the laws of this state and the date of formation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether all fees and penalties due to the Department of State under this act have been paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the limited partnership’s most recent annual report required by s. 620.1210 has been filed by the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the Department of State has administratively dissolved the limited partnership or received a record notifying the Department of State that the limited partnership has been dissolved by judicial action pursuant to s. 620.1802.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the Department of State has filed a certificate of dissolution for the limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the Department of State has filed a statement of termination for the limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State, upon request and payment of the requisite fee, shall furnish a certificate of status for a foreign limited partnership if the records filed in the Department of State show that the Department of State has filed a certificate of authority. A certificate of status must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited partnership’s name and any alternate name adopted under s. 620.1905(1) for use in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the foreign limited partnership is authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether all fees and penalties due to the Department of State under this act or other law have been paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the foreign limited partnership’s most recent annual report required by s. 620.1210 has been filed by the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the Department of State has revoked the foreign limited partnership’s certificate of authority or filed a notice of cancellation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to any qualification stated in the certificate, a certificate of status issued by the Department of State may be relied upon as conclusive evidence that the limited partnership or foreign limited partnership is in existence or is authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>