<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.2111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability of general partner after conversion or merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conversion or merger under this act does not discharge any liability under ss. 620.1404 and 620.1607 of a person that was a general partner in or dissociated as a general partner from a converting or constituent limited partnership, but:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act pertaining to the collection or discharge of the liability continue to apply to the liability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of applying those provisions, the converted or surviving organization is deemed to be the converting or constituent limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person is required to pay any amount under this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a right of contribution from each other person that was liable as a general partner under s. 620.1404 when the obligation was incurred and has not been released from the obligation under s. 620.1607.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contribution due from each of those persons is in proportion to the right to receive distributions in the capacity of general partner in effect for each of those persons when the obligation was incurred.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other liability provided by law:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that immediately before a conversion or merger became effective was a general partner in a converting or constituent limited partnership that was not a limited liability limited partnership is personally liable on a transaction entered into by the converted or surviving organization with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if, at the time the third party enters into the transaction, the third party:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The converted or surviving business is the converting or constituent limited partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The converting or constituent limited partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is a general partner in the converting or constituent limited partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that was dissociated as a general partner from a converting or constituent limited partnership before the conversion or merger became effective is personally liable on a transaction entered into by the converted or surviving organization with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately before the conversion or merger became effective the converting or surviving limited partnership was not a limited liability limited partnership.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the third party enters into the transaction less than 2 years have passed since the person dissociated as a general partner and the third party:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the dissociation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that the converted or surviving organization is the converting or constituent limited partnership, the converting or constituent limited partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership, and the person is a general partner in the converting or constituent limited partnership.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>