<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.2115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assertion of rights by nominees and beneficial owners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record limited partner may assert appraisal rights as to fewer than all the limited partner interests registered in the record limited partner’s name that are owned by a beneficial limited partner only if the record limited partner objects with respect to all limited partner interests of the class or series owned by that beneficial limited partner and notifies the limited partnership in writing of the name and address of each beneficial limited partner on whose behalf appraisal rights are being asserted. The rights of a record limited partner who asserts appraisal rights for only part of the limited partner interests of the class or series held of record in the record limited partner’s name under this subsection shall be determined as if the limited partner interests as to which the record limited partner objects and the record limited partner’s other limited partner interests were registered in the names of different record limited partners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficial limited partner may assert appraisal rights as to a limited partner interest held on behalf of the partner only if such beneficial limited partner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits to the limited partnership the record limited partner’s written consent to the assertion of such rights no later than the date referred to in s. 620.2118(2)(b)2.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does so with respect to all limited partner interests of the class or series that are beneficially owned by the beneficial limited partner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>