<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1910" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amending certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign limited partnership authorized to transact business in this state shall make application to the Department of State to obtain an amended certificate of authority to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change its name on the records of the Department of State;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amend its jurisdiction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change its general partners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Add or delete its status as a limited liability limited partnership; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amend any false statement contained in its application for certificate of authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such application shall be made within 30 days after the occurrence of any change mentioned in subsection (1), must be signed by at least one general partner, and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign limited partnership as it appears on the records of the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of its formation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the foreign limited partnership was authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the name of the foreign limited partnership has been changed, the name relinquished and its new name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the amendment changes the jurisdiction of the foreign limited partnership, a statement of such change.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the amendment changes the general partners, the name and address of each new general partner. Each general partner that is not an individual must be registered with the Department of State as required by law, must maintain an active status, and must not be dissolved, revoked, or withdrawn.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the foreign limited partnership corrects a false statement, the statement it is correcting and a statement containing the corrected information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 620.1902(2) for obtaining an original certificate of authority apply to obtaining an amended certificate under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>