<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1206" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery to and filing of records by Department of State; effective time and date.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record authorized or required to be delivered to the Department of State for filing under this act must be captioned to describe the record’s purpose, be in a medium permitted by the Department of State, and be delivered to the Department of State. Unless the Department of State determines that a record does not comply with the filing requirements of this act, and if all filing fees have been paid, the Department of State shall file the record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request and payment of a fee, the Department of State shall send to the requester a certified copy of the requested record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in ss. 620.1116 and 620.1207, a record delivered to the Department of State for filing under this act may specify an effective time and a delayed effective date. Except as otherwise provided in this act, a record filed by the Department of State is effective:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the record does not specify an effective time and does not specify a delayed effective date, on the date and at the time the record is filed as evidenced by the Department of State’s endorsement of the date and time on the record;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the record specifies an effective time but not a delayed effective date, on the date the record is filed at the time specified in the record;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the record specifies a delayed effective date but not an effective time, at 12:01 a.m. on the earlier of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specified date; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 90th day after the record is filed; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the record specifies an effective time and a delayed effective date, at the specified time on the earlier of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specified date; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 90th day after the record is filed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>