<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Act” means the Florida Revised Uniform Limited Partnership Act of 2005, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate of limited partnership” means the certificate required by s. 620.1201. The term includes the certificate as amended or restated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contribution,” except in the phrase “right of contribution,” means any benefit provided by a person to a limited partnership in order to become a partner or in the person’s capacity as a partner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Debtor in bankruptcy” means a person that is the subject of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order for relief under Title 11 U.S.C. or a comparable order under a successor statute of general application; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A comparable order under federal, state, or foreign law governing insolvency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Designated office” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a limited partnership, the office that the limited partnership is required to designate and maintain under s. 620.1114.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a foreign limited partnership, its principal office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Distribution” means a transfer of money or other property from a limited partnership to a partner in the partner’s capacity as a partner or to a transferee on account of a transferable interest owned by the transferee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign limited liability limited partnership” means a foreign limited partnership whose general partners have limited liability for the obligations of the foreign limited partnership under a provision similar to s. 620.1404(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign limited partnership” means a partnership formed under the laws of a jurisdiction other than this state and required by those laws to have one or more general partners and one or more limited partners. The term includes a foreign limited liability limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General partner” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a limited partnership, a person that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Becomes a general partner under s. 620.1401; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was a general partner in a limited partnership when the limited partnership became subject to this act under s. 620.2204(1) or (2).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a foreign limited partnership, a person that has rights, powers, and obligations similar to those of a general partner in a limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited liability limited partnership,” except in the phrase “foreign limited liability limited partnership,” means a limited partnership whose certificate of limited partnership states that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership, or which was a limited liability limited partnership when the limited partnership became subject to this act under s. 620.2204(1) or (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited partner” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a limited partnership, a person that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Becomes a limited partner under s. 620.1301; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was a limited partner in a limited partnership when the limited partnership became subject to this act under s. 620.2204(1) or (2).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a foreign limited partnership, a person that has rights, powers, and obligations similar to those of a limited partner in a limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited partnership,” except in the phrases “foreign limited partnership” and “foreign limited liability limited partnership,” means an entity, having one or more general partners and one or more limited partners, which is formed under this act by two or more persons or becomes subject to this act as the result of a conversion or merger under this act, or which was a limited partnership governed by the laws of this state when this act became a law and became subject to this act under s. 620.2204(1) or (2). The term includes a limited liability limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Partner” means a limited partner or general partner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Partnership agreement” means the partners’ agreement, whether oral, implied, in a record, or in any combination thereof, concerning the limited partnership. The term includes the agreement as amended or restated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, or government; governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality; public corporation; or any other legal or commercial entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person dissociated as a general partner” means a person dissociated as a general partner of a limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Principal office” means the office at which the principal executive office of a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership is located, whether or not the office is located in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered agent” means the person acting as the registered agent of the limited partnership for service of process and meeting the requirements in s. 620.1114.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered office” means the address of the registered agent meeting the requirements of s. 620.1114.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Required information” means the information that a limited partnership is required to maintain under s. 620.1111.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sign” means to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute or adopt a tangible symbol with the present intent to authenticate a record; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attach or logically associate an electronic symbol, sound, or process to or with a record with the present intent to authenticate the record.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transfer” includes an assignment, conveyance, deed, bill of sale, lease, mortgage, security interest, encumbrance, gift, or transfer by operation of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transferable interest” means a partner’s right to receive distributions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transferee” means a person to which all or part of a transferable interest has been transferred, whether or not the transferor is a partner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>