<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Knowledge and notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person knows a fact if the person has actual knowledge of the fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person has notice of a fact if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knows of the fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a notification of the fact; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has reason to know the fact exists from all other facts known to the person at the time in question.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person notifies or gives a notification to another by taking steps reasonably required to inform the other person in the ordinary course, whether or not the other person learns of it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person receives a notification when the notification:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comes to the person’s attention; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is duly delivered at the person’s place of business or at any other place held out by the person as a place for receiving communications.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (6), a person other than an individual knows, has notice, or receives a notification of a fact for purposes of a particular transaction when the individual conducting the transaction knows, has notice, or receives a notification of the fact, or in any event when the fact would have been brought to the individual’s attention if the person had exercised reasonable diligence. The person exercises reasonable diligence if the person maintains reasonable routines for communicating significant information to an individual conducting a transaction and there is reasonable compliance with the routines. Reasonable diligence does not require an individual acting for the person to communicate information unless the communication is part of the individual’s regular duties or the individual has reason to know of the transaction and that the transaction would be materially affected by the information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner’s knowledge, notice, or receipt of a notification of a fact relating to the partnership is effective immediately as knowledge by, notice to, or receipt of a notification by the partnership, except in the case of a fraud on the partnership committed by or with the consent of that partner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242.</History></Section>