<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1903" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Activities not constituting transacting business.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Activities of a foreign limited partnership which do not constitute transacting business in this state within the meaning of s. 620.1902 include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining, defending, and settling an action or proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holding meetings of its partners or carrying on any other activity concerning its internal affairs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining accounts in financial institutions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining offices or agencies for the transfer, exchange, and registration of the foreign limited partnership’s own securities or maintaining trustees or depositories with respect to those securities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling through independent contractors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting or obtaining orders, whether by mail or electronic means or through employees, agents, or otherwise, if the orders require acceptance outside this state before they become contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creating or acquiring indebtedness, mortgages, or security interests in real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securing or collecting debts or enforcing mortgages or other security interests in property securing the debts, and holding, protecting, and maintaining property so acquired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting an isolated transaction that is completed within 30 days and is not one in the course of similar transactions of a like manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transacting business in interstate commerce.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owning and controlling a subsidiary corporation incorporated in or transacting business within this state or voting the stock of any corporation which it has lawfully acquired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owning a limited partnership interest in a limited partnership that is doing business within this state, unless such limited partner manages or controls the partnership or exercises the powers and duties of a general partner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owning, without more, real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The list of activities in subsection (1) is not exhaustive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of s. 620.1902, the ownership in this state of income-producing real property or tangible personal property, other than property excluded under subsection (1), constitutes transacting business in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply in determining the contacts or activities that may subject a foreign limited partnership to service of process, taxation, or regulation under any other law of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>