<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Knowledge and notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person knows a fact if the person has actual knowledge of the fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person has notice of a fact if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knows of the fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a notification of the fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has reason to know the fact exists from all of the facts known to the person at the time in question; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has notice of the fact under subsection (3) or subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of limited partnership on file in the Department of State is notice that the partnership is a limited partnership and the persons designated in the certificate as general partners are general partners. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4), the certificate is not notice of any other fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person has notice of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Another person’s dissociation as a general partner 90 days after the effective date of an amendment to the certificate of limited partnership which states that the other person has dissociated or 90 days after the effective date of a statement of dissociation pertaining to the other person, whichever occurs first;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited partnership’s dissolution 90 days after the effective date of the certificate of dissolution of the limited partnership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited partnership’s termination 90 days after the effective date of a statement of termination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited partnership’s conversion under s. 620.2102 90 days after the effective date of the certificate of conversion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A merger under s. 620.2106 90 days after the effective date of the certificate of merger; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any limitations upon the authority of a general partner as set forth in the initial certificate of limited partnership or, if the limitations are added by an amendment or restatement of the certificate of limited partnership, 90 days after the effective date of the amendment or restatement, provided a provision in the certificate of limited partnership limiting the authority of a general partner to transfer real property held in the name of the limited partnership is not notice of the limitation to a person who is not a partner unless the limitation appears in an affidavit, certificate, or other instrument that bears the name of the limited partnership and is recorded in the office for recording transfers of such real property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person notifies or gives a notification to another person by taking steps reasonably required to inform the other person in the ordinary course, whether or not the other person learns of it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person receives a notification when the notification:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comes to the person’s attention; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is delivered at the person’s place of business or at any other place held out by the person as a place for receiving communications.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (8), a person other than an individual knows, has notice, or receives a notification of a fact for purposes of a particular transaction when the individual conducting the transaction for the person knows, has notice, or receives a notification of the fact, or in any event when the fact would have been brought to the individual’s attention if the person had exercised reasonable diligence. A person other than an individual exercises reasonable diligence if such person maintains reasonable routines for communicating significant information to the individual conducting the transaction for the person and there is reasonable compliance with the routines. Reasonable diligence does not require an individual acting for the person to communicate information unless the communication is part of the individual’s regular duties or the individual has reason to know of the transaction and that the transaction would be materially affected by the information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner’s knowledge, notice, or receipt of a notification of a fact relating to the limited partnership is effective immediately as knowledge of, notice to, or receipt of a notification by the limited partnership, except in the case of a fraud on the limited partnership committed by or with the consent of the general partner. A limited partner’s knowledge, notice, or receipt of a notification of a fact relating to the limited partnership is not effective as knowledge of, notice to, or receipt of a notification by the limited partnership.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>