<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of dissociation as general partner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a person’s dissociation as a general partner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s right to participate as a general partner in the management and conduct of the partnership’s activities terminates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s duty of loyalty as a general partner under s. 620.1408(2)(c) terminates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s duty of loyalty as a general partner under s. 620.1408(2)(a) and (b) and duty of care under s. 620.1408(3) continue only with regard to matters arising and events occurring before the person’s dissociation as a general partner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person may sign and deliver to the Department of State for filing a statement of dissociation pertaining to the person and, at the request of the limited partnership, shall sign an amendment to the certificate of limited partnership which states that the person has dissociated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to s. 620.1704 and ss. 620.2101-620.2125, any transferable interest owned by the person immediately before dissociation in the person’s capacity as a general partner is owned by the person as a mere transferee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person’s dissociation as a general partner does not of itself discharge the person from any obligation to the limited partnership or the other partners which the person incurred while a general partner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>