<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.9102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statement of foreign qualification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before transacting business in this state, a foreign limited liability partnership must comply with the requirements of s. 620.8105 and file a statement of foreign qualification. The statement must contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign limited liability partnership which satisfies the requirements of the state or other jurisdiction under whose law it is formed and ends with “Registered Limited Liability Partnership,” “Limited Liability Partnership,” “R.L.L.P.,” “L.L.P.,” “RLLP,” or “LLP”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of the partnership’s chief executive office and, if different, the street address of its principal office in this state, if there is one;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of the partnership’s agent for service of process who must be an individual resident of this state or other person authorized to do business in this state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deferred effective date, if any.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status of a partnership as a foreign limited liability partnership is effective on the later of the filing of the statement of foreign qualification or a date specified in the statement. The status remains effective, regardless of changes in the partnership, until it is canceled pursuant to s. 620.8105(7) or revoked pursuant to s. 620.9003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment or cancellation of a statement of foreign qualification is effective when it is filed or on a deferred effective date specified in the amendment or cancellation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 99-285.</History></Section>