<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8914" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filings required for conversion; effective date.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a plan of conversion is approved:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A converting partnership shall deliver to the Department of State for filing a registration statement in accordance with s. 620.8105, if such statement was not previously filed, and a certificate of conversion, in accordance with s. 620.8105, which must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the partnership has been converted into another organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and form of the organization and the jurisdiction of its governing law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the conversion is effective under the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by this act.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is a foreign organization not authorized to transact business in this state, the street and mailing address of an office which the Department of State may use for the purposes of s. 620.8915(3).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a converting organization converting into a partnership to be governed by this act, the converting organization shall deliver to the Department of State for filing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registration statement in accordance with s. 620.8105.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of conversion, in accordance with s. 620.8105, signed by a general partner of the partnership in accordance with s. 620.8105(6) and by the converting organization as required by applicable law, which certificate of conversion must include:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the partnership was converted from another organization.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and form of the converting organization and the jurisdiction of its governing law.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by this act.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved in a manner that complied with the converting organization’s governing law.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective time of the conversion, if other than the time of the filing of the certificate of conversion.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A converting domestic partnership is not required to file a certificate of conversion pursuant to paragraph (a) if the converting domestic partnership files a certificate of conversion that substantially complies with the requirements of this section pursuant to s. 607.1115, s. 608.439, or s. 620.2104(1)(b) and contains the signatures required by this chapter. In such a case, the other certificate of conversion may also be used for purposes of s. 620.8915(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conversion becomes effective:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is a partnership, at the time specified in the certificate of conversion, which may be as of or after the time of the filing of the certificate of conversion, and, if the certificate of conversion does not contain such an effective time, the effective time shall be upon the filing of the certificate of conversion with the Department of State. However, if the certificate has a delayed effective date, the certificate may not be effective any later than the 90th day after the date it was filed and the effective date may not be any earlier than the effective date of the registration statement filed with the Department of State for the partnership in accordance with s. 620.8105.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is not a partnership, as provided by the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A certificate of conversion acts as a cancellation of any registration statement for a converting partnership for purposes of s. 620.8105, and the cancellation shall be deemed filed upon the effective date of the conversion.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2005-267; s. 16, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>