<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statement of partnership authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership may file a statement of partnership authority, which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must include the name of the partnership, as identified in the records of the Department of State, and the names of the partners authorized to execute an instrument transferring real property held in the name of the partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May also state or include the authority, or limitations on the authority, of some or all of the partners to enter into other transactions on behalf of the partnership, and any other matter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a filed statement of partnership authority is executed pursuant to s. 620.8105(6) and states the name of the partnership but does not contain all of the other information required by subsection (1), the statement nevertheless operates with respect to a person not a partner as provided in subsections (3) and (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (6), a filed statement of partnership authority supplements the authority of a partner to enter into transactions on behalf of the partnership as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for transfers of real property, a grant of authority contained in a filed statement of partnership authority is conclusive in favor of a person who gives value without knowledge to the contrary, so long as and to the extent that a limitation on that authority is not then contained in another filed statement. A filed cancellation of a limitation on authority revives the previous grant of authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A grant of authority to transfer real property held in the name of the partnership contained in a certified copy of a filed statement of partnership authority recorded in the office for recording transfers of such real property is conclusive in favor of a person who gives value without knowledge to the contrary, so long as and to the extent that a certified copy of a filed statement containing a limitation on such authority is not then of record in the office for recording transfers of such real property. The recording in the office for recording transfers of such real property of a certified copy of a filed cancellation of a limitation on authority revives the previous grant of authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is not a partner is deemed to know of a limitation on the authority of a partner to transfer real property held in the name of the partnership if a certified copy of the filed statement containing the limitation on authority is of record in the office for recording transfers of such real property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3) and (4) and ss. 620.8704 and 620.8805, a person not a partner is not deemed to know of a limitation on the authority of a partner merely because the limitation is contained in a filed statement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless earlier canceled, a filed statement of partnership authority is canceled by operation of law 5 years after the date on which the statement, or the most recent amendment, was filed with the Department of State.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242; s. 7, ch. 99-285.</History></Section>