<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1110" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of partnership agreement; nonwaivable provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), the partnership agreement governs relations among the partners and between the partners and the partnership. To the extent the partnership agreement does not otherwise provide, this act governs relations among the partners and between the partners and the partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership agreement may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary a limited partnership’s power under s. 620.1105 to sue, be sued, and defend in its own name;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the law applicable to a limited partnership under s. 620.1106;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the requirements of s. 620.1204;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the information required under s. 620.1111 or unreasonably restrict the right to information under s. 620.1304 or s. 620.1407, but the partnership agreement may impose reasonable restrictions on the availability and use of information obtained under those sections and may define appropriate remedies, including liquidated damages, for a breach of any reasonable restriction on use;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate the duty of loyalty of a general partner under s. 620.1408 but the partnership agreement may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify specific types or categories of activities that do not violate the duty of loyalty, if not manifestly unreasonable; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the number, percentage, class, or other type of partners that may authorize or ratify, after full disclosure to all partners of all material facts, a specific act or transaction that otherwise would violate the duty of loyalty;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably reduce the duty of care of a general partner under s. 620.1408(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate the obligation of good faith and fair dealing under ss. 620.1305(2) and 620.1408(4), but the partnership agreement may prescribe the standards by which the performance of the obligation is to be measured, if the standards are not manifestly unreasonable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the power of a person to dissociate as a general partner under s. 620.1604(1), except to require that the notice under s. 620.1603(1) be in a record;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the power of a court to decree dissolution in the circumstances specified in s. 620.1802;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vary the requirement to wind up the partnership’s business as specified in s. 620.1803;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restrict the right to maintain an action under s. 620.2001 or s. 620.2002;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrict the right of a partner under s. 620.2110(1) to approve a conversion or merger or the right of a general partner under s. 620.2110(2) to consent to an amendment to the certificate of limited partnership which deletes a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrict rights under this act of a person other than a partner or a transferee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267; s. 72, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>