<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1906" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation of certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of authority of a foreign limited partnership to transact business in this state may be revoked by the Department of State in the manner provided in subsections (2) and (3) if the foreign limited partnership does not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay, within 60 days after the due date, any fee or penalty due to the Department of State under this act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver its annual report to the Department of State by 5 p.m. Eastern Time on the third Friday in September;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint and maintain an agent for service of process as required by s. 620.1114(2); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver for filing a statement of a change under s. 620.1115 within 30 days after a change has occurred in the name or address of the agent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of State determines that one or more grounds exist under this section for revocation of a foreign limited partnership, it shall notify the foreign limited partnership of its intent to revoke the foreign limited partnership’s certificate of authority. If the foreign limited partnership has provided the department with an electronic mail address, such notice shall be by electronic transmission. Revocation for failure to file an annual report shall occur on the fourth Friday in September of each year. The Department of State shall issue a certificate of revocation to each revoked foreign limited partnership. Issuance of the certificate of revocation may be by electronic transmission to any foreign limited partnership that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If within 60 days after sending a notice of revocation, the foreign limited partnership does not correct each ground for revocation under paragraph (1)(a), paragraph (1)(c), or paragraph (1)(d), or demonstrate to the reasonable satisfaction of the Department of State that each ground determined by the department does not exist, the department shall revoke the foreign limited partnership’s authority to transact business in this state and issue a certificate of revocation that states the grounds for revocation. Issuance of the certificate of revocation may be by electronic transmission to any foreign limited partnership that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority of the foreign limited partnership to transact business in this state ceases on the effective date of the certificate of revocation unless before that date the foreign limited partnership cures each failure to comply with subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267; s. 22, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>