<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Actions by partnership and partners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership may maintain an action against a partner for a breach of the partnership agreement, or for the violation of a duty to the partnership, causing harm to the partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner may maintain an action against the partnership or another partner for legal or equitable relief, with or without an accounting as to partnership business, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce such partner’s rights under the partnership agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce such partner’s rights under this act, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such partner’s rights under s. 620.8401, s. 620.8403, or s. 620.8404;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such partner’s right upon dissociation to have the partner’s interest in the partnership purchased pursuant to s. 620.8701 or enforce any other right under ss. 620.8601-620.8705; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such partner’s right to compel a dissolution and winding up of the partnership business under s. 620.8801 or enforce any other right under ss. 620.8801-620.8807; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the rights and otherwise protect the interests of such partner, including rights and interests arising independently of the partnership relationship.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accrual of, and any time limitation on, a right of action for a remedy under this section is governed by other law. A right to an accounting upon a dissolution and winding up does not revive a claim barred by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242.</History></Section>