<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Formation of limited partnership; certificate of limited partnership.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order for a limited partnership to be formed, a certificate of limited partnership must be delivered to the Department of State for filing. The certificate must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the limited partnership, which must comply with s. 620.1108.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street and mailing address of the initial designated office of the limited partnership, and the name, street address in this state, and written acceptance of the initial registered agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and the business address of each general partner; each general partner that is not an individual must be organized or otherwise registered with the Department of State as required by law, must maintain an active status, and must not be dissolved, revoked, or withdrawn.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional information which may be required by s. 620.2104 or s. 620.2108.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of limited partnership may also contain any other matters, but may not vary or otherwise affect the provisions specified in s. 620.1110(2) in a manner inconsistent with that section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there has been substantial compliance with subsection (1), then subject to s. 620.1206(3), a limited partnership is formed when the Department of State files the certificate of limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (2), if any provision of a partnership agreement is inconsistent with the filed certificate of limited partnership, or with a filed statement of dissociation, termination, or change, a filed certificate of conversion or merger, or a certificate of dissolution or revocation of dissolution, involving the limited partnership:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partnership agreement prevails as to partners and transferees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filed certificate of limited partnership, statement of dissociation, termination, or change, certificate of conversion or merger, or certificate of dissolution or revocation of dissolution prevails as to persons, other than partners and transferees, that reasonably rely on the filed record to their detriment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>