<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.2104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filings required for conversion; effective date.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a plan of conversion is approved:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A converting limited partnership shall deliver to the Department of State for filing a certificate of conversion, signed by each general partner listed in the certificate of limited partnership, and must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the limited partnership has been converted into another organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and form of the organization and the jurisdiction of its governing law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the conversion is effective under the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by this act.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is a foreign organization not authorized to transact business in this state, the street and mailing address of an office which the Department of State may use for the purposes of s. 620.2105(3).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converting organization is not a converting limited partnership, the converting organization shall deliver to the Department of State for filing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of limited partnership containing the information required by s. 620.1201, signed by each general partner as required by s. 620.1204(1)(a).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of conversion, signed by each general partner listed in the certificate of limited partnership submitted in accordance with subparagraph 1. and by the converting organization as required by applicable law, which certificate of conversion must include:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the limited partnership was converted from another organization.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and form of the converting organization and the jurisdiction of its governing law.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved as required by this act.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the conversion was approved in a manner that complied with the converting organization’s governing law.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A converting limited partnership is not required to file a certificate of conversion pursuant to paragraph (a) if the converting limited partnership files a certificate of conversion that substantially complies with the requirements of this section pursuant to s. 607.1115, s. 608.439, or s. 620.8914(1)(b) and contains the signatures required by this chapter. In such a case, the other certificate of conversion may also be used for purposes of s. 620.2105(4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conversion becomes effective:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is a limited partnership, when the certificate of limited partnership takes effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the converted organization is not a limited partnership, as provided by the governing law of the converted organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267; s. 9, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>