<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.9003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited liability partnership, and a foreign limited liability partnership authorized to transact business in this state, shall file an annual report in the office of the Secretary of State which contains:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the limited liability partnership and the state or other jurisdiction under whose laws the foreign limited liability partnership is formed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The current street address of the partnership’s chief executive office and, if different, the current street address of its principal office in this state, if there is one;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partnership’s Federal Employer Identification Number, if any, or, if none, whether one has been applied for; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of the partnership’s current agent for service of process, who must be an individual resident of this state or other person authorized to do business in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual report must be filed between January 1 and May 1 of each year following the calendar year in which a partnership files a statement of qualification or a foreign partnership becomes authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may administratively revoke the statement of qualification of a partnership that fails to file its annual report and pay the required filing fee by 5 p.m. Eastern Time on the third Friday in September. The Department of State shall serve a 60-day notice on the limited liability partnership of its intent to revoke the statement of qualification. If the partnership has provided the department with an electronic mail address, such notice shall be by electronic transmission. Revocation for failure to file an annual report shall occur on the fourth Friday in September of each year. The Department of State shall issue a certificate of revocation of the statement of qualification to each revoked partnership. Issuance of the certificate of revocation of the statement of qualification may be by electronic transmission to any partnership that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A revocation under subsection (3) affects only a partnership’s status as a limited liability partnership and is not an event of dissolution of the partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership whose statement of qualification has been administratively revoked may apply to the Secretary of State for reinstatement within 2 years after the effective date of the revocation. The application must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the partnership and the effective date of the revocation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the ground for revocation either did not exist or has been corrected.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reinstatement under subsection (5) relates back to and takes effect as of the effective date of the revocation, and the partnership’s status as a limited liability partnership continues as if the revocation had never occurred.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 99-285; s. 23, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>