<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8922" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power of partners and persons dissociated as partners to bind organization after conversion or merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act of a person who immediately before a conversion or merger became effective was a partner in a converting or constituent partnership binds the converted or surviving organization after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the conversion or merger became effective, the act would have bound the converting or constituent limited partnership under s. 620.8301.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the third party enters into the transaction, the third party:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that the converted or surviving business is the converting or constituent partnership and that the person is a partner in the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act of a person that before a conversion or merger became effective was dissociated as a partner from a converting or constituent partnership binds the converted or surviving organization after the conversion or merger becomes effective, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the conversion or merger became effective, the act would have bound the converting or constituent partnership under s. 620.8301 if the person had been a partner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the third party enters into the transaction, fewer than 2 years have passed since the person dissociated as a partner, and the third party:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the dissociation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonably believes that the converted or surviving organization is the converting or constituent partnership and that the person is a partner in the converting or constituent partnership.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person having knowledge of the conversion or merger causes a converted or surviving organization to incur an obligation under subsection (1) or subsection (2), the person is liable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the converted or surviving organization for any damage caused to the organization arising from the obligation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If another person is liable for the obligation, to that other person for any damage caused to that other person arising from the liability.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>