<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1606" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power to bind and liability to limited partnership before dissolution of partnership of person dissociated as general partner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a person is dissociated as a general partner and before the limited partnership is dissolved, converted under s. 620.2102, or merged out of existence under s. 620.2106, the limited partnership is bound by an act of the person only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The act would have bound the limited partnership under s. 620.1402 before the dissociation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the other party enters into the transaction:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Less than 2 years have passed since the dissociation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The other party does not have notice of the dissociation and reasonably believes that the person is a general partner.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a limited partnership is bound under subsection (1), the person dissociated as a general partner which caused the limited partnership to be bound is liable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the limited partnership for any damage caused to the limited partnership arising from the obligation incurred under subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a general partner or another person dissociated as a general partner is liable for the obligation, to the general partner or other person for any damage caused to the general partner or other person arising from the liability.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>