<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1117" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service of process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered agent appointed by a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership is an agent of the limited partnership or foreign limited partnership for service of any process, notice, or demand required or permitted by law to be served upon the limited partnership or foreign limited partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership does not appoint or maintain a registered agent in this state or the registered agent cannot with reasonable diligence be found at the address of the registered office, the Department of State shall be an agent of the limited partnership or foreign limited partnership upon whom process, notice, or demand may be served.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service of any process, notice, or demand on the Department of State may be made by delivering to and leaving with the Department of State duplicate copies of the process, notice, or demand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service is effected under subsection (3) upon the date shown as having been received by the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall keep a record of each process, notice, and demand served pursuant to this section and record the time of, and the action taken regarding, the service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the right to serve process, notice, or demand in any other manner provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>