<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1408" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General standards of conduct for general partner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The only fiduciary duties that a general partner has to the limited partnership and the other partners are the duties of loyalty and care under subsections (2) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner’s duty of loyalty to the limited partnership and the other partners is limited to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To account to the limited partnership and hold as trustee for it any property, profit, or benefit derived by the general partner in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities or derived from a use by the general partner of limited partnership property, including the appropriation of a limited partnership opportunity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refrain from dealing with the limited partnership in the conduct or winding up of the limited partnership’s activities as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refrain from competing with the limited partnership in the conduct of the limited partnership’s activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner’s duty of care to the limited partnership and the other partners in the conduct and winding up of the limited partnership’s activities is limited to refraining from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner shall discharge the duties to the partnership and the other partners under this act or under the partnership agreement and exercise any rights consistently with the obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner does not violate a duty or obligation under this act or under the partnership agreement merely because the general partner’s conduct furthers the general partner’s own interest.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>