<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.9001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statement of qualification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership may become a limited liability partnership pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and conditions on which a partnership becomes a limited liability partnership must be approved by the vote necessary to amend the partnership agreement except, in the case of a partnership agreement that expressly considers contribution obligations, the vote necessary to amend those provisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the approval required by subsection (2), a partnership may become a limited liability partnership by filing a statement of qualification. The statement must contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the partnership as identified in the records of the Department of State;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of the partnership’s chief executive office and, if different, the street address of its principal office in this state, if there is one;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of the partnership’s agent for service of process, who must be an individual resident of this state or other person authorized to do business in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the partnership elects to be a limited liability partnership; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deferred effective date, if any.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status of a partnership as a limited liability partnership is effective on the later of the filing of the statement or a date specified in the statement. The status remains effective, regardless of changes in the partnership, until it is canceled pursuant to s. 620.8105(7) or revoked pursuant to s. 620.9003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status of a partnership as a limited liability partnership and the liability of its partners are not affected by errors or later changes in the information required to be contained in the statement of qualification under subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a statement of qualification establishes that a partnership has satisfied all conditions precedent to the qualification of the partnership as a limited liability partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment or cancellation of a statement of qualification is effective when it is filed or on a deferred effective date specified in the amendment or cancellation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 99-285.</History></Section>