<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.1902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign limited partnership shall apply for a certificate of authority to transact business in this state by delivering a signed application to the Department of State for filing. The application must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign limited partnership and, if the name does not comply with s. 620.1108, an alternate name adopted pursuant to s. 620.1905(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state or other jurisdiction under whose law the foreign limited partnership is organized and the date of its formation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal office and mailing address of the foreign limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, street address in this state, and written acceptance of the foreign limited partnership’s initial registered agent in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and principal office and mailing address of each of the foreign limited partnership’s general partners. Each general partner that is not an individual must be organized or otherwise registered with the Department of State as required by law, must maintain an active status, and may not be dissolved, revoked, or withdrawn.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the foreign limited partnership is a foreign limited liability limited partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign limited partnership shall deliver with the completed application a certificate of existence or a record of similar import signed by the Department of State or other official having custody of the foreign limited partnership’s publicly filed records in the state or other jurisdiction under whose law the foreign limited partnership is organized, dated not more than 90 days prior to the delivery of the application to the Secretary of State.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>