<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General standards of partner’s conduct.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The only fiduciary duties a partner owes to the partnership and the other partners are the duty of loyalty and the duty of care, as set forth in subsections (2) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner’s duty of loyalty to the partnership and the other partners is limited to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To account to the partnership and hold as trustee for the partnership any property, profit, or benefit derived by the partner in the conduct and winding up of the partnership business or derived from a use by the partner of partnership property, including the appropriation of a partnership opportunity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refrain from dealing with the partnership in the conduct or winding up of the partnership business as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the partnership; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refrain from competing with the partnership in the conduct of the partnership business before the dissolution of the partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner’s duty of care to the partnership and the other partners in the conduct and winding up of the partnership business is limited to refraining from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner shall discharge the duties to the partnership and the other partners under this act or under the partnership agreement and exercise any rights consistently with the obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner does not violate a duty or obligation under this act or under a partnership agreement merely because the partner’s conduct furthers the partner’s own interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner may lend money to and transact other business with the partnership, and as to each loan or transaction, the rights and obligations of the partner are the same as those of a person who is not a partner, subject to other applicable law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to a person winding up the partnership business as the personal or legal representative of the last surviving partner as if the person were a partner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242; s. 21, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>