<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0620.8503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of partner’s transferable interest.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transfer, in whole or in part, of a partner’s transferable interest in the partnership:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is permissible.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not, by itself, cause the partner’s dissociation or a dissolution and winding up of the partnership business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not, as against the other partners or the partnership, entitle the transferee, during the continuance of the partnership, to participate in the management or conduct of the partnership business, to require access to information concerning partnership transactions, or to inspect or copy the partnership books or records.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transferee of a partner’s transferable interest in the partnership has a right:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive, in accordance with the transfer, distributions to which the transferor would otherwise be entitled;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive upon the dissolution and winding up of the partnership business, in accordance with the transfer, the net amount otherwise distributable to the transferor; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seek, under <Reference Number="1" />s. 620.839(6), a judicial determination that it is equitable to wind up the partnership business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a dissolution and winding up of a partnership, a transferee is entitled to an account of partnership transactions only from the date of the latest account agreed to by all the partners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon transfer, the transferor retains the rights and duties of a partner other than the interest in distributions transferred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership need not give effect to a transferee’s rights under this section until it has notice of the transfer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transfer of a partner’s transferable interest in the partnership in violation of a restriction on transfer contained in the partnership agreement is ineffective as to a person having notice of the restriction at the time of transfer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 95-242.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 620.839 does not exist.</Text></Note></Section>