<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0186.801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ten-year site plans.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 1974, each electric utility shall submit to the Public Service Commission a 10-year site plan which shall estimate its power-generating needs and the general location of its proposed power plant sites. The 10-year plan shall be reviewed and submitted not less frequently than every 2 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 9 months after the receipt of the proposed plan, the commission shall make a preliminary study of such plan and classify it as “suitable” or “unsuitable.” The commission may suggest alternatives to the plan. All findings of the commission shall be made available to the Department of Environmental Protection for its consideration at any subsequent electrical power plant site certification proceedings. It is recognized that 10-year site plans submitted by an electric utility are tentative information for planning purposes only and may be amended at any time at the discretion of the utility upon written notification to the commission. A complete application for certification of an electrical power plant site under chapter 403, when such site is not designated in the current 10-year site plan of the applicant, shall constitute an amendment to the 10-year site plan. In its preliminary study of each 10-year site plan, the commission shall consider such plan as a planning document and shall review:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need, including the need as determined by the commission, for electrical power in the area to be served.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect on fuel diversity within the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated environmental impact of each proposed electrical power plant site.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possible alternatives to the proposed plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The views of appropriate local, state, and federal agencies, including the views of the appropriate water management district as to the availability of water and its recommendation as to the use by the proposed plant of salt water or fresh water for cooling purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the plan is consistent with the state comprehensive plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan with respect to the information of the state on energy availability and consumption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of renewable energy resources the utility produces or purchases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of renewable energy resources the utility plans to produce or purchase over the 10-year planning horizon and the means by which the production or purchases will be achieved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement describing how the production and purchase of renewable energy resources impact the utility’s present and future capacity and energy needs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to enable it to carry out its duties under this section, the commission may, after hearing, establish a study fee which shall not exceed $1,000 for each proposed plan studied.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules governing the method of submitting, processing, and studying the 10-year plans as required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch 73-33; s. 2, ch. 76-76; s. 77, ch. 79-190; s. 2, ch. 81-167; s. 3, ch. 83-55; s. 41, ch. 94-356; s. 2, ch. 95-328; s. 15, ch. 2006-230; s. 2, ch. 2012-117.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 403.505, 23.0191.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>