<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0186.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 186.001-186.031, 186.801-186.901.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 186.001-186.031 and 186.801-186.901, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Executive Office of the Governor” means the Office of Planning and Budgeting of the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Goal” means the long-term end toward which programs and activities are ultimately directed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Objective” means a specific, measurable, intermediate end that is achievable and marks progress toward a goal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Policy” means the way in which programs and activities are conducted to achieve an identified goal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regional planning agency” means the regional planning council created pursuant to ss. 186.501-186.515 to exercise responsibilities under ss. 186.001-186.031 and 186.801-186.901 in a particular region of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State agency” or “agency” means any official, officer, commission, board, authority, council, committee, or department of the executive branch of state government. For purposes of this chapter, “state agency” or “agency” includes state attorneys, public defenders, the capital collateral regional counsel, the Justice Administrative Commission, and the Public Service Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State comprehensive plan” means the state planning document required in s. 19, Art. III of the State Constitution and published as ss. 187.101 and 187.201.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 72-295; s. 1, ch. 78-287; s. 66, ch. 79-190; s. 3, ch. 84-257; s. 31, ch. 88-122; s. 97, ch. 91-282; s. 88, ch. 92-142; s. 20, ch. 93-206; s. 24, ch. 95-280; s. 12, ch. 97-79; s. 17, ch. 98-176; s. 69, ch. 99-2; s. 67, ch. 99-245; s. 41, ch. 2000-371.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 23.0112.</Text></Note></Section>