<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0186.009" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Executive Office of the Governor shall prepare the proposed growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan in coordination with the Legislature, appropriate state agencies, regional entities, local governments, and citizens. The proposed growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan shall not be based upon the comprehensive format of the state comprehensive plan but shall be strategic in nature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide strategic guidance for state, regional, and local actions necessary to implement the state comprehensive plan with regard to the physical growth and development of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify metropolitan and urban growth centers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify areas of state and regional environmental significance and establish strategies to protect them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth and integrate state policy for Florida’s future growth as it relates to land development, air quality, transportation, and water resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide guidelines for determining where urban growth is appropriate and should be encouraged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide guidelines for state transportation corridors, public transportation corridors, new interchanges on limited access facilities, and new airports of regional or state significance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote land acquisition programs to provide for natural resource protection, open space needs, urban recreational opportunities, and water access.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth policies to establish state and regional solutions to the need for affordable housing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide coordinated state planning of road, rail, and waterborne transportation facilities designed to take the needs of agriculture into consideration and to provide for the transportation of agricultural products and supplies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish priorities regarding coastal planning and resource management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a statewide policy to enhance the multiuse waterfront development of existing deepwater ports, ensuring that priority is given to water-dependent land uses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth other goals, objectives, and policies related to the state’s natural and built environment that are necessary to effectuate those portions of the state comprehensive plan which are related to physical growth and development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth recommendations on when and to what degree local government comprehensive plans must be consistent with the proposed growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth recommendations on how to integrate the Florida water plan required by s. 373.036 and transportation plans required by chapter 339.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth recommendations concerning what degree of consistency is appropriate for the strategic regional policy plans.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan shall not include a land use map.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan, and all amendments, revisions, or updates to the plan, shall have legal effect only upon adoption by the Legislature as general law. The Legislature shall indicate, in adopting the growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan, which plans, activities, and permits must be consistent with the growth management portion of the state comprehensive plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 93-206; s. 19, ch. 97-160; s. 20, ch. 98-176.</History></Section>