<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0810.097" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trespass upon grounds or facilities of a school; penalties; arrest.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have legitimate business on the campus or any other authorization, license, or invitation to enter or remain upon school property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a student currently under suspension or expulsion;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and who enters or remains upon the campus or any other facility owned by any such school commits a trespass upon the grounds of a school facility and is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who enters or remains upon the campus or other facility of a school after the principal of such school, or his or her designee, has directed such person to leave such campus or facility or not to enter upon the campus or facility, commits a trespass upon the grounds of a school facility and is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief administrative officer of a school, or any employee thereof designated by the chief administrative officer to maintain order on such campus or facility, who has probable cause to believe that a person is trespassing upon school grounds in violation of this section may take such person into custody and detain him or her in a reasonable manner for a reasonable length of time pending arrival of a law enforcement officer. Such taking into custody and detention by an authorized person does not render that person criminally or civilly liable for false arrest, false imprisonment, or unlawful detention. If a trespasser is taken into custody, a law enforcement officer shall be called to the scene immediately after the person is taken into custody.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer may arrest either on or off the premises and without warrant any person the officer has probable cause for believing has committed the offense of trespass upon the grounds of a school facility. Such arrest shall not render the law enforcement officer criminally or civilly liable for false arrest, false imprisonment, or unlawful detention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “school” means the grounds or any facility of any kindergarten, elementary school, middle school, junior high school, or secondary school, whether public or nonpublic.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 68-3; s. 1, ch. 72-10; s. 1, ch. 72-221; s. 1, ch. 77-425; s. 48, ch. 79-164; s. 1, ch. 82-3; s. 27, ch. 91-224; s. 1207, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 99-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 228.21; s. 228.091.</Text></Note></Section>