<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0810.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings and intent; burglary.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the case of <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>, 776 So. 2d 233 (Fla. 2000), was decided contrary to legislative intent and the case law of this state relating to burglary prior to <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>. The Legislature finds that in order for a burglary to occur, it is not necessary for the licensed or invited person to remain in the dwelling, structure, or conveyance surreptitiously.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the holding in <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>, 776 So. 2d 233 (Fla. 2000) be nullified. It is further the intent of the Legislature that s. 810.02(1)(a) be construed in conformity with <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Raleigh v. State</Font>, 705 So. 2d 1324 (Fla. 1997); <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Jimenez v. State</Font>, 703 So. 2d 437 (Fla. 1997); <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Robertson v. State</Font>, 699 So. 2d 1343 (Fla. 1997); <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Routly v. State</Font>, 440 So. 2d 1257 (Fla. 1983); and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Ray v. State</Font>, 522 So. 2d 963 (Fla. 3rd DCA, 1988). This subsection shall operate retroactively to February 1, 2000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that consent remain an affirmative defense to burglary and that the lack of consent may be proven by circumstantial evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the cases of <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Floyd v. State</Font>, 850 So. 2d 383 (Fla. 2002); <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Fitzpatrick v. State</Font>, 859 So. 2d 486 (Fla. 2003); and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">State v. Ruiz</Font>/<Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">State v. Braggs</Font>, Slip Opinion Nos. SC02-389/SC02-524 were decided contrary to the Legislative intent expressed in this section. The Legislature finds that these cases were decided in such a manner as to give subsection (1) no effect. The February 1, 2000, date reflected in subsection (2) does not refer to an arbitrary date relating to the date offenses were committed, but to a date before which the law relating to burglary was untainted by <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>, 776 So. 2d 233 (Fla. 2000).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature provides the following special rules of construction to apply to this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All subsections in this section shall be construed to give effect to subsection (1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 775.021(1), this section shall be construed to give the interpretation of the burglary statute announced in <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>, 776 So. 2d 233 (Fla. 2000), and its progeny, no effect; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If language in this section is susceptible to differing constructions, it shall be construed in such manner as to approximate the law relating to burglary as if <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Delgado v. State</Font>, 776 So. 2d 233 (Fla. 2000) was never issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply retroactively.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-58; s. 1, ch. 2004-93.</History></Section>