<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0810.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Structure” means a building of any kind, either temporary or permanent, which has a roof over it, together with the curtilage thereof. However, during the time of a state of emergency declared by executive order or proclamation of the Governor under chapter 252 and within the area covered by such executive order or proclamation and for purposes of ss. 810.02 and 810.08 only, the term means a building of any kind or such portions or remnants thereof as exist at the original site, regardless of absence of a wall or roof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dwelling” means a building or conveyance of any kind, including any attached porch, whether such building or conveyance is temporary or permanent, mobile or immobile, which has a roof over it and is designed to be occupied by people lodging therein at night, together with the curtilage thereof. However, during the time of a state of emergency declared by executive order or proclamation of the Governor under chapter 252 and within the area covered by such executive order or proclamation and for purposes of ss. 810.02 and 810.08 only, the term includes such portions or remnants thereof as exist at the original site, regardless of absence of a wall or roof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conveyance” means any motor vehicle, ship, vessel, railroad vehicle or car, trailer, aircraft, or sleeping car; and “to enter a conveyance” includes taking apart any portion of the conveyance. However, during the time of a state of emergency declared by executive order or proclamation of the Governor under chapter 252 and within the area covered by such executive order or proclamation and for purposes of ss. 810.02 and 810.08 only, the term “conveyance” means a motor vehicle, ship, vessel, railroad vehicle or car, trailer, aircraft, or sleeping car or such portions thereof as exist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act is committed “in the course of committing” if it occurs in an attempt to commit the offense or in flight after the attempt or commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Posted land” is that land upon which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs are placed not more than 500 feet apart along, and at each corner of, the boundaries of the land, upon which signs there appears prominently, in letters of not less than 2 inches in height, the words “no trespassing” and in addition thereto the name of the owner, lessee, or occupant of said land. Said signs shall be placed along the boundary line of posted land in a manner and in such position as to be clearly noticeable from outside the boundary line; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspicuous no trespassing notice is painted on trees or posts on the property, provided that the notice is:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Painted in an international orange color and displaying the stenciled words “No Trespassing” in letters no less than 2 inches high and 1 inch wide either vertically or horizontally;</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placed so that the bottom of the painted notice is not less than 3 feet from the ground or more than 5 feet from the ground; and</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placed at locations that are readily visible to any person approaching the property and no more than 500 feet apart on agricultural land.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning October 1, 2007, when a landowner uses the painted no trespassing posting to identify a “no trespassing” area, those painted notices shall be accompanied by signs complying with subparagraph 1. and placed conspicuously at all places where entry to the property is normally expected or known to occur.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall not be necessary to give notice by posting on any enclosed land or place not exceeding 5 acres in area on which there is a dwelling house in order to obtain the benefits of ss. 810.09 and 810.12 pertaining to trespass on enclosed lands.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cultivated land” is that land which has been cleared of its natural vegetation and is presently planted with a crop, orchard, grove, pasture, or trees or is fallow land as part of a crop rotation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fenced land” is that land which has been enclosed by a fence of substantial construction, whether with rails, logs, post and railing, iron, steel, barbed wire, other wire, or other material, which stands at least 3 feet in height. For the purpose of this chapter, it shall not be necessary to fence any boundary or part of a boundary of any land which is formed by water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where lands are posted, cultivated, or fenced as described herein, then said lands, for the purpose of this chapter, shall be considered as enclosed and posted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Litter” means any garbage, rubbish, trash, refuse, debris, can, bottle, box, container, paper, tobacco product, tire, domestic or commercial appliance, mechanical equipment or part, building or construction material, tool, machinery, wood, motor vehicle or motor vehicle part, vessel, aircraft, or farm machinery or equipment; sludge from a waste treatment facility, water supply treatment plant, or air pollution control facility; or substance in any form resulting from domestic, industrial, commercial, mining, agricultural, or governmental operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dump” means to dump, throw, discard, place, deposit, or dispose of any litter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial horticulture property” means any property that is cleared of its natural vegetation and is planted in commercially cultivated horticulture products that are planted, grown, or harvested. The term also includes property that is used for the commercial sale, use, or distribution of horticulture products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural chemicals manufacturing facility” means any facility, and any properties or structures associated with the facility, used for the manufacture, processing, or storage of agricultural chemicals classified in Industry Group 287 contained in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual, 1987, as published by the Office of Management and Budget, Executive Office of the President.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Construction site” means any property upon which there is construction that is subject to building permit posting requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 76-46; s. 1, ch. 82-87; s. 1, ch. 92-351; s. 1, ch. 94-263; s. 1, ch. 94-307; s. 47, ch. 96-388; s. 13, ch. 99-188; s. 3, ch. 2001-182; s. 49, ch. 2001-279; s. 15, ch. 2006-289; s. 1, ch. 2007-123; s. 4, ch. 2007-244.</History></Section>