<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0290.0475" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rejection of grant applications; penalties for failure to meet application conditions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applications received for funding under all program categories shall be rejected without scoring only in the event that any of the following circumstances arise:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application is not received by the department by the application deadline.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed project does not meet one of the three national objectives as contained in federal and state legislation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed project is not an eligible activity as contained in the federal legislation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application is not consistent with the local government’s comprehensive plan adopted pursuant to s. 163.3184.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has an open community development block grant, except as provided in s. 290.046(2)(c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government is not in compliance with the citizen participation requirements prescribed in ss. 104(a)(1) and (2) and 106(d)(5)(c) of Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1984 and department rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information provided in the application that affects eligibility or scoring is found to have been misrepresented, and the information is not a mathematical error which may be discovered and corrected by readily computing available numbers or formulas provided in the application.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 85-223; s. 39, ch. 88-201; s. 5, ch. 90-275; s. 45, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>