<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0290.042" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Florida Small Cities Community Development Block Grant Program Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 290.0401-290.048, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative closeout” means the notification of a grantee by the department that all applicable administrative actions and all required work of the grant have been completed with the exception of the final audit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative costs” means the payment of all reasonable costs of management, coordination, monitoring, and evaluation, and similar costs and carrying charges, related to the planning and execution of community development activities which are funded in whole or in part under the Florida Small Cities Community Development Block Grant Program. Administrative costs shall include all costs of administration, including general administration, planning and urban design, and project administration costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible activities” means those community development activities authorized in s. 105(a) of Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, as amended, and applicable federal regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible local government” means any local government which qualifies as eligible to participate in the Florida Small Cities Community Development Block Grant Program in accordance with s. 102(a)(7) of Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, as amended, and applicable federal regulations, and any eligibility requirements which may be imposed by this act or by department rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person of low or moderate income” means any person who meets the definition established by the department in accordance with the guidelines established in Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, as amended.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service area” means the total geographic area to be directly or indirectly served by a community development block grant project where at least 51 percent of the residents are low-income and moderate-income persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 83-205; s. 70, ch. 85-80; s. 3, ch. 85-223; s. 1, ch. 90-275; s. 217, ch. 2011-142; s. 38, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>