<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0290.044" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Small Cities Community Development Block Grant Program Fund; administration; distribution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Small Cities Community Development Block Grant Program Fund is created. All revenue designated for deposit in such fund shall be deposited by the appropriate agency. The department shall administer this fund as a grant and loan guarantee program for carrying out the purposes of ss. 290.0401-290.048.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall distribute such funds as loan guarantees and grants to eligible local governments on the basis of a competitive selection process.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall define the broad community development objective to be achieved by the activities in each of the following grant program categories, and require applicants for grants to compete against each other in these grant program categories:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Housing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Economic development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neighborhood revitalization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commercial revitalization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Project planning and design.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may set aside an amount of up to 5 percent of the funds annually for use in any eligible local government jurisdiction for which an emergency or natural disaster has been declared by executive order. Such funds may only be provided to a local government to fund eligible emergency-related activities for which no other source of federal, state, or local disaster funds is available. The department may provide for such set-aside by rule. In the last quarter of the state fiscal year, any funds not allocated under the emergency-related set-aside shall be distributed to unfunded applications from the most recent funding cycle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a system of monitoring grants, including site visits, to ensure the proper expenditure of funds and compliance with the conditions of the recipient’s contract. The department shall establish criteria for implementation of internal control, to include, but not be limited to, the following measures:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring that subrecipient audits performed by a certified public accountant are received and responded to in a timely manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a uniform system of monitoring that documents appropriate followup as needed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing specific justification for contract amendments that takes into account any change in contracted activities and the resultant cost adjustments which shall be reflected in the amount of the grant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 83-205; s. 1, ch. 85-223; s. 2, ch. 90-275; s. 44, ch. 97-278; s. 2, ch. 2005-86; s. 219, ch. 2011-142; s. 39, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>