<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0290.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local government ordinances; encouragements and incentives; review for adverse effects; certain changes prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that each ordinance adopted by a local government possessing an approved enterprise zone after January 1, 1995, when applicable, provide encouragements and incentives to increase rehabilitation, renovation, restoration, improvement, or new construction of housing, and to increase the economic viability and profitability of business and commerce, located within enterprise zones designated pursuant to s. 290.0065.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local government possessing an approved enterprise zone may review its ordinances to determine which may have a negative impact upon the rehabilitation, renovation, restoration, improvement, or new construction of housing, or upon the economic viability and profitability of business and commerce, located within enterprise zones designated pursuant to s. 290.0065, and may waive, amend, or otherwise modify such ordinances so as to minimize the adverse impact. Such relief may include recommendations made by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, in its “1987 Guide for Local Government and Developers,” concerning zoning and subdivision ordinances, expedited administrative and processing procedures, site planning, streets, parking, sidewalks and walkways, curbs, gutters, storm drainage systems, sanitary sewers, water supply utilities and utility easements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section authorizes any local government to waive, amend, provide exceptions to, or otherwise modify or alter any ordinance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which is expressly required to implement or enforce any statutory provision or the legislative intent thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which is designed to protect persons against discrimination on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, age, handicap, or marital status; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The waiver, amendment, or modification of which is likely to present a significant risk to the public health, public safety, or the environment of the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The waiver, amendment, or modification of any ordinance pursuant to this section shall be accomplished in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not supersede any provision of chapter 163.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 91-262; ss. 34, 37, ch. 94-136; s. 11, ch. 2005-287.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed December 31, 2015, by s. 11, ch. 2005-287.</Text></Note></Section>