<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0290.048" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers of department under ss. 290.0401-290.048.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has all the powers necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes and provisions of the program, including the power to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make contracts and agreements with the Federal Government; other agencies of the state; any other public agency; or any other public person, association, corporation, local government, or entity in exercising its powers and performing its duties under ss. 290.0401-290.048.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek and accept funding from any public or private source.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and enforce rules not inconsistent with ss. 290.0401-290.048 for the administration of the fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in training employees of local governing authorities to help achieve and increase their capacity to administer programs pursuant to ss. 290.0401-290.048 and provide technical assistance and advice to local governing authorities involved with these programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and enforce strict requirements concerning an applicant’s written description of a service area. Each such description shall contain maps which illustrate the location of the proposed service area. All such maps must be clearly legible and must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a scale which is clearly marked on the map.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Show the boundaries of the locality.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Show the boundaries of the service area where the activities will be concentrated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display the location of all proposed area activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include the names of streets, route numbers, or easily identifiable landmarks where all service activities are located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pledge community development block grant revenues from the Federal Government in order to guarantee notes or other obligations of a public entity which are approved pursuant to s. 290.0455.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish an advisory committee of no more than 13 members to solicit participation in designing, administering, and evaluating the program and in linking the program with other housing and community development resources.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 83-205; s. 40, ch. 88-201; s. 6, ch. 90-275; s. 47, ch. 97-278; s. 45, ch. 2001-89; s. 24, ch. 2001-201; s. 222, ch. 2011-142; s. 40, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>