<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Governing board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of each water management district shall be composed of 9 members who shall reside within the district, except that the Southwest Florida Water Management District shall be composed of 13 members who shall reside within the district. Members of the governing boards shall be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate at the next regular session of the Legislature, and the refusal or failure of the Senate to confirm an appointment creates a vacancy in the office to which the appointment was made. The term of office for a governing board member is 4 years and commences on March 2 of the year in which the appointment is made and terminates on March 1 of the fourth calendar year of the term or may continue until a successor is appointed, but not more than 180 days. Terms of office of governing board members shall be staggered to help maintain consistency and continuity in the exercise of governing board duties and to minimize disruption in district operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commencing January 1, 2011, the Governor shall appoint the following number of governing board members in each year of the Governor’s 4-year term of office:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the first year of the Governor’s term of office, the Governor shall appoint four members to the governing board of the Southwest Florida Water Management District and appoint three members to the governing board of each other district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the second year of the Governor’s term of office, the Governor shall appoint three members to the governing board of the Southwest Florida Water Management District and two members to the governing board of each other district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the third year of the Governor’s term of office, the Governor shall appoint three members to the governing board of the Southwest Florida Water Management District and two members to the governing board of each other district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the fourth year of the Governor’s term of office, the Governor shall appoint three members to the governing board of the Southwest Florida Water Management District and two members to the governing board of each other district.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For any governing board vacancy that occurs before the date scheduled for the office to be filled under this paragraph, the Governor shall appoint a person meeting residency requirements of subsection (2) for a term that will expire on the date scheduled for the term of that office to terminate under this subsection. In addition to the residency requirements for the governing boards as provided by subsection (2), the Governor shall consider appointing governing board members to represent an equitable cross-section of regional interests and technical expertise.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership on governing boards shall be selected from candidates who have significant experience in one or more of the following areas, including, but not limited to: agriculture, the development industry, local government, government-owned or privately owned water utilities, law, civil engineering, environmental science, hydrology, accounting, or financial businesses. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or special law to the contrary, vacancies in the governing boards of the water management districts shall be filled according to the following residency requirements, representing areas designated by the United States Water Resources Council in United States Geological Survey, River Basin and Hydrological Unit Map of Florida<EmDash />1975, Map Series No. 72:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Northwest Florida Water Management District:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Perdido River Basin-Perdido Bay Coastal Area-Lower Conecuh River-Escambia River Basin” hydrologic units and that portion of the “Escambia Bay Coastal Area” hydrologic unit which lies west of Pensacola Bay and Escambia Bay.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Blackwater River Basin-Yellow River Basin-Choctawhatchee Bay Coastal Area” hydrologic units and that portion of the “Escambia Bay Coastal Area” hydrologic unit which lies east of Pensacola Bay and Escambia Bay.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Choctawhatchee River Basin-St. Andrews Bay Coastal Area” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Lower Chattahoochee-Apalachicola River-Chipola River Basin-Coastal Area between Ochlockonee River Apalachicola Rivers-Apalachicola Bay coastal area and offshore islands” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Ochlockonee River Basin-St. Marks and Wakulla Rivers and coastal area between Aucilla and Ochlockonee River Basin” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members shall be appointed at large, except that no county shall have more than two members on the governing board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suwannee River Water Management District:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Aucilla River Basin” hydrologic unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Coastal Area between Suwannee and Aucilla Rivers” hydrologic unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Withlacoochee River Basin-Alapaha River Basin-Suwannee River Basin above the Withlacoochee River” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Suwannee River Basin below the Withlacoochee River excluding the Santa Fe River Basin” hydrologic unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Santa Fe Basin-Waccasassa River and coastal area between Withlacoochee and Suwannee River” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members shall be appointed at large, except that no county shall have more than two members on the governing board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Johns River Water Management District:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “St. Marys River Basin-Coastal area between St. Marys and St. Johns Rivers” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “St. Johns River Basin below Oklawaha River-Coastal area between the St. Johns River and Ponce de Leon Inlet” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Oklawaha River Basin” hydrologic unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “St. Johns River Basin above the Oklawaha River” hydrologic unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area generally designated as the “Coastal area between Ponce de Leon Inlet and Sebastian Inlet-Coastal area Sebastian Inlet to St. Lucie River” hydrologic units.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members shall be appointed at large, except that no county shall have more than two members on the governing board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">South Florida Water Management District:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall reside in Miami-Dade County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Broward County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Palm Beach County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Collier County, Lee County, Hendry County, or Charlotte County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Glades County, Okeechobee County, Highlands County, Polk County, Orange County, or Osceola County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members, appointed at large, shall reside in an area consisting of St. Lucie, Martin, Palm Beach, Broward, Miami-Dade, and Monroe Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed at large, shall reside in an area consisting of Collier, Lee, Charlotte, Hendry, Glades, Osceola, Okeechobee, Polk, Highlands, and Orange Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No county shall have more than three members on the governing board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Southwest Florida Water Management District:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall reside in Hillsborough County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in the area consisting of Hillsborough and Pinellas Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall reside in Pinellas County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Manatee County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall reside in Polk County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall reside in Pasco County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be appointed at large from Levy, Citrus, Sumter, and Lake Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be appointed at large from Hardee, DeSoto, and Highlands Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be appointed at large from Marion and Hernando Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be appointed at large from Sarasota and Charlotte Counties.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, part I, ch. 72-299; s. 11, ch. 75-22; s. 6, ch. 76-243; s. 1, ch. 77-72; s. 3, ch. 80-259; s. 226, ch. 81-259; s. 1, ch. 82-46; ss. 1, 7, 25, ch. 88-242; ss. 1, 2, ch. 89-279; ss. 11, 12, ch. 90-217; s. 1, ch. 91-18; s. 9, ch. 97-160; s. 2, ch. 2005-215; s. 1, ch. 2007-120; s. 80, ch. 2008-4; s. 5, ch. 2009-243.</History></Section>