<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.4141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permits; processing.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of an application for a permit under this part, the department or the water management district shall review the application and shall request submittal of all additional information the department or the water management district is permitted by law to require. If the applicant believes any request for additional information is not authorized by law or rule, the applicant may request a hearing pursuant to s. 120.57. Within 30 days after receipt of such additional information, the department or water management district shall review it and may request only that information needed to clarify such additional information or to answer new questions raised by or directly related to such additional information. If the applicant believes the request of the department or water management district for such additional information is not authorized by law or rule, the department or water management district, at the applicant’s request, shall proceed to process the permit application.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit shall be approved, denied, or subject to a notice of proposed agency action within 60 days after receipt of the original application, the last item of timely requested additional material, or the applicant’s written request to begin processing the permit application.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Processing of applications for permits for affordable housing projects shall be expedited to a greater degree than other projects.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state agency or an agency of the state may not require as a condition of approval for a permit or as an item to complete a pending permit application that an applicant obtain a permit or approval from any other local, state, or federal agency without explicit statutory authority to require such permit or approval.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 96-370; s. 1, ch. 2002-160; s. 7, ch. 2012-205.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 14, ch. 2009-96, as reenacted by s. 12, ch. 2011-14, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), and in recognition of 2009 real estate market conditions, any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, that has an expiration date of September 1, 2008, through January 1, 2012, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years following its date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit. The 2-year extension also applies to build out dates including any build out date extension previously granted under s. 380.06(19)(c), Florida Statutes. This section shall not be construed to prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project shall be extended such that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension shall notify the authorizing agency in writing no later than December 31, 2009, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension, that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except when it can be demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision shall apply to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit that lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification shall not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) Nothing in this section shall impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property, that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intention to receive the extension of time granted by this section, to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 46, ch. 2010-147, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), a development order issued by a local government, a building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from September 1, 2008, through January 1, 2012, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This 2-year extension also applies to buildout dates, including any extension of a buildout date that was previously granted under s. 380.06(19)(c), Florida Statutes. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to the 2-year permit extension provided under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2010, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 47, ch. 2010-147, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Legislature hereby reauthorizes:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Any exemption granted for any project for which an application for development approval has been approved or filed pursuant to s. 380.06, Florida Statutes, or for which a complete development application or rescission request has been approved or is pending, and the application or rescission process is continuing in good faith, within a development that is located within an area that qualified for an exemption under s. 380.06, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Any 2-year extension authorized and timely applied for pursuant to section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Any amendment to a local comprehensive plan adopted pursuant to s. 163.3184, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, and in effect pursuant to s. 163.3189, Florida Statutes, which authorizes and implements a transportation concurrency exception area pursuant to s. 163.3180, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Subsection (1) is intended to be remedial in nature and to reenact provisions of existing law. This section shall apply retroactively to all actions specified in subsection (1) and therefore to any such actions lawfully undertaken in accordance with chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Section 163.3189, referenced in s. 47(1)(c), ch. 2010-147, above, was repealed by s. 19, chapter 2011-139.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">D. Section 73, ch. 2011-139, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Any permit or any other authorization that was extended under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, is extended and renewed for an additional period of 2 years after its previously scheduled expiration date. This extension is in addition to the 2-year permit extension provided under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. Permits that were extended by a total of 4 years pursuant to section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, and by section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, cannot be further extended under this provision.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project shall be extended such that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension shall notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2011, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension, that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This subsection applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit that lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification may not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intention to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">E. Section 79, ch. 2011-139, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), and in recognition of 2011 real estate market conditions, any building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from January 1, 2012, through January 1, 2014, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit including certificates of levels of service. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to any existing permit extension. Extensions granted pursuant to this section; section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; or section 74 of this act shall not exceed 4 years in total. Further, specific development order extensions granted pursuant to s. 380.06(19)(c)2., Florida Statutes, cannot be further extended by this section.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2011, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The reference to “section 74 of this act” in s. 79(1), ch. 2011-139, should be to s. 73; s. 74 relates to review of issues, and s. 73 provides for a 2-year permit extension.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">F. Section 23, ch. 2012-205, provides that “[t]he holder of a valid permit or other authorization is not required to make a payment to the authorizing agency for use of an extension granted under section 73 or section 79 of chapter 2011-139, Laws of Florida, or section 24 of this act. This section applies retroactively and is effective as of June 2, 2011.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">G. Section 24, ch. 2012-205, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Any building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from January 1, 2012, through January 1, 2014, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit including certificates of levels of service. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to any existing permit extension. Extensions granted pursuant to this section; section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; or section 74 or section 79 of chapter 2011-139, Laws of Florida, shall not exceed 4 years in total. Further, specific development order extensions granted pursuant to s. 380.06(19)(c)2., Florida Statutes, cannot be further extended by this section.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2012, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The reference to “section 74 of this act” in s. 79(1), ch. 2011-139, should be to s. 73; s. 74 relates to review of issues, and s. 73 provides for a 2-year permit extension.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>