<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.459" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Funds for surface water improvement and management.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legislative appropriations provided to the water management districts for surface water improvement and management activities shall be available for detailed planning and plan and program implementation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entity that receives state funding for the implementation of programs specified in ss. 373.451-373.459, including a water management district, federal, local, or regional agency, university, or nonprofit or private organization, shall provide a 50-percent match of cash or in-kind services towards the implementation of the specific project for which it is contracting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Ecosystem Management and Restoration Trust Fund shall be used for the deposit of funds appropriated by the Legislature for the purposes of ss. 373.451-373.4595. The department shall administer all funds appropriated to or received for surface water improvement and management activities. Expenditure of the moneys shall be limited to the costs of detailed planning and plan and program implementation for priority surface water bodies. Moneys from the fund shall not be expended for planning for, or construction or expansion of, treatment facilities for domestic or industrial waste disposal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall authorize the release of money from the fund in accordance with the provisions of s. 373.501(2) and procedures in s. 373.59(4) and (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the fund which are not needed to meet current obligations incurred under this section shall be transferred to the State Board of Administration, to the credit of the trust fund, to be invested in the manner provided by law. Interest received on such investments shall be credited to the trust fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The match requirement of subsection (2) shall not apply to the Suwannee River Water Management District, the Northwest Florida Water Management District, or a financially disadvantaged small local government as defined in former s. 403.885(3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 87-97; s. 29, ch. 89-279; s. 9, ch. 91-79; s. 11, ch. 91-305; s. 11, ch. 94-115; s. 504, ch. 94-356; s. 44, ch. 96-321; s. 6, ch. 2003-265; s. 8, ch. 2005-291; s. 33, ch. 2006-26; ss. 39, 54, ch. 2007-73; s. 3, ch. 2007-191; s. 17, ch. 2008-5.</History></Section>