<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Artesian wells; penalties for violation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No owner, tenant, occupant, or person in control of an artesian well shall knowingly and intentionally:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the well to flow continuously without a valve or mechanical device for checking or controlling the flow.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit the water to flow unnecessarily.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pump a well unnecessarily.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit the water from the well to go to waste.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A well is exempt from the provisions of this section unless the Department of Environmental Protection can show that the uncontrolled flow of water from the well does not have a reasonable-beneficial use, as defined in s. 373.019.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be subject to either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remedial measures provided for in s. 373.436; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty of $100 a day for each and every day of such violation and for each and every act of violation. The civil penalty may be recovered by the water management board of the water management district in which the well is located or by the department in a suit in a court of competent jurisdiction in the county where the defendant resides, in the county of residence of any defendant if there is more than one defendant, or in the county where the violation took place. The place of suit shall be selected by the board or department, and the suit, by direction of the board or department, shall be instituted and conducted in the name of the board or department by appropriate counsel. The payment of any such damages does not impair or abridge any cause of action which any person may have against the person violating any provision of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalties provided by this section shall apply notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28253, 1953; s. 323, ch. 71-136; s. 25, ch. 73-190; s. 1, ch. 74-279; s. 46, ch. 79-65; s. 146, ch. 79-400; s. 264, ch. 94-356; s. 93, ch. 95-143; s. 8, ch. 98-88.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 370.053, 373.041.</Text></Note></Section>