<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.591" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Management review teams.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine whether conservation, preservation, and recreation lands titled in the names of the water management districts are being managed for the purposes for which they were acquired and in accordance with land management objectives, the water management districts shall establish land management review teams to conduct periodic management reviews. The land management review teams shall be composed of the following members:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One individual from the county or local community in which the parcel is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One employee of the water management district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private land manager mutually agreeable to the governmental agency representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the local soil and water conservation district board of supervisors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One individual from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One individual from the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One individual representing a conservation organization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One individual from the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services’ Florida Forest Service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The management review team shall use the criteria provided in s. 259.036 in conducting its reviews.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining which lands shall be reviewed in any given year, the water management district may prioritize the properties to be reviewed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the land management review team finds that the lands reviewed are not being managed in accordance with their management plan, prepared in a manner and form prescribed by the governing board of the district and otherwise meeting the timber resource management requirements of s. 253.036, the land managing agency shall provide a written explanation to the management review team.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water management district shall, by October 1 of each year, provide its governing board with a report indicating which properties have been reviewed and the review team’s findings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 97-164; s. 3, ch. 98-332; s. 173, ch. 99-13; s. 192, ch. 99-245; s. 18, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>