<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.243" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation of permits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board or the department may revoke a permit as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any material false statement in an application to continue, initiate, or modify a use, or for any material false statement in any report or statement of fact required of the user pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, the governing board or the department may revoke the user’s permit, in whole or in part, permanently.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For willful violation of the conditions of the permit, the governing board or the department may permanently or temporarily revoke the permit, in whole or in part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For violation of any provision of this chapter, the governing board or the department may revoke the permit, in whole or in part, for a period not to exceed 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For nonuse of the water supply allowed by the permit for a period of 2 years or more, the governing board or the department may revoke the permit permanently and in whole unless the user can prove that his or her nonuse was due to extreme hardship caused by factors beyond the user’s control. For a permit issued pursuant to s. 373.236(7), the governing board or the department may revoke the permit only if the nonuse of the water supply allowed by the permit is for a period of 4 years or more.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board or the department may revoke a permit, permanently and in whole, with the written consent of the permittee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, part II, ch. 72-299; s. 14, ch. 78-95; s. 600, ch. 95-148; s. 11, ch. 2009-243.</History></Section>