<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.336" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice water well contracting without an active license issued pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construct, repair, or abandon a water well, or operate drilling equipment for such purpose, unless employed by or under the supervision of a licensed water well contractor or exempt under s. 373.326.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give false or forged evidence to obtain a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as his or her own the license of another.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a license to practice water well contracting which license has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in willful or repeated violation of this part or of any department rule or regulation or water management district or state agency rule or regulation relating to water wells which endangers the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for a business entity to engage in water well contracting or to perform any activity for which a license as a water well contractor is required unless a licensed water well contractor is responsible for supervising such activity of the business entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this part or regulation or order issued hereunder shall, upon conviction, be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Continuing violation after an order or conviction shall constitute a separate violation for each day so continued.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, part III, ch. 72-299; s. 17, ch. 73-190; s. 1, ch. 84-94; ss. 19, 23, 24, ch. 88-242; s. 57, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 605, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>