<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Abandoned artesian well” is defined as an artesian well:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That does not have a properly functioning valve;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of which has been permanently discontinued;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That does not meet current well construction standards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is discharging water containing greater than 500 milligrams per liter of chlorides into a drinking water aquifer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is in such a state of disrepair that it cannot be used for its intended purpose without having an adverse impact upon an aquifer which serves as a source of drinking water or which is likely to be such a source in the future; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That does not have proper flow control on or below the land surface.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An “artesian well” is defined as an artificial hole in the ground from which water supplies may be obtained and which penetrates any water-bearing rock, the water in which is raised to the surface by natural flow, or which rises to an elevation above the top of the water-bearing bed. “Artesian wells” are defined further to include all holes, drilled as a source of water, that penetrate any water-bearing beds that are a part of the artesian water system of Florida, as determined by representatives of the Florida Geological Survey or the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plugging” is defined as plugging, capping, or otherwise controlling a well as deemed appropriate by the department or by the appropriate water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Waste” is defined to be the causing, suffering, or permitting any water flowing from, or being pumped from, an artesian well to run into any river, creek, or other natural watercourse or channel, or into any bay or pond (unless used thereafter for the beneficial purposes of irrigation of land, mining, or other industrial purposes of domestic use), or into any street, road or highway, or upon the land of any person, or upon the public lands of the United States or of the state, unless it is used thereon for the beneficial purposes of the irrigation thereof, industrial purposes, domestic use, or the propagation of fish. The use of any water flowing from an artesian well for the irrigation of land shall be restricted to a minimum by the use of proper structural devices in the irrigation system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 4, ch. 28253, 1953; s. 1, ch. 59-248; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 25, ch. 73-190; s. 44, ch. 79-65; s. 6, ch. 83-310; s. 261, ch. 94-356.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 370.051, 373.021.</Text></Note></Section>