<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.093" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lease of lands or interest in land and personal property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of the district may lease any lands or interest in land, including but not limited to oil and mineral rights, to which the district has acquired title, or to which it may hereafter acquire title in the following manner, as long as the lease is consistent with the purposes for which the lands or any interest in land was acquired:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the best price and terms obtainable, to be determined by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before leasing any land, or interest in land including but not limited to oil and mineral rights, the district shall cause a notice of intention to lease to be published in a newspaper published in the county in which said land is situated and such other places as the board may determine once each week for 3 successive weeks (three insertions being sufficient), the first publication of which shall be not less than 30 nor more than 90 days prior to the date the board executes the lease, which said notice shall set forth the time and place of leasing and a description of the lands to be leased.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall not be necessary to publish the notice as provided by subsection (2) where the lease is made to a person in connection with land acquisition by the district and the lease results in a diminution of the cost to the district in the acquisition of the land.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of the district may lease existing communications towers and other similar structures which the district owns or which it may hereafter acquire, for the best price and terms obtainable, to be determined by the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 29790, 1955; s. 25, ch. 73-190; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 25, ch. 88-242; ss. 1, 2, ch. 89-279; ss. 11, 12, ch. 90-217; s. 11, ch. 92-288; ss. 3, 12, ch. 2001-256.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 378.49.</Text></Note></Section>