<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.45926" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Everglades Trust Fund; allocation of revenues and expenditure of funds for conservation and protection of natural resources and abatement of water pollution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE FINDINGS AND INTENT.<EmDash />The Legislature finds and declares the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Everglades ecological system is unique in the world and one of Florida’s great treasures. The Legislature has responded to adverse changes in water quality, and in quantity, distribution, and timing of flows, that endanger the Everglades ecological system, by enacting the Everglades Forever Act. The act authorized the Everglades Construction Project, which is by far the largest environmental cleanup and restoration program of this type ever undertaken and will require substantial expenditures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consideration of both the environmental benefits and public costs of the Everglades Construction Project, the Legislature finds that enhanced oversight and accountability is necessary to ensure that the Everglades Construction Project is completed in a timely manner and within the limits of the funds made available for its completion. The Legislature further finds that the implementation of the Everglades Forever Act is critical to the conservation and protection of natural resources and improvement of water quality in the Everglades Protection Area and the Everglades Agricultural Area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The South Florida Water Management District shall administer the Everglades Trust Fund consistent with the requirements of this section, as well as all other applicable laws.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The South Florida Water Management District shall furnish, as part of the consolidated annual report required by s. 373.036(7), a detailed copy of its expenditures from the Everglades Trust Fund to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and shall make copies available to the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following funds shall be deposited into the Everglades Trust Fund specifically for the implementation of the Everglades Forever Act.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alligator Alley toll revenues pursuant to s. 338.26(3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Everglades agricultural privilege tax revenues pursuant to s. 373.4592(6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">C-139 agricultural privilege tax revenues pursuant to s. 373.4592(7).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special assessment revenues pursuant to s. 373.4592(8).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ad valorem revenues pursuant to s. 373.4592(4)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal funds appropriated by the United States Congress for any component of the Everglades Construction Project.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preservation 2000 funds for acquisition of lands necessary for implementation of the Everglades Forever Act as prescribed in an annual appropriation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional funds specifically appropriated by the Legislature for this purpose.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gifts designated for implementation of the Everglades Forever Act from individuals, corporations, and other entities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional funds that become available for this purpose from any other source.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds deposited into the Everglades Trust Fund pursuant to this section shall be expended for implementation of the Everglades Forever Act as provided by s. 373.4592.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds from other sources deposited into the Everglades Trust Fund shall be used consistent with the purposes for which they were received.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually, no later than January 1, the South Florida Water Management District shall report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unencumbered balance which remains in the Everglades Trust Fund at the end of each fiscal year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revenues deposited in the Everglades Trust Fund pursuant to this section, by source, and the record of expenditures from the Everglades Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 97-258; s. 108, ch. 2001-266; s. 13, ch. 2005-36; s. 33, ch. 2011-34.</History>
</Section>