<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Topographic mapping.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to accelerate topographic mapping in this state by the United States Geological Survey, the Department of Transportation is hereby authorized and directed to set aside, to pledge, and to make available annually out of its State Transportation Trust Fund the sum of $30,000; and the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund is hereby authorized and directed to set aside, to pledge and to make available annually out of the Land Acquisition Trust Fund the sum of $10,000; and the South Florida Water Management District out of its funds to be derived out of the proceeds of special assessments of its flood control taxes, is authorized and directed to set aside, to pledge and to make available annually such sum as may be required to meet the needs for topographic mapping of areas affecting said district. Such sums shall be delivered to the Treasurer of the United States or to other proper officer, to be applied by the Department of the Interior, United States Geological Survey, as to said Department of Transportation and to said Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, toward the payment of not exceeding one-half the cost of standard topographic mapping in this state conducted by the United States Geological Survey and as to said flood control district to be applied toward the payment of such proportion or part of such cost as said district may determine. Provided, however, that said sums authorized in this section for the Department of Transportation and for the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund shall not prevent either of said agencies from providing additional amounts for topographic mapping of areas which either agency may consider of priority status in the interest of said agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To further accelerate the rate at which topographic mapping may be carried on in Florida, any state agency having funds available for the purpose, any county or drainage or reclamation or flood control district organized under the laws of this state, any person, firm or corporation, is authorized to contribute to the cost of such mapping by depositing with the Department of Transportation such amounts as may be determined to be applied in like manner toward topographic mapping in this state as set forth in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation, the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of this state, and the South Florida Water Management District are hereby authorized to make such arrangements or enter into such agreements with the United States as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, as and when copies of topographic maps are made available to it, shall file such maps in the same manner as other maps and plats of land surveys by the United States, and the maps shall be available for examination by any interested person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 57-775; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 65-475; ss. 23, 27, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 2, 3, ch. 73-57; s. 35, ch. 79-65.</History></Section>