<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.323" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure of water well contractors; application, qualifications, and examinations; equipment identification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person who wishes to engage in business as a water well contractor shall obtain from the water management district a license to conduct such business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person desiring to be licensed as a water well contractor shall apply to take the licensure examination. Application shall be made to the water management district in which the applicant resides or in which his or her principal place of business is located. A resident of another state shall apply to the water management district in which most of the business of the applicant will take place. Application shall be made on forms provided by the water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who meets the following requirements shall be entitled to take the water well contractor licensure examination:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has at least 2 years of experience in constructing, repairing, or abandoning water wells. Satisfactory proof of such experience shall be demonstrated by providing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of the length of time the applicant has been engaged in the business of the construction, repair, or abandonment of water wells as a major activity, as attested to by a letter from three of the following persons:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A water well contractor.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A water well driller.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A water well parts and equipment vendor.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A water well inspector employed by a governmental agency.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of at least 10 water wells that the applicant has constructed, repaired, or abandoned within the preceding 5 years. Of these wells, at least seven must have been constructed, as defined in s. 373.303(2), by the applicant. The list shall also include:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner or owners of each well.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location, primary use, and approximate depth and diameter of each well that the applicant has constructed, repaired, or abandoned.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The approximate date the construction, repair, or abandonment of each well was completed.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare an examination which shall test an applicant’s knowledge of rules and regulations adopted under this part; ability to construct, repair, and abandon a well; and ability to supervise, direct, manage, and control the contracting activities of a water well contracting business. The department shall provide each water management district and representatives of the water well contracting industry with meaningful opportunity to participate in the development of the examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The water management district shall issue a water well contracting license to any applicant who receives a passing grade on the examination, has paid the initial application fee, takes and completes, to the satisfaction of the department, a minimum of 12 hours of approved coursework, and has complied with the requirements of this section. A passing grade on the examination shall be as established by the department by rule. A license issued by any water management district shall be valid in every water management district in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee of a political subdivision or of a governmental entity engaged in water well drilling shall be licensed pursuant to this part but shall be exempt from paying fees required pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a water management district has probable cause to believe that any person not licensed as a water well contractor has violated any provision of this part or any statute that relates to the construction, repair, or abandonment of water wells, or any rule adopted pursuant thereto, the water management district may issue and deliver to such person a notice to cease and desist from such violation. In addition, the water management district may issue and deliver a notice to cease and desist to any person who aids and abets the unlicensed construction, repair, or abandonment of a water well by employing an unlicensed person. For the purpose of enforcing a cease and desist order, a water management district may file a proceeding in the name of the state seeking issuance of an injunction or a writ of mandamus against any person who violates any provision of such order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules which specifically provide for uniformity among all water management districts for the application process and qualifications for licensure, providing each water management district and representatives of the water well contracting industry with meaningful opportunity to participate in the development of the rules as they are drafted. The rules shall be adopted by each water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each piece of drilling equipment owned, leased, or operated by a water well contractor shall have the water well contractor’s license number prominently displayed thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water well contractors licensed under this section may install, repair, and modify pumps and tanks in accordance with the Florida Building Code, Plumbing; Section 612<EmDash />Wells pumps and tanks used for private potable water systems. In addition, licensed water well contractors may install pumps, tanks, and water conditioning equipment for all water well systems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed well water contractor may facilitate the performance of additional work by an appropriately licensed contractor which is incidental to the construction, repair, or abandonment of a water well. For purposes of this subsection, incidental work is limited to the electrical connection of a pump, connecting a well to a residential dwelling, constructing a pump house or pump vault of 100 square feet or less, constructing a nonstructural well slab of 100 square feet or less, constructing fencing, and landscaping. This part does not authorize a licensed water well contractor to perform any services or work for which a license under chapter 489 is required.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, part III, ch. 72-299; s. 114, ch. 77-104; s. 14, ch. 78-95; s. 77, ch. 83-310; s. 1, ch. 84-94; ss. 12, 23, 24, ch. 88-242; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 602, ch. 95-148; s. 4, ch. 2001-186; s. 16, ch. 2001-270; s. 1, ch. 2006-87; s. 9, ch. 2009-243.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As enacted by s. 4, ch. 2001-186. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Subsection (10) was also added by s. 16, ch. 2001-270, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(10) Water well contractors licensed pursuant to this section shall be authorized to install, repair, and modify pumps and tanks in accordance with the Florida Building Code, chapter 29; Section 612—Well Pumps and Tanks Used for Private Potable Water Systems. In addition, licensed water well contractors shall be able to install pumps, tanks, and water conditioning equipment for all water well systems.</Text></Note></Section>