<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.468" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Harris Chain of Lakes restoration program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and the St. Johns River Water Management District, in conjunction with the Department of Environmental Protection, pertinent local governments, and the Harris Chain of Lakes Restoration Council, shall review existing restoration proposals to determine which ones are the most environmentally sound and economically feasible methods of improving the fish and wildlife habitat and natural systems of the Harris Chain of Lakes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To initiate the Harris Chain of Lakes restoration program recommended by the Harris Chain of Lakes Restoration Council, the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, with assistance from the St. Johns River Water Management District and in consultation and by agreement with the Department of Environmental Protection and pertinent local governments, shall develop tasks to be undertaken by those entities for the enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat. These agencies shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate different methodologies for removing the extensive tussocks and buildup of organic matter along the shoreline and of the aquatic vegetation in the lake.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct any additional studies as recommended by the Harris Chain of Lakes Restoration Council.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent on the Legislature’s appropriating funds for the Harris Chain of Lakes restoration program and in conjunction with financial participation by federal, other state, and local governments, the appropriate agencies shall, through competitive bid, award contracts to implement the activities of the Harris Chain of Lakes restoration program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is authorized to conduct a demonstration restoration project on the Harris Chain of Lakes for the purpose of creating better habitat for fish and wildlife.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 2001-246.</History></Section>