<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure for water use and impoundment construction permit applications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applications for water use permits, under part II of this chapter; for permits for construction or alteration of dams, impoundments, reservoirs, and appurtenant works, under part IV of this chapter; and for permits under s. 403.812 shall be filed with the water management district on appropriate forms provided by the governing board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of an application for a permit of the type referred to in subsection (1), the governing board shall cause a notice thereof to be published in a newspaper having general circulation within the affected area. In addition, the governing board shall send, by regular or electronic mail, a copy of such notice to any person who has filed a written request for notification of any pending applications affecting this particular designated area. At the option of the applicable county or city government, notice of application for the consumptive use of water shall be mailed by regular or electronic mail to the county and appropriate city government from which boundaries the withdrawal is proposed to be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All permits issued under this section shall include the following language:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">This permit does not convey to the permittee any property rights or privileges other than those specified herein, nor relieve the permittee from complying with any applicable local government, state, or federal law, rule, or ordinance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, part I, ch. 72-299; s. 14, ch. 78-95; s. 73, ch. 83-310; s. 3, ch. 96-339; s. 1, ch. 2003-124; s. 3, ch. 2004-381.</History></Section>