<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to obtain the most beneficial use of the water resources of the state and to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and the interests of the water users affected, governing boards, by action not inconsistent with the other provisions of this law and without impairing property rights, may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules or issue orders affecting the use of water, as conditions warrant, and forbidding the construction of new diversion facilities or wells, the initiation of new water uses, or the modification of any existing uses, diversion facilities, or storage facilities within the affected area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulate the use of water within the affected area by apportioning, limiting, or rotating uses of water or by preventing those uses which the governing board finds have ceased to be reasonable or beneficial.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue orders and adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In adopting rules and issuing orders under this law, the governing board shall act with a view to full protection of the existing rights to water in this state insofar as is consistent with the purpose of this law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rule or order shall require any modification of existing use or disposition of water in the district unless it is shown that the use or disposition proposed to be modified is detrimental to other water users or to the water resources of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rules adopted by the governing board shall be filed with the Department of State as provided in chapter 120. An information copy will be filed with the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 57-380; s. 8, ch. 63-336; ss. 10, 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 8, ch. 76-243; s. 1, ch. 77-117; s. 14, ch. 78-95; s. 256, ch. 94-356; s. 84, ch. 98-200.</History></Section>