<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers and duties of the governing board.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other powers and duties allowed it by law, the governing board is authorized to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with public agencies, private corporations, or other persons; sue and be sued; and appoint and remove agents and employees, including specialists and consultants.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue orders to implement or enforce any of the provisions of this chapter or regulations thereunder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make surveys and investigations of the water supply and resources of the district and cooperate with other governmental agencies in similar activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicit and accept donations or grants of funds or services from both public and private sources for the planning and implementation of district undertakings and delegations, including, but not limited to, projects, programs, works, and studies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute any of the powers, duties, and functions vested in the governing board through a member, the executive director, or other district staff as designated by the governing board. The governing board may establish the scope and terms of any delegation, and no delegation shall be subject to the rulemaking requirements of chapter 120. However, if the governing board delegates to the executive director its authority to take final action on permit applications under part II or petitions for variances or waivers of permitting requirements under part II, the executive director may execute such delegated authority through designated staff. However, the governing board must provide a process for referring a denial of such application or petition to the governing board for the purpose of taking final action. The authority to delegate under this subsection is supplemental to any other provision of this chapter granting authority to the governing board to delegate specific powers, duties, or functions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, part I, ch. 72-299; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 25, ch. 88-242; ss. 1, 2, ch. 89-279; ss. 11, 12, ch. 90-217; s. 1, ch. 97-70; s. 1, ch. 2000-133; s. 2, ch. 2001-256; s. 7, ch. 2009-243; s. 52, ch. 2010-205.</History>
</Section>