<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.441" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Role of counties, municipalities, and local pollution control programs in permit processing; delegation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, by December 1, 1994, adopt rules to guide the participation of counties, municipalities, and local pollution control programs in an efficient, streamlined permitting system. Such rules must seek to increase governmental efficiency, maintain environmental standards, and include consideration of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions under which the environmental resource permit program is delegated, upon approval of the department, only to a county, municipality, or local pollution control program that has the financial, technical, and administrative capabilities and desire to implement and enforce the program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions under which a locally delegated permit program may have stricter environmental standards than state standards;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for identifying and reconciling any duplicative permitting by January 1, 1995;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for timely and cost-efficient notification by the reviewing agency of permit applications, and permit requirements, to counties, municipalities, local pollution control programs, the department, or water management districts, as appropriate;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for ensuring the consistency of permit applications with local comprehensive plans;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for the partial delegation of the environmental resource permit program to counties, municipalities, or local pollution control programs, and standards and criteria to be employed in the implementation of such delegation by counties, municipalities, and local pollution control programs;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special provisions under which the environmental resource permit program may be delegated to counties having populations of 75,000 or fewer, or municipalities with, or local pollution control programs serving, populations of 50,000 or fewer; </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for the applicability of chapter 120 to local government programs when the environmental resource permit program is delegated to counties, municipalities, or local pollution control programs; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for a local government to petition the Governor and Cabinet for review of a request for a delegation of authority that is not approved or denied within 1 year after being initiated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any denial by the department of a local government’s request for a delegation of authority must provide specific detail of those statutory or rule provisions that were not satisfied. Such detail shall also include specific actions that can be taken in order to allow for the delegation of authority. A local government, upon being denied a request for a delegation of authority, may petition the Governor and Cabinet for a review of the request. The Governor and Cabinet may reverse the decision of the department and may provide any necessary conditions to allow the delegation of authority to occur.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegation of authority shall be approved if the local government meets the requirements set forth in rule 62-344, Florida Administrative Code. This section does not require a local government to seek delegation of the environmental resource permit program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect or modify land development regulations adopted by a local government to implement its comprehensive plan pursuant to chapter 163.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review environmental resource permit applications for electrical distribution and transmission lines and other facilities related to the production, transmission, and distribution of electricity which are not certified under ss. 403.52-403.5365, the Florida Electric Transmission Line Siting Act, regulated under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 93-213; s. 17, ch. 94-122; s. 33, ch. 95-146; s. 13, ch. 98-258; s. 67, ch. 2006-230; s. 41, ch. 2010-147.</History>
</Section>