<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.423" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the construction or alteration of any stormwater management system, dam, impoundment, reservoir, appurtenant work, or works, the governing board or department pursuant to s. 403.091 shall make at its expense such periodic inspections as it deems necessary to ensure conformity with the approved plans and specifications included in the permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If during construction or alteration the governing board or department finds that the work is not being done in accordance with the approved plans and specifications as indicated in the permit, it shall give the permittee written notice stating with which particulars of the approved plans and specifications the construction is not in compliance and shall order immediate compliance with such plans and specifications. The failure to act in accordance with the orders of the governing board or department after receipt of written notice shall result in the initiation of revocation proceedings in accordance with s. 373.429.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon completion of the work, the executive director of the district or the Department of Environmental Protection or its successor agency shall have periodic inspections made of permitted stormwater management systems, dams, reservoirs, impoundments, appurtenant work, or works to protect the public health and safety and the natural resources of the state. No person shall refuse immediate entry or access to any authorized representative of the governing board or the department who requests entry for purposes of such inspection and presents appropriate credentials.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, part IV, ch. 72-299; s. 21, ch. 73-190; s. 48, ch. 79-65; s. 13, ch. 84-341; s. 17, ch. 89-279; s. 269, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>