<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.0697" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Basin taxes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The respective basins may, pursuant to s. 9(b), Art. VII of the State Constitution, by resolution request the governing board of the district to levy ad valorem taxes within such basin. Upon receipt of such request, a basin tax levy shall be made by the governing board of the district to finance basin functions enumerated in s. 373.0695, notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or special law to the contrary, and subject to the provisions of s. 373.503(3).</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of money to be raised by said tax levy shall be determined by the adoption of an annual budget by the district board of governors, and the average millage for the basin shall be that amount required to raise the amount called for by the annual budget when applied to the total assessment of the basin as determined for county taxing purposes. However, no such tax shall be levied within the basin unless and until the annual budget and required tax levy shall have been approved by formal action of the basin board, and no county in the district shall be taxed under this provision at a rate to exceed 1 mill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxes provided for in this section shall be extended by the county property appraiser on the county tax roll in each county within, or partly within, the basin and shall be collected by the tax collector in the same manner and time as county taxes, and the proceeds therefrom paid to the district for basin purposes. Said taxes shall be a lien, until paid, on the property against which assessed and enforceable in like manner as county taxes. The property appraisers, tax collectors, and clerks of the circuit court of the respective counties shall be entitled to compensation for services performed in connection with such taxes at the same rates as apply to county taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is hereby determined that the taxes authorized by this subsection are in proportion to the benefits to be derived by the several parcels of real estate within the basin from the works authorized herein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 73-190; s. 2, ch. 75-125; s. 5, ch. 76-243.</History></Section>