<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0373.472" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Save Our Everglades Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Environmental Protection the Save Our Everglades Trust Fund. Funds in the trust fund shall be expended to implement the comprehensive plan defined in s. 373.470(2)(b); the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan defined in s. 373.4595(2); the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Protection Plan defined in s. 373.4595(2); the St. Lucie River Watershed Protection Plan defined in s. 373.4595(2); and the Florida Keys Area of Critical State Concern protection program under ss. 380.05 and 380.0552 to restore and conserve natural systems through the implementation of water management projects, including wastewater management projects identified in the “Keys Wastewater Plan” dated November 2007 and submitted to the Florida House of Representatives on December 4, 2007; and to pay debt service for Everglades restoration bonds issued pursuant to s. 215.619. The trust fund shall serve as the repository for state, local, and federal project contributions in accordance with s. 373.470(4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trust fund is not subject to the service charge described in s. 215.20(1). All income of a revenue nature, including interest or other earnings received or credited by the trust fund, shall be credited to the fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund at the end of the year and shall be available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-132; s. 5, ch. 2002-261; s. 23, ch. 2003-394; s. 5, ch. 2007-253; s. 89, ch. 2008-4; s. 3, ch. 2008-49; s. 45, ch. 2008-153; s. 11, ch. 2010-4.</History>
</Section>