<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.4595" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Northern Everglades and Estuaries Protection Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FINDINGS AND INTENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed are critical water resources of the state, providing many economic, natural habitat, and biodiversity functions benefiting the public interest, including agricultural, public, and environmental water supply; flood control; fishing; navigation and recreation; and habitat to endangered and threatened species and other flora and fauna.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that changes in land uses, the construction of the Central and Southern Florida Project, and the loss of surface water storage have resulted in adverse changes to the hydrology and water quality of Lake Okeechobee and the Caloosahatchee and St. Lucie Rivers and their estuaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that improvement to the hydrology, water quality, and associated aquatic habitats within the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed, is essential to the protection of the greater Everglades ecosystem.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature also finds that it is imperative for the state, local governments, and agricultural and environmental communities to commit to restoring and protecting the surface water resources of the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed, and that a watershed-based approach to address these issues must be developed and implemented immediately.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that phosphorus loads from the Lake Okeechobee watershed have contributed to excessive phosphorus levels throughout the Lake Okeechobee watershed and downstream receiving waters and that a reduction in levels of phosphorus will benefit the ecology of these systems. The excessive levels of phosphorus have also resulted in an accumulation of phosphorus in the sediments of Lake Okeechobee. If not removed, internal phosphorus loads from the sediments are expected to delay responses of the lake to external phosphorus reductions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the Lake Okeechobee phosphorus loads set forth in the total maximum daily loads established in accordance with s. 403.067 represent an appropriate basis for restoration of the Lake Okeechobee watershed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that, in addition to phosphorus, other pollutants are contributing to water quality problems in the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed, and that the total maximum daily load requirements of s. 403.067 provide a means of identifying and addressing these problems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the expeditious implementation of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan and the River Watershed Protection Plans is needed to improve the quality, quantity, timing, and distribution of water in the northern Everglades ecosystem and that this section, in conjunction with s. 403.067, including the implementation of the plans developed and approved pursuant to subsections (3) and (4), and any related basin management action plan developed and implemented pursuant to s. 403.067(7)(a), provide a reasonable means of achieving the total maximum daily load requirements and achieving and maintaining compliance with state water quality standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the implementation of the programs contained in this section is for the benefit of the public health, safety, and welfare and is in the public interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that sufficient research has been conducted and sufficient plans developed to immediately expand and accelerate programs to address the hydrology and water quality in the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that a continuing source of funding is needed to effectively implement the programs developed and approved under this section which are needed to address the hydrology and water quality problems within the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to protect and restore surface water resources and achieve and maintain compliance with water quality standards in the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed, and downstream receiving waters, through the phased, comprehensive, and innovative protection program set forth in this section which includes long-term solutions based upon the total maximum daily loads established in accordance with s. 403.067. This program shall be watershed-based, shall provide for consideration of all water quality issues needed to meet the total maximum daily load, and shall include research and monitoring, development and implementation of best management practices, refinement of existing regulations, and structural and nonstructural projects, including public works.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that this section be implemented in coordination with the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan project components and other federal programs in order to maximize opportunities for the most efficient and timely expenditures of public funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the coordinating agencies encourage and support the development of creative public-private partnerships and programs, including opportunities for water storage and quality improvement on private lands and water quality credit trading, to facilitate or further the restoration of the surface water resources of the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed, consistent with s. 403.067.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Best management practice” means a practice or combination of practices determined by the coordinating agencies, based on research, field-testing, and expert review, to be the most effective and practicable on-location means, including economic and technological considerations, for improving water quality in agricultural and urban discharges. Best management practices for agricultural discharges shall reflect a balance between water quality improvements and agricultural productivity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Caloosahatchee River watershed” means the Caloosahatchee River, its tributaries, its estuary, and the area within Charlotte, Glades, Hendry, and Lee Counties from which surface water flow is directed or drains, naturally or by constructed works, to the river, its tributaries, or its estuary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Coordinating agencies” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, the Department of Environmental Protection, and the South Florida Water Management District.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corps of Engineers” means the United States Army Corps of Engineers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District” means the South Florida Water Management District.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District’s WOD program” means the program implemented pursuant to rules adopted as authorized by this section and ss. 373.016, 373.044, 373.085, 373.086, 373.109, 373.113, 373.118, 373.451, and 373.453, entitled “Works of the District Basin.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project” means the construction project developed pursuant to paragraph (3)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan” means the plan developed pursuant to this section and ss. 373.451-373.459.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lake Okeechobee watershed” means Lake Okeechobee, its tributaries, and the area within which surface water flow is directed or drains, naturally or by constructed works, to the lake or its tributaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lake Okeechobee Watershed Phosphorus Control Program” means the program developed pursuant to paragraph (3)(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Northern Everglades” means the Lake Okeechobee watershed, the Caloosahatchee River watershed, and the St. Lucie River watershed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project component” means any structural or operational change, resulting from the Restudy, to the Central and Southern Florida Project as it existed and was operated as of January 1, 1999.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Restudy” means the Comprehensive Review Study of the Central and Southern Florida Project, for which federal participation was authorized by the Federal Water Resources Development Acts of 1992 and 1996 together with related Congressional resolutions and for which participation by the South Florida Water Management District is authorized by s. 373.1501. The term includes all actions undertaken pursuant to the aforementioned authorizations which will result in recommendations for modifications or additions to the Central and Southern Florida Project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“River Watershed Protection Plans” means the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Protection Plan and the St. Lucie River Watershed Protection Plan developed pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“St. Lucie River watershed” means the St. Lucie River, its tributaries, its estuary, and the area within Martin, Okeechobee, and St. Lucie Counties from which surface water flow is directed or drains, naturally or by constructed works, to the river, its tributaries, or its estuary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Total maximum daily load” means the sum of the individual wasteload allocations for point sources and the load allocations for nonpoint sources and natural background. Prior to determining individual wasteload allocations and load allocations, the maximum amount of a pollutant that a water body or water segment can assimilate from all sources without exceeding water quality standards must first be calculated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LAKE OKEECHOBEE WATERSHED PROTECTION PROGRAM.<EmDash />A protection program for Lake Okeechobee that achieves phosphorus load reductions for Lake Okeechobee shall be immediately implemented as specified in this subsection. The program shall address the reduction of phosphorus loading to the lake from both internal and external sources. Phosphorus load reductions shall be achieved through a phased program of implementation. Initial implementation actions shall be technology-based, based upon a consideration of both the availability of appropriate technology and the cost of such technology, and shall include phosphorus reduction measures at both the source and the regional level. The initial phase of phosphorus load reductions shall be based upon the district’s Technical Publication 81-2 and the district’s WOD program, with subsequent phases of phosphorus load reductions based upon the total maximum daily loads established in accordance with s. 403.067. In the development and administration of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Program, the coordinating agencies shall maximize opportunities provided by federal cost-sharing programs and opportunities for partnerships with the private sector.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan.</Font><EmDash />In order to protect and restore surface water resources, the district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies, shall complete a Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan in accordance with this section and ss. 373.451-373.459. The plan shall identify the geographic extent of the watershed, be coordinated with the plans developed pursuant to paragraphs (4)(a) and (b), and contain an implementation schedule for subsequent phases of phosphorus load reduction consistent with the total maximum daily loads established in accordance with s. 403.067. The plan shall consider and build upon a review and analysis of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance of projects constructed during Phase I and Phase II of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project, pursuant to paragraph (b).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relevant information resulting from the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Phosphorus Control Program, pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relevant information resulting from the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program, pursuant to paragraph (d).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relevant information resulting from the Lake Okeechobee Exotic Species Control Program, pursuant to paragraph (e).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relevant information resulting from the Lake Okeechobee Internal Phosphorus Management Program, pursuant to paragraph (f).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project.</Font><EmDash />To improve the hydrology and water quality of Lake Okeechobee and downstream receiving waters, including the Caloosahatchee and St. Lucie Rivers and their estuaries, the district shall design and construct the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Phase I.<EmDash />Phase I of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project shall consist of a series of project features consistent with the recommendations of the South Florida Ecosystem Restoration Working Group’s Lake Okeechobee Action Plan. Priority basins for such projects include S-191, S-154, and Pools D and E in the Lower Kissimmee River. In order to obtain phosphorus load reductions to Lake Okeechobee as soon as possible, the following actions shall be implemented:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district shall serve as a full partner with the Corps of Engineers in the design and construction of the Grassy Island Ranch and New Palm Dairy stormwater treatment facilities as components of the Lake Okeechobee Water Retention/Phosphorus Removal Critical Project. The Corps of Engineers shall have the lead in design and construction of these facilities. Should delays be encountered in the implementation of either of these facilities, the district shall notify the department and recommend corrective actions.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district shall obtain permits and complete construction of two of the isolated wetland restoration projects that are part of the Lake Okeechobee Water Retention/Phosphorus Removal Critical Project. The additional isolated wetland projects included in this critical project shall further reduce phosphorus loading to Lake Okeechobee.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district shall work with the Corps of Engineers to expedite initiation of the design process for the Taylor Creek/Nubbins Slough Reservoir Assisted Stormwater Treatment Area, a project component of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan. The district shall propose to the Corps of Engineers that the district take the lead in the design and construction of the Reservoir Assisted Stormwater Treatment Area and receive credit towards the local share of the total cost of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Phase II.<EmDash />By February 1, 2008, the district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies, shall develop a detailed technical plan for Phase II of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project. The detailed technical plan shall include measures for the improvement of the quality, quantity, timing, and distribution of water in the northern Everglades ecosystem, including the Lake Okeechobee watershed and the estuaries, and for facilitating the achievement of water quality standards. Use of cost-effective biologically based, hybrid wetland/chemical and other innovative nutrient control technologies shall be incorporated in the plan where appropriate. The detailed technical plan shall also include a Process Development and Engineering component to finalize the detail and design of Phase II projects and identify additional measures needed to increase the certainty that the overall objectives for improving water quality and quantity can be met. Based on information and recommendations from the Process Development and Engineering component, the Phase II detailed technical plan shall be periodically updated. Phase II shall include construction of additional facilities in the priority basins identified in subparagraph 1., as well as facilities for other basins in the Lake Okeechobee watershed. This detailed technical plan will require legislative ratification pursuant to paragraph (i). The technical plan shall:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facilities designed to contribute to achieving all applicable total maximum daily loads established pursuant to s. 403.067 within the Lake Okeechobee watershed.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the size and location of all such Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facilities.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a construction schedule for all such Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facilities, including the sequencing and specific timeframe for construction of each Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facility.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a schedule for the acquisition of lands or sufficient interests necessary to achieve the construction schedule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a detailed schedule of costs associated with the construction schedule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify, to the maximum extent practicable, impacts on wetlands and state-listed species expected to be associated with construction of such facilities, including potential alternatives to minimize and mitigate such impacts, as appropriate.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for additional measures, including voluntary water storage and quality improvements on private land, to increase water storage and reduce excess water levels in Lake Okeechobee and to reduce excess discharges to the estuaries. The technical plan shall also develop the appropriate water quantity storage goal to achieve the desired Lake Okeechobee range of lake levels and inflow volumes to the Caloosahatchee and St. Lucie estuaries while meeting the other water-related needs of the region, including water supply and flood protection.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for additional source controls needed to enhance performance of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facilities. Such additional source controls shall be incorporated into the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Phosphorous Control Program pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation.<EmDash />By January 1, 2004, and every 3 years thereafter, the district, in cooperation with the coordinating agencies, shall conduct an evaluation of any further load reductions necessary to achieve compliance with all Lake Okeechobee watershed total maximum daily loads established pursuant to s. 403.067. Additionally, the district shall identify modifications to facilities of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project as appropriate to meet the total maximum daily loads. The evaluation shall be included in the applicable annual progress report submitted pursuant to subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination and review.<EmDash />To ensure the timely implementation of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project, the design of project facilities shall be coordinated with the department and other interested parties, including affected local governments, to the maximum extent practicable. Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project facilities shall be reviewed and commented upon by the department prior to the execution of a construction contract by the district for that facility.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Watershed Phosphorus Control Program.</Font><EmDash />The Lake Okeechobee Watershed Phosphorus Control Program is designed to be a multifaceted approach to reducing phosphorus loads by improving the management of phosphorus sources within the Lake Okeechobee watershed through implementation of regulations and best management practices, development and implementation of improved best management practices, improvement and restoration of the hydrologic function of natural and managed systems, and utilization of alternative technologies for nutrient reduction. The coordinating agencies shall facilitate the application of federal programs that offer opportunities for water quality treatment, including preservation, restoration, or creation of wetlands on agricultural lands.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agricultural nonpoint source best management practices, developed in accordance with s. 403.067 and designed to achieve the objectives of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Program, shall be implemented on an expedited basis. The coordinating agencies shall develop an interagency agreement pursuant to ss. 373.046 and 373.406(5) that assures the development of best management practices that complement existing regulatory programs and specifies how those best management practices are implemented and verified. The interagency agreement shall address measures to be taken by the coordinating agencies during any best management practice reevaluation performed pursuant to sub-subparagraph d. The department shall use best professional judgment in making the initial determination of best management practice effectiveness.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As provided in s. 403.067(7)(c), the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in consultation with the department, the district, and affected parties, shall initiate rule development for interim measures, best management practices, conservation plans, nutrient management plans, or other measures necessary for Lake Okeechobee watershed total maximum daily load reduction. The rule shall include thresholds for requiring conservation and nutrient management plans and criteria for the contents of such plans. Development of agricultural nonpoint source best management practices shall initially focus on those priority basins listed in subparagraph (b)1. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in consultation with the department, the district, and affected parties, shall conduct an ongoing program for improvement of existing and development of new interim measures or best management practices for the purpose of adoption of such practices by rule. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall work with the University of Florida’s Institute of Food and Agriculture Sciences to review and, where appropriate, develop revised nutrient application rates for all agricultural soil amendments in the watershed.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where agricultural nonpoint source best management practices or interim measures have been adopted by rule of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, the owner or operator of an agricultural nonpoint source addressed by such rule shall either implement interim measures or best management practices or demonstrate compliance with the district’s WOD program by conducting monitoring prescribed by the department or the district. Owners or operators of agricultural nonpoint sources who implement interim measures or best management practices adopted by rule of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall be subject to the provisions of s. 403.067(7). The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in cooperation with the department and the district, shall provide technical and financial assistance for implementation of agricultural best management practices, subject to the availability of funds.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district or department shall conduct monitoring at representative sites to verify the effectiveness of agricultural nonpoint source best management practices.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where water quality problems are detected for agricultural nonpoint sources despite the appropriate implementation of adopted best management practices, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in consultation with the other coordinating agencies and affected parties, shall institute a reevaluation of the best management practices and make appropriate changes to the rule adopting best management practices.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices, developed in accordance with s. 403.067 and designed to achieve the objectives of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Program, shall be implemented on an expedited basis. The department and the district shall develop an interagency agreement pursuant to ss. 373.046 and 373.406(5) that assures the development of best management practices that complement existing regulatory programs and specifies how those best management practices are implemented and verified. The interagency agreement shall address measures to be taken by the department and the district during any best management practice reevaluation performed pursuant to sub-subparagraph d.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the district are directed to work with the University of Florida’s Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences to develop appropriate nutrient application rates for all nonagricultural soil amendments in the watershed. As provided in s. 403.067(7)(c), the department, in consultation with the district and affected parties, shall develop interim measures, best management practices, or other measures necessary for Lake Okeechobee watershed total maximum daily load reduction. Development of nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices shall initially focus on those priority basins listed in subparagraph (b)1. The department, the district, and affected parties shall conduct an ongoing program for improvement of existing and development of new interim measures or best management practices. The district shall adopt technology-based standards under the district’s WOD program for nonagricultural nonpoint sources of phosphorus. Nothing in this sub-subparagraph shall affect the authority of the department or the district to adopt basin-specific criteria under this part to prevent harm to the water resources of the district.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices or interim measures have been developed by the department and adopted by the district, the owner or operator of a nonagricultural nonpoint source shall implement interim measures or best management practices and be subject to the provisions of s. 403.067(7). The department and district shall provide technical and financial assistance for implementation of nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices, subject to the availability of funds.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district or the department shall conduct monitoring at representative sites to verify the effectiveness of nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where water quality problems are detected for nonagricultural nonpoint sources despite the appropriate implementation of adopted best management practices, the department and the district shall institute a reevaluation of the best management practices.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subparagraphs 1. and 2. shall not preclude the department or the district from requiring compliance with water quality standards or with current best management practices requirements set forth in any applicable regulatory program authorized by law for the purpose of protecting water quality. Additionally, subparagraphs 1. and 2. are applicable only to the extent that they do not conflict with any rules promulgated by the department that are necessary to maintain a federally delegated or approved program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects that reduce the phosphorus load originating from domestic wastewater systems within the Lake Okeechobee watershed shall be given funding priority in the department’s revolving loan program under s. 403.1835. The department shall coordinate and provide assistance to those local governments seeking financial assistance for such priority projects.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects that make use of private lands, or lands held in trust for Indian tribes, to reduce nutrient loadings or concentrations within a basin by one or more of the following methods: restoring the natural hydrology of the basin, restoring wildlife habitat or impacted wetlands, reducing peak flows after storm events, increasing aquifer recharge, or protecting range and timberland from conversion to development, are eligible for grants available under this section from the coordinating agencies. For projects of otherwise equal priority, special funding priority will be given to those projects that make best use of the methods outlined above that involve public-private partnerships or that obtain federal match money. Preference ranking above the special funding priority will be given to projects located in a rural area of critical economic concern designated by the Governor. Grant applications may be submitted by any person or tribal entity, and eligible projects may include, but are not limited to, the purchase of conservation and flowage easements, hydrologic restoration of wetlands, creating treatment wetlands, development of a management plan for natural resources, and financial support to implement a management plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require all entities disposing of domestic wastewater residuals within the Lake Okeechobee watershed and the remaining areas of Okeechobee, Glades, and Hendry Counties to develop and submit to the department an agricultural use plan that limits applications based upon phosphorus loading. By July 1, 2005, phosphorus concentrations originating from these application sites shall not exceed the limits established in the district’s WOD program. After December 31, 2007, the department may not authorize the disposal of domestic wastewater residuals within the Lake Okeechobee watershed unless the applicant can affirmatively demonstrate that the phosphorus in the residuals will not add to phosphorus loadings in Lake Okeechobee or its tributaries. This demonstration shall be based on achieving a net balance between phosphorus imports relative to exports on the permitted application site. Exports shall include only phosphorus removed from the Lake Okeechobee watershed through products generated on the permitted application site. This prohibition does not apply to Class AA residuals that are marketed and distributed as fertilizer products in accordance with department rule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private and government-owned utilities within Monroe, Miami-Dade, Broward, Palm Beach, Martin, St. Lucie, Indian River, Okeechobee, Highlands, Hendry, and Glades Counties that dispose of wastewater residual sludge from utility operations and septic removal by land spreading in the Lake Okeechobee watershed may use a line item on local sewer rates to cover wastewater residual treatment and disposal if such disposal and treatment is done by approved alternative treatment methodology at a facility located within the areas designated by the Governor as rural areas of critical economic concern pursuant to s. 288.0656. This additional line item is an environmental protection disposal fee above the present sewer rate and shall not be considered a part of the present sewer rate to customers, notwithstanding provisions to the contrary in chapter 367. The fee shall be established by the county commission or its designated assignee in the county in which the alternative method treatment facility is located. The fee shall be calculated to be no higher than that necessary to recover the facility’s prudent cost of providing the service. Upon request by an affected county commission, the Florida Public Service Commission will provide assistance in establishing the fee. Further, for utilities and utility authorities that use the additional line item environmental protection disposal fee, such fee shall not be considered a rate increase under the rules of the Public Service Commission and shall be exempt from such rules. Utilities using the provisions of this section may immediately include in their sewer invoicing the new environmental protection disposal fee. Proceeds from this environmental protection disposal fee shall be used for treatment and disposal of wastewater residuals, including any treatment technology that helps reduce the volume of residuals that require final disposal, but such proceeds shall not be used for transportation or shipment costs for disposal or any costs relating to the land application of residuals in the Lake Okeechobee watershed.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No less frequently than once every 3 years, the Florida Public Service Commission or the county commission through the services of an independent auditor shall perform a financial audit of all facilities receiving compensation from an environmental protection disposal fee. The Florida Public Service Commission or the county commission through the services of an independent auditor shall also perform an audit of the methodology used in establishing the environmental protection disposal fee. The Florida Public Service Commission or the county commission shall, within 120 days after completion of an audit, file the audit report with the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and shall provide copies to the county commissions of the counties set forth in sub-subparagraph b. The books and records of any facilities receiving compensation from an environmental protection disposal fee shall be open to the Florida Public Service Commission and the Auditor General for review upon request.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall require all entities disposing of septage within the Lake Okeechobee watershed to develop and submit to that agency an agricultural use plan that limits applications based upon phosphorus loading. By July 1, 2005, phosphorus concentrations originating from these application sites shall not exceed the limits established in the district’s WOD program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall initiate rulemaking requiring entities within the Lake Okeechobee watershed which land-apply animal manure to develop resource management system level conservation plans, according to United States Department of Agriculture criteria, which limit such application. Such rules may include criteria and thresholds for the requirement to develop a conservation or nutrient management plan, requirements for plan approval, and recordkeeping requirements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district, the department, or the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, as appropriate, shall implement those alternative nutrient reduction technologies determined to be feasible pursuant to subparagraph (d)6.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program.</Font><EmDash />The district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies, shall establish a Lake Okeechobee Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program that builds upon the district’s existing Lake Okeechobee research program. The program shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate all available existing water quality data concerning total phosphorus in the Lake Okeechobee watershed, develop a water quality baseline to represent existing conditions for total phosphorus, monitor long-term ecological changes, including water quality for total phosphorus, and measure compliance with water quality standards for total phosphorus, including any applicable total maximum daily load for the Lake Okeechobee watershed as established pursuant to s. 403.067. Every 3 years, the district shall reevaluate water quality and quantity data to ensure that the appropriate projects are being designated and implemented to meet the water quality and storage goals of the plan. The district shall also implement a total phosphorus monitoring program at appropriate structures owned or operated by the South Florida Water Management District and within the Lake Okeechobee watershed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a Lake Okeechobee water quality model that reasonably represents phosphorus dynamics of the lake and incorporates an uncertainty analysis associated with model predictions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the relative contribution of phosphorus from all identifiable sources and all primary and secondary land uses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct an assessment of the sources of phosphorus from the Upper Kissimmee Chain-of-Lakes and Lake Istokpoga, and their relative contribution to the water quality of Lake Okeechobee. The results of this assessment shall be used by the coordinating agencies to develop interim measures, best management practices, or regulation, as applicable.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assess current water management practices within the Lake Okeechobee watershed and develop recommendations for structural and operational improvements. Such recommendations shall balance water supply, flood control, estuarine salinity, maintenance of a healthy lake littoral zone, and water quality considerations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate the feasibility of alternative nutrient reduction technologies, including sediment traps, canal and ditch maintenance, fish production or other aquaculture, bioenergy conversion processes, and algal or other biological treatment technologies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct an assessment of the water volumes and timing from the Lake Okeechobee watershed and their relative contribution to the water level changes in Lake Okeechobee and to the timing and volume of water delivered to the estuaries.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Exotic Species Control Program.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies shall identify the exotic species that threaten the native flora and fauna within the Lake Okeechobee watershed and develop and implement measures to protect the native flora and fauna.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Internal Phosphorus Management Program.</Font><EmDash />The district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies and interested parties, shall complete a Lake Okeechobee internal phosphorus load removal feasibility study. The feasibility study shall be based on technical feasibility, as well as economic considerations, and address all reasonable methods of phosphorus removal. If methods are found to be feasible, the district shall immediately pursue the design, funding, and permitting for implementing such methods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan implementation.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies shall be jointly responsible for implementing the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Protection Plan, consistent with the statutory authority and responsibility of each agency. Annual funding priorities shall be jointly established, and the highest priority shall be assigned to programs and projects that address sources that have the highest relative contribution to loading and the greatest potential for reductions needed to meet the total maximum daily loads. In determining funding priorities, the coordinating agencies shall also consider the need for regulatory compliance, the extent to which the program or project is ready to proceed, and the availability of federal matching funds or other nonstate funding, including public-private partnerships. Federal and other nonstate funding shall be maximized to the greatest extent practicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Priorities and implementation schedules.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies are authorized and directed to establish priorities and implementation schedules for the achievement of total maximum daily loads, compliance with the requirements of s. 403.067, and compliance with applicable water quality standards within the waters and watersheds subject to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Legislative ratification.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies shall submit the Phase II technical plan developed pursuant to paragraph (b) to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives prior to the 2008 legislative session for review. If the Legislature takes no action on the plan during the 2008 legislative session, the plan is deemed approved and may be implemented.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CALOOSAHATCHEE AND ST. LUCIE RIVER WATERSHED PROTECTION PROGRAM.<EmDash />A protection program shall be developed and implemented as specified in this subsection. In order to protect and restore surface water resources, the program shall address the reduction of pollutant loadings, restoration of natural hydrology, and compliance with applicable state water quality standards. The program shall be achieved through a phased program of implementation. In addition, pollutant load reductions based upon adopted total maximum daily loads established in accordance with s. 403.067 shall serve as a program objective. In the development and administration of the program, the coordinating agencies shall maximize opportunities provided by federal and local government cost-sharing programs and opportunities for partnerships with the private sector and local government. The plan shall include a goal for salinity envelopes and freshwater inflow targets for the estuaries based upon existing research and documentation. The goal may be revised as new information is available. This goal shall seek to reduce the frequency and duration of undesirable salinity ranges while meeting the other water-related needs of the region, including water supply and flood protection, while recognizing the extent to which water inflows are within the control and jurisdiction of the district.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Caloosahatchee River Watershed Protection Plan.</Font><EmDash />No later than January 1, 2009, the district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies, Lee County, and affected counties and municipalities, shall complete a River Watershed Protection Plan in accordance with this subsection. The plan shall identify the geographic extent of the watershed, be coordinated as needed with the plans developed pursuant to paragraph (3)(a) and paragraph (b) of this subsection, and contain an implementation schedule for pollutant load reductions consistent with any adopted total maximum daily loads and compliance with applicable state water quality standards. The plan shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Caloosahatchee River Watershed Construction Project.<EmDash />To improve the hydrology, water quality, and aquatic habitats within the watershed, the district shall, no later than January 1, 2012, plan, design, and construct the initial phase of the Watershed Construction Project. In doing so, the district shall:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and designate the facilities to be constructed to achieve stated goals and objectives of the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Protection Plan.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct scientific studies that are necessary to support the design of the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Construction Project facilities.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the size and location of all such facilities.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a construction schedule for all such facilities, including the sequencing and specific timeframe for construction of each facility.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a schedule for the acquisition of lands or sufficient interests necessary to achieve the construction schedule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a schedule of costs and benefits associated with each construction project and identify funding sources.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure timely implementation, coordinate the design, scheduling, and sequencing of project facilities with the coordinating agencies, Lee County, other affected counties and municipalities, and other affected parties.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Caloosahatchee River Watershed Pollutant Control Program.<EmDash />The Caloosahatchee River Watershed Pollutant Control Program is designed to be a multifaceted approach to reducing pollutant loads by improving the management of pollutant sources within the Caloosahatchee River watershed through implementation of regulations and best management practices, development and implementation of improved best management practices, improvement and restoration of the hydrologic function of natural and managed systems, and utilization of alternative technologies for pollutant reduction, such as cost-effective biologically based, hybrid wetland/chemical and other innovative nutrient control technologies. The coordinating agencies shall facilitate the utilization of federal programs that offer opportunities for water quality treatment, including preservation, restoration, or creation of wetlands on agricultural lands.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpoint source best management practices consistent with paragraph (3)(c), designed to achieve the objectives of the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Protection Program, shall be implemented on an expedited basis. The coordinating agencies may develop an intergovernmental agreement with local governments to implement the nonagricultural, nonpoint-source best management practices within their respective geographic boundaries.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not preclude the department or the district from requiring compliance with water quality standards, adopted total maximum daily loads, or current best management practices requirements set forth in any applicable regulatory program authorized by law for the purpose of protecting water quality. This subsection applies only to the extent that it does not conflict with any rules adopted by the department or district which are necessary to maintain a federally delegated or approved program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects that make use of private lands, or lands held in trust for Indian tribes, to reduce pollutant loadings or concentrations within a basin, or that reduce the volume of harmful discharges by one or more of the following methods: restoring the natural hydrology of the basin, restoring wildlife habitat or impacted wetlands, reducing peak flows after storm events, or increasing aquifer recharge, are eligible for grants available under this section from the coordinating agencies.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Caloosahatchee River Watershed Pollutant Control Program shall require assessment of current water management practices within the watershed and shall require development of recommendations for structural, nonstructural, and operational improvements. Such recommendations shall consider and balance water supply, flood control, estuarine salinity, aquatic habitat, and water quality considerations.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After December 31, 2007, the department may not authorize the disposal of domestic wastewater residuals within the Caloosahatchee River watershed unless the applicant can affirmatively demonstrate that the nutrients in the residuals will not add to nutrient loadings in the watershed. This demonstration shall be based on achieving a net balance between nutrient imports relative to exports on the permitted application site. Exports shall include only nutrients removed from the watershed through products generated on the permitted application site. This prohibition does not apply to Class AA residuals that are marketed and distributed as fertilizer products in accordance with department rule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall require all entities disposing of septage within the Caloosahatchee River watershed to develop and submit to that agency an agricultural use plan that limits applications based upon nutrient loading. By July 1, 2008, nutrient concentrations originating from these application sites may not exceed the limits established in the district’s WOD program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall initiate rulemaking requiring entities within the Caloosahatchee River watershed which land-apply animal manure to develop a resource management system level conservation plan, according to United States Department of Agriculture criteria, which limit such application. Such rules may include criteria and thresholds for the requirement to develop a conservation or nutrient management plan, requirements for plan approval, and recordkeeping requirements.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Caloosahatchee River Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program.<EmDash />The district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies and local governments, shall establish a Caloosahatchee River Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program that builds upon the district’s existing research program and that is sufficient to carry out, comply with, or assess the plans, programs, and other responsibilities created by this subsection. The program shall also conduct an assessment of the water volumes and timing from the Lake Okeechobee and Caloosahatchee River watersheds and their relative contributions to the timing and volume of water delivered to the estuary.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">St. Lucie River Watershed Protection Plan.</Font><EmDash />No later than January 1, 2009, the district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies, Martin County, and affected counties and municipalities shall complete a plan in accordance with this subsection. The plan shall identify the geographic extent of the watershed, be coordinated as needed with the plans developed pursuant to paragraph (3)(a) and paragraph (a) of this subsection, and contain an implementation schedule for pollutant load reductions consistent with any adopted total maximum daily loads and compliance with applicable state water quality standards. The plan shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Lucie River Watershed Construction Project.<EmDash />To improve the hydrology, water quality, and aquatic habitats within the watershed, the district shall, no later than January 1, 2012, plan, design, and construct the initial phase of the Watershed Construction Project. In doing so, the district shall:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and designate the facilities to be constructed to achieve stated goals and objectives of the St. Lucie River Watershed Protection Plan.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the size and location of all such facilities.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a construction schedule for all such facilities, including the sequencing and specific timeframe for construction of each facility.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a schedule for the acquisition of lands or sufficient interests necessary to achieve the construction schedule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a schedule of costs and benefits associated with each construction project and identify funding sources.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure timely implementation, coordinate the design, scheduling, and sequencing of project facilities with the coordinating agencies, Martin County, St. Lucie County, other interested parties, and other affected local governments.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Lucie River Watershed Pollutant Control Program.<EmDash />The St. Lucie River Watershed Pollutant Control Program is designed to be a multifaceted approach to reducing pollutant loads by improving the management of pollutant sources within the St. Lucie River watershed through implementation of regulations and best management practices, development and implementation of improved best management practices, improvement and restoration of the hydrologic function of natural and managed systems, and utilization of alternative technologies for pollutant reduction, such as cost-effective biologically based, hybrid wetland/chemical and other innovative nutrient control technologies. The coordinating agencies shall facilitate the utilization of federal programs that offer opportunities for water quality treatment, including preservation, restoration, or creation of wetlands on agricultural lands.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpoint source best management practices consistent with paragraph (3)(c), designed to achieve the objectives of the St. Lucie River Watershed Protection Program, shall be implemented on an expedited basis. The coordinating agencies may develop an intergovernmental agreement with local governments to implement the nonagricultural nonpoint source best management practices within their respective geographic boundaries.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not preclude the department or the district from requiring compliance with water quality standards, adopted total maximum daily loads, or current best management practices requirements set forth in any applicable regulatory program authorized by law for the purpose of protecting water quality. This subsection applies only to the extent that it does not conflict with any rules adopted by the department or district which are necessary to maintain a federally delegated or approved program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects that make use of private lands, or lands held in trust for Indian tribes, to reduce pollutant loadings or concentrations within a basin, or that reduce the volume of harmful discharges by one or more of the following methods: restoring the natural hydrology of the basin, restoring wildlife habitat or impacted wetlands, reducing peak flows after storm events, or increasing aquifer recharge, are eligible for grants available under this section from the coordinating agencies.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The St. Lucie River Watershed Pollutant Control Program shall require assessment of current water management practices within the watershed and shall require development of recommendations for structural, nonstructural, and operational improvements. Such recommendations shall consider and balance water supply, flood control, estuarine salinity, aquatic habitat, and water quality considerations.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After December 31, 2007, the department may not authorize the disposal of domestic wastewater residuals within the St. Lucie River watershed unless the applicant can affirmatively demonstrate that the nutrients in the residuals will not add to nutrient loadings in the watershed. This demonstration shall be based on achieving a net balance between nutrient imports relative to exports on the permitted application site. Exports shall include only nutrients removed from the St. Lucie River watershed through products generated on the permitted application site. This prohibition does not apply to Class AA residuals that are marketed and distributed as fertilizer products in accordance with department rule.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall require all entities disposing of septage within the St. Lucie River watershed to develop and submit to that agency an agricultural use plan that limits applications based upon nutrient loading. By July 1, 2008, nutrient concentrations originating from these application sites may not exceed the limits established in the district’s WOD program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall initiate rulemaking requiring entities within the St. Lucie River watershed which land-apply animal manure to develop a resource management system level conservation plan, according to United States Department of Agriculture criteria, which limit such application. Such rules may include criteria and thresholds for the requirement to develop a conservation or nutrient management plan, requirements for plan approval, and recordkeeping requirements.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Lucie River Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program.<EmDash />The district, in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies and local governments, shall establish a St. Lucie River Watershed Research and Water Quality Monitoring Program that builds upon the district’s existing research program and that is sufficient to carry out, comply with, or assess the plans, programs, and other responsibilities created by this subsection. The program shall also conduct an assessment of the water volumes and timing from the Lake Okeechobee and St. Lucie River watersheds and their relative contributions to the timing and volume of water delivered to the estuary.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">River Watershed Protection Plan implementation.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies shall be jointly responsible for implementing the River Watershed Protection Plans, consistent with the statutory authority and responsibility of each agency. Annual funding priorities shall be jointly established, and the highest priority shall be assigned to programs and projects that have the greatest potential for achieving the goals and objectives of the plans. In determining funding priorities, the coordinating agencies shall also consider the need for regulatory compliance, the extent to which the program or project is ready to proceed, and the availability of federal or local government matching funds. Federal and other nonstate funding shall be maximized to the greatest extent practicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Evaluation.</Font><EmDash />By March 1, 2012, and every 3 years thereafter, the district in cooperation with the coordinating agencies, shall conduct an evaluation of any pollutant load reduction goals, as well as any other specific objectives and goals, as stated in the River Watershed Protection Plans. Additionally, the district shall identify modifications to facilities of the River Watershed Construction Projects, as appropriate, or any other elements of the River Watershed Protection Plans. The evaluation shall be included in the annual progress report submitted pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Priorities and implementation schedules.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies are authorized and directed to establish priorities and implementation schedules for the achievement of total maximum daily loads, the requirements of s. 403.067, and compliance with applicable water quality standards within the waters and watersheds subject to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Legislative ratification.</Font><EmDash />The coordinating agencies shall submit the River Watershed Protection Plans developed pursuant to paragraphs (a) and (b) to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives prior to the 2009 legislative session for review. If the Legislature takes no action on the plan during the 2009 legislative session, the plan is deemed approved and may be implemented.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADOPTION AND IMPLEMENTATION OF TOTAL MAXIMUM DAILY LOADS AND DEVELOPMENT OF BASIN MANAGEMENT ACTION PLANS.<EmDash />The department is directed to expedite development and adoption of total maximum daily loads for the Caloosahatchee River and estuary. The department is further directed to, no later than December 31, 2008, propose for final agency action total maximum daily loads for nutrients in the tidal portions of the Caloosahatchee River and estuary. The department shall initiate development of basin management action plans as provided in s. 403.067(7)(a) as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basin management action plans shall be developed as soon as practicable as determined necessary by the department to achieve the total maximum daily loads established for the Lake Okeechobee watershed and the estuaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Phase II technical plan development pursuant to paragraph (3)(b), and the River Watershed Protection Plans developed pursuant to paragraphs (4)(a) and (b), shall provide the basis for basin management action plans developed by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As determined necessary by the department in order to achieve the total maximum daily loads, additional or modified projects or programs that complement those in the legislatively ratified plans may be included during the development of the basin management action plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of basin management action plans that implement the provisions of the legislatively ratified plans shall be initiated by the department no later than September 30 of the year in which the applicable plan is ratified. Where a total maximum daily load has not been established at the time of plan ratification, development of basin management action plans shall be initiated no later than 90 days following adoption of the applicable total maximum daily load.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL PROGRESS REPORT.<EmDash />Each March 1 the district shall report on implementation of this section as part of the consolidated annual report required in s. 373.036(7). The annual report shall include a summary of the conditions of the hydrology, water quality, and aquatic habitat in the northern Everglades based on the results of the Research and Water Quality Monitoring Programs, the status of the Lake Okeechobee Watershed Construction Project, the status of the Caloosahatchee River Watershed Construction Project, and the status of the St. Lucie River Watershed Construction Project. In addition, the report shall contain an annual accounting of the expenditure of funds from the Save Our Everglades Trust Fund. At a minimum, the annual report shall provide detail by program and plan, including specific information concerning the amount and use of funds from federal, state, or local government sources. In detailing the use of these funds, the district shall indicate those designated to meet requirements for matching funds. The district shall prepare the report in cooperation with the other coordinating agencies and affected local governments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LAKE OKEECHOBEE PROTECTION PERMITS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the Lake Okeechobee Protection Program will benefit Lake Okeechobee and downstream receiving waters and is consistent with the public interest. The Lake Okeechobee Construction Project and structures discharging into or from Lake Okeechobee shall be constructed, operated, and maintained in accordance with this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits obtained pursuant to this section are in lieu of all other permits under this chapter or chapter 403, except those issued under s. 403.0885, if applicable. No additional permits are required for the Lake Okeechobee Construction Project or structures discharging into or from Lake Okeechobee, if permitted under this section. Construction activities related to implementation of the Lake Okeechobee Construction Project may be initiated prior to final agency action, or notice of intended agency action, on any permit from the department under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days of completion of the diversion plans set forth in Department Consent Orders 91-0694, 91-0707, 91-0706, 91-0705, and RT50-205564, owners or operators of existing structures which discharge into or from Lake Okeechobee that are subject to the provisions of s. 373.4592(4)(a) shall apply for a permit from the department to operate and maintain such structures. By September 1, 2000, owners or operators of all other existing structures which discharge into or from Lake Okeechobee shall apply for a permit from the department to operate and maintain such structures. The department shall issue one or more such permits for a term of 5 years upon the demonstration of reasonable assurance that schedules and strategies to achieve and maintain compliance with water quality standards have been provided for, to the maximum extent practicable, and that operation of the structures otherwise complies with provisions of ss. 373.413 and 373.416.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits issued under this paragraph shall also contain reasonable conditions to ensure that discharges of waters through structures:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are adequately and accurately monitored;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will not degrade existing Lake Okeechobee water quality and will result in an overall reduction of phosphorus input into Lake Okeechobee, as set forth in the district’s Technical Publication 81-2 and the total maximum daily load established in accordance with s. 403.067, to the maximum extent practicable; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do not pose a serious danger to public health, safety, or welfare.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this paragraph, owners and operators of existing structures which are subject to the provisions of s. 373.4592(4)(a) and which discharge into or from Lake Okeechobee shall be deemed in compliance with the term “maximum extent practicable” if they are in full compliance with the conditions of permits under chapters 40E-61 and 40E-63, Florida Administrative Code.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1, 2004, the district shall submit to the department a permit modification to the Lake Okeechobee structure permits to incorporate proposed changes necessary to ensure that discharges through the structures covered by this permit achieve state water quality standards, including the total maximum daily load established in accordance with s. 403.067. These changes shall be designed to achieve such compliance with state water quality standards no later than January 1, 2015.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require permits for Lake Okeechobee Construction Project facilities. However, projects identified in sub-subparagraph (3)(b)1.b. that qualify as exempt pursuant to s. 373.406 shall not need permits under this section. Such permits shall be issued for a term of 5 years upon the demonstration of reasonable assurances that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Lake Okeechobee Construction Project facility, based upon the conceptual design documents and any subsequent detailed design documents developed by the district, will achieve the design objectives for phosphorus required in paragraph (3)(b);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For water quality standards other than phosphorus, the quality of water discharged from the facility is of equal or better quality than the inflows;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discharges from the facility do not pose a serious danger to public health, safety, or welfare; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any impacts on wetlands or state-listed species resulting from implementation of that facility of the Lake Okeechobee Construction Project are minimized and mitigated, as appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 60 days prior to the expiration of any permit issued under this section, the permittee may apply for a renewal thereof for a period of 5 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits issued under this section may include any standard conditions provided by department rule which are appropriate and consistent with this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits issued pursuant to this section may be modified, as appropriate, upon review and approval by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESTRICTIONS ON WATER DIVERSIONS.<EmDash />The South Florida Water Management District shall not divert waters to the St. Lucie River, the Indian River estuary, the Caloosahatchee River or its estuary, or the Everglades National Park, in such a way that the state water quality standards are violated, that the nutrients in such diverted waters adversely affect indigenous vegetation communities or wildlife, or that fresh waters diverted to the St. Lucie River or the Caloosahatchee or Indian River estuaries adversely affect the estuarine vegetation or wildlife, unless the receiving waters will biologically benefit by the diversion. However, diversion is permitted when an emergency is declared by the water management district, if the Secretary of Environmental Protection concurs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRESERVATION OF PROVISIONS RELATING TO THE EVERGLADES.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify any provision of s. 373.4592.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHTS OF SEMINOLE TRIBE OF FLORIDA.<EmDash />Nothing in this section is intended to diminish or alter the governmental authority and powers of the Seminole Tribe of Florida, or diminish or alter the rights of that tribe, including, but not limited to, rights under the water rights compact among the Seminole Tribe of Florida, the state, and the South Florida Water Management District as enacted by Pub. L. No. 100-228, 101 Stat. 1556, and chapter 87-292, Laws of Florida, and codified in s. 285.165, and rights under any other agreement between the Seminole Tribe of Florida and the state or its agencies. No land of the Seminole Tribe of Florida shall be used for water storage or stormwater treatment without the consent of the tribe.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RELATIONSHIP TO STATE WATER QUALITY STANDARDS.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify any existing state water quality standard or to modify the provisions of s. 403.067(6) and (7)(a).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The governing board of the district is authorized to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRESERVATION OF AUTHORITY.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the authority otherwise granted to agencies pursuant to this chapter and chapter 403, and provisions of this section shall be deemed supplemental to the authority granted to agencies pursuant to this chapter and chapter 403.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 87-97; s. 274, ch. 94-356; s. 1011, ch. 95-148; s. 189, ch. 99-245; s. 1, ch. 2000-130; s. 6, ch. 2001-172; s. 1, ch. 2001-193; s. 3, ch. 2002-165; s. 42, ch. 2002-296; s. 1, ch. 2005-29; s. 14, ch. 2005-36; s. 7, ch. 2005-166; s. 14, ch. 2005-291; s. 4, ch. 2007-191; s. 3, ch. 2007-253; s. 87, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>