<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit application fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a water management district governing board, the department, or a local government implements a regulatory system under this chapter or one which has been delegated pursuant to chapter 403, it may establish a schedule of fees for filing applications for the required permits. Such fees shall not exceed the cost to the district, the department, or the local government for processing, monitoring, and inspecting for compliance with the permit.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall initiate rulemaking no later than December 1, 2008, to increase each application fee authorized under part IV of this chapter and adopted by rule to ensure that such fees reflect, at a minimum, any upward adjustment in the Consumer Price Index compiled by the United States Department of Labor, or similar inflation indicator, since the original fee was established or most recently revised. The department shall establish by rule the inflation index to be used for this purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall charge a fee of at least $250 for a noticed general permit or individual permit as established in department rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.60(2), the fee for verification that an activity is exempt from regulation under s. 403.813 or part IV of this chapter shall be at least $100 or as otherwise established by department rule, but not to exceed $500.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall charge a fee of at least $100 and not to exceed $500 for conducting informal wetland boundary determinations as a public service to applicants or potential applicants for permits under part IV of this chapter. An informal wetland boundary determination is not an application for a permit, is not subject to the permit review timeframes established in this chapter or chapter 120, and does not constitute final agency action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review the fees authorized under part IV of this chapter at least once every 5 years and shall adjust the fees upward, as necessary, to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index or similar inflation indicator. In the event of deflation, the department shall consult with the Executive Office of the Governor and the Legislature to determine whether downward fee adjustments are appropriate based on the current budget and appropriation considerations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received under the provisions of this section shall be allocated for the use of the water management district, the department, or the local government, whichever processed the permit, and shall be in addition to moneys otherwise appropriated in any general appropriations act. All moneys received by the department under the provisions of this section shall be deposited in the Florida Permit Fee Trust Fund established by s. 403.0871 and shall be used by the department as provided therein. Moneys received by a water management district or the department under the provisions of this section shall be in addition to moneys otherwise appropriated in any general appropriations act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of any person to pay the fees established hereunder constitutes grounds for revocation or denial of the permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2008, the minimum fee amounts shall be the minimum fees prescribed in this section, and such fee amounts shall remain in effect until the effective date of fees adopted by rule by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, part I, ch. 72-299; s. 7, ch. 76-243; s. 8, ch. 84-341; s. 27, ch. 87-225; s. 10, ch. 89-279; s. 25, ch. 93-213; s. 18, ch. 2008-150.</History></Section>