<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.217" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Superseded laws and regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to provide a means whereby reasonable programs for the issuance of permits authorizing the consumptive use of particular quantities of water may be authorized by the Department of Environmental Protection, subject to judicial review and also subject to review by the Governor and Cabinet, sitting as the Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission as provided in s. 373.114.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the further intent of the Legislature that Part II of the Florida Water Resources Act of 1972, as amended, as set forth in ss. 373.203-373.249, shall provide the exclusive authority for requiring permits for the consumptive use of water and for authorizing transportation thereof pursuant to s. 373.223(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any provision of Part II of the Florida Water Resources Act of 1972, as amended, as set forth in ss. 373.203-373.249, is in conflict with any other provision, limitation, or restriction which is now in effect under any law or ordinance of this state or any political subdivision or municipality, or any rule or regulation promulgated thereunder, Part II shall govern and control, and such other law or ordinance or rule or regulation promulgated thereunder shall be deemed superseded for the purpose of regulating the consumptive use of water. However, this section shall not be construed to supersede the provisions of the Florida Electrical Power Plant Siting Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other than as provided in subsection (3) of this section, Part II of the Florida Water Resources Act of 1972, as amended, preempts the regulation of the consumptive use of water as defined in this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 76-243; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 265, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>