<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0373.539" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Imposition of taxes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year the governing board of the district shall certify to the property appraiser of the county in which the property is situate, timely for the preparation of the tax roll, the tax rate to be applied in determining the amount of the district’s annual tax, and the property appraiser shall extend on his or her county tax roll the amount of such tax, determined at the rate certified to the property appraiser by the governing board, and shall certify the same to the tax collector at the same time and in like manner as for county taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection of district taxes, the issuance of tax sale certificates for nonpayment thereof, the redemption or sale of said certificates, the vesting of title by tax forfeiture, and the sale of the land and other real estate so forfeited shall be at the same time, in conjunction with, and by like procedure and of like effect as is provided by law with respect to county taxes, nor may either the county or the district taxes be paid or redemption effected without the payment or redemption of both. The title to district tax forfeited land shall vest in the county on behalf of said district along with that of the county for county tax forfeited land, said district tax forfeited land to be held, sold, or otherwise disposed of by said county for the benefit of said district. The proceeds therefrom, after deducting costs, shall be paid to the district in amounts proportionate to the respective tax liens thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district tax liens shall be of equal dignity with those of the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax officers of the county are hereby authorized and directed to perform the duties devolving upon them under this chapter, and to receive compensation therefor at such rates or charges as are provided by law with respect to similar services or charges in other cases.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 25209, 1949; s. 25, ch. 73-190; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 608, ch. 95-148.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 378.29.</Text></Note></Section>