<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0773.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Helmet requirements; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “equine” has the same meaning as provided in s. 773.01.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is younger than 16 years of age must wear a helmet that meets the current applicable standards of the American Society of Testing and Materials for protective headgear used in horseback riding and that is properly fitted and fastened securely upon the child’s head by a strap when the child is riding an equine upon:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public roadway or right-of-way;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public equestrian trail, public recreational trail, public park or preserve, or public school site; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other publicly owned or controlled property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trainer, instructor, supervisor, or other person may not knowingly rent or lease an equine to be ridden by a child younger than 16 years of age unless the child possesses a helmet meeting the requirements of this section or the trainer, instructor, supervisor, or other person renting or leasing the equine supplies the child with a helmet meeting the standards of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent or guardian of a child younger than 16 years of age may not authorize or knowingly permit the child to violate this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates subsection (3) or subsection (4) commits a noncriminal violation, punishable as provided in s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a child younger than 16 years of age who is riding an equine when the child is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing for, riding to or from, or competing or performing in shows or events, including, but not limited to, rodeos and parades, where helmets are not historically a part of the show or event;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Riding on privately owned land even if the land is occasionally separated by a public road or right-of-way that must be crossed; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaged in an agricultural practice or pursuit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2009-105.</History></Section>