<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0427.802" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assistive technology devices” means manual wheelchairs, motorized wheelchairs, motorized scooters, voice-synthesized computer modules, optical scanners, talking software, braille printers, environmental control devices for use by a person with quadriplegia, motor vehicle adaptive transportation aids, devices that enable persons with severe speech disabilities to in effect speak, personal transfer systems, and specialty beds, including a demonstrator, that a consumer purchases or accepts transfer of in this state for use by a person with a disability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person with a disability” means any person who has one or more permanent physical or mental limitations that restrict his or her ability to perform the normal activities of daily living and impede his or her capacity to live independently.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assistive technology device dealer” means a person who is engaged in the business of selling assistive technology devices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assistive technology device lessor” means a person who leases an assistive technology device to a consumer, or holds the lessor’s rights, under a written lease.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Collateral costs” means expenses incurred by a consumer in connection with the repair of a nonconformity, including the costs of obtaining an alternative assistive technology device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer” means any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser of an assistive technology device, if the assistive technology device was purchased from an assistive technology device dealer or manufacturer for purposes other than resale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person to whom the assistive technology device is transferred for purposes other than resale, if the transfer occurs before the expiration of an express warranty applicable to the assistive technology device.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who may enforce the warranty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who leases an assistive technology device from an assistive technology device lessor under a written lease.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Demonstrator” means an assistive technology device used primarily for the purpose of demonstration to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Early termination cost” means any expense or obligation that an assistive technology device lessor incurs as a result of both the termination of a written lease before the termination date set forth in that lease and the return of an assistive technology device to a manufacturer pursuant to this section. The term includes a penalty for prepayment under a financial arrangement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Early termination saving” means any expense or obligation that an assistive technology device lessor avoids as a result of both the termination of a written lease before the termination date set forth in the lease and the return of an assistive technology device to a manufacturer pursuant to this section. The term includes an interest charge that the assistive technology device lessor would have paid to finance the assistive technology device or, if the assistive technology device lessor does not finance the assistive technology device, the difference between the total amount for which the lease obligates the consumer during the period of the lease term remaining after the early termination and the present value of that amount at the date of the early termination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer” means a business entity that manufactures or produces assistive technology devices for sale and agents of that business entity, including an importer, a distributor, a factory branch, a distributor branch, and any warrantors of the manufacturer’s assistive technology device, but not including an assistive technology device dealer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonconformity” means a condition or defect of an assistive technology device which substantially impairs the use, value, or safety of the device and which is covered by an express warranty applicable to the assistive technology device, but does not include a condition or defect that is the result of abuse, neglect, excessive wear, or unauthorized modification or alteration of the assistive technology device by a consumer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reasonable attempt to repair” means, within the terms of an express warranty applicable to a new assistive technology device:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of three efforts by the manufacturer, the assistive technology device lessor, or any of the manufacturer’s authorized assistive technology device dealers to repair a nonconformity that is subject to repair under the warranty; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The passage of at least 30 cumulative days during which the assistive technology device is out of service because of a nonconformity that is covered by the warranty.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-47; s. 17, ch. 99-307; s. 3, ch. 2001-214.</History></Section>