<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0427.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purchasing agencies; duties and responsibilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each purchasing agency, in carrying out the policies and procedures of the commission, shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the coordinated transportation system for provision of services to its clients, unless each department or purchasing agency meets the criteria outlined in rule or statute to use an alternative provider.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the rates established in the service plan or negotiated statewide contract, unless the purchasing agency has completed the procedure for using an alternative provider and demonstrated that a proposed alternative provider can provide a more cost-effective transportation service of comparable quality and standards or unless the agency has satisfied the requirements of subsection (3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not procure transportation disadvantaged services without initially negotiating with the commission, as provided in s. 287.057(3)(f)12., or unless otherwise authorized by statute. If the purchasing agency, after consultation with the commission, determines that it cannot reach mutually acceptable contract terms with the commission, the purchasing agency may contract for the same transportation services provided in a more cost-effective manner and of comparable or higher quality and standards. The Medicaid agency shall implement this subsection in a manner consistent with s. 409.908(18) and as otherwise limited or directed by the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify in the legislative budget request provided to the Governor each year for the General Appropriations Act the specific amount of money the purchasing agency will allocate to provide transportation disadvantaged services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the commission, by September 15 of each year, an accounting of all funds spent as well as how many trips were purchased with agency funds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist communities in developing coordinated transportation systems designed to serve the transportation disadvantaged. However, a purchasing agency may not serve as the community transportation coordinator in any designated service area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that its rules, procedures, guidelines, and directives are conducive to the coordination of transportation funds and services for the transportation disadvantaged.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance, as needed, to community transportation coordinators or transportation operators or participating agencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 14, ch. 89-376; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 66, ch. 94-237; s. 4, ch. 95-394; s. 10, ch. 96-417; s. 26, ch. 2000-266; s. 5, ch. 2008-203; s. 34, ch. 2010-151.</History>
</Section>