<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0427.0155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community transportation coordinators; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community transportation coordinators shall have the following powers and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute uniform contracts for service using a standard contract, which includes performance standards for operators.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect annual operating data for submittal to the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review all transportation operator contracts annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve and coordinate the utilization of school bus and public transportation services in accordance with the transportation disadvantaged service plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with a functioning coordinating board, review all applications for local government, federal, and state transportation disadvantaged funds, and develop cost-effective coordination strategies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with, and approved by, the coordinating board, develop, negotiate, implement, and monitor a memorandum of agreement including a service plan, for submittal to the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with the coordinating board and pursuant to criteria developed by the Commission for the Transportation Disadvantaged, establish eligibility guidelines and priorities with regard to the recipients of nonsponsored transportation disadvantaged services that are purchased with Transportation Disadvantaged Trust Fund moneys.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have full responsibility for the delivery of transportation services for the transportation disadvantaged as outlined in s. 427.015(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work cooperatively with regional workforce boards established in chapter 445 to provide assistance in the development of innovative transportation services for participants in the welfare transition program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 14, ch. 89-376; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 85, ch. 92-152; s. 68, ch. 94-237; s. 18, ch. 98-57; s. 103, ch. 2000-165; s. 7, ch. 2008-203.</History></Section>