<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0427.708" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain public safety and health care providers required to purchase and operate TDD’s.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The central communications office of each county sheriff’s department shall purchase and continually operate at least one TDD.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The central communications office of each police department and each firefighting agency in a municipality with a population of 25,000 to 250,000 shall purchase and continually operate at least one TDD.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The central communications office of each police department and each firefighting agency in a municipality with a population exceeding 250,000 persons shall purchase and continually operate at least two TDD’s.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each hospital as defined in s. 395.002 shall purchase and continually operate at least one TDD.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each emergency telephone number “911” system, as provided in s. 365.171, and each agency receiving automatically routed calls through such a system shall purchase and continually operate at least one TDD.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public safety office, health care provider, and emergency telephone number “911” system required to obtain a TDD pursuant to this section shall continuously operate and staff such equipment on a 24-hour basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each office or organization required to purchase TDD’s pursuant to this section shall buy such equipment which meets the same specifications as those selected by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each office or organization required to operate TDD’s pursuant to this section shall utilize equipment in accordance with standards established by the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 91-111; s. 80, ch. 92-289; s. 46, ch. 94-324; s. 19, ch. 95-327.</History></Section>