<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0427.016" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Expenditure of local government, state, and federal funds for the transportation disadvantaged.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All transportation disadvantaged funds expended within the state shall be expended to purchase transportation services from community transportation coordinators or public, private, or private nonprofit transportation operators within the coordinated transportation system, except when the rates charged by proposed alternate operators are proven, pursuant to rules generated by the Commission for the Transportation Disadvantaged, to be more cost-effective and are not a risk to the public health, safety, or welfare. However, in areas where transportation suited to the unique needs of a transportation disadvantaged person cannot be purchased through the coordinated system, or where the agency has met the rule criteria for using an alternative provider, the service may be contracted for directly by the appropriate agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not preclude a purchasing agency from establishing maximum fee schedules, individualized reimbursement policies by provider type, negotiated fees, or any other mechanism, including contracting after initial negotiation with the commission, which the agency considers more cost-effective and of comparable or higher quality and standards than those of the commission for the purchase of services on behalf of its clients if it has fulfilled the requirements of s. 427.0135(3) or the procedure for using an alternative provider. State and local agencies shall not contract for any transportation disadvantaged services, including Medicaid reimbursable transportation services, with any community transportation coordinator or transportation operator that has been determined by the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Department of Legal Affairs Medicaid Fraud Control Unit, or any state or federal agency to have engaged in any abusive or fraudulent billing activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year, each agency, whether or not it is an ex officio, nonvoting adviser to the Commission for the Transportation Disadvantaged, shall identify in the legislative budget request provided to the Governor for the General Appropriations Act the specific amount of any money the agency will allocate for the provision of transportation disadvantaged services. Additionally, each state agency shall, by September 15 of each year, provide the commission with an accounting of the actual amount of funds expended and the total number of trips purchased.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each metropolitan planning organization or designated official planning agency shall annually compile a report accounting for all local government and direct federal funds for transportation for the disadvantaged expended in its jurisdiction and forward this report by September 15 to the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 9, ch. 79-180; ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-56; ss. 10, 14, ch. 89-376; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 88, ch. 92-152; s. 70, ch. 94-237; s. 5, ch. 95-394; s. 11, ch. 2008-203.</History></Section>