<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0427.0159" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transportation Disadvantaged Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established in the State Treasury the Transportation Disadvantaged Trust Fund to be administered by the Commission for the Transportation Disadvantaged. All fees collected for the transportation disadvantaged program under s. 320.03(9) shall be deposited in the trust fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds deposited in the trust fund shall be appropriated by the Legislature to the commission and shall be used to carry out the responsibilities of the commission and to fund the administrative expenses of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds deposited in the trust fund may be used by the commission to subsidize a portion of a transportation disadvantaged person’s transportation costs which is not sponsored by an agency, only if a cash or in-kind match is required. Funds for nonsponsored transportation disadvantaged services shall be distributed based upon the need of the recipient and according to criteria developed by the Commission for the Transportation Disadvantaged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchasing agency may deposit funds into the Transportation Disadvantaged Trust Fund for the commission to implement, manage, and administer the purchasing agency’s transportation disadvantaged funds, as defined in s. 427.011(10).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 14, ch. 89-376; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 87, ch. 92-152; s. 69, ch. 94-237; s. 21, ch. 2000-257; s. 61, ch. 2001-62; s. 10, ch. 2008-203.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 22, ch. 2000-257, provides that “[n]otwithstanding any other law to the contrary the requirements of sections 206.46(3) and 206.606(2), Florida Statutes, shall not apply to any funding, programs, or other provisions contained in this act.”</Text></Note></Section>