<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0460.4062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chiropractic medicine faculty certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a chiropractic medicine faculty certificate without examination to an individual who remits a nonrefundable application fee, not to exceed $100 as determined by rule of the board, and who demonstrates to the board that he or she meets the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an accredited school or college of chiropractic accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid current license to practice chiropractic medicine in another jurisdiction in the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 21 years of age and of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed any act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for discipline under this chapter or chapter 456.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performs research or has been offered and has accepted a full-time or part-time faculty appointment to teach in a program of chiropractic medicine at a publicly funded state university or college or at a college of chiropractic located in the state and accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides a certification from the dean of the appointing college acknowledging the appointment.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate shall authorize the holder to practice only in conjunction with his or her faculty position at a university or college and its affiliated clinics that are registered with the board as sites at which holders of chiropractic medicine faculty certificates will be practicing. Except as provided in subsection (4), such certificate shall automatically expire upon termination of the holder’s relationship with the university or college or after a period of 2 years, whichever occurs first.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder of a faculty certificate may engage in the practice of chiropractic medicine as permitted by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (2), a chiropractic medicine faculty certificate is renewable every 2 years by a holder who applies to the board on a form prescribed by the board and who continues to satisfy the requirements set forth in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-2; s. 2, ch. 2007-240; s. 1, ch. 2012-171.</History></Section>