<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0460.4165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certified chiropractic physician’s assistants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />The purpose of this section is to encourage the more effective utilization of the skills of chiropractic physicians by enabling them to delegate health care tasks to qualified assistants when such delegation is consistent with the patient’s health and welfare and to allow for innovative development of programs for the education of physician’s assistants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERFORMANCE BY CERTIFIED CHIROPRACTIC PHYSICIAN’S ASSISTANT.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant may perform chiropractic services in the specialty area or areas for which the certified chiropractic physician’s assistant is trained or experienced when such services are rendered under the supervision of a licensed chiropractic physician or group of chiropractic physicians certified by the board. Any certified chiropractic physician’s assistant certified under this section to perform services may perform those services only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the office of the chiropractic physician to whom the certified chiropractic physician’s assistant has been assigned, in which office such physician maintains her or his primary practice;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under indirect supervision if the indirect supervision occurs at the supervising chiropractic physician’s address of record required by s. 456.035, other than at a clinic licensed under part X of chapter 400, of the chiropractic physician to whom she or he is assigned as defined by rule of the board;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a hospital in which the chiropractic physician to whom she or he is assigned is a member of the staff; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On calls outside the office of the chiropractic physician to whom she or he is assigned, on the direct order of the chiropractic physician to whom she or he is assigned.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIRD-PARTY PAYOR.<EmDash />This chapter does not prevent third-party payors from reimbursing employers of chiropractic physician’s assistants for covered services rendered by certified chiropractic physician’s assistants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERFORMANCE BY TRAINEES.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a trainee may perform chiropractic services when such services are rendered within the scope of an approved program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM APPROVAL.<EmDash />The department shall issue certificates of approval for programs for the education and training of certified chiropractic physician’s assistants which meet board standards. Any basic program curriculum certified by the board must consist of a curriculum of at least 200 didactic classroom hours.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In developing criteria for program approval, the board shall give consideration to, and encourage, the use of equivalency and proficiency testing and other mechanisms whereby full credit is given to trainees for past education and experience in health fields.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall create groups of specialty classifications of training for certified chiropractic physician’s assistants. These classifications must reflect the training and experience of the certified chiropractic physician’s assistant. The certified chiropractic physician’s assistant may receive training in one or more such classifications, which shall be shown on the certificate issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt and publish standards to ensure that such programs operate in a manner that does not endanger the health and welfare of the patients who receive services within the scope of the program. The board shall review the quality of the curricula, faculties, and facilities of such programs; issue certificates of approval; and take whatever other action is necessary to determine that the purposes of this section are being met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION APPROVAL.<EmDash />Any person desiring to be licensed as a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant must apply to the department. The application shall include a work-arrangement proposal and, as part of the application process, the board shall interview the proposed supervising chiropractic physician, whose license must not be encumbered or restricted, and the applicant to determine whether the work-arrangement proposal provides for responsible supervision, as a condition of certification and approval of any subsequent changes in the supervising physician. The department shall issue a certificate to any person certified by the board as having met the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an approved program or its equivalent and is fully certified by reason of experience and education, as defined by board rule, to perform chiropractic services under the responsible supervision of a licensed chiropractic physician and when the board is satisfied that the public will be adequately protected by the arrangement proposed in the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted an application fee set by the board pursuant to this section. An application for certification made by a chiropractic physician’s assistant must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of completion of a physician’s assistant training program specified in subsection (5).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement of any prior felony conviction in any jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement of any previous revocation or denial of licensure or certification in any state or jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTY.<EmDash />Any person who has not been certified by the board and approved by the department and who represents herself or himself as a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant or who uses any other term in indicating or implying that she or he is a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.084 or by a fine not exceeding $5,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVOCATION OF APPROVAL.<EmDash />The certificate of approval to supervise a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant held by any chiropractic physician or group of chiropractic physicians may be revoked when the board determines that the intent of this section is not being carried out.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fee not to exceed $100 set by the board shall accompany the application by a chiropractic physician for authorization to supervise a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of an application for certification of a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant in a specialty area, the applicant shall be charged an initial certification fee for the first biennium not to exceed $250; and a biennial renewal fee not to exceed $250 shall accompany each application for renewal of the certified chiropractic physician’s assistant certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXISTING PROGRAMS.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed to eliminate or supersede existing laws relating to other paramedical professions or services. It is the intent of this section to supplement all such existing programs relating to the certification and the practice of paramedical professions as may be authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIABILITY.<EmDash />Each chiropractic physician or group of chiropractic physicians utilizing certified chiropractic physician’s assistants shall be liable for any act or omission of any physician’s assistant acting under her or his or its supervision and control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPERVISION OF REGISTERED CHIROPRACTIC ASSISTANT.<EmDash />A certified chiropractic physician’s assistant may directly supervise a registered chiropractic assistant and other persons who are not licensed as chiropractic physicians who are employed or supervised by the chiropractic physician to whom the certified chiropractic physician’s assistant is assigned.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CERTIFIED CHIROPRACTIC ASSISTANT CERTIFICATION RENEWAL.<EmDash />The certification must be renewed biennially.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each renewal must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A renewal fee as set by the board pursuant to this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement of no felony convictions in the previous 2 years in any jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certified chiropractic physician’s assistant shall biennially complete 24 hours of continuing education courses sponsored by chiropractic colleges accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education and approved by the board. The board shall approve those courses that build upon the basic courses required for the practice of chiropractic medicine, and the board may also approve courses in adjunctive modalities. The board may make exception from the requirements of this section in emergency or hardship cases. The board may adopt rules within the requirements of this section which are necessary for its implementation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon employment as a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant, a certified chiropractic physician’s assistant must notify the department in writing within 30 days after such employment or any change of the supervising chiropractic physician. The notification must include the full name, Florida chiropractic medical license number, specialty, and address of the supervising chiropractic physician.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPERVISION OF CERTIFIED CHIROPRACTIC PHYSICIAN’S ASSISTANTS AT LICENSED CLINICS.<EmDash />A certified chiropractic physician’s assistant certified under this section to perform services at a clinic licensed under part X of chapter 400 may perform those services only under direct supervision of the chiropractic physician to whom she or he is assigned.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-393; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 86, ch. 83-218; ss. 14, 17, 18, ch. 86-285; s. 32, ch. 89-162; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 220, ch. 97-103; s. 72, ch. 97-264; s. 108, ch. 99-397; s. 3, ch. 2007-240; s. 5, ch. 2012-171.</History></Section>