<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0460.4166" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registered chiropractic assistants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITION.<EmDash />As used in this section, “registered chiropractic assistant” means a professional, multiskilled person dedicated to assisting in all aspects of chiropractic medical practice under the direct supervision and responsibility of a chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant. A registered chiropractic assistant assists with patient care management, executes administrative and clinical procedures, and often performs managerial and supervisory functions. Competence in the field also requires that a registered chiropractic assistant adhere to ethical and legal standards of professional practice, recognize and respond to emergencies, and demonstrate professional characteristics.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUTIES.<EmDash />Under the direct supervision and responsibility of a licensed chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant, a registered chiropractic assistant may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform clinical procedures, which include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparing patients for the chiropractic physician’s care.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking vital signs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Observing and reporting patients’ signs or symptoms.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer basic first aid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist with patient examinations or treatments other than manipulations or adjustments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operate office equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect routine laboratory specimens as directed by the chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer nutritional supplements as directed by the chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform office procedures required by the chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant under direct supervision of the chiropractic physician or certified chiropractic physician’s assistant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REGISTRATION.<EmDash />Registered chiropractic assistants may be registered by the board for a biennial fee not to exceed $25.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 96-296; s. 279, ch. 98-166; s. 110, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>