<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0460.4061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restricted license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for licensure as a chiropractic physician may apply to the department for a restricted license without undergoing a state or national written or clinical competency examination for licensure if the applicant initially applies not later than October 31, 1994, for the restricted license and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a degree from a college of chiropractic accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education or its predecessor agency and holds a bachelor’s degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has continuously held, since 1979, a license to practice as a chiropractic physician in another state, territory, or national jurisdiction and has actively practiced as a chiropractic physician for the 5 years immediately preceding application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has never been disciplined for an offense that would be a violation under this chapter or chapter 456, imposed by another jurisdiction on the applicant’s license to practice as a chiropractic physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides a completed application on forms approved by the department and pays all application and licensure fees applicable to applicants for licensure by examination, except the examination fee itself.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before granting a restricted license, the board may require an applicant to appear before the board. The board may not require a restricted licensee to practice under the direct supervision of a full licensee. However, the board may impose reasonable restrictions on the applicant’s license to practice as a chiropractic physician in this state. These restrictions include, but are not limited to, requiring a restricted licensee to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to periodic and random departmental audits of the licensee’s patients’ treatment records and review of those records by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequently appear before the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit written reports to the department and board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A restricted licensee shall meet all statutory and regulatory requirements that are not in conflict with this section and that are imposed on a full licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A restricted licensee shall, if a disciplinary action against the licensee is not pending before the department and the licensee is not under discipline by the board, become a full licensee upon expiration of the 2-year restricted license if the licensee pays all applicable fees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 94-173; s. 57, ch. 98-166; s. 116, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>