<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0479.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Erection of noise-attenuation barrier blocking view of sign; procedures; application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a lawfully erected sign that is governed by and conforms to state and federal requirements for land use, size, height, and spacing may increase the height above ground level of such sign at its permitted location if a noise-attenuation barrier is permitted by or erected by any governmental entity in such a way as to screen or block visibility of the sign. Any increase in height permitted under this section may only be the increase in height which is required to achieve the same degree of visibility from the right-of-way which the sign had prior to the construction of the noise-attenuation barrier, notwithstanding the restrictions contained in s. 479.07(9)(b). A sign reconstructed under this section shall comply with the building standards and wind load requirements set forth in the Florida Building Code. If construction of a proposed noise-attenuation barrier will screen a sign lawfully permitted under this chapter, the department shall provide notice to the local government or local jurisdiction within which the sign is located prior to erection of the noise-attenuation barrier. Upon a determination that an increase in the height of a sign as permitted under this section will violate a provision contained in an ordinance or land development regulation of the local government or local jurisdiction, the local government or local jurisdiction shall so notify the department. When notice has been received from the local government or local jurisdiction prior to erection of the noise-attenuation barrier, the department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct a written survey of all property owners identified as impacted by highway noise and who may benefit from the proposed noise-attenuation barrier. The written survey shall inform the property owners of the location, date, and time of the public hearing described in paragraph (b) and shall specifically advise the impacted property owners that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Erection of the noise-attenuation barrier may block the visibility of an existing outdoor advertising sign;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government or local jurisdiction may restrict or prohibit increasing the height of the existing outdoor advertising sign to make it visible over the barrier; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of the impacted property owners vote for construction of the noise-attenuation barrier, the local government or local jurisdiction will be required to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow an increase in the height of the sign in violation of a local ordinance or land development regulation;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the sign to be relocated or reconstructed at another location if the sign owner agrees; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the fair market value of the sign and its associated interest in the real property.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a public hearing within the boundaries of the affected local governments or local jurisdictions to receive input on the proposed noise-attenuation barrier and its conflict with the local ordinance or land development regulation and to suggest or consider alternatives or modifications to the proposed noise-attenuation barrier to alleviate or minimize the conflict with the local ordinance or land development regulation or minimize any costs that may be associated with relocating, reconstructing, or paying for the affected sign. The public hearing may be held concurrently with other public hearings scheduled for the project. The department shall provide a written notification to the local government or local jurisdiction of the date and time of the public hearing and shall provide general notice of the public hearing in accordance with the notice provisions of s. 335.02(1). The notice shall not be placed in that portion of a newspaper in which legal notices or classified advertisements appear. The notice shall specifically state that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Erection of the proposed noise-attenuation barrier may block the visibility of an existing outdoor advertising sign;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government or local jurisdiction may restrict or prohibit increasing the height of the existing outdoor advertising sign to make it visible over the barrier; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of the impacted property owners vote for construction of the noise-attenuation barrier, the local government or local jurisdiction will be required to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow an increase in the height of the sign in violation of a local ordinance or land development regulation;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the sign to be relocated or reconstructed at another location if the sign owner agrees; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the fair market value of the sign and its associated interest in the real property.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not permit erection of the noise-attenuation barrier to the extent the barrier screens or blocks visibility of the sign until after the public hearing is held and until such time as the survey has been conducted and a majority of the impacted property owners have indicated approval to erect the noise-attenuation barrier. When the impacted property owners approve of the noise-attenuation barrier construction, the department shall notify the local governments or local jurisdictions. The local government or local jurisdiction shall, notwithstanding the provisions of a conflicting ordinance or land development regulation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a permit by variance or otherwise for the reconstruction of a sign under this section;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the relocation of a sign, or construction of another sign, at an alternative location that is permittable under the provisions of this chapter, if the sign owner agrees to relocate the sign or construct another sign; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse to issue the required permits for reconstruction of a sign under this section and pay fair market value of the sign and its associated interest in the real property to the owner of the sign.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to the provisions of any existing written agreement executed before July 1, 2006, between any local government and the owner of an outdoor advertising sign.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2002-13; s. 2, ch. 2006-249.</History></Section>