<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0479.156" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wall murals.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a municipality or county may permit and regulate wall murals within areas designated by such government. If a municipality or county permits wall murals, a wall mural that displays a commercial message and is within 660 feet of the nearest edge of the right-of-way within an area adjacent to the interstate highway system or the federal-aid primary highway system shall be located in an area that is zoned for industrial or commercial use and the municipality or county shall establish and enforce regulations for such areas that, at a minimum, set forth criteria governing the size, lighting, and spacing of wall murals consistent with the intent of the Highway Beautification Act of 1965 and with customary use. Whenever a municipality or county exercises such control and makes a determination of customary use pursuant to 23 U.S.C. s. 131(d), such determination shall be accepted in lieu of controls in the agreement between the state and the United States Department of Transportation, and the department shall notify the Federal Highway Administration pursuant to the agreement, 23 U.S.C. s. 131(d), and 23 C.F.R. s. 750.706(c). A wall mural that is subject to municipal or county regulation and the Highway Beautification Act of 1965 must be approved by the Department of Transportation and the Federal Highway Administration when required by federal law and federal regulation under the agreement between the state and the United States Department of Transportation and federal regulations enforced by the Department of Transportation under s. 479.02(1). The existence of a wall mural as defined in s. 479.01(30) shall not be considered in determining whether a sign as defined in s. 479.01(20), either existing or new, is in compliance with s. 479.07(9)(a).</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 62, ch. 2007-196; s. 24, ch. 2009-85; s. 48, ch. 2010-225.</History>
</Section>