<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0479.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Signs for which permits are not required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following signs are exempt from the requirement that a permit for a sign be obtained under the provisions of this chapter but are required to comply with the provisions of s. 479.11(4)-(8):</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs erected on the premises of an establishment, which signs consist primarily of the name of the establishment or which identify the principal or accessory merchandise, services, activities, or entertainment sold, produced, manufactured, or furnished on the premises of the establishment and which comply with the lighting restrictions under department rule adopted pursuant to s. 479.11(5), or signs owned by a municipality or a county located on the premises of such municipality or such county which display information regarding government services, activities, events, or entertainment. For purposes of this section, the following types of messages shall not be considered information regarding government services, activities, events, or entertainment:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Messages which specifically reference any commercial enterprise.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Messages which reference a commercial sponsor of any event.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal messages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Political campaign messages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If a sign located on the premises of an establishment consists principally of brand name or trade name advertising and the merchandise or service is only incidental to the principal activity, or if the owner of the establishment receives rental income from the sign, then the sign is not exempt under this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs erected, used, or maintained on a farm by the owner or lessee of such farm and relating solely to farm produce, merchandise, service, or entertainment sold, produced, manufactured, or furnished on such farm.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs posted or displayed on real property by the owner or by the authority of the owner, stating that the real property is for sale or rent. However, if the sign contains any message not pertaining to the sale or rental of that real property, then it is not exempt under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official notices or advertisements posted or displayed on private property by or under the direction of any public or court officer in the performance of her or his official or directed duties, or by trustees under deeds of trust or deeds of assignment or other similar instruments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Danger or precautionary signs relating to the premises on which they are located; forest fire warning signs erected under the authority of the Florida Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services; and signs, notices, or symbols erected by the United States Government under the direction of the United States Forestry Service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notices of any railroad, bridge, ferry, or other transportation or transmission company necessary for the direction or safety of the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs, notices, or symbols for the information of aviators as to location, directions, and landings and conditions affecting safety in aviation erected or authorized by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs or notices erected or maintained upon property stating only the name of the owner, lessee, or occupant of the premises and not exceeding 8 square feet in area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Historical markers erected by duly constituted and authorized public authorities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official traffic control signs and markers erected, caused to be erected, or approved by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs erected upon property warning the public against hunting and fishing or trespassing thereon.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs not in excess of 8 square feet that are owned by and relate to the facilities and activities of churches, civic organizations, fraternal organizations, charitable organizations, or units or agencies of government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except that signs placed on benches, transit shelters, and waste receptacles as provided for in s. 337.408 are exempt from all provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs relating exclusively to political campaigns.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs not in excess of 16 square feet placed at a road junction with the State Highway System denoting only the distance or direction of a residence or farm operation, or, in a rural area where a hardship is created because a small business is not visible from the road junction with the State Highway System, one sign not in excess of 16 square feet, denoting only the name of the business and the distance and direction to the business. The small-business-sign provision of this subsection does not apply to charter counties and may not be implemented if the Federal Government notifies the department that implementation will adversely affect the allocation of federal funds to the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 20446, 1941; s. 4, ch. 26959, 1951; s. 2, ch. 65-397; s. 5, ch. 67-461; ss. 14, 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 71-971; s. 4, ch. 75-202; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 17, 25, 26, ch. 84-227; s. 76, ch. 85-81; s. 1, ch. 88-245; s. 28, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 45, ch. 94-237; s. 33, ch. 95-257; s. 1, ch. 97-89; s. 410, ch. 97-103; s. 39, ch. 99-385; s. 29, ch. 2000-266; s. 21, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>