<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0479.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Signs on highway rights-of-way; removal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sign located on the right-of-way of a highway on the State Highway System or on any portion of the interstate or federal-aid primary highway system which is in violation of s. 479.11(8) may be removed by the department as provided in this section. However, a permittee of a sign which is located on the right-of-way in violation of s. 479.11(8) and for which sign a permit has been issued under the provisions of this chapter must be given notice in accordance with s. 479.08. Upon a determination by the department that a sign is in violation of s. 479.11(8), the department shall prominently post on the sign structure a notice visible from the main-traveled way stating that the sign is illegal and must be permanently removed from the right-of-way within 10 working days after the posting of the notice. However, if the sign bears the name of the licensee or the name and address of the nonlicensed sign owner, the department shall, concurrently with and in addition to posting the notice on the sign, provide written notice to the owner, stating that the sign is illegal and must be permanently removed from the right-of-way within the 10-day period specified on the posted notice and that the owner has a right to request a hearing, which request must be filed with the department within 30 days after the date of the notice. However, the request for a hearing will not stay the removal of the sign. If, pursuant to the notice provided, the sign is not removed from the right-of-way by the owner within the prescribed period, then the department shall immediately remove the sign without further notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1), the department is authorized to remove, without notice, any sign on the right-of-way which it determines to be a safety hazard to the traveling public or any unpermitted sign on the right-of-way.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a sign that has been noticed pursuant to this section is returned to the right-of-way, the department shall immediately remove the sign without further notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If after a hearing, it is determined that a sign has been wrongfully or erroneously removed pursuant to this section, the department, at the sign owner’s discretion, shall either pay just compensation to the owner of the sign or reerect the sign in kind at the same location at the expense of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of removing a sign, whether by the department or an independent contractor, shall be assessed by the department against the owner of the sign. Furthermore, the department shall assess a fine of $75 against the sign owner for any sign which violates the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 26, ch. 84-227; s. 60, ch. 87-225; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 39, ch. 94-237.</History></Section>