<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0479.262" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tourist-oriented directional sign program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tourist-oriented directional sign program to provide directions to rural tourist-oriented businesses, services, and activities may be established in rural counties identified by criteria and population in s. 288.0656 when approved and permitted by county or local government entities within their respective jurisdictional areas at intersections on rural and conventional state, county, or municipal roads. A county or local government which issues permits for a tourist-oriented directional sign program shall be responsible for sign construction, maintenance, and program operation in compliance with subsection (3) for roads on the state highway system and may establish permit fees sufficient to offset associated costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not create a proprietary or compensable interest in any tourist-oriented directional sign site or location for any permittee on any rural and conventional state, county, or municipal roads. The department or the permitting entity may terminate permits or change locations of tourist-oriented directional sign sites as determined necessary for construction or improvement of transportation facilities or for improved traffic control or safety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tourist-oriented directional signs installed on the state highway system shall comply with the requirements of the federal Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices and rules established by the department. The department may adopt rules to establish requirements for participant qualification, construction standards, location of sign sites, and other criteria necessary to implement this program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-48.</History></Section>