<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0812.145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Theft of copper or other nonferrous metals.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications services” means the transmission, conveyance, or routing of voice, data, audio, video, or any other information or signals, including cable services, to a point, or between or among points, by or through any electronic, radio, satellite, cable, optical, microwave, or other medium or method now in existence or hereafter devised, regardless of the protocol used for such transmission or conveyance. The term includes such transmission, conveyance, or routing in which computer processing applications are used to act on the form, code, or protocol of the content for purposes of transmission, conveyance, or routing without regard to whether such service is referred to as voice-over-Internet-protocol services or is classified by the Federal Communications Commission as enhanced or value-added.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications services provider” includes any person, firm, corporation, or political subdivision, whether private, municipal, county, or cooperative, which is engaged in the sale, generation, provision, or delivery of communications services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Copper or other nonferrous metals” means metals not containing significant quantities of iron or steel, including, without limitation, copper, copper alloy, copper utility or communications service wire, brass, aluminum, bronze, lead, zinc, nickel, and alloys thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electrical substation” means a facility that takes electricity from the transmission grid and converts it to a lower voltage so it can be distributed to customers in the local area on the local distribution grid through one or more distribution lines less than 69 kilovolts in size.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Utility” means a public utility or electric utility as defined in s. 366.02, or a person, firm, corporation, association, or political subdivision, whether private, municipal, county, or cooperative, which is engaged in the sale, generation, provision, or delivery of gas, electricity, heat, water, oil, sewer service, or telephone, telegraph, radio, telecommunications, or communications service. The term includes any person, firm, corporation, association, or political subdivision, whether private, municipal, county, or cooperative, which is engaged in the sale, generation, provision, or delivery of gas or electricity services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Utility service” means electricity for light, heat, or power and natural or manufactured gas for light, heat, or power, including the transportation, delivery, transmission, and distribution of electricity or natural or manufactured gas.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly and intentionally takes copper or other nonferrous metals from a utility or communications services provider, thereby causing damage to the facilities of a utility or communications services provider, interrupting or interfering with utility service or communications services, or interfering with the ability of a utility or communications services provider to provide service, commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is found in a civil action to have illegally taken copper or other nonferrous metals from a utility or communications services provider based on a conviction for a violation of subsection (2) is liable to the utility or communications services provider for damages in an amount equal to three times the actual damages sustained by the utility or communications services provider due to any personal injury, wrongful death, or property damage caused by the illegal taking of the nonferrous metals or an amount equal to three times any claim made against the utility or communications services provider for any personal injury, wrongful death, or property damage caused by the malfunction of the facilities of the utility or communications services provider resulting from the violation of subsection (2), whichever is greater.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly and intentionally removes copper or other nonferrous metals from an electrical substation without authorization of the utility commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-195; s. 11, ch. 2012-179; s. 2, ch. 2012-185.</History>
</Section>