<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.0191" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dealing in property paid for in whole or in part by the Medicaid program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property paid for in whole or in part by the Medicaid program” means any devices, goods, services, drugs, or any other property furnished or intended to be furnished to a recipient of benefits under the Medicaid program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Value” means the amount billed to Medicaid for the property dispensed or the market value of the devices, goods, services, or drugs at the time and place of the offense. If the market value cannot be determined, the term means the replacement cost of the devices, goods, services, or drugs within a reasonable time after the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who traffics in, or endeavors to traffic in, property that he or she knows or should have known was paid for in whole or in part by the Medicaid program commits a felony.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property involved is less than $20,000, the crime is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property involved is $20,000 or more but less than $100,000, the crime is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property involved is $100,000 or more, the crime is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The value of individual items of the devices, goods, services, drugs, or other property involved in distinct transactions committed during a single scheme or course of conduct, whether involving a single person or several persons, may be aggregated when determining the punishment for the offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly initiates, organizes, plans, finances, directs, manages, or supervises the obtaining of property paid for in whole or in part by the Medicaid program and who traffics in, or endeavors to traffic in, such property commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2004-344.</History></Section>