<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.0145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Theft from persons 65 years of age or older; reclassification of offenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is convicted of theft of more than $1,000 from a person 65 years of age or older shall be ordered by the sentencing judge to make restitution to the victim of such offense and to perform up to 500 hours of community service work. Restitution and community service work shall be in addition to any fine or sentence which may be imposed and shall not be in lieu thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person is charged with committing theft from a person 65 years of age or older, when he or she knows or has reason to believe that the victim was 65 years of age or older, the offense for which the person is charged shall be reclassified as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds, assets, or property involved in the theft from a person 65 years of age or older is valued at $50,000 or more, the offender commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds, assets, or property involved in the theft from a person 65 years of age or older is valued at $10,000 or more, but less than $50,000, the offender commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds, assets, or property involved in the theft from a person 65 years of age or older is valued at $300 or more, but less than $10,000, the offender commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-162.</History></Section>