<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unauthorized reception of communications services; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cable operator” means a communications service provider who provides some or all of its communications services pursuant to a “cable television franchise” issued by a “franchising authority,” as those terms are defined in 47 U.S.C. s. 522(9) and (10) (1992).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cable system” means any communications service network, system, or facility owned or operated by a cable operator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications device” means any type of electronic mechanism, transmission line or connections and appurtenances thereto, instrument, device, machine, equipment, or software that is capable of intercepting, transmitting, acquiring, decrypting, or receiving any communications service, or any part, accessory, or component thereof, including any computer circuit, splitter, connector, switches, transmission hardware, security module, smart card, software, computer chip, electronic mechanism, or other component, accessory, or part of any communications device which is capable of facilitating the interception, transmission, retransmission, acquisition, decryption, or reception of any communications service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications service” means any service lawfully provided for a charge or compensation by any cable system or by any radio, fiber optic, photooptical, electromagnetic, photoelectronic, satellite, microwave, data transmission, Internet-based, or wireless distribution network, system, or facility, including, but not limited to, any electronic, data, video, audio, Internet access, microwave, and radio communications, transmissions, signals, and services, and any such communications, transmissions, signals, and services lawfully provided for a charge or compensation, directly or indirectly by or through any of those networks, systems, or facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications service provider” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity owning or operating any cable system or any fiber optic, photooptical, electromagnetic, photoelectronic, satellite, wireless, microwave, radio, data transmission, or Internet-based distribution network, system, or facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity providing any lawful communications service, whether directly or indirectly, as a reseller or licensee, by or through any such distribution network, system, or facility.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacture, development, or assembly of a communications device” means to make, produce, develop, or assemble a communications device or any part, accessory, or component thereof, or to modify, alter, program, or reprogram any communications device so that it is capable of facilitating the commission of a violation of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Multipurpose device” means any communications device that is capable of more than one function and includes any component thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly intercept, receive, decrypt, disrupt, transmit, retransmit, or acquire access to any communications service without the express authorization of the cable operator or other communications service provider, as stated in a contract or otherwise, with the intent to defraud the cable operator or communications service provider, or to knowingly assist others in doing those acts with the intent to defraud the cable operator or other communications provider. For the purpose of this section, the term “assist others” includes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, transfer, license, distribution, deployment, lease, manufacture, development, or assembly of a communications device for the purpose of facilitating the unauthorized receipt, acquisition, interception, disruption, decryption, transmission, retransmission, or access to any communications service offered by a cable operator or any other communications service provider; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, transfer, license, distribution, deployment, lease, manufacture, development, or assembly of a communications device for the purpose of defeating or circumventing any effective technology, device, or software, or any component or part thereof, used by a cable operator or other communications service provider to protect any communications service from unauthorized receipt, acquisition, interception, disruption, access, decryption, transmission, or retransmission.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully violates paragraph (2)(a), paragraph (4)(a), or subsection (5) and who has been previously convicted of any such provision commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and for purposes of direct or indirect commercial advantage or private financial gain violates paragraph (2)(a), paragraph (4)(a), or subsection (5) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who intentionally possesses a communications device, knowing or having reason to know that the design of such device renders it primarily useful for the purpose of committing, or assisting others in committing, a violation of paragraph (2)(a) commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who intentionally possesses five or more communications devices and knows or has reason to know that the design of such devices renders them primarily useful for committing, or assisting others in committing, a violation of paragraph (2)(a) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who intentionally possesses fifty or more communications devices and knows or has reason to know that the design of such devices renders them primarily useful for committing, or assisting others in committing, a violation of paragraph (2)(a) commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to place in any newspaper, magazine, handbill, or other publication, including any electronic medium, any advertisement that, in whole or in part, promotes the sale of a communications device if the person placing the advertisement knows or has reason to know that the device is designed to be primarily useful for committing, or assisting others in committing, a violation of paragraph (2)(a). Any person who violates this subsection shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fines shall be imposed as provided in s. 775.083 for each communications device involved in the prohibited activity or for each day a defendant is in violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall, in addition to any other sentence authorized by law, sentence a person convicted of violating this section to make restitution as authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon conviction of a defendant for violating this section, the court may, in addition to any other sentence authorized by law, direct that the defendant forfeit any communications device in the defendant’s possession or control which was involved in the violation for which the defendant was convicted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of paragraph (2)(a) may be deemed to have been committed at any place where the defendant manufactures, develops, or assembles any communications devices involved in the violation, or assists others in these acts, or any place where the communications device is sold or delivered to a purchaser or recipient. It is not a defense to a violation of paragraph (2)(a) that some of the acts constituting the violation occurred outside the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person aggrieved by any violation of this section may bring a civil action in a circuit court or in any other court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grant temporary and final injunctions on terms it finds reasonable to prevent or restrain violations of this section in conformity with the principles that govern the granting of injunctive relief from threatened loss or damage in other civil cases, except that a showing of special or irreparable damages to the person need not be made.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time while the action is pending, order the impounding, on reasonable terms, of any communications device that is in the custody or control of the violator and that the court has reasonable cause to believe was involved in the alleged violation of this section, and may grant other equitable relief, including the imposition of a constructive trust, as the court considers reasonable and necessary.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Award damages pursuant to paragraphs (c), (d), and (e).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct the recovery of full costs, including awarding reasonable attorney’s fees, to an aggrieved party who prevails.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of a final judgment or decree finding a violation of this section, order the remedial modification or destruction of any communications device, or any other device or equipment, involved in the violation which is in the custody or control of the violator or has been impounded under subparagraph 2.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damages awarded by any court under this section shall be computed in accordance with subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2.:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party aggrieved may recover the actual damages suffered by him or her as a result of the violation and any profits of the violator that are attributable to the violation which are not taken into account in computing the actual damages.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actual damages include the retail value of all communications services to which the violator had unauthorized access as a result of the violation and the retail value of any communications service illegally available to each person to whom the violator directly or indirectly provided or distributed a communications device. In proving actual damages, the party aggrieved must prove only that the violator manufactured, distributed, or sold a communications device and is not required to prove that any such device was actually used in violation of this section.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the violator’s profits, the party aggrieved must prove only the violator’s gross revenue, and the violator must prove his or her deductible expenses and the elements of profit attributable to factors other than the violation.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon election of such damages at any time before final judgment is entered, the party aggrieved may recover an award of statutory damages for each communications device involved in the action, in a sum of not less than $250 or more than $10,000 for each such device, as the court considers just.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which the court finds that the violation was committed willfully and for purposes of commercial advantage or financial gain, the court in its discretion may increase the award of damages, whether actual or statutory under this section, by an amount of not more than $50,000 for each communications device involved in the action and for each day the defendant is in violation of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which the court finds that the violator was not aware and had no reason to believe that his or her acts constituted a violation of this section, the court in its discretion may reduce the award of damages to a sum of not less than $100.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed to impose any criminal or civil liability upon any state or local law enforcement agency; any state or local government agency, municipality, or authority; or any communications service provider unless such entity is acting knowingly and with intent to defraud a communications service provider as defined in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that manufactures, produces, assembles, designs, sells, distributes, licenses, or develops a multipurpose device shall not be in violation of this section unless that person acts knowingly and with an intent to defraud a communications services provider and the multipurpose device:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is manufactured, developed, assembled, produced, designed, distributed, sold, or licensed for the primary purpose of committing a violation of this section;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has only a limited commercially significant purpose or use other than for the commission of any violation of this section; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is marketed by that person or another acting in concert with that person with that person’s knowledge for the purpose of committing any violation of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall require that the design of, or design and selection of parts, software code, or components for, a communications device provide for a response to any particular technology, device, or software, or any component or part thereof, used by the provider, owner, or licensee of any communications service or of any data, audio or video programs, or transmissions, to protect any such communications, data, audio or video service, programs, or transmissions from unauthorized receipt, acquisition, interception, access, decryption, disclosure, communication, transmission, or retransmission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 92-155; s. 1241, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 98-214; s. 1, ch. 99-261; s. 1, ch. 2003-186.</History></Section>