<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Robbery.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Robbery” means the taking of money or other property which may be the subject of larceny from the person or custody of another, with intent to either permanently or temporarily deprive the person or the owner of the money or other property, when in the course of the taking there is the use of force, violence, assault, or putting in fear.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in the course of committing the robbery the offender carried a firearm or other deadly weapon, then the robbery is a felony of the first degree, punishable by imprisonment for a term of years not exceeding life imprisonment or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in the course of committing the robbery the offender carried a weapon, then the robbery is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in the course of committing the robbery the offender carried no firearm, deadly weapon, or other weapon, then the robbery is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act shall be deemed “in the course of committing the robbery” if it occurs in an attempt to commit robbery or in flight after the attempt or commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act shall be deemed “in the course of the taking” if it occurs either prior to, contemporaneous with, or subsequent to the taking of the property and if it and the act of taking constitute a continuous series of acts or events.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 28217, 1953; s. 1, ch. 29930, 1955; s. 839, ch. 71-136; s. 38, ch. 74-383; s. 29, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 87-315; s. 1, ch. 92-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 813.011.</Text></Note></Section>