<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement; civil fine.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation of any provision of this act by any owner or principal operator of a convenience business shall result in a notice of violation from the Attorney General. Violators shall have 30 days after receipt of the notice to provide proof of compliance to the Attorney General’s office. If the violation continues after the 30-day period, the Attorney General may impose a civil fine not to exceed $5,000. The Attorney General has the authority to investigate any alleged violation and may compromise any alleged violation by accepting from the owner or principal operator an amount not to exceed $5,000. The Attorney General may suspend the imposition of any fine conditioned upon terms the Attorney General’s office in its discretion deems appropriate. Notices of violation and civil fines shall be subject to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys received by the Attorney General pursuant to this act shall be deposited in the General Revenue Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General is given full power and authority to petition for an injunction when it is determined that the health, safety, and public welfare is threatened by continued operation of a convenience business in violation of this act. In any action for injunction, the Attorney General may seek a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 per violation, plus attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General may enter into agreements with local governments to assist in the enforcement of ss. 812.1701-812.175. Such agreements may include provision for reimbursement of investigative and enforcement costs incurred by such local governments.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 90-346; s. 7, ch. 92-103; s. 2, ch. 94-265.</History></Section>