<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.173" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Convenience business security.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every convenience business shall be equipped with the following security devices and standards:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security camera system capable of recording and retrieving an image to assist in offender identification and apprehension.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drop safe or cash management device for restricted access to cash receipts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lighted parking lot illuminated at an intensity of at least 2 foot-candles per square foot at 18 inches above the surface.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conspicuous notice at the entrance which states that the cash register contains $50 or less.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Window signage that allows a clear and unobstructed view from outside the building and in a normal line of sight of the cash register and sales transaction area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Height markers at the entrance of the convenience business which display height measures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cash management policy to limit the cash on hand at all times after 11 p.m.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A convenience business shall not have window tinting that reduces exterior or interior view in a normal line of sight.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every convenience business shall be equipped with a silent alarm to law enforcement or a private security agency, unless application for an exemption is made to and granted by the Attorney General. An application for exemption must be in writing and must be accompanied by an administrative fee of $25 for each store for which an exemption would apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a murder, robbery, sexual battery, aggravated assault, aggravated battery, or kidnapping or false imprisonment, as those crimes are identified and defined by Florida Statutes, occurs or has occurred at a convenience business since July 1, 1989, and arises out of the operation of the convenience business, that convenience business shall implement at least one of the following security measures:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide at least two employees on the premises at all times after 11 p.m. and before 5 a.m.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Install for use by employees at all times after 11 p.m. and before 5 a.m. a secured safety enclosure of transparent polycarbonate or other material that meets at least one of the following minimum standards:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">American Society for Testing and Materials Standard D3935 (classification PC110 B 3 0800700) and that has a thickness of at least 0.375 inches and has an impact strength of at least 200 foot pounds; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Underwriters Laboratory Standard UL 752 for medium power small arms (level one), Bullet Resisting Equipment;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a security guard on the premises at all times after 11 p.m. and before 5 a.m.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lock the business premises throughout the hours of 11 p.m. to 5 a.m., and only transact business through an indirect pass-through trough, trapdoor, or window; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Close the business at all times after 11 p.m. and before 5 a.m.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, any convenience business that by law implemented any of the security measures set forth in paragraphs (4)(a)-(e) and has maintained said measures as required by the Department of Legal Affairs without any occurrence or incidence of the crimes identified by subsection (4) for a period of no less than 24 months immediately preceding the filing of a notice of exemption, may file with the department a notice of exemption from these enhanced security measures. In no event shall this exemption be interpreted to preclude full compliance with the security measures set forth in subsection (4) should any occurrence or incidence of the crimes identified by subsection (4) cause subsection (4) to be statutorily applicable. As of the date this act becomes law, the Department of Legal Affairs will provide notice to any convenience business to which a subsection (4) incident has previously occurred. In no event shall the state or the Department of Legal Affairs incur any liability for the regulation and enforcement of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-346; s. 5, ch. 92-103.</History></Section>