<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 812.012-812.037:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cargo” means partial or entire shipments, containers, or cartons of property which are contained in or on a trailer, motortruck, aircraft, vessel, warehouse, freight station, freight consolidation facility, or air navigation facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer in property” means any person in the business of buying and selling property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Obtains or uses” means any manner of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking or exercising control over property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any unauthorized use, disposition, or transfer of property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining property by fraud, willful misrepresentation of a future act, or false promise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct previously known as stealing; larceny; purloining; abstracting; embezzlement; misapplication; misappropriation; conversion; or obtaining money or property by false pretenses, fraud, or deception; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other conduct similar in nature.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” means anything of value, and includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property, including things growing on, affixed to, and found in land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tangible or intangible personal property, including rights, privileges, interests, and claims.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property of another” means property in which a person has an interest upon which another person is not privileged to infringe without consent, whether or not the other person also has an interest in the property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Services” means anything of value resulting from a person’s physical or mental labor or skill, or from the use, possession, or presence of property, and includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repairs or improvements to property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private, public, or government communication, transportation, power, water, or sanitation services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lodging accommodations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Admissions to places of exhibition or entertainment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stolen property” means property that has been the subject of any criminally wrongful taking.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Traffic” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sell, transfer, distribute, dispense, or otherwise dispose of property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To buy, receive, possess, obtain control of, or use property with the intent to sell, transfer, distribute, dispense, or otherwise dispose of such property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enterprise” means any individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, corporation, business trust, union chartered under the laws of this state, or other legal entity, or any unchartered union, association, or group of individuals associated in fact although not a legal entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Value” means value determined according to any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Value means the market value of the property at the time and place of the offense or, if such cannot be satisfactorily ascertained, the cost of replacement of the property within a reasonable time after the offense.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of a written instrument that does not have a readily ascertainable market value, in the case of an instrument such as a check, draft, or promissory note, is the amount due or collectible or is, in the case of any other instrument which creates, releases, discharges, or otherwise affects any valuable legal right, privilege, or obligation, the greatest amount of economic loss that the owner of the instrument might reasonably suffer by virtue of the loss of the instrument.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of a trade secret that does not have a readily ascertainable market value is any reasonable value representing the damage to the owner, suffered by reason of losing an advantage over those who do not know of or use the trade secret.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of property cannot be ascertained, the trier of fact may find the value to be not less than a certain amount; if no such minimum value can be ascertained, the value is an amount less than $100.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts of value of separate properties involved in thefts committed pursuant to one scheme or course of conduct, whether the thefts are from the same person or from several persons, may be aggregated in determining the grade of the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 77-342; s. 292, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 81-85; s. 1, ch. 2001-115.</History></Section>