<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Robbery by sudden snatching.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Robbery by sudden snatching” means the taking of money or other property from the victim’s person, with intent to permanently or temporarily deprive the victim or the owner of the money or other property, when, in the course of the taking, the victim was or became aware of the taking. In order to satisfy this definition, it is not necessary to show that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offender used any amount of force beyond that effort necessary to obtain possession of the money or other property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There was any resistance offered by the victim to the offender or that there was injury to the victim’s person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in the course of committing a robbery by sudden snatching, the offender carried a firearm or other deadly weapon, the robbery by sudden snatching is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in the course of committing a robbery by sudden snatching, the offender carried no firearm or other deadly weapon, the robbery by sudden snatching is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act shall be deemed “in the course of committing a robbery by sudden snatching” if the act occurs in an attempt to commit robbery by sudden snatching or in fleeing after the attempt or commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act shall be deemed “in the course of the taking” if the act occurs prior to, contemporaneous with, or subsequent to the taking of the property and if such act and the act of taking constitute a continuous series of acts or events.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-175.</History></Section>