<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0812.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Evidence of theft or dealing in stolen property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that a person presented false identification, or identification not current with respect to name, address, place of employment, or other material aspects, in connection with the leasing of personal property, or failed to return leased property within 72 hours of the termination of the leasing agreement, unless satisfactorily explained, gives rise to an inference that such property was obtained or is now used with intent to commit theft.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (5), proof of possession of property recently stolen, unless satisfactorily explained, gives rise to an inference that the person in possession of the property knew or should have known that the property had been stolen.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of the purchase or sale of stolen property at a price substantially below the fair market value, unless satisfactorily explained, gives rise to an inference that the person buying or selling the property knew or should have known that the property had been stolen.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of the purchase or sale of stolen property by a dealer in property, out of the regular course of business or without the usual indicia of ownership other than mere possession, unless satisfactorily explained, gives rise to an inference that the person buying or selling the property knew or should have known that it had been stolen.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that a dealer who regularly deals in used property possesses stolen property upon which a name and phone number of a person other than the offeror of the property are conspicuously displayed gives rise to an inference that the dealer possessing the property knew or should have known that the property was stolen.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the name and phone number are for a business that rents property, the dealer avoids the inference by contacting such business, prior to accepting the property, to verify that the property was not stolen from such business. If the name and phone number are not for a business that rents property, the dealer avoids the inference by contacting the local law enforcement agency in the jurisdiction where the dealer is located, prior to accepting the property, to verify that the property has not been reported stolen. An accurate written record, which contains the number called, the date and time of such call, and the name and place of employment of the person who verified that the property was not stolen, is sufficient evidence to avoid the inference pursuant to this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons, entities, or transactions exempt from chapter 538.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Used sports equipment that does not contain a serial number, printed or recorded materials, computer software, or videos or video games.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer who implements, in a continuous and consistent manner, a program for identification and return of stolen property that meets the following criteria:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a dealer is offered property for pawn or purchase that contains conspicuous identifying information that includes a name and phone number, or a dealer is offered property for pawn or purchase that contains ownership information that is affixed to the property pursuant to a written agreement with a business entity or group of associated business entities, the dealer will promptly contact the individual or company whose name is affixed to the property by phone to confirm that the property has not been stolen. If the individual or business contacted indicates that the property has been stolen, the dealer shall not accept the property.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the dealer is unable to verify whether the property is stolen from the individual or business, and if the dealer accepts the property that is later determined to have been stolen, the dealer will voluntarily return the property at no cost and without the necessity of a replevin action, if the property owner files the appropriate theft reports with law enforcement and enters into an agreement with the dealer to actively participate in the prosecution of the person or persons who perpetrated the crime.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a dealer is required by law to complete and submit a transaction form to law enforcement, the dealer shall include all conspicuously displayed ownership information on the transaction form.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that a person was in possession of a stolen motor vehicle and that the ignition mechanism of the motor vehicle had been bypassed or the steering wheel locking mechanism had been broken or bypassed, unless satisfactorily explained, gives rise to an inference that the person in possession of the stolen motor vehicle knew or should have known that the motor vehicle had been stolen.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 77-342; s. 1, ch. 2004-341; s. 1, ch. 2006-107.</History></Section>