<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.2045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enclosed indoor workplaces; specific exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 386.204, tobacco smoking may be permitted in each of the following places:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRIVATE RESIDENCE.<EmDash />A private residence whenever it is not being used commercially to provide child care, adult care, or health care, or any combination thereof as defined in s. 386.203(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RETAIL TOBACCO SHOP.<EmDash />An enclosed indoor workplace dedicated to or predominantly for the retail sale of tobacco, tobacco products, and accessories for such products, as defined in s. 386.203(8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DESIGNATED SMOKING GUEST ROOM.<EmDash />A designated smoking guest room at a public lodging establishment as defined in s. 386.203(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STAND-ALONE BAR.<EmDash />A business that meets the definition of a stand-alone bar as defined in s. 386.203(11) and that otherwise complies with all applicable provisions of the Beverage Law and this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SMOKING CESSATION PROGRAM, MEDICAL OR SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH.<EmDash />An enclosed indoor workplace, to the extent that tobacco smoking is an integral part of a smoking cessation program approved by the department, or medical or scientific research conducted therein. Each room in which tobacco smoking is permitted must comply with the signage requirements in s. 386.206.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CUSTOMS SMOKING ROOM.<EmDash />A customs smoking room in an airport in-transit lounge under the authority and control of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the United States Department of Homeland Security subject to the restrictions contained in s. 386.205.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2003-398.</History></Section>