<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Customs smoking rooms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customs smoking room may be designated by the person in charge of an airport in-transit lounge under the authority and control of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the United States Department of Homeland Security. A customs smoking room may only be designated in an airport in-transit lounge under the authority and control of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the United States Department of Homeland Security. A customs smoking room may not be designated in an elevator, restroom, or any common area as defined by s. 386.203. Each customs smoking room must conform to the following requirements:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work, other than essential services defined in s. 386.203(6), must not be performed in the room at any given time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tobacco smoking must not be permitted in the room while any essential services are being performed in the room.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each customs smoking room must be enclosed by physical barriers that are impenetrable by secondhand tobacco smoke and prevent the escape of secondhand tobacco smoke into the enclosed indoor workplace.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each customs smoking room must exhaust tobacco smoke directly to the outside and away from air intake ducts, and be maintained under negative pressure, with respect to surrounding spaces, sufficient to contain tobacco smoke within the room.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each customs smoking room must comply with the signage requirements in s. 386.206.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 85-257; s. 5, ch. 92-185; s. 79, ch. 97-101; s. 1, ch. 2000-185; s. 1, ch. 2000-370; s. 6, ch. 2003-398.</History></Section>