<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.207" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration; enforcement; civil penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the Division of Hotels and Restaurants or the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall enforce this part based upon each department’s specific areas of regulatory authority and to implement such enforcement shall adopt, in consultation with the State Fire Marshal, rules specifying procedures to be followed by enforcement personnel in investigating complaints and notifying alleged violators and rules specifying procedures by which appeals may be taken by aggrieved parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public agencies responsible for the management and maintenance of government buildings shall report observed violations to the department. The State Fire Marshal shall report to the department observed violations of this part found during its periodic inspections conducted under its regulatory authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the Division of Hotels and Restaurants or the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, upon notification of observed violations of this part, shall issue to the proprietor or other person in charge of such enclosed indoor workplace a notice to comply with this part. If the person fails to comply within 30 days after receipt of the notice, the department or the Division of Hotels and Restaurants or the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall assess a civil penalty against the person of not less than $250 and not to exceed $750 for the first violation and not less than $500 and not to exceed $2,000 for each subsequent violation. The imposition of the fine must be in accordance with chapter 120. If a person refuses to comply with this part, after having been assessed such penalty, the department or the Division of Hotels and Restaurants or the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation may file a complaint in the circuit court of the county in which the enclosed indoor workplace is located to require compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fine moneys collected pursuant to this section shall be used by the department for children’s medical services programs pursuant to the provisions of part I of chapter 391.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 85-257; s. 2, ch. 88-266; s. 1, ch. 89-109; s. 688, ch. 95-148; s. 8, ch. 2003-398.</History></Section>