<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nuisances injurious to health.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following conditions existing, permitted, maintained, kept, or caused by any individual, municipal organization, or corporation, governmental or private, shall constitute prima facie evidence of maintaining a nuisance injurious to health:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Untreated or improperly treated human waste, garbage, offal, dead animals, or dangerous waste materials from manufacturing processes harmful to human or animal life and air pollutants, gases, and noisome odors which are harmful to human or animal life.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly built or maintained septic tanks, water closets, or privies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The keeping of diseased animals dangerous to human health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unclean or filthy places where animals are slaughtered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The creation, maintenance, or causing of any condition capable of breeding flies, mosquitoes, or other arthropods capable of transmitting diseases, directly or indirectly to humans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other condition determined to be a sanitary nuisance as defined in s. 386.01.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health, its agents and deputies, or local health authorities are authorized to investigate any condition or alleged nuisance in any city, town, or place within the state, and if such condition is determined to constitute a sanitary nuisance, they may take such action to abate the said nuisance condition in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 63-64; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 150, ch. 77-147; s. 77, ch. 97-101.</History></Section>