<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.212" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Smoking prohibited near school property; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person under 18 years of age to smoke tobacco in, on, or within 1,000 feet of the real property comprising a public or private elementary, middle, or secondary school between the hours of 6 a.m. and midnight. This section does not apply to any person occupying a moving vehicle or within a private residence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement officer may issue a citation in such form as prescribed by a county or municipality to any person violating the provisions of this section. Any such citation must contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time of issuance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person cited.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time the civil infraction was committed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statute violated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facts constituting the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and authority of the law enforcement officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure for the person to follow to pay the civil penalty, to contest the citation, or to appear in court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicable civil penalty if the person elects not to contest the citation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicable civil penalty if the person elects to contest the citation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person issued a citation pursuant to this section shall be deemed to be charged with a civil infraction punishable by a maximum civil penalty not to exceed $25, or 50 hours of community service or, where available, successful completion of a school-approved anti-tobacco “alternative to suspension” program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with the directions on the citation shall be deemed to waive his or her right to contest the citation and an order to show cause may be issued by the court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 96-217; s. 12, ch. 2003-398.</History></Section>