<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0386.206" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Posting of signs; requiring policies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proprietor or other person in charge of an enclosed indoor workplace must develop and implement a policy regarding the smoking prohibitions established in this part. The policy may include, but is not limited to, procedures to be taken when the proprietor or other person in charge witnesses or is made aware of a violation of s. 386.204 in the enclosed indoor workplace and must include a policy which prohibits an employee from smoking in the enclosed indoor workplace. In order to increase public awareness, the person in charge of an enclosed indoor workplace may, at his or her discretion, post “NO SMOKING” signs as deemed appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person in charge of an airport terminal that includes a designated customs smoking room must conspicuously post, or cause to be posted, signs stating that no smoking is permitted except in the designated customs smoking room located in the customs area of the airport. Each sign posted pursuant to this section must have letters of reasonable size that can be easily read. The color, design, and precise locations at which such signs are posted shall be left to the discretion of the person in charge of the premises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proprietor or other person in charge of an enclosed indoor workplace where a smoking cessation program, medical research, or scientific research is conducted or performed must conspicuously post, or cause to be posted, signs stating that smoking is permitted for such purposes in designated areas in the enclosed indoor workplace. Each sign posted pursuant to this section must have letters of reasonable size which can be easily read. The color, design, and precise locations at which such signs are posted shall be left to the discretion of the person in charge of the premises.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 85-257; s. 6, ch. 92-185; s. 687, ch. 95-148; s. 7, ch. 2003-398; s. 10, ch. 2006-2.</History></Section>