<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0941.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for issuance of requisition; by whom made; contents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the return to this state of a person charged with crime in this state is required, the bailiff or state attorney shall present to the Governor his or her written application for a requisition for the return of the person charged, in which application shall be stated the name of the person so charged, the crime charged against the person, the approximate time, place, and circumstances of its commission, the state in which the person is believed to be, including the location of the accused therein, at the time the application is made and certifying that, in the opinion of the said state attorney the ends of justice require the arrest and return of the accused to this state for trial and that the proceeding is not instituted to enforce a private claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the return to this state is required of a person who has been convicted of a crime in this state and has escaped from confinement or broken the terms of his or her bail, probation, or parole, the state attorney of the county in which the offense was committed, the Parole Commission, the Department of Corrections, or the warden of the institution or sheriff of the county, from which escape was made, shall present to the Governor a written application for a requisition for the return of such person, in which application shall be stated the name of the person, the crime of which the person was convicted, the circumstances of his or her escape from confinement or of the breach of the terms of his or her bail, probation, or parole, and the state in which the person is believed to be, including the location of the person therein at the time application is made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be verified by affidavit, shall be executed in duplicate, and shall be accompanied by two certified copies of the indictment returned or information and affidavit filed or of the complaint made to the judge, stating the offense with which the accused is charged, or of the judgment of conviction or of the sentence. The prosecuting officer, Parole Commission, Department of Corrections, warden, or sheriff may also attach such further affidavits and other documents in duplicate as he or she shall deem proper to be submitted with such application. One copy of the application, with the action of the Governor indicated by endorsement thereon, and one of the certified copies of the indictment, complaint, information, and affidavits or of the judgment of conviction or of the sentence shall be filed in the office of the Department of State to remain of record in that office. The other copies of all papers shall be forwarded with the Governor’s requisition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 20460, 1941; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 44, ch. 73-334; s. 19, ch. 77-120; s. 32, ch. 79-3; s. 49, ch. 88-122; s. 1614, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>