<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0122.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Membership in division B.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Officers and employees, within the contemplation of this system, may become members of division B of this system in the manner and under circumstances as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer or employee who is a member of this system on June 19, 1957, or who becomes such a member after June 19, 1957, and prior to execution of the agreement in pursuance of affirmative referendum as hereinafter provided, may transfer to this division by electing to do so in writing filed with the administrator. While membership in division B shall date from the filing of such election with the administrator, for the purposes of contributions to the system and benefits to members under division B, membership in division B shall take effect upon the date of execution of the agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who becomes a member of this system after execution of the agreement shall become a member of division B of the system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is in a position covered by this system and who is not a member of this system but is eligible to become a member thereof shall, but only for the purposes of subsection 218(d) of the Social Security Act (other than paragraph (8) of said subsection), be regarded as a member of this system. If such person becomes a contributing member of this system after December 31, 1957, he or she shall become a member of division B as required by subsection (2) of this section. In addition he or she may, under the conditions prescribed by s. 218(d)(6)(E) of the Social Security Act, and if still in a position covered by this system, obtain division B coverage effective January 1, 1956, or the date he or she first occupied a position covered by this system, whichever is the later, by filing a written request therefor with the administrator by December 1, 1959, and paying the contributions and interest incident to such coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the conditions prescribed by s. 218(d)(6)(F) of the Social Security Act, a person who was a member of division A of this system on December 31, 1957, and who is still such a member, may transfer to division B of this system by filing a written request therefor with the administrator by December 1, 1959. Social security coverage incidental to such elective membership in division B shall be effective as of January 1, 1956, or the date such person became a member of this system, whichever is the later.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under conditions prescribed by s. 218(d)(6)(F) of the Social Security Act, any person who was a member of division A of this system on December 31, 1957, and who still is a member of division A, may transfer to division B of this system by filing a written request therefor with the administrator in accordance with, subject to and within the time specified in the agreement or modification thereof between the state and the Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare permitting such transfer. Social security coverage incidental to such elective membership in division B shall be effective as of January 1, 1956, or the date such person became a member of this system, whichever is later, but in no event earlier than the effective date specified in the agreement or modification thereof. All amounts required from a member for retroactive social security coverage shall, at the time such election is made, be deducted from the individual account of the member and the difference between the amount remaining in the individual account of such member and the total amount which such member would have contributed had he or she become a member of division B as of January 1, 1956, shall be paid into the retirement fund, and added to his or her individual account, prior to July 1, 1970, or by his or her date of retirement if earlier. If such payment is made after July 1, 1970, the member shall be required to pay interest at the rate of 10 percent of the unpaid balance compounded annually each June 30 from July 1, 1972, to the date of repayment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any highway patrol officer who becomes disabled to the extent that he or she is no longer qualified for the highway patrol and is retired from the highway patrol on account of disability but is able to render useful and efficient service to the state may be employed by the state or a county of the state and upon such employment become a member of the state and county retirement system under division B. Any highway patrol officer who has retired from the highway patrol and is subsequently employed by the state or a county of the state shall be eligible to participate under social security in the same manner as any other state or county employee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 57-382; s. 3, ch. 59-285; s. 4, ch. 65-484; s. 1, ch. 69-215; s. 29, ch. 71-355; s. 1, ch. 72-341; s. 792, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>