<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0122.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contributions; participants; prior service credit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From and after July 1, 1955, the officer or board paying salaries to officers or employees entitled to the benefits of this law shall deduct 6 percent from each installment of salary of each officer or employee so long as such officer or employee shall hold office, or be employed and said amount so deducted shall be deposited in a special trust fund hereby established in the State Treasury, to be known as the “State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund.” Provided further, whenever any county now or hereafter authorized by law to take over and perform the functions of a municipality, exercises such power and takes over functions heretofore performed by a municipality, and as a result thereof municipal employees become county employees and are paid salaries from county funds, such employees who are members and continue to be members of a municipal retirement system shall not be eligible to participate in the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund. Such employees, whose pension or retirement rights are otherwise preserved, who by merger, transfer or assignment of governmental units or functions, become county employees, shall not lose their municipal pension or retirement rights, or any reserves accrued to their benefit during their period of employment with a municipality and the county is authorized to pay into such municipal retirement system during the period that such employees remain as county employees the sums of money previously paid by the municipality for the benefits of such employees, and may make appropriate deductions from the employees’ salaries to preserve their retirement benefits. Provided further, such employees who by merger, transfer or assignment of government units or functions, become county employees shall have 6 months from the date they become county employees to elect to remain in the retirement system of which they were members as municipal employees or become compulsory members of the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement System. Such employees becoming compulsory members of the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement System shall be classed as new members of the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement System and any service rendered by such employees as municipal officers or employees, prior to becoming compulsory members of the State and County Retirement System, shall not be allowed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall not apply to members covered under s. 122.32, when transferred to state employment by statute on or after July 1, 1967. Should such employees be transferred by statute, they shall be transferred from division A to division B with service credit under division A up until date of transfer and service credit under division B thereafter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who held office or was employed by the state or a county of the state on July 1, 1945, or October 1, 1950, and has been holding office or has been continuously employed from April 1, 1955:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May receive credit for prior service rendered subsequent to 1945;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit for service rendered prior to July 1, 1945, shall be continuous except that one period of absence not more than 5 years shall be allowed, and in computing such service credit, the period of absence shall not be creditable service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided any person receiving prior service credit under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) pays into the retirement trust fund the amount he or she would have paid had he or she been a member since July 1, 1945, plus interest compounded annually from date of service to date of payment at the rate of 3 percent for any period of time before July 1, 1975, and at the rate of 6.5 percent compounded annually for any period of time after and including July 1, 1975; however, no officer or employee shall make contributions under this section for less than 10 years or for his or her total service being claimed, whichever is less.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee claiming prior service under subsection (2) of this section shall make the required payment on or before the time of actual retirement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who formerly rejected the provisions of the retirement law may elect to become a member of the retirement system at any time. Any person becoming a member under this subsection shall not receive any prior service credit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any state or county officer or employee who prior to becoming a state or county officer or employee was a member of the Department of Public Safety Pension Fund, and who is not receiving retirement benefits under said fund, shall be a compulsory member of the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement System, and if any such state or county officer or employee has not received a refund from the Department of Public Safety Pension Fund, the amount he or she has paid into said fund, plus the amount the state has paid into said fund to match the employee’s payment, shall be transferred from the Department of Public Safety Pension Fund to the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund, or if such person has received a refund from the Department of Public Safety Pension Fund, then any such state or county officer or employee shall, within 24 months from the time such person becomes a state or county officer or employee, or within 24 months from July 1, 1963, whichever is the later date, pay into the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund 5 percent of the salary he or she has received from the Department of Public Safety, beginning with July 1, 1945, to June 30, 1955, inclusive and from July 1, 1955, 6 percent of the salary he or she has received from the Department of Public Safety, plus 3 percent per annum interest thereon. Thereupon the total time spent with the Department of Public Safety since its creation in chapter 19551, Acts of 1939, shall be added to and computed with such person’s service as a state or county officer or employee. No state or county officer or employee who is receiving benefits under the Department of Public Safety Pension Fund shall be eligible to become a member of the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who held office or was employed by the state or a county of the state continuously from May 1, 1959, and who has not previously received credit for, or is not eligible to claim credit for, prior years of service under subsection (2); or any officer or employee who holds office or is employed by the state or a county of the state on June 1, 1961, and is continuously employed; or any officer or employee who holds office or is employed by the state or county of the state after June 1, 1961, and who is continuously employed for 3 years, during which period of time no back payments may be made:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May claim credit for all prior years of service under the conditions hereinafter set forth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit for service prior to July 1, 1955, may be allowed, provided a contribution of 5 percent of all salary received in the period being claimed, plus interest compounded annually from date of service to date of payment at the rate of 3 percent for any period of time before July 1, 1975, and at the rate of 6.5 percent for any period of time after and including July 1, 1975, is made to the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund on or before the time of actual retirement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit for service subsequent to July 1, 1955, may be allowed, provided a contribution of 6 percent of all salary received in the period being claimed, plus interest compounded annually from date of service to date of payment at the rate of 3 percent for any period of time before July 1, 1975, and at the rate of 6.5 percent for any period of time after and including July 1, 1975, is made to the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement Trust Fund on or before the time of actual retirement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior service allowance may be made only for those periods in which state or county records of service and salary are available, or at least three affidavits and such other information as might be required by the department to meet the provisions of this law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the retirement system created by this chapter who has been eligible or becomes eligible to receive workers’ compensation payments for an injury or illness occurring during his or her employment while a member of any state retirement system shall, upon his or her return to active employment with a covered employer for 1 calendar month or upon his or her approval for disability retirement in accordance with s. 122.09, receive full retirement credit for the period prior to such return to active employment or disability retirement for which the workers’ compensation payments were received. However, no member may receive retirement credit for any such period occurring after the earlier of the date of maximum medical improvement as defined in s. 440.02 or the date termination has occurred as defined in s. 121.021(39). The employer of record at the time of the worker’s compensation injury or illness shall make the required employee and employer retirement contributions based on the member’s rate of monthly compensation immediately prior to receipt of workers’ compensation payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any surviving spouse of a county official or former county official, who was formerly employed full time in the office of the county official and who is presently employed by the said county official or is a county official of any such county and who did not receive compensation for a period of more than 10 years as such employee, may receive credit for retirement purposes as provided for in this chapter by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributing to the said retirement trust fund on a salary computed on the basis of one-third of the compensation received by the said county official for the period of time the said employee did not receive any compensation, and interest on said contribution shall be paid at the rate of 3 percent per annum from July 1, 1945.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting affidavits from two county officials or former county officials from any such county to substantiate said employment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surviving spouse or other dependent of any member whose employment is terminated by death shall, upon application to the department, be permitted to pay the required contributions for any service performed by the member which could have been claimed by the member at the time of death. Such service shall be added to the creditable service of the member and shall be used in the calculation of any benefits which may be payable to the surviving spouse or other surviving dependent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 29801, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-350; ss. 1, 2, ch. 57-363; s. 1, ch. 57-1986; s. 1, ch. 59-203; s. 1, ch. 59-285; s. 1, ch. 59-303; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 61-291; s. 1, ch. 61-434; s. 9, ch. 63-555; s. 8, ch. 65-484; s. 8, ch. 69-82; ss. 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 69-124; s. 1, ch. 69-128; s. 1, ch. 69-1753; s. 2, ch. 72-334; s. 3, ch. 72-345; s. 3, ch. 72-347; s. 4, ch. 74-328; s. 58, ch. 79-40; s. 12, ch. 92-122; s. 63, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 781, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 95-154; s. 57, ch. 99-2; s. 55, ch. 99-255; s. 34, ch. 2001-266; s. 8, ch. 2002-194.</History></Section>