<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0339.0801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Allocation of increased revenues derived from amendments to s. 319.32(5)(a) by ch. 2012-128.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds that result from increased revenues to the State Transportation Trust Fund derived from the amendments to s. 319.32(5)(a) made by this act must be used as follows, notwithstanding any other provision of law:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the 2012-2013 fiscal year, $200 million, or actual receipts up to $200 million, shall be transferred to the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall transfer the actual receipts monthly to the General Revenue Fund. These transfers shall be made in the month following the deposit of those receipts into the State Transportation Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2013-2014 fiscal year and annually for up to 30 years thereafter, $10 million shall be for the purpose of funding any seaport project identified in the adopted work program of the Department of Transportation, to be known as the Seaport Investment Program. The revenues may be assigned, pledged, or set aside as a trust for the payment of principal or interest on bonds, tax anticipation certificates, or other forms of indebtedness issued by an individual port or appropriate local government having jurisdiction thereof, or collectively by interlocal agreement among any of the ports, or used to purchase credit support to permit such borrowings. However, the debt is not a general obligation of the state. The state covenants with holders of the revenue bonds or other instruments of indebtedness issued pursuant to this subsection that it will not repeal or impair or amend this subsection in any manner that will materially or adversely affect the rights of holders so long as bonds authorized by this subsection are outstanding. The proceeds of any bonds or other indebtedness secured by a pledge of the funding, after payment of costs of issuance and establishment of any required reserves, shall be invested in projects approved by the Department of Transportation and included in the department’s adopted work program, by amendment if necessary. Any revenues that are not pledged to the repayment of bonds as authorized by this section may be used for purposes authorized under the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program. This revenue source is in addition to any amounts provided for and appropriated in accordance with ss. 311.07 and 320.20(3) and (4). Revenue bonds shall be issued by the Division of Bond Finance at the request of the Department of Transportation pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2013-2014 fiscal year and annually for up to 30 years thereafter, $35 million shall be transferred to Florida’s Turnpike Enterprise, to be used in accordance with Florida Turnpike Enterprise Law, to the maximum extent feasible for feeder roads, structures, interchanges, appurtenances, and other rights to create or facilitate access to the existing turnpike system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2013-2014 fiscal year and annually thereafter, $10 million shall be transferred to the Transportation Disadvantaged Trust Fund, to be used as specified in s. 427.0159.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2013-2014 fiscal year and annually thereafter, $10 million shall be allocated to the Small County Outreach Program, to be used as specified in s. 339.2818. These funds are in addition to the funds provided in s. 201.15(1)(c)1.b.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the distributions required pursuant to subsections (1)-(5), the remaining funds shall be used annually for transportation projects within this state for existing or planned strategic transportation projects which connect major markets within this state or between this state and other states, which focus on job creation, and which increase this state’s viability in the national and global markets.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 339.135(7), the department shall amend the work program to add the projects provided for in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2012-128.</History>
</Section>