<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0339.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Work program; legislative budget request; definitions; preparation, adoption, execution, and amendment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fiscal year” of the department means the period beginning July 1 of each year and ending June 30 of the succeeding year. Such fiscal year constitutes a budget year for all operating funds of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District work program” means the 5-year listing of transportation projects planned for each fiscal year which is prepared by each of the districts and which must be submitted to the central office for review and development of the tentative work program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tentative work program” means the 5-year listing of all transportation projects planned for each fiscal year which is developed by the central office based on the district work programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adopted work program” means the 5-year work program adopted by the department as provided in subsection (5).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUBMISSION OF LEGISLATIVE BUDGET REQUEST AND REQUEST FOR LIST OF ADDITIONAL TRANSPORTATION PROJECTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall file the legislative budget request in the manner required by chapter 216, setting forth the department’s proposed revenues and expenditures for operational and fixed capital outlay needs to accomplish the objectives of the department in the ensuing fiscal year. The right-of-way, construction, preliminary engineering, maintenance, and all grants and aids programs of the department shall be set forth only in program totals. The legislative budget request must include a balanced 36-month forecast of cash and expenditures and a 5-year finance plan. The legislative budget request shall be amended to conform to the tentative work program. Prior to the submission of the tentative work program pursuant to paragraph (4)(f), the department may amend its legislative budget request and the tentative work program for the most recent estimating conference estimate of revenues and the most recent federal aid apportionments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the written request by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the department shall prepare a list of projects, from the transportation needs identified pursuant to this paragraph, that meet the following criteria:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project can be made production-ready within the 5 fiscal years following the end of the current fiscal year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project is not included in the current adopted work program or in the tentative work program to be submitted by the department for the next fiscal year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project is included in the transportation improvement program of any metropolitan planning organization within whose boundaries the project is located in whole or in part.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project is not inconsistent with an approved local comprehensive plan of any local government within whose boundaries the project is located in whole or in part, or, if inconsistent, is accompanied by an explanation of why the inconsistency should be undertaken.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall submit the list of projects prepared pursuant to this subsection to the legislative appropriations committees, together with the following plans and reports:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An enhanced program and resource plan that adds the list of projects and required support costs to the projects and other programs of the tentative work program required to be submitted by the department pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A variance report comparing the enhanced plan with the plan for the tentative work program covering the same period of time.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 36-month cash forecast identifying the additional revenues needed to finance the enhanced plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NATURE AND SCOPE OF THE TENTATIVE AND ADOPTED WORK PROGRAMS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tentative and adopted work programs required by subsections (4) and (5) shall be based on a complete, balanced financial plan for the State Transportation Trust Fund and the other funds managed by the department. The tentative and adopted work programs shall set forth the proposed commitments and planned expenditures, respectively, of the department classified by major program and fixed capital appropriation categories to accomplish the objectives of the department included in the program and resource plan of the Florida Transportation Plan required in s. 339.155.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tentative and adopted work programs for the State Transportation Trust Fund and other funds managed by the department, except as otherwise provided by law, must be so planned as to deplete the estimated resources of each fund for the fiscal year. An emergency reserve may be requested in the legislative budget request for the purpose of performing emergency work necessary during the fiscal year in order to prevent the stoppage of travel over any transportation facility over which the department has jurisdiction and control.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No anticipated funds estimated to be received from various federal-aid acts of Congress shall be budgeted in excess of the amount which may be earned by the amount of state funds set aside to match such federal aid; and the state funds thus set aside to match federal-aid funds shall be used only for such matching purposes. The department shall, prior to the preparation of the tentative work program, ascertain the amount of apportionments of federal-aid funds which are estimated to be available to the department for expenditure in the fiscal years for which the tentative work program is prepared; and the department shall budget sufficient funds for matching purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is not required to match federal-aid funds that are allocated for use on a project that is not on the State Highway System. If a metropolitan planning organization allocates available federal-aid funds for a project that is not on the State Highway System, the department may not provide more than 50 percent of the nonfederal share, except that, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 341.051, the department may provide 100 percent of the nonfederal share of a transit project or transit-related project that is funded under the federal Congestion Mitigation and Air Quality Attainment Program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING AND DEVELOPING A TENTATIVE WORK PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assure that no district or county is penalized for local efforts to improve the State Highway System, the department shall, for the purpose of developing a tentative work program, allocate funds for new construction to the districts, except for the turnpike enterprise, based on equal parts of population and motor fuel tax collections. Funds for resurfacing, bridge repair and rehabilitation, bridge fender system construction or repair, public transit projects except public transit block grants as provided in s. 341.052, and other programs with quantitative needs assessments shall be allocated based on the results of these assessments. The department may not transfer any funds allocated to a district under this paragraph to any other district except as provided in subsection (7). Funds for public transit block grants shall be allocated to the districts pursuant to s. 341.052. Funds for the intercity bus program provided for under s. 5311(f) of the federal nonurbanized area formula program shall be administered and allocated directly to eligible bus carriers as defined in s. 341.031(12) at the state level rather than the district. In order to provide state funding to support the intercity bus program provided for under provisions of the federal 5311(f) program, the department shall allocate an amount equal to the federal share of the 5311(f) program from amounts calculated pursuant to s. 206.46(3).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph 1., the department shall allocate at least 50 percent of any new discretionary highway capacity funds to the Florida Strategic Intermodal System created pursuant to s. 339.61. Any remaining new discretionary highway capacity funds shall be allocated to the districts for new construction as provided in subparagraph 1. For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “new discretionary highway capacity funds” means any funds available to the department above the prior year funding level for capacity improvements, which the department has the discretion to allocate to highway projects.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subparagraphs 1. and 2. and ss. 201.15(1)(c)1.a.-d., 206.46(3), 334.044(26), and 339.2819(3), and for the 2011-2012 fiscal year only, the department shall reduce work program levels to balance the finance plan to the revised funding levels resulting from any reduction in the 2011-2012 General Appropriations Act. This subparagraph expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2011-2012 fiscal year only, before any project or phase thereof is deferred, the department’s cash balances shall be as provided in paragraph (6)(b), and the reductions in subparagraph 3. shall be made to financial projects not programmed for contract letting as identified with a work program contract class code 8 and the box code RV. These reductions shall not negatively impact safety or maintenance or project contingency percentage levels as of April 21, 2011. This subparagraph expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subparagraphs 1. and 2. and ss. 206.46(3) and 334.044(26), and for fiscal years 2009-2010 through 2013-2014 only, the department shall annually allocate up to $15 million of the first proceeds of the increased revenues estimated by the November 2009 Revenue Estimating Conference to be deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund to provide for the portion of the transfer of funds included in s. 343.58(4)(a)1.a. or 2.a., as applicable. The transfer of funds included in s. 343.58(4) shall not negatively impact projects included in fiscal years 2009-2010 through 2013-2014 of the work program as of July 1, 2009, as amended pursuant to subsection (7). This subparagraph expires July 1, 2014.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tentative work program, including the ensuing fiscal year and the successive 4 fiscal years, shall be prepared for the State Transportation Trust Fund and other funds managed by the department, unless otherwise provided by law. The tentative work program shall be based on the district work programs and shall set forth all projects by phase to be undertaken during the ensuing fiscal year and planned for the successive 4 fiscal years. The total amount of the liabilities accruing in each fiscal year of the tentative work program may not exceed the revenues available for expenditure during the respective fiscal year based on the cash forecast for that respective fiscal year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tentative work program shall be developed in accordance with the Florida Transportation Plan required in s. 339.155 and must comply with the program funding levels contained in the program and resource plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may include in the tentative work program proposed changes to the programs contained in the previous work program adopted pursuant to subsection (5); however, the department shall minimize changes and adjustments that affect the scheduling of project phases in the 4 common fiscal years contained in the previous adopted work program and the tentative work program. The department, in the development of the tentative work program, shall advance by 1 fiscal year all projects included in the second year of the previous year’s adopted work program, unless the secretary specifically determines that it is necessary, for specific reasons, to reschedule or delete one or more projects from that year. Such changes and adjustments shall be clearly identified, and the effect on the 4 common fiscal years contained in the previous adopted work program and the tentative work program shall be shown. It is the intent of the Legislature that the first 3 years of the adopted work program stand as the commitment of the state to undertake transportation projects that local governments may rely on for planning and concurrency purposes and in the development and amendment of the capital improvements elements of their local government comprehensive plans.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tentative work program must include a balanced 36-month forecast of cash and expenditures and a 5-year finance plan supporting the tentative work program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the board of county commissioners shall serve as the metropolitan planning organization in those counties which are not located in a metropolitan planning organization and shall be involved in the development of the district work program to the same extent as a metropolitan planning organization.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district work program shall be developed cooperatively from the outset with the various metropolitan planning organizations of the state and include, to the maximum extent feasible, the project priorities of metropolitan planning organizations which have been submitted to the district by October 1 of each year pursuant to s. 339.175(8)(b); however, the department and a metropolitan planning organization may, in writing, cooperatively agree to vary this submittal date. To assist the metropolitan planning organizations in developing their lists of project priorities, the district shall disclose to each metropolitan planning organization any anticipated changes in the allocation or programming of state and federal funds which may affect the inclusion of metropolitan planning organization project priorities in the district work program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to submittal of the district work program to the central office, the district shall provide the affected metropolitan planning organization with written justification for any project proposed to be rescheduled or deleted from the district work program which project is part of the metropolitan planning organization’s transportation improvement program and is contained in the last 4 years of the previous adopted work program. By no later than 14 days after submittal of the district work program to the central office, the affected metropolitan planning organization may file an objection to such rescheduling or deletion. When an objection is filed with the secretary, the rescheduling or deletion may not be included in the district work program unless the inclusion of such rescheduling or deletion is specifically approved by the secretary. The Florida Transportation Commission shall include such objections in its evaluation of the tentative work program only when the secretary has approved the rescheduling or deletion.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the submission of the district work program to the central office, each district office shall hold a public hearing in at least one urbanized area in the district and shall make a presentation at a meeting of each metropolitan planning organization in the district to determine the necessity of making any changes to projects included or to be included in the district work program and to hear requests for new projects to be added to, or existing projects to be deleted from, the district work program. However, the district and metropolitan planning organization shall minimize changes to, deletions from, or adjustments to projects or project phases contained in the 4 common years of the previous adopted work program and the district work program. The district shall provide the metropolitan planning organization with a written explanation for any project which is contained in the metropolitan planning organization’s transportation improvement program and which is not included in the district work program. The metropolitan planning organization may request in writing to the appropriate district secretary further consideration of any specific project not included or not adequately addressed in the district work program. The district secretary shall acknowledge and review all such requests prior to the submission of the district work program to the central office and shall forward a copy of such requests to the secretary and the Florida Transportation Commission. The commission shall include such requests in its evaluation of the tentative work program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following submission of each district work program to the central office, the department shall develop the tentative work program based on the district work programs, review the individual district work programs for compliance with the work program instructions prepared by the department, and ensure that the tentative work program complies with the requirements of paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The central office shall submit a preliminary copy of the tentative work program to the Executive Office of the Governor, the legislative appropriations committees, the Florida Transportation Commission, and the Department of Economic Opportunity at least 14 days prior to the convening of the regular legislative session. Prior to the statewide public hearing required by paragraph (g), the Department of Economic Opportunity shall transmit to the Florida Transportation Commission a list of those projects and project phases contained in the tentative work program which are identified as being inconsistent with approved local government comprehensive plans. For urbanized areas of metropolitan planning organizations, the list may not contain any project or project phase that is scheduled in a transportation improvement program unless such inconsistency has been previously reported to the affected metropolitan planning organization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Transportation Commission shall conduct a statewide public hearing on the tentative work program and shall advertise the time, place, and purpose of the hearing in the Florida Administrative Weekly at least 7 days prior to the hearing. As part of the statewide public hearing, the commission shall, at a minimum:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct an in-depth evaluation of the tentative work program for compliance with applicable laws and departmental policies; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hear all questions, suggestions, or other comments offered by the public.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By no later than 14 days after the regular legislative session begins, the commission shall submit to the Executive Office of the Governor and the legislative appropriations committees a report that evaluates the tentative work program for:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial soundness;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stability;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Production capacity;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accomplishments, including compliance with program objectives in s. 334.046;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with approved local government comprehensive plans;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Objections and requests by metropolitan planning organizations;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policy changes and effects thereof;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of statewide or regional projects; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with all other applicable laws.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following evaluation by the Florida Transportation Commission, the department shall submit the tentative work program to the Executive Office of the Governor and the legislative appropriations committees no later than 14 days after the regular legislative session begins.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADOPTION OF THE WORK PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original approved budget for operational and fixed capital expenditures for the department shall be the Governor’s budget recommendation and the first year of the tentative work program, as both are amended by the General Appropriations Act and any other act containing appropriations. In accordance with the appropriations act, the department shall, before the beginning of the fiscal year, adopt a final work program which shall only include the original approved budget for the department for the ensuing fiscal year, together with any roll forwards approved pursuant to paragraph (6)(c), and the portion of the tentative work program for the following 4 fiscal years revised in accordance with the original approved budget for the department for the ensuing fiscal year together with the roll forwards. The adopted work program may include only those projects submitted as part of the tentative work program developed under the provisions of subsection (4), plus any projects which are separately identified by specific appropriation in the General Appropriations Act and any roll forwards approved pursuant to paragraph (6)(c). However, any transportation project of the department which is identified by specific appropriation in the General Appropriations Act shall be deducted from the funds annually distributed to the respective district pursuant to paragraph (4)(a). In addition, the department shall not in any year include any project or allocate funds to a program in the adopted work program that is contrary to existing law for that particular year. Projects shall not be undertaken unless they are listed in the adopted work program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), and for the 2011-2012 fiscal year only, the Department of Transportation shall transfer funds to the Department of Economic Opportunity in an amount equal to $15 million for the purpose of funding transportation-related needs of economic development projects. This transfer does not reduce, delete, or defer any existing projects funded, as of July 1, 2011, in the Department of Transportation’s 5-year work program. This paragraph expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), and for the 2011-2012 fiscal year only, the Department of Transportation shall fund airport development projects specified in the General Appropriations Act and, unless requested by the airport sponsor, may not reduce, delete, or defer any existing projects funded as of July 1, 2011, in the Department of Transportation’s 5-year work program. This paragraph expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXECUTION OF THE BUDGET.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, during any fiscal year, shall not expend money, incur any liability, or enter into any contract which, by its terms, involves the expenditure of money in excess of the amounts budgeted as available for expenditure during such fiscal year. Any contract, verbal or written, made in violation of this subsection is null and void, and no money may be paid on such contract. The department shall require a statement from the comptroller of the department that funds are available prior to entering into any such contract or other binding commitment of funds. Nothing herein contained shall prevent the making of contracts for periods exceeding 1 year, but any contract so made shall be executory only for the value of the services to be rendered or agreed to be paid for in succeeding fiscal years; and this paragraph shall be incorporated verbatim in all contracts of the department which are for an amount in excess of $25,000 and which have a term for a period of more than 1 year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of the State Transportation Trust Fund, the department shall have on hand at the close of business, which closing shall not be later than the 10th calendar day of the month following the end of each quarter of the fiscal year, an available cash balance (which shall include cash on deposit with the treasury and short-term investments of the department) equivalent to not less than $50 million, or 5 percent of the unpaid balance of all State Transportation Trust Fund obligations at the close of such quarter, whichever amount is less. In the event that this cash position is not maintained, no further contracts or other fund commitments shall be approved, entered into, awarded, or executed until the cash balance, as defined above, has been regained.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of ss. 216.301(2) and 216.351, any unexpended balance remaining at the end of the fiscal year in the appropriations to the department for special categories; aid to local governments; lump sums for project phases which are part of the adopted work program, and for which contracts have been executed or bids have been let; and for right-of-way land acquisition and relocation assistance for parcels from project phases in the adopted work program for which appraisals have been completed and approved, may be certified forward as fixed capital outlay at the end of each fiscal year, to be certified by the head of the state agency on or before August 1 of each year to the Executive Office of the Governor, showing in detail the commitment or to whom obligated and the amount of such commitment or obligation. On or before September 1 of each year, the Executive Office of the Governor shall review and approve or disapprove, consistent with legislative policy and intent, any or all of the items and amounts certified by the head of the state agency and shall furnish the Chief Financial Officer, the legislative appropriations committees, and the Auditor General a detailed listing of the items and amounts approved as legal encumbrances against the undisbursed balances of such appropriations. In the event such certification is not made and the balance of the appropriation has reverted and the obligation is proven to be legal, due, and unpaid, then the same shall be presented to the Legislature for its consideration. Such certification as herein required shall be in the form and on the date approved by the Executive Office of the Governor. Any project phases in the adopted work program not certified forward shall be available for roll forward for the next fiscal year of the adopted work program. Spending authority associated with such project phases may be rolled forward to the next fiscal year upon approval by the Legislative Budget Commission. Increases in spending authority shall be limited to amounts of unexpended balances by appropriation category. Any project phase certified forward for which bids have been let but subsequently rejected shall be available for roll forward in the adopted work program for the next fiscal year. Spending authority associated with such project phases may be rolled forward into the current year from funds certified forward. The amount certified forward may include contingency allowances for right-of-way acquisition and relocation, asphalt and petroleum product escalation clauses, and contract overages, which allowances shall be separately identified in the certification detail. Right-of-way acquisition and relocation and contract overages contingency allowances shall be based on documented historical patterns. These contingency amounts shall be incorporated in the certification for each specific category, but when a category has an excess and another category has a deficiency, the Executive Office of the Governor is authorized to transfer the excess to the deficient account.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall allocate resources provided in the General Appropriations Act to the districts prior to July 31 of each year. The allocation shall be promptly reported to the Executive Office of the Governor and the legislative appropriations committees, and all subsequent amendments shall be reported promptly to the secretary of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to any bonds issued on behalf of the department pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AMENDMENT OF THE ADOPTED WORK PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of ss. 216.292 and 216.351, the adopted work program may be amended only pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not transfer any funds for any project or project phase between department districts. However, a district secretary may agree to a loan of funds to another district, if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds are used solely to maximize the use or amount of funds available to the state;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The loan agreement is executed in writing and is signed by the district secretaries of the respective districts;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repayment of the loan is to be made within 3 years after the date on which the agreement was entered into; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adopted work program of the district loaning the funds would not be substantially impaired if the loan were made, according to the district secretary.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The loan constitutes an amendment to the adopted work program and is subject to the procedures specified in <Reference Number="1"/>paragraph (e).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may amend the adopted work program to transfer fixed capital outlay appropriations for projects within the same appropriations category or between appropriations categories, including the following amendments which shall be subject to the procedures in <Reference Number="2"/>paragraph (f):</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amendment which deletes any project or project phase estimated to cost over $150,000;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amendment which adds a project estimated to cost over $500,000 in funds appropriated by the Legislature;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amendment which advances or defers to another fiscal year, a right-of-way phase, a construction phase, or a public transportation project phase estimated to cost over $1.5 million in funds appropriated by the Legislature, except an amendment advancing a phase by 1 year to the current fiscal year or deferring a phase for a period of 90 days or less; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amendment which advances or defers to another fiscal year, any preliminary engineering phase or design phase estimated to cost over $500,000 in funds appropriated by the Legislature, except an amendment advancing a phase by 1 year to the current fiscal year or deferring a phase for a period of 90 days or less.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Beginning July 1, 2013, the department shall index the budget amendment threshold amounts established in this paragraph to the Consumer Price Index or similar inflation indicators. Threshold adjustments for inflation under this paragraph may be made no more frequently than once a year. Adjustments for inflation are subject to the notice and review procedures contained in s. 216.177.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the department proposes any amendment to the adopted work program, as defined in <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)1. or <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)3., which deletes or defers a construction phase on a capacity project, it shall notify each county affected by the amendment and each municipality within the county. The notification shall be issued in writing to the chief elected official of each affected county, each municipality within the county, and the chair of each affected metropolitan planning organization. Each affected county and each municipality in the county is encouraged to coordinate with each other in order to determine how the amendment affects local concurrency management and regional transportation planning efforts. Each affected county, and each municipality within the county, shall have 14 days to provide written comments to the department regarding how the amendment will affect its respective concurrency management systems, including whether any development permits were issued contingent upon the capacity improvement, if applicable. After receipt of written comments from the affected local governments, the department shall include any written comments submitted by such local governments in its preparation of the proposed amendment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the 14-day comment period in subparagraph 1., if applicable, whenever the department proposes any amendment to the adopted work program, which amendment is defined in <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)1., <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)2., <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)3., or <Reference Number="1"/>subparagraph (e)4., it shall submit the proposed amendment to the Governor for approval and shall immediately notify the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees, the chairs of the legislative transportation committees, and each member of the Legislature who represents a district affected by the proposed amendment. It shall also notify each metropolitan planning organization affected by the proposed amendment, and each unit of local government affected by the proposed amendment, unless it provided to each the notification required by subparagraph 1. Such proposed amendment shall provide a complete justification of the need for the proposed amendment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor may not approve a proposed amendment until 14 days following the notification required in subparagraph 2.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If either of the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees or the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Representatives objects in writing to a proposed amendment within 14 days following notification and specifies the reasons for such objection, the Governor shall disapprove the proposed amendment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraphs <Reference Number="2"/>(f) and <Reference Number="3"/>(i) and ss. 216.177(2) and 216.351, the secretary may request the Executive Office of the Governor to amend the adopted work program when an emergency exists, as defined in s. 252.34, and the emergency relates to the repair or rehabilitation of any state transportation facility. The Executive Office of the Governor may approve the amendment to the adopted work program and amend that portion of the department’s approved budget if a delay incident to the notification requirements in <Reference Number="2"/>paragraph (f) would be detrimental to the interests of the state. However, the department shall immediately notify the parties specified in <Reference Number="2"/>paragraph (f) and provide such parties written justification for the emergency action within 7 days after approval by the Executive Office of the Governor of the amendment to the adopted work program and the department’s budget. The adopted work program may not be amended under this subsection without certification by the comptroller of the department that there are sufficient funds available pursuant to the 36-month cash forecast and applicable statutes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may authorize the investment of the earnings accrued and collected upon the investment of the minimum balance of funds required to be maintained in the State Transportation Trust Fund pursuant to <Reference Number="4"/>paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any work program amendment which also requires the transfer of fixed capital outlay appropriations between categories within the department or the increase of an appropriation category is subject to the approval of the Legislative Budget Commission. If a meeting of the Legislative Budget Commission cannot be held within 30 days of the department submitting an amendment to the Legislative Budget Commission, then the chair and vice chair of the Legislative Budget Commission may authorize such amendment to be approved pursuant to the provisions of s. 216.177.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 9, ch. 57-318; s. 1, ch. 61-80; ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-371; s. 1, ch. 69-396; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-996; s. 1, ch. 72-66; ss. 2, 3, ch. 73-58; s. 1, ch. 75-3; s. 1, ch. 82-31; s. 1, ch. 83-232; s. 214, ch. 84-309; s. 1, ch. 84-332; s. 24, ch. 85-180; s. 36, ch. 86-243; s. 1, ch. 87-131; s. 3, ch. 88-247; s. 26, ch. 88-557; s. 4, ch. 89-301; ss. 35, 119, ch. 90-136; s. 37, ch. 91-109; s. 3, ch. 91-272; s. 89, ch. 92-152; ss. 5, 13, 23, ch. 93-164; s. 43, ch. 93-187; s. 2, ch. 94-237; s. 972, ch. 95-148; s. 51, ch. 95-257; s. 14, ch. 97-100; s. 24, ch. 97-280; s. 135, ch. 99-13; ss. 46, 101, ch. 99-385; s. 14, ch. 2000-325; s. 56, ch. 2000-371; s. 10, ch. 2001-380; s. 4, ch. 2002-13; s. 26, ch. 2002-20; s. 10, ch. 2003-2; s. 5, ch. 2003-291; s. 9, ch. 2004-366; s. 43, ch. 2005-71; s. 47, ch. 2005-152; s. 9, ch. 2005-290; s. 9, ch. 2007-6; s. 31, ch. 2007-73; s. 31, ch. 2008-153; ss. 8, 9, ch. 2009-82; s. 18, ch. 2009-85; s. 3, ch. 2009-271; s. 14, ch. 2010-139; ss. 33, 51, 72, ch. 2010-153; s. 9, ch. 2011-3; s. 21, ch. 2011-4; ss. 42, 43, ch. 2011-47; s. 239, ch. 2011-142; s. 5, ch. 2012-6; s. 55, ch. 2012-96; s. 53, ch. 2012-174.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (e) was redesignated as paragraph (c) to conform to s. 5, ch. 2012-6.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (f) was redesignated as paragraph (d) to conform to s. 5, ch. 2012-6.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (i) was redesignated as paragraph (g) to conform to s. 5, ch. 2012-6.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="4">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (b) was repealed by s. 5, ch. 2012-6.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 334.21.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>