<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0339.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of transportation tax revenues; restrictions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds available to the department shall not be used for any nontransportation purpose. However, the department shall construct and maintain roads, parking areas, and other transportation facilities adjacent to and within the grounds of state institutions, public community colleges, farmers’ markets, and wayside parks upon request of the proper authorities. The department is encouraged and permitted to use funds to construct and maintain noise mitigation facilities or walls upon request of the proper authorities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, in cooperation with the Federal Government, expend transportation tax revenues pursuant to rules adopted by the department, for control of undesirable rodents, relocation assistance, and moving costs of persons displaced by highway construction and other related transportation projects to the extent, but only to the extent, required by federal law to be undertaken by the state to continue to be eligible for federal highway funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may expend transportation tax revenues, pursuant to rules adopted by the department, on non-federal-aid projects which shall include relocation assistance and moving costs to persons displaced by transportation facilities or other related projects. Such rules shall, in no case, exceed the provisions of the Surface Transportation and Uniform Relocation Assistance Act of 1987. The department has the authority to carry out its responsibilities under this act; however, such authority does not extend to the power of eminent domain. Whenever possible, such costs shall be financed out of funds used for the principal project.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 140, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 1, ch. 63-385; s. 1, ch. 69-233; ss. 17, 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 70-239; s. 1, ch. 72-208; s. 70, ch. 72-221; s. 1, ch. 73-283; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 57, 209, ch. 84-309; s. 1, ch. 89-209; s. 18, ch. 2000-266; s. 39, ch. 2007-196.</History></Section>