<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0339.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">System facilities designated; additions and deletions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial Strategic Intermodal System shall include all facilities that meet the criteria recommended by the Strategic Intermodal Steering Committee in a report titled “Steering Committee Final Report: Recommendations for Designating Florida’s Strategic Intermodal System” dated December 2002.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Strategic Intermodal System and the Emerging Strategic Intermodal System include five different types of facilities that each form one component of an interconnected transportation system which types include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing or planned hubs that are ports and terminals including airports, seaports, spaceports, passenger terminals, and rail terminals serving to move goods or people between Florida regions or between Florida and other markets in the United States and the rest of the world.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing or planned corridors that are highways, rail lines, waterways, and other exclusive-use facilities connecting major markets within Florida or between Florida and other states or nations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing or planned intermodal connectors that are highways, rail lines, waterways or local public transit systems serving as connectors between the components listed in paragraphs (a) and (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing or planned military access facilities that are highways or rail lines linking Strategic Intermodal System corridors to the state’s strategic military installations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing or planned facilities that significantly improve the state’s competitive position to compete for the movement of additional goods into and through this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the initial designation of the Strategic Intermodal System under subsection (1), the department shall, in coordination with the metropolitan planning organizations, local governments, regional planning councils, transportation providers, and affected public agencies, add facilities to or delete facilities from the Strategic Intermodal System described in paragraphs (2)(b) and (c) based upon criteria adopted by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the initial designation of the Strategic Intermodal System under subsection (1), the department shall, in coordination with the metropolitan planning organizations, local governments, regional planning councils, transportation providers, and affected public agencies, add facilities to or delete facilities from the Strategic Intermodal System described in paragraph (2)(a) based upon criteria adopted by the department. However, an airport that is designated as a reliever airport to a Strategic Intermodal System airport which has at least 75,000 itinerant operations per year, has a runway length of at least 5,500 linear feet, is capable of handling aircraft weighing at least 60,000 pounds with a dual wheel configuration which is served by at least one precision instrument approach, and serves a cluster of aviation-dependent industries, shall be designated as part of the Strategic Intermodal System by the Secretary of Transportation upon the request of a reliever airport meeting this criteria.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Transportation shall designate a planned facility as part of the Strategic Intermodal System upon request of the facility if it meets the criteria and thresholds established by the department pursuant to subsection (4), meets the definition of an “intermodal logistics center” <Reference Number="1"/>as defined in s. 311.101(2), and has been designated in a local comprehensive plan or local government development order as an intermodal logistics center or an equivalent planning term. <Reference Number="2"/>For the purpose of this section, the term “intermodal logistics center” means a facility or group of facilities, including, but not limited to, an inland port, serving as a point of intermodal transfer of freight in a specific area physically separated from a seaport whose activities relating to transport, logistics, goods distribution, consolidation, or value-added activities are carried out and whose activities and services are designed to support or be supported by one or more seaports, as provided in s. 311.09, or an airport whose activities and services are designed to support the transport, logistics, goods distribution, consolidation, or value-added activities related to airborne cargo.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility designated part of the Strategic Intermodal System pursuant to paragraph (a) that is within the jurisdiction of a local government <Reference Number="3"/>that maintains a transportation concurrency system shall receive a waiver of transportation concurrency requirements applicable to Strategic Intermodal System facilities in order to accommodate any development at the facility which occurs pursuant to a building permit issued on or before December 31, 2017, but only if such facility is located:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within an area designated pursuant to s. 288.0656(7) as a rural area of critical economic concern;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within a rural enterprise zone as defined in s. 290.004(5); or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 miles of the boundary of a rural area of critical economic concern or a rural enterprise zone.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 48, ch. 2003-286; s. 45, ch. 2007-196; s. 5, ch. 2011-164; s. 35, ch. 2012-128; s. 58, ch. 2012-174.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 58, ch. 2012-174. Subsection (5) was also created by s. 35, ch. 2012-128, and that version did not include the words “as defined in s. 311.101(2).”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 35, ch. 2012-128. Subsection (5) was also created by s. 58, ch. 2012-174, and that version did not include this sentence.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 58, ch. 2012-174. Subsection (5) was also created by s. 35, ch. 2012-128, and that version used the words “and which” instead of the word “that.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>