<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0339.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of moneys in State Transportation Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall expend moneys in the State Transportation Trust Fund accruing to the department, in accordance with its annual budget. The use of such moneys shall be restricted to the following purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay administrative expenses of the department, including administrative expenses incurred by the several state transportation districts, but excluding administrative expenses of commuter rail authorities that do not operate rail service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of construction of the State Highway System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of maintaining the State Highway System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of public transportation projects in accordance with chapter 341 and ss. 332.003-332.007.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reimburse counties or municipalities for expenditures made on projects in the State Highway System as authorized by s. 339.12(4) upon legislative approval.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of economic development transportation projects in accordance with s. 339.2821.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To lend or pay a portion of the operating, maintenance, and capital costs of a revenue-producing transportation project that is located on the State Highway System or that is demonstrated to relieve traffic congestion on the State Highway System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To match any federal-aid funds allocated for any other transportation purpose, including funds allocated to projects not located in the State Highway System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of county road projects selected in accordance with the Small County Road Assistance Program created in s. 339.2816.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of county or municipal road projects selected in accordance with the County Incentive Grant Program created in s. 339.2817, the Small County Outreach Program created in s. 339.2818, and the Enhanced Bridge Program for Sustainable Transportation created in s. 339.285.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide loans and credit enhancements for use in constructing and improving highway transportation facilities selected in accordance with the state-funded infrastructure bank created in s. 339.55.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of projects on the Florida Strategic Intermodal System created in s. 339.61.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the cost of transportation projects selected in accordance with the Transportation Regional Incentive Program created in s. 339.2819.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay other lawful expenditures of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless specifically provided in the General Appropriations Act or the substantive bill implementing the General Appropriations Act, no moneys in the State Transportation Trust Fund may be used to fund the operational or capital outlay cost for any correctional facility of the Department of Corrections. The department shall, however, enter into contractual arrangements with the Department of Corrections for those specific maintenance functions that can be performed effectively by prison inmates under the supervision of Department of Corrections personnel with technical assistance being provided by the department. The cost of such contracts must not exceed the cost that would be incurred by the department if these functions were to be performed by its personnel or by contract with another entity unless, notwithstanding cost, the department can clearly demonstrate that for reasons of expediency or efficiency it is in the best interests of the department to contract with the Department of Corrections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may authorize the investment of the earnings accrued and collected upon the investment of the minimum balance of funds required to be maintained in the State Transportation Trust Fund pursuant to s. 339.135(6)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2011-2012 fiscal year only and notwithstanding this section and ss. 339.09(1) and 215.32(2)(b)4., funds may be transferred from the State Transportation Trust Fund to the State School Trust Fund or the General Revenue Fund as specified in the General Appropriations Act. Notwithstanding ss. 206.46(3) and 206.606(2), the total amount transferred shall be reduced from total state revenues deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund for the calculation requirements of ss. 206.46(3) and 206.606(2). This subsection expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 139, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 1, ch. 31416, 1956; s. 19, ch. 57-318; s. 1, ch. 63-219; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 13, ch. 77-165; s. 4, ch. 77-416; s. 1, ch. 78-286; s. 118, ch. 79-190; s. 2, ch. 80-312; s. 1, ch. 82-120; s. 38, ch. 83-3; s. 1, ch. 83-346; ss. 207, 213, ch. 84-309; ss. 70, 81, ch. 85-180; s. 6, ch. 87-93; s. 4, ch. 87-164; s. 45, ch. 88-201; s. 24, ch. 88-557; s. 71, ch. 92-152; s. 69, ch. 93-164; s. 42, ch. 93-187; s. 40, ch. 96-323; ss. 31, 99, ch. 99-385; s. 14, ch. 2000-257; s. 77, ch. 2003-399; s. 8, ch. 2004-366; s. 14, ch. 2005-3; s. 20, ch. 2005-290; ss. 29, 53, ch. 2007-73; s. 38, ch. 2007-196; s. 33, ch. 2008-153; ss. 41, 42, 43, ch. 2009-82; s. 13, ch. 2010-139; ss. 37, 38, 39, 72, ch. 2010-153; ss. 44, 45, 81, ch. 2011-47; s. 4, ch. 2012-6; s. 30, ch. 2012-128.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 22, ch. 2000-257, provides that “[n]otwithstanding any other law to the contrary the requirements of sections 206.46(3) and 206.606(2), Florida Statutes, shall not apply to any funding, programs, or other provisions contained in this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>