<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0339.177" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transportation management programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall, in cooperation with metropolitan planning organizations and other affected governmental entities, develop and implement a separate and distinct system for managing each of the following program areas:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Highway pavement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bridges;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Highway safety;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Traffic congestion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public transportation facilities and equipment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intermodal transportation facilities and equipment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each metropolitan planning organization within the state must develop and implement a traffic congestion management system. The development of the state traffic congestion management system pursuant to subsection (1) shall be coordinated with metropolitan planning organizations so that the state system is reflective of the individual systems developed by the metropolitan planning organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The management systems required by this section should be developed and implemented so as to provide the information needed to make informed decisions regarding the proper allocation of transportation resources. Each system must use appropriate data gathered at the state or local level to define problems, identify needs, analyze alternatives, and measure effectiveness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transportation management system that is in existence on July 1, 1993, and that complies with this section and applicable federal law may continue to be used by the department in lieu of the development of a system under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 61, ch. 93-164.</History></Section>