<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0310.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, except where the context clearly indicates otherwise:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vessel” includes every description of watercraft or other artificial contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation on water.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pilot” means a licensed state pilot or a certificated deputy pilot.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Pilot Commissioners.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Port” means any place in the state into which vessels enter or depart and includes, without limitation, Fernandina, Nassau Inlet, Jacksonville, St. Augustine, Canaveral, Ft. Pierce, Palm Beach, Port Everglades, Miami, Key West, Boca Grande, Charlotte Harbor, Punta Gorda, Tampa, Port Tampa, Port Manatee, St. Petersburg, Clearwater, Apalachicola, Carrabelle, Panama City, Port St. Joe, and Pensacola.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pilotage waters of the state” means the navigable waters within the boundaries of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Piloting” means the acts of pilots in conducting vessels through the pilotage waters of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pilotage” means the compensation fixed by the Pilotage Rate Review Committee which is payable by a vessel, its owners, agents, charterers, or consignees to one or more pilots in the port where piloting is performed. The word “pilotage” also means the compensation of all types and sources derived by one or more pilots or deputy pilots for the performance of piloting at that port by licensed pilots or by certificated deputy pilots, whether such piloting is performed pursuant to this chapter or is performed by state-licensed pilots or state-certificated deputy pilots when acting as a federal pilot for vessels not required by this chapter to use a state-licensed pilot or state-certificated deputy pilot.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” or “certificate” means the document issued by the board under seal of the department to pilots.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 75-201; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 16, ch. 78-140; s. 185, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 3, ch. 84-185; ss. 1, 10, 11, ch. 86-280; s. 2, ch. 89-262; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 339, ch. 94-119; s. 32, ch. 94-218; s. 3, ch. 2010-225.</History>
</Section>