<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0310.073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State pilot licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to meeting other requirements specified in this chapter, each applicant for license as a state pilot must:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 21 years of age, as evidenced by a copy of a birth certificate or other legal proof of age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have successfully completed 12 years of formal education, as evidenced by a high school diploma or by equivalent evidence thereof that is satisfactory to the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be in good physical and mental health, as evidenced by documentary proof of having satisfactorily passed a complete physical examination administered by a licensed physician within the preceding 6 months. The board shall adopt rules to establish requirements for passing the physical examination, which rules shall establish minimum standards for the physical or mental capabilities necessary to carry out the professional duties of a licensed state pilot. Such standards shall include zero tolerance for any controlled substance regulated under chapter 893 unless that individual is under the care of a physician and that controlled substance was prescribed by that physician. To maintain eligibility as a licensed state pilot, each licensed state pilot must annually provide documentary proof of having satisfactorily passed a complete physical examination administered by a licensed physician. The physician must know the minimum standards and certify that the licensee satisfactorily meets the standards. The standards for licensees shall include a drug test.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have had at least 2 years of service as a deputy pilot in the port in which license as a licensed state pilot is desired, which service must have been attained during the period immediately preceding the examination required under s. 310.081(1). Further, at the time of application, each applicant must have a valid United States Coast Guard first-class unlimited pilot’s license covering all of the waters of the port in which license as a state pilot is desired and must have successfully completed the board-approved deputy pilot training program in the port in which license as a state pilot is desired.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 11, ch. 86-280; s. 2, ch. 89-262; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 342, ch. 94-119.</History></Section>