<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.713" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance against liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bidder must provide an adequate plan of insurance against liability, including liability for violations of an inmate’s civil rights by an insurance agency licensed in this state, pursuant to chapter 287. The insurance plan shall, at a minimum, protect the department from actions of a third party, assure the private vendor’s ability to fulfill the conditions of the contract, and provide adequate protection for the department against claims arising as a result of any occurrence during the term of the contract on an occurrence basis. The adequacy of the insurance plan shall be determined, at the bidder’s expense, by an independent risk management or actuarial firm selected by the Department of Management Services. The risk management or actuarial firm selected must have demonstrated experience in assessing public liability of state government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall provide for indemnification of the state by the private vendor for any liabilities incurred up to the limits provided under s. 768.28(5). The contract shall provide that the private vendor, or the insurer of the private vendor, is liable to pay any claim or judgment for any one person which does not exceed the sum of $100,000 or any claim or judgment, or portions thereof, which, when totaled with all other claims or judgments arising out of the same incident or occurrence, does not exceed the sum of $200,000. In addition, the contractor must agree to defend, hold harmless, and indemnify the department against any and all actions, claims, damages and losses, including costs and attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 89-526; s. 316, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326.</History></Section>