<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.613" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Methods of transportation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OUT-OF-STATE RELEASEE.<EmDash />In instances when a releasee intends or is required to leave the state, transportation shall be provided by common carrier utilizing the most economical means. Transportation as authorized herein shall be furnished by nonnegotiable travel voucher payable to the common carrier being utilized, and in no event shall there be any cash disbursement to the releasee or any person, firm, or corporation. Such travel voucher shall not be valid for more than 5 days after its issuance. The source of any private transportation must be by a family member or friend whose purpose is to immediately transport the releasee out of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA RELEASEE.<EmDash />In instances when a releasee remains in this state but leaves the county where the correctional institution or facility of her or his confinement is located, transportation shall be provided by common carrier using the most economical means. Transportation as authorized herein shall be furnished by nonnegotiable travel voucher payable to the common carrier being utilized, and in no event shall there be any cash disbursement to the releasee or any person, firm, or corporation. Such travel voucher is to be utilized immediately by the releasee. The source of any private transportation must be a family member or friend whose purpose is to immediately transport the releasee to the approved location pursuant to <Reference Number="1" />section 1.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 83-131; s. 1660, ch. 97-102.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This cross-reference is erroneous; the intended reference may be to s. 38, ch. 83-131, compiled as s. 944.611.</Text></Note></Section>