<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.1905" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Initial inmate classification; inmate reclassification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall classify inmates pursuant to an objective classification scheme. The initial inmate classification questionnaire and the inmate reclassification questionnaire must cover both aggravating and mitigating factors.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In scoring either the initial inmate classification questionnaire or the inmate reclassification questionnaire, points must be added to the inmate’s overall score for factors indicating the inmate’s custody risk. Such factors may include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the crime;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The length of the sentence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The verified history involving intentional violence.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In scoring the initial inmate classification questionnaire, points may be deducted from the inmate’s overall score for factors indicating the inmate’s stability. Such factors may include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Age 30 or over;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">High school diploma or GED received; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time employment, full-time school attendance, or part-time employment and part-time school attendance for 6 months or longer at the time of arrest.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Points may be deducted from the inmate’s overall score on the inmate reclassification questionnaire for continuous positive behavior. Continuous positive behavior may include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lack of any major penalties for a specified period of time;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of any correctional programs aimed at self-betterment, such as drug or alcohol counseling, vocational training, or academic programs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Above-average behavior or progress on work squads outside the perimeter of the institution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Above-average behavior or progress in any employment inside the perimeter of the institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall cross-validate the initial inmate classification questionnaire and the inmate reclassification questionnaire using custody score sheets from other states to determine the validity of the Florida model. If any items prove to be invalid, the department may revise either questionnaire as needed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or chapter 958, the department shall assign to facilities housing youthful offenders all inmates who are less than 18 years of age and who have not been assigned to a facility for youthful offenders under the provisions of chapter 958. Such an inmate shall be assigned to a facility for youthful offenders until the inmate is 18 years of age; however, the department may assign the inmate to a facility for youthful offenders until the inmate reaches an age not to exceed 21 years if the department determines that the continued assignment is in the best interests of the inmate and the assignment does not pose an unreasonable risk to other inmates in the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inmate who is assigned to a facility under paragraph (a) is subject to the provisions of s. 958.11 regarding facility assignments, and shall be removed and reassigned to the general inmate population if his or her behavior threatens the safety of other inmates or correctional staff.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 83, ch. 88-122; s. 1, ch. 2001-210; s. 148, ch. 2005-2; s. 3, ch. 2008-250.</History></Section>