<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.485" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subsistence fees with respect to certain prisoners; time of adoption; requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the fact that many prisoners in the correctional system have sources of income and assets outside of the correctional system, which may include bank accounts, inheritances, real estate, social security payments, veteran’s payments, and other types of financial resources, and in recognition of the fact that the daily subsistence cost of incarcerating prisoners in the correctional system is a great burden on the taxpayers of the state, each prisoner in the state correctional system, except those who have entered into an agreement under s. 947.135 prior to October 1, 1978:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall disclose all revenue or assets as a condition of parole or other release eligibility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall pay from such income and assets, except where such income is exempt by state or federal law, all or a fair portion of the prisoner’s daily subsistence costs, based upon the inmate’s ability to pay, the liability or potential liability of the inmate to the victim or the guardian or the estate of the victim, and the needs of his or her dependents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any prisoner who is directed to pay all or a fair portion of daily subsistence costs is entitled to reasonable advance notice of the assessment and shall be afforded an opportunity to present reasons for opposition to the assessment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order directing payment of all or a fair portion of a prisoner’s daily subsistence costs may survive against the estate of the prisoner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-441; s. 1, ch. 92-298; s. 1652, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>