<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.096" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budget requests for residential facility construction; estimates; appropriations; population in excess of capacity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning October 1, 1983, all legislative budget requests for the construction of additional residential facilities in the Department of Corrections shall utilize the estimates of the Criminal Justice Estimating Conference. The estimates shall be based on current legal and constitutional standards and be accompanied by a supporting projected estimate of the inmate population for the period covered by the budget request. Each estimate shall include, but shall not be limited to, consideration of the following factors:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current sentencing practices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current parole practices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current Department of Corrections program rules.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature shall accept the projected estimate from the Criminal Justice Estimating Conference as accurate, but it is not obligated to fund any budget based on the estimate. The Legislature may elect to modify any programs, practices, or procedures listed in subsection (1) and, based on a revised estimate of the impact of these modifications by the Criminal Justice Estimating Conference, adjust the level of required funding accordingly. Alternatively, the Legislature may elect to offset the need for funding the construction of residential facilities to meet the projected need through the establishment of programs alternative to incarceration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the inmate population exceeds the total capacity of the residential facilities provided by the Legislature pursuant to this section, the control release procedures as defined in s. 947.146 shall apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal Justice Estimating Conference” means the designated professional staffs of the Governor’s office, the Legislature, and the Supreme Court who meet in regularly scheduled meetings chaired by the state economist or the state economist’s designee to forecast inmate and caseload counts and other information needed to support the state budgeting process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Total capacity” of the state correctional system as defined in s. 944.023(1)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State correctional system” means the system as defined in s. 944.02.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 4, ch. 83-131; s. 2, ch. 87-234; s. 14, ch. 89-531; s. 9, ch. 92-47; s. 78, ch. 95-211; s. 3, ch. 95-251; s. 1644, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>