<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.707" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Postrelease special services; job placement services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall generate and provide to every releasee, identified by the prerelease needs assessment, support services such as, but not limited to, substance abuse counseling, family counseling, and employment support programs. The department may select and contract with public or private organizations, including faith-based service groups, for the provision of these basic support services. When selecting a provider, the department shall consider faith-based service groups on an equal basis with other private organizations. Provider selection criteria include, but are not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depth and scope of services provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The geographic area to be served.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of inmates to be served and the cost of services per inmate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual provider’s record of success in the provision of inmate services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, with the assistance of the State Office on Homelessness, shall maintain and regularly update a comprehensive directory of support services offered by private organizations and faith-based service groups for the purpose of assisting transition assistance specialists and chaplains in making individualized placements and referrals.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 12, ch. 87-298; s. 13, ch. 88-122; s. 32, ch. 89-526; s. 11, ch. 92-310; s. 24, ch. 95-283; s. 12, ch. 2001-110.</History></Section>