<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Housing of inmates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 944.17, the department may contract with county or municipal facilities for the purpose of housing inmates committed to the department.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 944.17 and 944.1905, before transferring a state inmate to another facility as authorized under this section, the inmate must be reclassified and scored as to custody risk based on the current offense and not on prior criminal history. Upon return to a state correctional institution, the inmate must be reclassified based on ss. 944.17 and 944.1905.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inmate placed in another facility under this section remains under the jurisdiction of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 944.17, the department may enter into contracts with another state, a political subdivision of another state, or a correctional management services vendor in another state for the transfer and confinement in that state of inmates who have been committed to the custody of the department.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such contract must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A termination date.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions concerning the costs of inmate maintenance, extraordinary medical and dental expenses, and any participation in or receipt by inmates of rehabilitative or correctional services, facilities, programs, or treatment, including those costs not reasonably included as part of normal maintenance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions concerning participation in programs of inmate employment, if any, the disposition or crediting of any payments received by inmates on account of employment, and the crediting of proceeds or disposal of any products resulting from employment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for the delivery and retaking of inmates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision for a waiver of extradition by the parties to the contract.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retention of jurisdiction of the inmates transferred by Florida.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regular reporting procedures concerning Florida inmates by officials of the state, political subdivision, or correctional management services vendor with which the department is contracting.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions concerning procedures for community supervision, including probation, parole, conditional release, and discharge.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The same standards of reasonable and humane care as the inmates would receive in an appropriate institution in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other matters that are necessary and appropriate to establish the obligations, responsibilities, and rights of Florida and the state, political subdivision, or correctional management services vendor with which the department is contracting.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inmates from Florida state prisons while in an institution in another state are subject to all the laws and rules concerning the confinement of persons committed for violations of the laws of that state, except that the sentence must be executed consistent with the sentencing and gain-time laws of this state and except as otherwise provided for by any contract entered into under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Parole Commission shall conduct any parole hearing for an inmate confined under a contract pursuant to this section according to the rules of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracts under this section shall be procured in accordance with s. 287.057.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any beds contracted under this section shall be added to the total capacity of the correctional system as defined in s. 944.023, notwithstanding any law to the contrary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making placements authorized by this section, the department shall consider, to the extent possible, the proximity of the receiving facility to the inmate’s family, consistent with s. 944.8031.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2009-63.</History></Section>