<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is desirable that each inmate be confined in and released from an institution or facility as close to the inmate’s permanent residence or county of commitment as possible, in order to lessen the transportation expense to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent possible, an inmate be returned, upon release, to the same area from which the inmate was committed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inmate being released from a community work-release program is not eligible for the provision of transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation provided for an eligible inmate upon release shall be to one of the following points:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county where parole placement has been approved and supervision is to commence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Another state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county of employment within the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county of legal residence within the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county of original commitment within the state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each releasee who is eligible for the provision of transportation shall be escorted to the site of embarkation by an officer of the correctional facility, who shall remain until the releasee has departed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 38, ch. 83-131; s. 1658, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>