<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Release orientation program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide participation in a standardized release orientation program to every eligible inmate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The release orientation program instruction must include, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment skills.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Money management skills.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal development and planning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community reentry concerns.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community reentry support.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other appropriate instruction to ensure the inmate’s successful reentry into the community.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inmate who claims to be a victim of domestic violence as defined in s. 741.28 shall receive, as part of the release orientation program, referral to the nearest domestic violence center certified under chapter 39.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct a needs assessment of every inmate to determine which, if any, basic support services the inmate needs after release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract with public or private entities, including faith-based service groups, for the provision of all or part of the services pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall notify every inmate, in no less than 18-point type in the inmate’s release documents, that the inmate may be sentenced pursuant to s. 775.082(9) if the inmate commits any felony offense described in s. 775.082(9) within 3 years after the inmate’s release. This notice must be prefaced by the word “WARNING” in boldfaced type.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section precludes the sentencing of a person pursuant to s. 775.082(9), nor shall evidence that the department failed to provide this notice prohibit a person from being sentenced pursuant to s. 775.082(9). The state shall not be required to demonstrate that a person received any notice from the department in order for the court to impose a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082(9).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 12, ch. 87-298; ss. 12, 13, ch. 88-122; s. 31, ch. 89-526; s. 9, ch. 91-210; s. 9, ch. 92-310; s. 26, ch. 94-134; s. 26, ch. 94-135; s. 3, ch. 97-239; s. 17, ch. 98-204; s. 164, ch. 98-403; s. 10, ch. 2001-110.</History></Section>