<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of correctional institutions for women.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Corrections Equality Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All regularly employed assistants, officers, and employees whose duties bring them into contact with the inmates of the institution shall be women as far as practicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Women inmates shall have access to programs of education, vocational training, rehabilitation, and substance abuse treatment that are equivalent to those programs which are provided for male inmates. The department shall ensure that women inmates are given opportunities for exercise, recreation, and visitation privileges according to the same standards as those privileges are provided for men. Women inmates shall be given opportunities to participate in work-release programs which are comparable to the opportunities provided for male inmates and shall be eligible for early release according to the same standards and procedures under which male inmates are eligible for early release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall continue to provide prenatal care and such medical treatment as determined by the Assistant Secretary for Health Services for an inmate who is pregnant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inmate who is pregnant shall be provided with prenatal care and medical treatment for the duration of her pregnancy. The department shall ensure that a pregnant inmate receives supplemental food and clothing and is excused from inappropriate work assignments. An inmate shall be transferred to a hospital outside the prison grounds if a condition develops which is beyond the scope and capabilities of the prison’s medical facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any woman inmate who gives birth to a child during her term of imprisonment may be temporarily taken to a hospital outside the prison for the purpose of childbirth, and the charge for hospital and medical care shall be charged against the funds allocated to the institution. The department shall provide for the care of any child so born and shall pay for the child’s care until the child is suitably placed outside the prison system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 57-121; s. 18, ch. 61-530; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 46, ch. 77-120; s. 55, ch. 79-3; s. 1, ch. 79-331; ss. 1, 2, ch. 81-15; s. 1, ch. 91-195; s. 29, ch. 91-225.</History></Section>