<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.47" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Introduction, removal, or possession of certain articles unlawful; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except through regular channels as authorized by the officer in charge of the correctional institution, it is unlawful to introduce into or upon the grounds of any state correctional institution, or to take or attempt to take or send or attempt to send therefrom, any of the following articles which are hereby declared to be contraband for the purposes of this section, to wit:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any written or recorded communication or any currency or coin given or transmitted, or intended to be given or transmitted, to any inmate of any state correctional institution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any article of food or clothing given or transmitted, or intended to be given or transmitted, to any inmate of any state correctional institution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any intoxicating beverage or beverage which causes or may cause an intoxicating effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any controlled substance as defined in s. 893.02(4) or any prescription or nonprescription drug having a hypnotic, stimulating, or depressing effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firearm or weapon of any kind or any explosive substance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any cellular telephone or other portable communication device intentionally and unlawfully introduced inside the secure perimeter of any state correctional institution without prior authorization or consent from the officer in charge of such correctional institution. As used in this subparagraph, the term “portable communication device” means any device carried, worn, or stored which is designed or intended to receive or transmit verbal or written messages, access or store data, or connect electronically to the Internet or any other electronic device and which allows communications in any form. Such devices include, but are not limited to, portable two-way pagers, hand-held radios, cellular telephones, Blackberry-type devices, personal digital assistants or PDA’s, laptop computers, or any components of these devices which are intended to be used to assemble such devices. The term also includes any new technology that is developed for similar purposes. Excluded from this definition is any device having communication capabilities which has been approved or issued by the department for investigative or institutional security purposes or for conducting other state business.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to transmit or attempt to transmit to, or cause or attempt to cause to be transmitted to or received by, any inmate of any state correctional institution any article or thing declared by this subsection to be contraband, at any place which is outside the grounds of such institution, except through regular channels as authorized by the officer in charge of such correctional institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any inmate of any state correctional institution or any person while upon the grounds of any state correctional institution to be in actual or constructive possession of any article or thing declared by this section to be contraband, except as authorized by the officer in charge of such correctional institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of this section as it pertains to an article of contraband described in subparagraph (1)(a)1., subparagraph (1)(a)2., or subparagraph (1)(a)6. commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. In all other cases, a violation of a provision of this section constitutes a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 57-313; s. 8, ch. 61-192; s. 1, ch. 65-225; s. 1, ch. 67-160; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1176, ch. 71-136; s. 60, ch. 77-120; s. 1, ch. 78-42; s. 70, ch. 79-3; s. 2, ch. 81-88; s. 1, ch. 82-124; s. 184, ch. 83-216; s. 1, ch. 84-1; s. 52, ch. 91-110; s. 4, ch. 2008-250.</History></Section>