<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0944.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Corrections to provide buildings; sale and purchase of land; contracts to provide services and inmate labor.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to expedite the siting of, acquisition of land for, and construction by the Department of Corrections of state correctional facilities operated by the department or a private vendor under contract with the department. Other agencies shall cooperate with the department and expeditiously fulfill their responsibilities to avoid unnecessary delay in the siting of, acquisition of land for, and construction of state correctional facilities. This section and all other laws of the state shall be construed to accomplish this intent. This section shall take precedence over any other law to the contrary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall cause all necessary buildings, facilities, and physical plants to be erected to accommodate all prisoners and from time to time shall make such additional alterations as may be necessary to provide for any increase in the number of prisoners; it shall cause to be established proper accommodations for such officers of the department who are required to reside constantly within the precincts of the institutions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into lease-purchase agreements to provide correctional facilities for the housing of state inmates. However, no such lease-purchase agreement shall be entered into without specific legislative authorization of that agreement, and funds must be specifically appropriated for each lease-purchase agreement. The facilities provided through such agreements shall meet the program plans and specifications of the department. The department may enter into such lease agreements with private corporations and other governmental entities. However, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 255.25(3)(a), no such lease agreement may be entered into except upon advertisement for and receipt of competitive bids and award to the lowest and best bidder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such a lease-purchase agreement which is for a term extending beyond the end of a fiscal year shall be subject to the provisions of s. 216.311.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025 or s. 287.057, whenever the department finds it to be necessary for timely site acquisition, it may contract without the need for competitive selection with one or more appraisers whose names are contained on the list of approved appraisers maintained by the Division of State Lands of the Department of Environmental Protection in accordance with s. 253.025(6)(b). In those instances in which the department directly contracts for appraisal services, it must also contract with an approved appraiser who is not employed by the same appraisal firm for review services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025(6), the department may negotiate and enter into an option contract before an appraisal is obtained. The option contract must state that the final purchase price cannot exceed the maximum value allowed by law. The consideration for such an option contract may not exceed 10 percent of the estimate obtained by the department or 10 percent of the value of the parcel, whichever amount is greater.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to any purchase or acquisition of state land except for a purchase or acquisition made specifically for correctional facilities. This subsection does not mitigate in any manner the authority of the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund or the Division of State Lands to approve any contract for purchase for state lands as provided by law or to require policies and procedures to obtain clear legal title to parcels purchased for state purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may sell, to the best possible advantage, any or all detached parcels of land belonging to the bodies of land purchased for the state correctional institutions. The department is authorized to purchase any contiguous parcels of land within the boundary lines of the lands purchased for state correctional institutions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to begin preliminary site preparation and obtain the appropriate permits with regard to the construction of state correctional institutions after approval by the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of the purchase agreement or option agreement if, in the department’s discretion, commencing construction is in the best interests of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into contracts with federal, state, or local governmental entities or subdivisions to provide services and inmate labor for the construction of buildings, parks, roads, any detention or commitment facilities, or any other project deemed to be appropriate by the Department of Corrections, which includes site acquisition or preparation, management, or construction of such projects. The department may charge fees for providing such services. All fees collected must be placed in the Correctional Work Program Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 57-121; s. 18, ch. 61-530; ss. 19, 22, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-441; s. 2, ch. 75-70; s. 35, ch. 77-120; s. 45, ch. 79-3; s. 4, ch. 85-340; s. 60, ch. 85-349; s. 50, ch. 91-110; s. 315, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 1, ch. 94-273; s. 40, ch. 96-312; s. 7, ch. 98-388; s. 118, ch. 99-3; s. 1, ch. 99-258; s. 4, ch. 99-271; ss. 3, 4, ch. 2009-63.</History>
</Section>