<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security of correctional institutions and facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the Department of Corrections shall be responsible for the security of the correctional institutions and facilities. The security of the state’s correctional institutions and facilities is critical to ensure public safety and to contain violent and chronic offenders until offenders are otherwise released from the department’s custody pursuant to law. The Secretary of Corrections shall, at a minimum:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a security review committee which shall, at a minimum, be composed of: the inspector general, the statewide security coordinator, the regional security coordinators, and three wardens and one correctional officer. The security review committee shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a periodic schedule for the physical inspection of buildings and structures of each state and private correctional institution to determine security deficiencies. In scheduling the inspections, priority shall be given to older institutions, institutions that house a large proportion of violent offenders, and institutions that have experienced a significant number of escapes or escape attempts in the past.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct or cause to be conducted announced and unannounced comprehensive security audits of all state and private correctional institutions. In conducting the security audits, priority shall be given to older institutions, institutions that house a large proportion of violent offenders, and institutions that have experienced a history of escapes or escape attempts. At a minimum, the audit shall include an evaluation of the physical plant, landscaping, fencing, security alarms and perimeter lighting, and inmate classification and staffing policies. Each correctional institution shall be audited at least annually. The secretary shall report the general survey findings annually to the Governor and the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and enforce minimum security standards and policies that include, but are not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Random monitoring of outgoing telephone calls by inmates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of current photographs of all inmates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Daily inmate counts at varied intervals.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of canine units, where appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of escape alarms and perimeter lighting.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Crime Information Center/National Crime Information Center capabilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment background investigations.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually make written prioritized budget recommendations to the secretary that identify critical security deficiencies at major correctional institutions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate and evaluate the usefulness and dependability of existing security technology at the institutions and new technology available and make periodic written recommendations to the secretary on the discontinuation or purchase of various security devices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract, if deemed necessary, with security personnel, consulting engineers, architects, or other security experts the committee deems necessary for security audits and security consultant services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a periodic schedule for conducting announced and unannounced escape simulation drills.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain and produce quarterly reports with accurate escape statistics. For the purposes of these reports, “escape” includes all possible types of escape, regardless of prosecution by the state attorney, and including offenders who walk away from nonsecure community facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, enforce, and annually evaluate the emergency escape response procedures, which shall at a minimum include the immediate notification and inclusion of local and state law enforcement through a mutual aid agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit in the annual legislative budget request a prioritized summary of critical repair and renovation security needs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 95-283; s. 13, ch. 2000-161.</History></Section>