<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0944.095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Siting of additional correctional facilities; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the siting of additional correctional facilities shall be achieved in the most cost-efficient manner possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department proposes a site for a state correctional facility, it shall request that the local government having jurisdiction over such proposed site determine whether or not the proposed site is in compliance with local government comprehensive plans, local land use ordinances, local zoning ordinances or regulations, and other local ordinances in effect at the time of such request. If no such determination is made within 90 days of the request, it shall be presumed that the proposed site is in compliance with such plans, ordinances, or regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government determines within 90 days of the request that construction of a correctional facility on the proposed site does not comply with any such plan, ordinance, or regulation, the department may request a modification of such plan, ordinance, or regulation without having an ownership interest in such property. For the purposes of this section, modification includes, but is not limited to, a variance, rezoning, special exception, or any other action of the local government having jurisdiction over the proposed site which would authorize siting of a correctional facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a request for modification from the department, the local government may recommend alternative sites to the department and shall give notice and hold a public hearing on the request for modification in the same manner as for a rezoning as provided under the appropriate special or local law or ordinance, except that such proceeding shall be recorded by tape or by a certified court reporter and made available for transcription at the expense of any interested party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department requests such a modification and it is denied by the local government or there is no action on such request within 90 days of the request, the department may appeal the decision of the local government on the requested modification of local plans, ordinances, or regulations to the Governor and Cabinet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet shall consider the following when determining whether to grant the appeal from the decision of the local government on the requested modification:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The record of the proceedings before the local government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports and studies by any other agency relating to matters within the jurisdiction of such agency which matters may be potentially affected by the proposed site.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing studies and reports and information maintained by the department as the Governor and Cabinet may request addressing the feasibility and availability of alternative sites in the general area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet, upon determining that the local government has recommended no feasible alternative site and that the interests of the state in providing correctional facilities outweigh the concerns of the local government, shall authorize construction and operation of a correctional facility on the proposed site notwithstanding any local plan, ordinance, or regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet may adopt rules of procedure to govern these proceedings in accordance with the provisions of s. 120.54.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the department or the Governor and Cabinet pursuant to this section shall not be subject to the provisions of ss. 120.56, 120.569, and 120.57. The decision by the Governor and Cabinet shall be subject to judicial review pursuant to s. 120.68 in the District Court of Appeal, First District.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insofar as the provisions of this section are inconsistent with the provisions of any other law, general, special, or local, the provisions of this section are controlling. Additionally, the criteria and procedures set forth in this section supersede and are in lieu of any review and approval required by s. 380.06.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 83-131; s. 74, ch. 85-62; s. 4, ch. 89-375; s. 4, ch. 89-536; s. 5, ch. 93-408; s. 17, ch. 95-283; s. 320, ch. 96-410.</History></Section>