<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0171.043" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Character of the area to be annexed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipal governing body may propose to annex an area only if it meets the general standards of subsection (1) and the requirements of either subsection (2) or subsection (3).</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total area to be annexed must be contiguous to the municipality’s boundaries at the time the annexation proceeding is begun and reasonably compact, and no part of the area shall be included within the boundary of another incorporated municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Part or all of the area to be annexed must be developed for urban purposes. An area developed for urban purposes is defined as any area which meets any one of the following standards:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It has a total resident population equal to at least two persons for each acre of land included within its boundaries;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It has a total resident population equal to at least one person for each acre of land included within its boundaries and is subdivided into lots and tracts so that at least 60 percent of the total number of lots and tracts are 1 acre or less in size; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is so developed that at least 60 percent of the total number of lots and tracts in the area at the time of annexation are used for urban purposes, and it is subdivided into lots and tracts so that at least 60 percent of the total acreage, not counting the acreage used at the time of annexation for nonresidential urban purposes, consists of lots and tracts 5 acres or less in size.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the area developed for urban purposes, a municipal governing body may include in the area to be annexed any area which does not meet the requirements of subsection (2) if such area either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lies between the municipal boundary and an area developed for urban purposes, so that the area developed for urban purposes is either not adjacent to the municipal boundary or cannot be served by the municipality without extending services or water or sewer lines through such sparsely developed area; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is adjacent, on at least 60 percent of its external boundary, to any combination of the municipal boundary and the boundary of an area or areas developed for urban purposes as defined in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The purpose of this subsection is to permit municipal governing bodies to extend corporate limits to include all nearby areas developed for urban purposes and, where necessary, to include areas which at the time of annexation are not yet developed for urban purposes whose future probable use is urban and which constitute necessary land connections between the municipality and areas developed for urban purposes or between two or more areas developed for urban purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-190; s. 2, ch. 76-176.</History></Section>