<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0171.204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prerequisites to annexation under this part.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interlocal service boundary agreement may describe the character of land that may be annexed under this part and may provide that the restrictions on the character of land that may be annexed pursuant to part I are not restrictions on land that may be annexed pursuant to this part. As determined in the interlocal service boundary agreement, any character of land may be annexed, including, but not limited to, an annexation of land not contiguous to the boundaries of the annexing municipality, an annexation that creates an enclave, or an annexation where the annexed area is not reasonably compact; however, such area must be “urban in character” as defined in s. 171.031(8). The interlocal service boundary agreement may not allow for annexation of land within a municipality that is not a party to the agreement or of land that is within another county. Before annexation of land that is not contiguous to the boundaries of the annexing municipality, an annexation that creates an enclave, or an annexation of land that is not currently served by water or sewer utilities, one of the following options must be followed:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The municipality shall transmit a comprehensive plan amendment that proposes specific amendments relating to the property anticipated for annexation to the Department of Economic Opportunity for review under chapter 163. After considering the department’s review, the municipality may approve the annexation and comprehensive plan amendment concurrently. The local government must adopt the annexation and the comprehensive plan amendment as separate and distinct actions but may take such actions at a single public hearing; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality and county shall enter into a joint planning agreement under s. 163.3171, which is adopted into the municipal comprehensive plan. The joint planning agreement must identify the geographic areas anticipated for annexation, the future land uses that the municipality would seek to establish, necessary public facilities and services, including transportation and school facilities and how they will be provided, and natural resources, including surface water and groundwater resources, and how they will be protected. An amendment to the future land use map of a comprehensive plan which is consistent with the joint planning agreement must be considered a small scale amendment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2006-218; s. 61, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>