<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0171.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effects of annexations or contractions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area annexed to a municipality shall be subject to all laws, ordinances, and regulations in force in that municipality and shall be entitled to the same privileges and benefits as other parts of that municipality upon the effective date of the annexation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the area annexed was subject to a county land use plan and county zoning or subdivision regulations, these regulations remain in full force and effect until the municipality adopts a comprehensive plan amendment that includes the annexed area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area excluded from a municipality shall no longer be subject to any laws, ordinances, or regulations in force in the municipality from which it was excluded and shall no longer be entitled to the privileges and benefits accruing to the area within the municipal boundaries upon the effective date of the exclusion. It shall be subject to all laws, ordinances, and regulations in force in that county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party that has an exclusive franchise which was in effect for at least 6 months prior to the initiation of an annexation to provide solid waste collection services in an unincorporated area may continue to provide such services to an annexed area for 5 years or the remainder of the franchise term, whichever is shorter, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The franchisee provides, if the annexing municipality requires, a level of quality and frequency of service which is equivalent to that required by the municipality in other areas of the municipality not served by the franchisee, and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The franchisee provides such service to the annexed area at a reasonable cost. The cost must include the following as related to providing services to the annexed area:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Capital costs for land, structures, vehicles, equipment, and other items used for solid waste management;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating and maintenance costs for solid waste management;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Costs to comply with applicable statutes, rules, permit conditions, and insurance requirements;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disposal costs; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reasonable profit.</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the municipality and the franchisee cannot enter into an agreement as to such cost, they shall submit the matter of cost to arbitration.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality, at its option, may allow the franchisee to continue providing services pursuant to the existing franchise agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality may terminate any franchise if the franchisee does not agree to comply with the requirements of paragraph (a) within 90 days after the effective date of the proposed annexation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party that has a contract that was in effect for at least 6 months prior to the initiation of an annexation to provide solid waste collection services in an unincorporated area may continue to provide such services to an annexed area for 5 years or the remainder of the contract term, whichever is shorter. Within a reasonable time following a written request to do so, the party shall provide the annexing municipality with a copy of the pertinent portion of the contract or other written evidence showing the duration of the contract, excluding any automatic renewals or so-called “evergreen” provisions. This subsection does not apply to contracts to provide solid waste collection services to single-family residential properties in those enclaves described in s. 171.046.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-190; s. 22, ch. 85-55; s. 1, ch. 88-92; s. 17, ch. 93-206; s. 2, ch. 93-243; s. 2, ch. 2000-304.</History></Section>