<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0171.0413" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annexation procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipality may annex contiguous, compact, unincorporated territory in the following manner:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An ordinance proposing to annex an area of contiguous, compact, unincorporated territory shall be adopted by the governing body of the annexing municipality pursuant to the procedure for the adoption of a nonemergency ordinance established by s. 166.041. Prior to the adoption of the ordinance of annexation, the local governing body shall hold at least two advertised public hearings. The first public hearing shall be on a weekday at least 7 days after the day that the first advertisement is published. The second public hearing shall be held on a weekday at least 5 days after the day that the second advertisement is published. Each such ordinance shall propose only one reasonably compact area to be annexed. However, prior to the ordinance of annexation becoming effective, a referendum on annexation shall be held as set out below, and, if approved by the referendum, the ordinance shall become effective 10 days after the referendum or as otherwise provided in the ordinance, but not more than 1 year following the date of the referendum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the final adoption of the ordinance of annexation by the governing body of the annexing municipality, the ordinance shall be submitted to a vote of the registered electors of the area proposed to be annexed. The governing body of the annexing municipality may also choose to submit the ordinance of annexation to a separate vote of the registered electors of the annexing municipality. The referendum on annexation shall be called and conducted and the expense thereof paid by the governing body of the annexing municipality.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The referendum on annexation shall be held at the next regularly scheduled election following the final adoption of the ordinance of annexation by the governing body of the annexing municipality or at a special election called for the purpose of holding the referendum. However, the referendum, whether held at a regularly scheduled election or at a special election, shall not be held sooner than 30 days following the final adoption of the ordinance by the governing body of the annexing municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of the annexing municipality shall publish notice of the referendum on annexation at least once each week for 2 consecutive weeks immediately preceding the date of the referendum in a newspaper of general circulation in the area in which the referendum is to be held. The notice shall give the ordinance number, the time and places for the referendum, and a brief, general description of the area proposed to be annexed. The description shall include a map clearly showing the area and a statement that the complete legal description by metes and bounds and the ordinance can be obtained from the office of the city clerk.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the day of the referendum on annexation there shall be prominently displayed at each polling place a copy of the ordinance of annexation and a description of the property proposed to be annexed. The description shall be by metes and bounds and shall include a map clearly showing such area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ballots or mechanical voting devices used in the referendum on annexation shall offer the choice “For annexation of property described in ordinance number <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> of the City of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />” and “Against annexation of property described in ordinance number <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> of the City of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />” in that order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the referendum is held only in the area proposed to be annexed and receives a majority vote, or if the ordinance is submitted to a separate vote of the registered electors of the annexing municipality and the area proposed to be annexed and there is a separate majority vote for annexation in the annexing municipality and in the area proposed to be annexed, the ordinance of annexation shall become effective on the effective date specified therein. If there is any majority vote against annexation, the ordinance shall not become effective, and the area proposed to be annexed shall not be the subject of an annexation ordinance by the annexing municipality for a period of 2 years from the date of the referendum on annexation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any parcel of land which is owned by one individual, corporation, or legal entity, or owned collectively by one or more individuals, corporations, or legal entities, proposed to be annexed under the provisions of this act shall not be severed, separated, divided, or partitioned by the provisions of said ordinance, but shall, if intended to be annexed, or if annexed, under the provisions of this act, be annexed in its entirety and as a whole. However, nothing herein contained shall be construed as affecting the validity or enforceability of any ordinance declaring an intention to annex land under the existing law that has been enacted by a municipality prior to July 1, 1975. The owner of such property may waive the requirements of this subsection if such owner does not desire all of the tract or parcel included in said annexation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this law, the annexation procedure as set forth in this section shall constitute a uniform method for the adoption of an ordinance of annexation by the governing body of any municipality in this state, and all existing provisions of special laws which establish municipal annexation procedures are repealed hereby; except that any provision or provisions of special law or laws which prohibit annexation of territory that is separated from the annexing municipality by a body of water or watercourse shall not be repealed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If more than 70 percent of the land in an area proposed to be annexed is owned by individuals, corporations, or legal entities which are not registered electors of such area, such area shall not be annexed unless the owners of more than 50 percent of the land in such area consent to such annexation. Such consent shall be obtained by the parties proposing the annexation prior to the referendum to be held on the annexation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2), if the area proposed to be annexed does not have any registered electors on the date the ordinance is finally adopted, a vote of electors of the area proposed to be annexed is not required. In addition to the requirements of subsection (5), the area may not be annexed unless the owners of more than 50 percent of the parcels of land in the area proposed to be annexed consent to the annexation. If the governing body does not choose to hold a referendum of the annexing municipality pursuant to subsection (2), then the property owner consents required pursuant to subsection (5) shall be obtained by the parties proposing the annexation prior to the final adoption of the ordinance, and the annexation ordinance shall be effective upon becoming a law or as otherwise provided in the ordinance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 75-297; s. 1, ch. 76-176; s. 44, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 80-350; s. 76, ch. 81-259; s. 1, ch. 86-113; s. 15, ch. 90-279; s. 16, ch. 93-206; s. 1, ch. 93-243; s. 1, ch. 94-196; s. 1448, ch. 95-147; s. 12, ch. 99-378.</History></Section>