<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0153.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Call election to determine creation of district, issuance of bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board of county commissioners shall deem that the creation of the proposed district is necessary in the public interest as provided in s. 153.55, it shall call an election for the purpose of submitting to the qualified electors residing in said proposed district the question of the creation and establishment of said district and may also submit at a separate election to be held at the same time, to the qualified electors who are freeholders residing in such district, the question of the issuance of general obligation bonds of said district to pay all or part of the cost of the proposed improvements. Said election shall be held not less than 30 days from the date of the first publication or posting of the notice thereof and such notice shall be published once a week for 4 successive weeks in a newspaper published in the county and circulating in the area of the proposed district, and if no such newspaper be published in the county and circulating in the district, such notice shall be posted in at least 10 different public places within the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this law, said election shall be held and conducted pursuant to the general laws of the state applicable thereto, provided, that if the question of the issuance of general obligation bonds is to be voted upon, the election thereon shall conform to the applicable provisions of the constitution and statutes of Florida relating to freeholder elections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said call for election of the qualified electors and notice thereof shall include a description of the proposed boundaries of said district, which need not be by metes and bounds but shall be in such detail as to give a reasonable and accurate description thereof and shall further specifically recite that said district, if created, shall be authorized:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct or acquire a sewer system or water system or both for said district and any improvements, additions and extensions thereto and to have exclusive control and jurisdiction thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To finance the cost of such construction or acquisition of such improvements by the issuance of either its revenue bonds, general obligation bonds or assessment bonds, as defined in this law, or any combination thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said notice shall further expressly state that such district, if created and established, shall constitute a special tax district, all the property within which shall be subject to the levy of ad valorem taxes without limitation of rate or amount to secure payment of any of its general obligations, and for the maintenance of such district within the limitations of this law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of the separate election of the qualified freeholder electors, if held at the same time, shall be in substantially the form provided in the applicable statutes of Florida relating to freeholder elections.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such elections may be held at any time, including the dates upon which general or primary elections are held in such county.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 59-466.</History></Section>