<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0153.66" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Covenants of district board with bondholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the other provisions and requirements of this law any resolution authorizing the issuance of revenue bonds, general obligation bonds, assessment bonds or any other obligations issued hereunder, may contain provisions and the district board is authorized to provide and may covenant and agree with the several holders of such bonds as to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable deposits with the district in advance to ensure the payment of rates, fees or charges for the facilities of the system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The discontinuance of the services and facilities of any water system or sewer system, or both, for delinquent payments for either water services or sewer services, and the terms and conditions of the restoration of such service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracts with private or public owners of a water system or sewer system not owned and operated by the district for the discontinuance of service to any users of the water system or sewer system, as the case may be, owned and operated by the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the powers of the district to construct, acquire or operate, or permit the construction, acquisition or operation of any plants, structures, facilities or properties which may compete or tend to compete with any water system or sewer system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner and method of paying service charges and fees and the levying of penalties for delinquent payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to this law the manner and order of priority of the disposition of revenues or redemption of any bonds or other obligations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terms and conditions for modification or amendment of any provisions or covenants in any such proceedings authorizing the issuance of bonds or other obligations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for and limitations on the appointment of a trustee for bondholders for any water system or sewer system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions as to the appointment of a receiver of any sewer system or water system or both, on default of principal or interest on any such bonds or other obligations or the breach of any covenant or condition of such authorizing proceedings or the provisions and requirements of this law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions as to the execution and entering into of trust agreements regarding the holding and disposition of revenues derived from such systems and the proceeds of bonds issued for the cost of acquisition or construction or improvement of a water system or sewer system or both, or for any other purposes necessary to secure any such revenue bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions as to the maintenance of any such systems and reasonable insurance thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other matters necessary to secure such bonds and the payment of the principal and interest thereof.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All such provisions of the bond proceedings and all such covenants and agreements in addition to the other provisions and requirements of this law shall constitute valid and legally binding contracts between the district and several holders of any such bonds and shall be enforceable by any such holder or holders by mandamus or other appropriate action, suit or proceeding in law or in equity in any court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 59-466.</History></Section>