<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0486.0715" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Physical therapist; issuance of temporary permit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall issue a temporary physical therapist permit to an applicant who meets the following requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completes an application for a temporary permit on a form approved by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an approved United States physical therapy educational program and meets all the eligibility requirements for licensure under ch. 456, s. 486.031(1)-(3)(a), and related rules, except passage of a national examination approved by the board is not required.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits an application for licensure under s. 486.041.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrates proof of possessing malpractice insurance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits documentation, under rules adopted by the board, verifying that the applicant will practice under the direct supervision of a licensed physical therapist as provided in subsection (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary permit is not renewable and is valid until a license is granted by the board. A temporary permit is void if the permittee does not pass a national examination approved by the board within 6 months after the date of graduation from a physical therapy training program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a temporary permit may not work as a physical therapist until a temporary permit is issued by the board. A physical therapist who is practicing under a temporary permit must do so under the direct supervision of a licensed physical therapist. A supervising physical therapist shall supervise only one permittee at any given time. The supervising physical therapist must be licensed for a minimum of 6 months before the supervision period begins and must cosign all patient records produced by the physical therapist who is practicing under a temporary permit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-69.</History>
</Section>