<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0486.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of this chapter shall be construed to prohibit any person licensed in this state from using any physical agent as a part of, or incidental to, the lawful practice of her or his profession under the statutes applicable to the profession of chiropractic physician, podiatric physician, doctor of medicine, massage therapist, nurse, osteopathic physician or surgeon, occupational therapist, or naturopath.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of this chapter shall be construed to prohibit:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any student who is enrolled in a school or course of physical therapy approved by the board from performing such acts of physical therapy as are incidental to her or his course of study; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physical therapist from another state from performing physical therapy incidental to a course of study when taking or giving a postgraduate course or other course of study in this state, provided such physical therapist is licensed in another jurisdiction or holds an appointment on the faculty of a school approved for training physical therapists or physical therapist assistants.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of this chapter prohibits a licensed physical therapist from delegating, to a person qualified by training, experience, or education, specific patient care activities, as defined and limited by board rule, to assist the licensed physical therapist in performing duties in compliance with the standards of the practice of physical therapy. Specific patient care activities, as defined and limited by board rule, must be performed under the direct supervision of the licensed physical therapist or physical therapist assistant in the immediate area, if the person is not a licensed physical therapist assistant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 57-67; s. 2, ch. 65-170; s. 5, ch. 78-278; s. 2, ch. 79-116; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 21, 24, ch. 83-86; ss. 17, 18, ch. 86-31; s. 64, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 326, ch. 94-119; s. 472, ch. 97-103; ss. 219, 288, ch. 98-166.</History></Section>