<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0486.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Physical therapist assistant; renewal of license; inactive status; reactivation of license; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall renew a license upon receipt of the renewal application and the fee set by the board not to exceed $150.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the biennial renewal of licenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license that has become inactive may be reactivated upon application to the department and completion of the requirements for reactivation under this section. The board shall prescribe by rule continuing education requirements as a condition of reactivating a license. The continuing education requirements for reactivating a license may not exceed 10 classroom hours for each year the license was inactive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall prescribe by rule an application fee for inactive status, a renewal fee for inactive status, a delinquency fee, and a fee for the reactivation of a license. None of these fees may exceed the biennial renewal fee established by the board for an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not reactivate a license unless the inactive or delinquent licensee has paid any applicable biennial renewal or delinquency fee, or both, and a reactivation fee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not reactivate a license unless the inactive licensee has met the continuing education requirements of subsection (3) or has fulfilled one of the following requirements for reactivation of a license:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides evidence satisfactory to the board that she or he has actively engaged in the practice of physical therapy in good standing in another state for the 4 years immediately preceding the filing of an application for reinstatement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes application for and passes the examination as provided by s. 486.104 and pays the fee therefor as provided in s. 486.103.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 67-537; s. 9, ch. 73-354; s. 4, ch. 78-278; s. 2, ch. 79-116; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 16, 24, ch. 83-86; ss. 14, 17, 18, ch. 86-31; s. 34, ch. 88-205; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 254, ch. 94-119; s. 469, ch. 97-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 486.105.</Text></Note></Section>