<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0486.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Physical therapist; licensing requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for licensing as a physical therapist, an applicant must:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 18 years old;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be of good moral character; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been graduated from a school of physical therapy which has been approved for the educational preparation of physical therapists by the appropriate accrediting agency recognized by the Commission on Recognition of Postsecondary Accreditation or the United States Department of Education at the time of her or his graduation and have passed, to the satisfaction of the board, the American Registry Examination prior to 1971 or a national examination approved by the board to determine her or his fitness for practice as a physical therapist as hereinafter provided;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have received a diploma from a program in physical therapy in a foreign country and have educational credentials deemed equivalent to those required for the educational preparation of physical therapists in this country, as recognized by the appropriate agency as identified by the board, and have passed to the satisfaction of the board an examination to determine her or his fitness for practice as a physical therapist as hereinafter provided; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be entitled to licensure without examination as provided in s. 486.081.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 57-67; s. 2, ch. 67-537; s. 39, ch. 77-121; s. 3, ch. 78-278; s. 2, ch. 79-116; s. 362, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 24, ch. 83-86; ss. 17, 18, ch. 86-31; s. 5, ch. 89-124; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 28, ch. 94-310; s. 458, ch. 97-103; s. 177, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>