<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0486.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Physical Therapy Practice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means the document of authorization granted by the board and issued by the department for a person to engage in the practice of physical therapy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Endorsement” means licensure granted by the board pursuant to the provisions of s. 486.081 or s. 486.107.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical therapist” means a person who is licensed and who practices physical therapy in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical therapist assistant” means a person who is licensed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter to perform patient-related activities, including the use of physical agents, whose license is in good standing, and whose activities are performed under the direction of a physical therapist as set forth in rules adopted pursuant to this chapter. Patient-related activities performed by a physical therapist assistant for a board-certified orthopedic physician or physiatrist licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459 or a practitioner licensed under chapter 460 shall be under the general supervision of a physical therapist, but shall not require onsite supervision by a physical therapist. Patient-related activities performed for all other health care practitioners licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 and those patient-related activities performed for practitioners licensed under chapter 461 or chapter 466 shall be performed under the onsite supervision of a physical therapist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical therapy practitioner” means a physical therapist or a physical therapist assistant who is licensed and who practices physical therapy in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical therapy” or “physiotherapy,” each of which terms is deemed identical and interchangeable with each other, means a health care profession.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means supervision by a physical therapist who is licensed pursuant to this chapter. Except in a case of emergency, direct supervision requires the physical presence of the licensed physical therapist for consultation and direction of the actions of a physical therapist or physical therapist assistant who is practicing under a temporary permit and who is a candidate for licensure by examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical therapy assessment” means observational, verbal, or manual determinations of the function of the musculoskeletal or neuromuscular system relative to physical therapy, including, but not limited to, range of motion of a joint, motor power, postural attitudes, biomechanical function, locomotion, or functional abilities, for the purpose of making recommendations for treatment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of physical therapy” means the performance of physical therapy assessments and the treatment of any disability, injury, disease, or other health condition of human beings, or the prevention of such disability, injury, disease, or other condition of health, and rehabilitation as related thereto by the use of the physical, chemical, and other properties of air; electricity; exercise; massage; the performance of acupuncture only upon compliance with the criteria set forth by the Board of Medicine, when no penetration of the skin occurs; the use of radiant energy, including ultraviolet, visible, and infrared rays; ultrasound; water; the use of apparatus and equipment in the application of the foregoing or related thereto; the performance of tests of neuromuscular functions as an aid to the diagnosis or treatment of any human condition; or the performance of electromyography as an aid to the diagnosis of any human condition only upon compliance with the criteria set forth by the Board of Medicine. A physical therapist may implement a plan of treatment for a patient. The physical therapist shall refer the patient to or consult with a health care practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466, if the patient’s condition is found to be outside the scope of physical therapy. If physical therapy treatment for a patient is required beyond 21 days for a condition not previously assessed by a practitioner of record, the physical therapist shall obtain a practitioner of record who will review and sign the plan. A health care practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466 and engaged in active practice is eligible to serve as a practitioner of record. The use of roentgen rays and radium for diagnostic and therapeutic purposes and the use of electricity for surgical purposes, including cauterization, are not authorized under the term “physical therapy” as used in this chapter. The practice of physical therapy as defined in this chapter does not authorize a physical therapy practitioner to practice chiropractic medicine as defined in chapter 460, including specific spinal manipulation. For the performance of specific chiropractic spinal manipulation, a physical therapist shall refer the patient to a health care practitioner licensed under chapter 460. Nothing in this subsection authorizes a physical therapist to implement a plan of treatment for a patient currently being treated in a facility licensed pursuant to chapter 395.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 57-67; s. 1, ch. 67-537; s. 1, ch. 73-354; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-278; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-116; s. 361, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 24, ch. 83-86; s. 1, ch. 83-93; s. 1, ch. 84-275; ss. 3, 17, 18, ch. 86-31; s. 2, ch. 89-124; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 92-70; s. 181, ch. 94-218; s. 175, ch. 97-264; s. 287, ch. 98-166.</History></Section>