<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0486.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">False representation of licensure, or willful misrepresentation or fraudulent representation to obtain license, unlawful.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person who is not licensed under this chapter as a physical therapist, or whose license has been suspended or revoked, to use in connection with her or his name or place of business the words “physical therapist,” “physiotherapist,” “physical therapy,” “physiotherapy,” “registered physical therapist,” or “licensed physical therapist”; or the letters “P.T.,” “Ph.T.,” “R.P.T.,” or “L.P.T.”; or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying that she or he is a physical therapist or to represent herself or himself as a physical therapist in any other way, orally, in writing, in print, or by sign, directly or by implication, unless physical therapy services are provided or supplied by a physical therapist licensed in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person who is not licensed under this chapter as a physical therapist assistant, or whose license has been suspended or revoked, to use in connection with her or his name the words “physical therapist assistant,” “licensed physical therapist assistant,” “registered physical therapist assistant,” or “physical therapy technician”; or the letters “P.T.A.,” “L.P.T.A.,” “R.P.T.A.,” or “P.T.T.”; or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying that she or he is a physical therapist assistant or to represent herself or himself as a physical therapist assistant in any other way, orally, in writing, in print, or by sign, directly or by implication.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to obtain or attempt to obtain a license under this chapter by any willful misrepresentation or any fraudulent representation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 57-67; s. 9, ch. 67-537; s. 2, ch. 79-116; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 19, 24, ch. 83-86; ss. 17, 18, ch. 86-31; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 471, ch. 97-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 486.101.</Text></Note></Section>