<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0071.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reestablishment of papers, records, and files.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All papers, written or printed, of any kind whatsoever, and the records and files of any official, court or public office, may be reestablished in the manner hereinafter provided.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WHO MAY REESTABLISH.<EmDash />Any person interested in the paper, file or record to be reestablished may reestablish it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VENUE.<EmDash />If reestablishment is sought of a record or file, venue is in the county where the record or file existed before its loss or destruction. If it is a private paper, venue is in the county where any person affected thereby lives or if such persons are nonresidents of the state, then in any county in which the person seeking the reestablishment desires.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REMEDY CONCURRENT.<EmDash />Nothing herein shall prevent the reestablishment of lost papers, records and files at common law or in equity in the usual manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EFFECT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any paper, record or file reestablished has the effect of the original. A private paper has such effect immediately on recording the judgment reestablishing it, but a reestablished record does not have that effect until recorded and a reestablished paper or file of any official, court or public officer does not have that effect until a certified copy is filed with the official or in the court or public office where the original belonged. A certified copy of any reestablished paper, the original of which is required or authorized by law to be recorded, may be recorded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any deed forming a link in a chain of title to land in this state has been placed on the proper record without having been acknowledged or proven for record and has thereafter been lost or destroyed, certified copies of the record of the deed as so recorded may be received as evidence to reestablish the deed if the deed has been so recorded for 20 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPLAINT.<EmDash />A person desiring to establish any paper, record or file, except when otherwise provided, shall file a complaint in chancery setting forth that the paper, record or file has been lost or destroyed and is not in the custody or control of the petitioner, the time and manner of loss or destruction, that a copy attached is a substantial copy of that lost or destroyed, that the persons named in the complaint are the only persons known to plaintiff who are interested for or against such reestablishment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, Nov. 21, 1829; s. 12, ch. 1369, 1862; s. 2, ch. 3019, 1877; RS 1523-1527, 1533; s. 1, ch. 5162, 1903; GS 1978-1982, 1997; RGS 3246-3250, 3265; CGL 5054-5058, 5073; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 24, ch. 67-254.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 71.01-71.06.</Text></Note></Section>