<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0847.0141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexting; prohibited acts; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor commits the offense of sexting if he or she knowingly:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses a computer, or any other device capable of electronic data transmission or distribution, to transmit or distribute to another minor any photograph or video of any person which depicts nudity, as defined in s. 847.001(9), and is harmful to minors, as defined in s. 847.001(6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a photograph or video of any person that was transmitted or distributed by another minor which depicts nudity, as defined in s. 847.001(9), and is harmful to minors, as defined in s. 847.001(6). A minor does not violate this paragraph if all of the following apply:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor did not solicit the photograph or video.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor took reasonable steps to report the photograph or video to the minor’s legal guardian or to a school or law enforcement official.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor did not transmit or distribute the photograph or video to a third party.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transmission or distribution of multiple photographs or videos prohibited by paragraph (1)(a) is a single offense if the photographs or videos were transmitted or distributed within the same 24-hour period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The possession of multiple photographs or videos that were transmitted or distributed by a minor prohibited by paragraph (1)(b) is a single offense if the photographs or videos were transmitted or distributed by a minor in the same 24-hour period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor who violates subsection (1):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits a noncriminal violation for a first violation, punishable by 8 hours of community service or, if ordered by the court in lieu of community service, a $60 fine. The court may also order the minor to participate in suitable training or instruction in lieu of, or in addition to, community service or a fine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits a misdemeanor of the first degree for a violation that occurs after being found to have committed a noncriminal violation for sexting, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits a felony of the third degree for a violation that occurs after being found to have committed a misdemeanor of the first degree for sexting, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the prosecution of a minor for a violation of any law of this state if the photograph or video that depicts nudity also includes the depiction of sexual conduct or sexual excitement, and does not prohibit the prosecution of a minor for stalking under s. 784.048.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “found to have committed” means a determination of guilt that is the result of a plea or trial, or a finding of delinquency that is the result of a plea or an adjudicatory hearing, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-180; s. 85, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>