<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0847.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Child pornography prosecutions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer who, pursuant to a criminal investigation, recovers images or movies of child pornography shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide such images or movies to the law enforcement agency representative assigned to the Child Victim Identification Program at the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, as required by the center’s guidelines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request the law enforcement agency contact information from the Child Victim Identification Program for any images or movies recovered which contain an identified victim of child pornography as defined in s. 960.03.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide case information to the Child Victim Identification Program, as required by the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children guidelines, in any case where the law enforcement officer identifies a previously unidentified victim of child pornography.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer submitting a case for prosecution which involves the production, promotion, or possession of child pornography shall submit to the designated prosecutor the law enforcement agency contact information provided by the Child Victim Identification Program at the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, for any images or movies involved in the case which contain the depiction of an identified victim of child pornography as defined in s. 960.03.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In every filed case involving an identified victim of child pornography, as defined in s. 960.03, the prosecuting agency shall enter the following information into the Victims in Child Pornography Tracking Repeat Exploitation database maintained by the Office of the Attorney General:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case number and agency file number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The named defendant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court division and county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current court dates and the status of the case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contact information for the prosecutor assigned.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Verification that the prosecutor is or is not in possession of a victim impact statement and will use the statement in sentencing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2008-172.</History></Section>