<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0847.0133" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Protection of minors; prohibition of certain acts in connection with obscenity; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly sell, rent, loan, give away, distribute, transmit, or show any obscene material to a minor. For purposes of this section “obscene material” means any obscene book, magazine, periodical, pamphlet, newspaper, comic book, story paper, written or printed story or article, writing paper, card, picture, drawing, photograph, motion picture film, figure, image, videotape, videocassette, phonograph record, or wire or tape or other recording, or any written, printed, or recorded matter of any such character which may or may not require mechanical or other means to be transmuted into auditory, visual, or sensory representations of such character, or any article or instrument for obscene use, or purporting to be for obscene use or purpose. The term “obscene” has the same meaning as set forth in s. 847.001.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section “knowingly” has the same meaning set forth in s. 847.012(1). A “minor” is any person under the age of 18 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the provisions of this section constitutes a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 63, ch. 90-306; s. 7, ch. 93-4; s. 5, ch. 2008-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 7, ch. 2008-120, provides that “[t]he amendments to ss. 847.012, 847.011, 847.013, and 847.0133, Florida Statutes, by this act do not apply to providers of communications services as defined in s. 202.11, Florida Statutes, or to providers of information services, including, but not limited to, Internet access service providers and hosting service providers, when they only provide the transmission, storage, or caching of electronic communications or messages of others or provide other related communications or information services used by others in violation of such amended provisions. This exemption shall not apply to providers of communications services as defined in s. 202.11, Florida Statutes, or providers of information services that knowingly for commercial advantage or private financial gain facilitate the specific violation of such amended provisions by others.”</Text></Note></Section>