<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0847.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exposing minors to harmful motion pictures, exhibitions, shows, presentations, or representations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“KNOWINGLY” DEFINED.<EmDash />As used in this section “knowingly” means having general knowledge of, reason to know, or a belief or ground for belief which warrants further inspection or inquiry of both:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The character and content of any motion picture described herein which is reasonably susceptible of examination by the defendant, or the character of any exhibition, presentation, representation, or show described herein, other than a motion picture show, which is reasonably susceptible of being ascertained by the defendant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The age of the minor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINOR’S AGE.<EmDash />A person’s ignorance of a minor’s age, a minor’s misrepresentation of his or her age, a bona fide belief of a minor’s age, or a minor’s consent may not be raised as a defense in a prosecution for a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFENSES AND PENALTIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly exhibit for a monetary consideration to a minor or knowingly sell or rent a videotape of a motion picture to a minor or knowingly sell to a minor an admission ticket or pass or knowingly admit a minor for a monetary consideration to premises whereon there is exhibited a motion picture, exhibition, show, representation, or other presentation which, in whole or in part, depicts nudity, sexual conduct, sexual excitement, sexual battery, bestiality, or sadomasochistic abuse and which is harmful to minors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly rent or sell, or loan to a minor for monetary consideration, a videocassette or a videotape of a motion picture, or similar presentation, which, in whole or in part, depicts nudity, sexual conduct, sexual excitement, sexual battery, bestiality, or sadomasochistic abuse and which is harmful to minors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraph (a) do not apply to a minor when the minor is accompanied by his or her parents or either of them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor may not falsely represent to the owner of any premises mentioned in paragraph (a), or to the owner’s agent, or to any person mentioned in paragraph (b), that the minor is 17 years of age or older, with the intent to procure the minor’s admission to such premises, or the minor’s purchase or rental of a videotape, for a monetary consideration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly make a false representation to the owner of any premises mentioned in paragraph (a), or to the owner’s agent, or to any person mentioned in paragraph (b), that he or she is the parent of any minor or that any minor is 17 years of age or older, with intent to procure the minor’s admission to the premises or to aid the minor in procuring admission thereto, or to aid or enable the minor’s purchase or rental of a videotape, for a monetary consideration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any provision of this subsection constitutes a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INJUNCTIVE PROCEEDINGS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court has jurisdiction to enjoin a threatened violation of subsection (2) upon complaint filed by the state attorney in the name of the state upon the relation of such state attorney.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the filing of such a complaint, the judge to whom it is presented may grant an order restraining the person or persons complained of until final hearing or further order of the court. Whenever the relator requests a judge of the court to set a hearing upon an application for a restraining order, the judge shall set the hearing for a time within 3 days after the making of the request. An order may not be made unless the judge is satisfied that sufficient notice of the application therefor has been given to the person or persons restrained of the time when and place where the application for the restraining order is to be heard. However, the notice shall be dispensed with when it is manifest to the judge, from the allegations of a sworn complaint or independent affidavit, sworn to by the relator or by some person associated with him or her in the field of law enforcement and filed by the relator, that the apprehended violation will be committed if an immediate remedy is not afforded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person or persons sought to be enjoined are entitled to a trial of the issues within 1 day after joinder of issue, and a decision shall be rendered by the court within 2 days after the conclusion of the trial.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action brought as provided in this section, a bond or undertaking is not required of the state or the relator state attorney before the issuance of a restraining order provided for by this section, and there is no liability on the part of the state or the relator state attorney for costs or damages sustained by reason of such restraining order in any case in which a final decree is rendered in favor of the person or persons sought to be enjoined.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person who has possession, custody, or control of, or otherwise deals with, any motion picture, exhibition, show, representation, or presentation described in this section, after the service upon him or her of a summons and complaint in an action for injunction brought under this section, is chargeable with knowledge of the contents or character thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />In order to make the application and enforcement of this section uniform throughout the state, it is the intent of the Legislature to preempt the field, to the exclusion of counties and municipalities, insofar as it concerns exposing persons under 17 years of age to harmful motion pictures, exhibitions, shows, representations, presentations, and commercial or sexual exploitation. To that end, it is hereby declared that every county ordinance and every municipal ordinance adopted prior to July 1, 1969, and relating to such subject shall stand abrogated and unenforceable on and after such date and that no county, municipality, or consolidated county-municipal government shall have the power to adopt any ordinance relating to that subject on or after such effective date.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 69-10; s. 1055, ch. 71-136; s. 34, ch. 73-334; s. 3, ch. 83-77; s. 4, ch. 86-38; s. 5, ch. 86-238; s. 6, ch. 88-283; s. 1350, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 2008-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 7, ch. 2008-120, provides that “[t]he amendments to ss. 847.012, 847.011, 847.013, and 847.0133, Florida Statutes, by this act do not apply to providers of communications services as defined in s. 202.11, Florida Statutes, or to providers of information services, including, but not limited to, Internet access service providers and hosting service providers, when they only provide the transmission, storage, or caching of electronic communications or messages of others or provide other related communications or information services used by others in violation of such amended provisions. This exemption shall not apply to providers of communications services as defined in s. 202.11, Florida Statutes, or providers of information services that knowingly for commercial advantage or private financial gain facilitate the specific violation of such amended provisions by others.”</Text></Note></Section>