<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0847.201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obscene programming on cable television during promotional period unlawful; penalty; applicability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any owner or operator of any cable television service to provide on any basic cable channel during a promotional “free weekend” or other advertising period obscene programming or programming otherwise unprotected by the Constitution of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of subsection (1) is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable by a fine of up to $2,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to any owner or operator of any cable television service who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides to its subscribers of basic cable channels at least once annually, and to its new subscribers of basic cable channels at the time of subscription, at least 30 days’ advance written notice that such aforesaid programming may be shown, which notice shall include the dates and times such programming may be shown; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of the subscribers of basic cable channels and during such promotional period, electronically “locks out” the aforesaid programming from the basic cable channels so that it is not received in the television receivers of such subscribers requesting not to receive such programming, or makes available at no cost to the subscribers of basic cable channels parental control devices, sometimes known as “lock boxes,” which devices shall have the capability of “locking out” or denying reception to the television receivers of such aforesaid subscribers requesting same.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-215.</History></Section>