<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0576.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration; rules; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter and all rules adopted hereunder shall be administered and enforced by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized, by rule, to implement, make specific, and interpret the provisions of this chapter, and specifically to determine the composition and uses of fertilizer as defined in this chapter, including, without limiting the foregoing general terms, the taking and handling of samples, the establishment of investigational allowances, deficiencies, and penalties where not specifically provided for in this chapter; to prohibit the sale or use in fertilizer of any material proven to be detrimental to agriculture, public health, or the environment, or of questionable value; to provide for the incorporation into fertilizer of such other substances as pesticides and proper labeling of such mixture; and to prescribe the information which shall appear on the label other than specifically set forth in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish by rule requirements governing aircraft used for the aerial application of fertilizers, including requirements for recordkeeping, annual aircraft registration, secure storage when not in use, area-of-application information, and reporting any sale, lease, purchase, rental, or transfer of such aircraft to another person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish by rule requirements governing the secure storage of fertilizers used by aerial fertilizer applicators.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (b), the department has exclusive authority to regulate the sale, composition, packaging, labeling, wholesale and retail distribution, and formulation, including nutrient content level and release rates, of fertilizer. This subsection expressly preempts such regulation of fertilizer to the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An ordinance regulating the sale of fertilizer adopted by a county or municipal government before July 1, 2011, is exempt from this subsection, and the county or municipal government may enforce such ordinance within its respective jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-348; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 240, ch. 71-377; s. 6, ch. 78-95; ss. 17, 19, ch. 92-143; ss. 10, 11, ch. 97-6; s. 3, ch. 2001-360; s. 33, ch. 2011-206.</History></Section>