<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0576.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration and licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose name appears upon a label and who guarantees a fertilizer may not distribute that fertilizer to a nonlicensee until a license to distribute has been obtained by that person from the department upon payment of a $100 fee. All licenses shall expire on June 30 each year. An application for license shall include the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the distribution point. The name and address shown on the license shall be shown on all labels, pertinent invoices, and storage facilities for fertilizer distributed by the licensee in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not distribute a specialty fertilizer in this state until it is registered with the department by the licensee whose name appears on the label. An application for registration of each grade of specialty fertilizer shall be made on a form furnished by the department and shall be accompanied by an annual fee of $100 for each specialty fertilizer that is registered. All specialty fertilizer registrations expire June 30 each year. All licensing and registration fees paid to the department under this section shall be deposited into the State Treasury to be placed in the General Inspection Trust Fund to be used for the sole purpose of funding the fertilizer inspection program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Labels for each brand and product grade shall accompany the application and shall include the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brand and grade.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guaranteed analysis.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the licensee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net weight.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sources from which the nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium are derived.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sources of secondary plant nutrients and micro plant nutrients if guaranteed, claimed, or advertised.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-348; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 76-35; s. 2, ch. 87-170; ss. 2, 19, ch. 92-143; ss. 2, 11, ch. 97-6; s. 41, ch. 2009-66.</History></Section>