<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0319.225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer and reassignment forms; odometer disclosure statements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every certificate of title issued by the department must contain the following statement on its reverse side: “Federal and state law require the completion of the odometer statement set out below. Failure to complete or providing false information may result in fines, imprisonment, or both.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certificate of title issued by the department must contain on its reverse side a form for transfer of title by the titleholder of record, which form must contain an odometer disclosure statement in the form required by 49 C.F.R. s. 580.5.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certificate of title issued by the department must contain on its reverse side as many forms as space allows for reassignment of title by a licensed dealer as permitted by s. 319.21(3), which form or forms shall contain an odometer disclosure statement in the form required by 49 C.F.R. s. 580.5. When all dealer reassignment forms provided on the back of the title certificate have been filled in, a dealer may reassign the title certificate by using a separate dealer reassignment form issued by the department in compliance with 49 C.F.R. ss. 580.4 and 580.5, which form shall contain two carbon copies one of which shall be submitted directly to the department by the dealer within 5 business days after the transfer and one of which shall be retained by the dealer in his or her records for 5 years. The provisions of this subsection shall also apply to vehicles not previously titled in this state and vehicles whose title certificates do not contain the forms required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon transfer or reassignment of a certificate of title to a used motor vehicle, the transferor shall complete the odometer disclosure statement provided for by this section and the transferee shall acknowledge the disclosure by signing and printing his or her name in the spaces provided. This subsection does not apply to a vehicle that has a gross vehicle rating of more than 16,000 pounds, a vehicle that is not self-propelled, or a vehicle that is 10 years old or older. A lessor who transfers title to his or her vehicle without obtaining possession of the vehicle shall make odometer disclosure as provided by 49 C.F.R. s. 580.7. Any person who fails to complete or acknowledge a disclosure statement as required by this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. The department may not issue a certificate of title unless this subsection has been complied with.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The same person may not sign a disclosure statement as both the transferor and the transferee in the same transaction except as provided in subsection (6).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the certificate of title is physically held by a lienholder, the transferor may give a power of attorney to his or her transferee for the purpose of odometer disclosure. The power of attorney must be on a form issued or authorized by the department, which form must be in compliance with 49 C.F.R. ss. 580.4 and 580.13. The department shall not require the signature of the transferor to be notarized on the form; however, in lieu of notarization, the form shall include an affidavit with the following wording: UNDER PENALTY OF PERJURY, I DECLARE THAT I HAVE READ THE FOREGOING DOCUMENT AND THAT THE FACTS STATED IN IT ARE TRUE. The transferee shall sign the power of attorney form, print his or her name, and return a copy of the power of attorney form to the transferor. Upon receipt of a title certificate, the transferee shall complete the space for mileage disclosure on the title certificate exactly as the mileage was disclosed by the transferor on the power of attorney form. If the transferee is a licensed motor vehicle dealer who is transferring the vehicle to a retail purchaser, the dealer shall make application on behalf of the retail purchaser as provided in s. 319.23(6) and shall submit the original power of attorney form to the department with the application for title and the transferor’s title certificate; otherwise, a dealer may reassign the title certificate by using the dealer reassignment form in the manner prescribed in subsection (3), and, at the time of physical transfer of the vehicle, the original power of attorney shall be delivered to the person designated as the transferee of the dealer on the dealer reassignment form. A copy of the executed power of attorney shall be submitted to the department with a copy of the executed dealer reassignment form within 5 business days after the certificate of title and dealer reassignment form are delivered by the dealer to its transferee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the certificate of title is lost or otherwise unavailable, the transferor may give a power of attorney to his or her transferee for the purpose of odometer disclosure. The power of attorney must be on a form issued or authorized by the department, which form must be in compliance with 49 C.F.R. ss. 580.4 and 580.13. The department shall not require the signature of the transferor to be notarized on the form; however, in lieu of notarization, the form shall include an affidavit with the following wording: UNDER PENALTY OF PERJURY, I DECLARE THAT I HAVE READ THE FOREGOING DOCUMENT AND THAT THE FACTS STATED IN IT ARE TRUE. The transferee shall sign the power of attorney form, print his or her name, and return a copy of the power of attorney form to the transferor. Upon receipt of the title certificate or a duplicate title certificate, the transferee shall complete the space for mileage disclosure on the title certificate exactly as the mileage was disclosed by the transferor on the power of attorney form. If the transferee is a licensed motor vehicle dealer who is transferring the vehicle to a retail purchaser, the dealer shall make application on behalf of the retail purchaser as provided in s. 319.23(6) and shall submit the original power of attorney form to the department with the application for title and the transferor’s title certificate or duplicate title certificate; otherwise, a dealer may reassign the title certificate by using the dealer reassignment form in the manner prescribed in subsection (3), and, at the time of physical transfer of the vehicle, the original power of attorney shall be delivered to the person designated as the transferee of the dealer on the dealer reassignment form. A copy of the executed power of attorney shall be submitted to the department with a copy of the executed dealer reassignment form within 5 business days after the duplicate certificate of title and dealer reassignment form are delivered by the dealer to its transferee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the mechanics of the transfer of title to a motor vehicle in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) are determined to be incompatible with and unlawful under the provisions of 49 C.F.R. part 580, the transfer of title to a motor vehicle by operation of this subsection can be effected in any manner not inconsistent with 49 C.F.R. part 580 and Florida law; provided, any power of attorney form issued or authorized by the department under this subsection shall contain two carbon copies, one of which shall be submitted directly to the department by the dealer within 5 business days of use by the dealer to effect transfer of a title certificate as provided in paragraphs (a) and (b) and one of which shall be retained by the dealer in its records for 5 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to complete the information required by this subsection or to file with the department the forms required by this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. The department shall not issue a certificate of title unless this subsection has been complied with.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certificate of title issued by the department must contain on its reverse side a minimum of four spaces for notation of the name and license number of any auction through which the vehicle is sold and the date the vehicle was auctioned. Each separate dealer reassignment form issued by the department must also have the space referred to in this section. When a transfer of title is made at a motor vehicle auction, the reassignment must note the name and address of the auction, but the auction shall not thereby be deemed to be the owner, seller, transferor, or assignor of title. A motor vehicle auction is required to execute a dealer reassignment only when it is the owner of a vehicle being sold.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon transfer or reassignment of a used motor vehicle through the services of an auction, the auction shall complete the information in the space provided for by subsection (7). Any person who fails to complete the information as required by this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. The department shall not issue a certificate of title unless this subsection has been complied with.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be construed to conform to 49 C.F.R. part 580.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 89-333; s. 2, ch. 90-270; s. 338, ch. 95-148; s. 12, ch. 96-413; s. 6, ch. 2010-198.</History>
</Section>