<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0619.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Articles of incorporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each association formed under this chapter must prepare and file articles of incorporation in the same manner and under the same regulations as required under chapter 607, and therein shall set forth:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose for which it is formed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The place where its principal business will be transacted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term for which it is to exist, not exceeding 50 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of directors thereof, which must not be less than three and which may be any number in excess thereof, and the names and residences of those selected for the first year and until their successors shall have been elected and shall have accepted office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the voting power and the property rights and interest of each member shall be equal, or unequal, and if unequal these articles shall set forth a general rule applicable to all members by which the voting power and the property rights and interests, respectively, of each member may and shall be determined and fixed, but the association shall have power to admit new members, who shall be entitled to vote and to share in the property of the association with the old members, in accordance with such general rule. This provision of the articles of incorporation shall not be altered, amended or repealed except by the unanimous written consent or the vote of all the members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said articles must be subscribed by the original members and acknowledged by one of them before an officer authorized by the law of this state to take and certify acknowledgments of deeds of conveyance, and shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of law, and when so filed the said articles of incorporation or certified copies thereof shall be received in all the courts of this state and other places as prima facie evidence of the facts contained therein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 5958, 1909; RGS 4512; CGL 6511; s. 9, ch. 79-9.</History></Section>