<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.316" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fiscal intermediary services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature, through the adoption of this section, to ensure the financial soundness of fiscal intermediary services organizations established to develop, manage, and administer the business affairs of health care professional providers such as medical doctors, doctors of osteopathy, doctors of chiropractic medicine, doctors of podiatric medicine, doctors of dentistry, or other health professionals regulated by the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “fiduciary” or “fiscal intermediary services” means reimbursements received or collected on behalf of health care professionals for services rendered, patient and provider accounting, financial reporting and auditing, receipts and collections management, compensation and reimbursement disbursement services, or other related fiduciary services pursuant to health care professional contracts with health maintenance organizations. All payments to a health care provider by a fiscal intermediary for noncapitated providers must include an explanation of services being reimbursed which includes, at a minimum, the patient’s name, the date of service, the procedure code, the amount of reimbursement, and the identification of the plan on whose behalf the payment is being made. For capitated providers, the statement of services must include the number of patients covered by the contract, the rate per patient, the total amount of the payment, and the identification of the plan on whose behalf the payment is being made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “fiscal intermediary services organization” means a person or entity that performs fiduciary or fiscal intermediary services to health care professionals who contract with health maintenance organizations other than a hospital licensed under chapter 395, an insurer licensed under chapter 624, a third-party administrator licensed under chapter 626, a prepaid limited health service organization licensed under chapter 636, a health maintenance organization licensed under this chapter, or a physician group practice as defined in s. 456.053(3)(h) which provides services under the scope of licenses of the members of the group practice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiscal intermediary services organization that is operated for the purpose of acquiring and administering provider contracts with managed care plans for professional health care services, including, but not limited to, medical, surgical, chiropractic, dental, and podiatric care, and which performs fiduciary or fiscal intermediary services shall be required to secure and maintain a fidelity bond in the minimum amount of 10 percent of the funds handled by the intermediary in connection with its fiscal and fiduciary services during the prior year or $1 million, whichever is less. The minimum bond amount shall be $50,000. The fidelity bond shall protect the fiscal intermediary from loss caused by the dishonesty of its employees and must remain unimpaired for as long as the intermediary continues in business in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiscal intermediary services organization, as described in subsection (3), shall secure and maintain a surety bond on file with the office, naming the intermediary as principal. The bond must be obtained from a company authorized to write surety insurance in the state, and the office shall be obligee on behalf of itself and third parties. The penal sum of the bond may not be less than 5 percent of the funds handled by the intermediary in connection with its fiscal and fiduciary services during the prior year or $250,000, whichever is less. The minimum bond amount must be $10,000. The condition of the bond must be that the intermediary shall register with the office and shall not misappropriate funds within its control or custody as a fiscal intermediary or fiduciary. The aggregate liability of the surety for any and all breaches of the conditions of the bond may not exceed the penal sum of the bond. The bond must be continuous in form, must be renewed annually by a continuation certificate, and may be terminated by the surety upon its giving 30 days’ written notice of termination to the office. This subsection does not apply to a fiscal intermediary services organization that is owned, operated, or controlled by a third-party administrator holding a certificate of authority under part VII of chapter 626.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiscal intermediary services organization may not collect from the subscriber any payment other than the copayment or deductible specified in the subscriber agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any fiscal intermediary services organization, other than a hospital licensed under chapter 395, an insurer licensed under chapter 624, a third-party administrator licensed under chapter 626, a prepaid limited health service organization licensed under chapter 636, a health maintenance organization licensed under this chapter, a not-for-profit corporation that provides health care services directly to patients through employed, salaried physicians and that is affiliated with an accredited hospital licensed in this state, or a physician group practice as defined in s. 456.053(3)(h) which provides services under the scope of licenses of the members of the group practice, must register with the office and meet the requirements of this section. In order to register as a fiscal intermediary services organization, the organization must comply with ss. 641.21(1)(c), (d), and (j), 641.22(6), and 641.27. The fiscal intermediary services organization must also comply with the provisions of ss. 641.3155, 641.3156, and 641.51(4). Should the office determine that the fiscal intermediary services organization does not meet the requirements of this section, the registration shall be denied. If the registrant fails to maintain compliance with this section, the office may revoke or suspend the registration. In lieu of revocation or suspension of the registration, the office may levy an administrative penalty in accordance with s. 641.25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 97-159; s. 26, ch. 98-159; ss. 162, 293, ch. 98-166; s. 5, ch. 99-275; s. 174, ch. 99-397; s. 3, ch. 2000-155; s. 223, ch. 2000-160; s. 1585, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2007-140.</History></Section>