<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.31095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for mammograms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every health maintenance contract issued or renewed on or after January 1, 1996, shall provide coverage for at least the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A baseline mammogram for any woman who is 35 years of age or older, but younger than 40 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mammogram every 2 years for any woman who is 40 years of age or older, but younger than 50 years of age, or more frequently based on the patient’s physician’s recommendations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mammogram every year for any woman who is 50 years of age or older.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more mammograms a year, based upon a physician’s recommendation for any woman who is at risk for breast cancer because of a personal or family history of breast cancer, because of having a history of biopsy-proven benign breast disease, because of having a mother, sister, or daughter who has had breast cancer, or because a woman has not given birth before the age of 30.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coverage required by this section is subject to the deductible and copayment provisions applicable to outpatient visits, and is also subject to all other terms and conditions applicable to other benefits. A health maintenance organization shall make available to the subscriber as part of the application, for an appropriate additional premium, the coverage required in this section without such coverage being subject to any deductible or copayment provisions in the contract.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 95-188.</History></Section>