<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.54" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Information disclosure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every health maintenance organization shall maintain a current list, by geographic area, of all hospitals which are routinely and regularly used by the organization, indicating to which hospitals the organization may refer particular subscribers for nonemergency services. The list shall also include all physicians under the organization’s direct employ or who are under contract or other arrangement with the organization to provide health care services to subscribers. The list shall contain the following information for each physician:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Office location.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical area or areas of specialty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board certification or eligibility in any area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License number.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The list shall be made available, upon request, to the office. The list shall also be made available, upon request:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to negotiation, application, or effectuation of a group health maintenance contract, to the employer or other person who will hold the contract on behalf of the subscriber group. The list may be restricted to include only physicians and hospitals in the group’s geographic area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an individual health maintenance contract or any contract offered to a person who is entitled to have payments for health care costs made under Medicare, to the person considering or making application to, or under contract with, the health maintenance organization. The list may be restricted to include only physicians and hospitals in the person’s geographic area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization shall make available to subscribers, upon request, a detailed description of the authorization and referral process for health care services. Any changes in the organization’s authorization and referral process shall be reported to the agency immediately.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization shall make available to subscribers, upon request, a detailed description of the process used to determine whether health care services are “medically necessary.” Any change in the organization’s definition of “medically necessary” or the process used to determine medical necessity shall be reported to the agency immediately.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each organization shall provide to subscribers, upon request, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the organization’s quality assurance program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies and procedures relating to the organization’s prescription drug benefits, including the disclosure, upon request of a subscriber or potential subscriber, of whether the organization uses a formulary. A subscriber or potential subscriber may also request information as to whether a specific drug is covered by the organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies and procedures relating to the confidentiality and disclosure of the subscriber’s medical records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decisionmaking process used for approving or denying experimental or investigational medical treatments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies and procedures for addressing the needs of non-English-speaking subscribers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A detailed description of the process used to examine qualifications of and the credentialing of all providers under contract with or employed by the organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance organization shall make available to its subscribers the estimated copay, coinsurance percentage, or deductible, whichever is applicable, for any covered services, the status of the subscriber’s maximum annual out-of-pocket payments for a covered individual or family, and the status of the subscriber’s maximum lifetime benefit. Such estimate shall not preclude the actual copay, coinsurance percentage, or deductible, whichever is applicable, from exceeding the estimate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance organization shall make available on its Internet website a link to the performance outcome and financial data that is published by the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to s. 408.05(3)(k) and shall include in every policy delivered or issued for delivery to any person in the state or any materials provided as required by s. 627.64725 notice that such information is available electronically and the address of its Internet website.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 31, 47, ch. 85-177; s. 22, ch. 87-236; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 91, ch. 91-282; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 9, ch. 97-159; s. 1631, ch. 2003-261; s. 41, ch. 2004-297; s. 16, ch. 2006-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 641.3109.</Text></Note></Section>