<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provider contracts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract between a health maintenance organization and a provider of health care services must be in writing and must contain a provision that the subscriber is not liable to the provider for any services for which the health maintenance organization is liable as specified in s. 641.3154.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all provider contracts executed after October 1, 1991, and within 180 days after October 1, 1991, for contracts in existence as of October 1, 1991:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contracts must require the provider to give 60 days’ advance written notice to the health maintenance organization and the office before canceling the contract with the health maintenance organization for any reason; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract must also provide that nonpayment for goods or services rendered by the provider to the health maintenance organization is not a valid reason for avoiding the 60-day advance notice of cancellation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provider contracts must provide that the health maintenance organization will provide 60 days’ advance written notice to the provider and the office before canceling, without cause, the contract with the provider, except in a case in which a patient’s health is subject to imminent danger or a physician’s ability to practice medicine is effectively impaired by an action by the Board of Medicine or other governmental agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt by the health maintenance organization of a 60-day cancellation notice, the health maintenance organization may, if requested by the provider, terminate the contract in less than 60 days if the health maintenance organization is not financially impaired or insolvent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a contract exists between a health maintenance organization and a provider, the health maintenance organization shall disclose to the provider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mailing address or electronic address where claims should be sent for processing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The telephone number that a provider may call to have questions and concerns regarding claims addressed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address of any separate claims-processing centers for specific types of services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The complete schedule of reimbursements for all the services for which a health maintenance organization and a provider have contracted and any changes in or deviations from the contracted schedule of reimbursements. The health maintenance organization may satisfy this requirement by:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing the schedule of reimbursements or changes in or deviations from the schedule by electronic means to the provider; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing a written copy of the schedule of reimbursements or changes or deviations from the schedule if requested by the provider.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The schedule of reimbursements is subject to the nondisclosure provisions of the contract, and the provider shall maintain the confidentiality of the schedule. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “provider” means a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A health maintenance organization shall provide to its contracted providers no less than 30 calendar days’ prior written notice of any changes in the information required in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between a health maintenance organization and a provider of health care services shall not contain any provision restricting the provider’s ability to communicate information to the provider’s patient regarding medical care or treatment options for the patient when the provider deems knowledge of such information by the patient to be in the best interest of the health of the patient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between a health maintenance organization and a provider of health care services may not contain any provision that in any way prohibits or restricts:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health care provider from entering into a commercial contract with any other health maintenance organization; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health maintenance organization from entering into a commercial contract with any other health care provider.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization or health care provider may not terminate a contract with a health care provider or health maintenance organization unless the party terminating the contract provides the terminated party with a written reason for the contract termination, which may include termination for business reasons of the terminating party. The reason provided in the notice required in this section or any other information relating to the reason for termination does not create any new administrative or civil action and may not be used as substantive evidence in any such action, but may be used for impeachment purposes. As used in this subsection, the term “health care provider” means a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461, or a dentist licensed under chapter 466.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health maintenance organization must establish written procedures for a contract provider to request and the health maintenance organization to grant authorization for utilization of health care services. The health maintenance organization must give written notice to the contract provider prior to any change in these procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between a health maintenance organization and a contracted primary care or admitting physician may not contain any provision that prohibits such physician from providing inpatient services in a contracted hospital to a subscriber if such services are determined by the organization to be medically necessary and covered services under the organization’s contract with the contract holder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization shall not require a contracted health care practitioner as defined in s. 456.001(4) to accept the terms of other health care practitioner contracts with the health maintenance organization or any insurer, or other health maintenance organization, under common management and control with the health maintenance organization, including Medicare and Medicaid practitioner contracts and those authorized by s. 627.6471, s. 627.6472, s. 636.035, or this section, except for a practitioner in a group practice as defined in s. 456.053 who must accept the terms of a contract negotiated for the practitioner by the group, as a condition of continuation or renewal of the contract. Any contract provision that violates this section is void. A violation of this section is not subject to the criminal penalty specified in s. 624.15.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 795, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 12, ch. 83-198; s. 17, ch. 88-388; ss. 125, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 96-223; s. 2, ch. 97-159; s. 2, ch. 99-264; s. 4, ch. 99-275; s. 1, ch. 2000-252; s. 24, ch. 2000-256; s. 3, ch. 2001-107; s. 1582, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2004-321; s. 3, ch. 2009-41.</History></Section>