<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health maintenance organization subscriber protections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to the provisions of this part and part III, the principles expressed in the following statements shall serve as standards to be followed by the commission, the office, the department, and the Agency for Health Care Administration in exercising their powers and duties, in exercising administrative discretion, in administrative interpretations of the law, in enforcing its provisions, and in adopting rules:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization shall ensure that the health care services provided to its subscribers shall be rendered under reasonable standards of quality of care which are at a minimum consistent with the prevailing standards of medical practice in the community pursuant to ss. 641.495(1) and 641.51.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive quality health care from a broad panel of providers, including referrals, preventive care pursuant to s. 641.402(1), emergency screening and services pursuant to ss. 641.31(12) and 641.513, and second opinions pursuant to s. 641.51.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive assurance that the health maintenance organization has been independently accredited by a national review organization pursuant to s. 641.512, and is financially secure as determined by the state pursuant to ss. 641.221, 641.225, and 641.228.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive continuity of health care, even after the provider is no longer with the health maintenance organization pursuant to s. 641.51(8).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive timely, concise information regarding the health maintenance organization’s reimbursement to providers and services pursuant to ss. 641.31 and 641.31015 and should receive prompt payment from the organization pursuant to s. 641.3155.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive the flexibility to transfer to another Florida health maintenance organization, regardless of health status, pursuant to ss. 641.228, 641.3104, 641.3107, 641.3111, 641.3921, and 641.3922.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should be eligible for coverage without discrimination against individual participants and beneficiaries of group plans based on health status pursuant to s. 641.31073.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization that issues a group health contract must: provide coverage for preexisting conditions pursuant to s. 641.31071; guarantee renewability of coverage pursuant to s. 641.31074; provide notice of cancellation pursuant to s. 641.3108; provide extension of benefits pursuant to s. 641.3111; provide for conversion on termination of eligibility pursuant to s. 641.3921; and provide for conversion contracts and conditions pursuant to s. 641.3922.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber should receive timely and, if necessary, urgent grievances and appeals within the health maintenance organization pursuant to ss. 641.228, 641.31(5), 641.47, and 641.511.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization should receive timely and, if necessary, urgent review by an independent state external review organization for unresolved grievances and appeals pursuant to s. 408.7056.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber shall be given written notice at least 30 days in advance of a rate change pursuant to s. 641.31(3)(b). In the case of a group member, there may be a contractual agreement with the health maintenance organization to have the employer provide the required notice to the individual members of the group pursuant to s. 641.31(3)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subscriber shall be given a copy of the applicable health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook specifying: all the provisions, disclosure, and limitations required pursuant to s. 641.31(1) and (4); the covered services, including those services, medical conditions, and provider types specified in ss. 641.31, 641.31094, 641.31095, 641.31096, 641.51(11), and 641.513; and where and in what manner services may be obtained pursuant to s. 641.31(4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed as creating a civil cause of action by any subscriber or provider against any health maintenance organization.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 2000-256; s. 6, ch. 2001-64; s. 8, ch. 2002-389; s. 1554, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>