<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditions precedent to issuance or maintenance of certificate of authority; effect of bankruptcy proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition precedent to the issuance or maintenance of a certificate of authority, a health maintenance organization insurer must file or have on file with the office:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An acknowledgment that a delinquency proceeding pursuant to part I of chapter 631, or supervision by the department pursuant to ss. 624.80-624.87, constitutes the sole and exclusive method for the liquidation, rehabilitation, reorganization, or conservation of a health maintenance organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A waiver of any right to file or be subject to a bankruptcy proceeding.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement of a bankruptcy proceeding either by or against a health maintenance organization shall, by operation of law:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the health maintenance organization’s certificate of authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vest in the office for the use and benefit of the subscribers of the health maintenance organization the title to any deposits of the insurer held by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the proceeding is initiated by a party other than the health maintenance organization, the operation of subsection (2) shall be stayed for a period of 60 days following the date of commencement of the proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 113, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1559, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>