<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0641.3903" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices defined.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are defined as unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION AND FALSE ADVERTISING OF HEALTH MAINTENANCE CONTRACTS.<EmDash />Knowingly making, issuing, or circulating, or causing to be made, issued, or circulated, any estimate, illustration, circular, statement, sales presentation, omission, or comparison which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the benefits, advantages, conditions, or terms of any health maintenance contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is misleading, or is a misrepresentation as to the financial condition of any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses any name or title of any contract misrepresenting the true nature thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a misrepresentation for the purpose of inducing, or tending to induce, the lapse, forfeiture, exchange, conversion, or surrender of any health maintenance contract or health insurance policy, or contract providing health insurance as defined in s. 624.603.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the benefits, nature, characteristics, uses, standard, quantity, quality, cost, rate, scope, source, or geographic origin or location of any goods or services available from or provided by, directly or indirectly, any health maintenance organization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the affiliation, connection, or association of any goods, services, or business establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertises goods or services with intent not to sell them as advertised.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disparages the goods, services, or business of another person by any false or misleading representation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the sponsorship, endorsement, approval, or certification of goods or services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses an advertising format which, by virtue of the design, location, or size of printed matter, is deceptive or misleading or which would be deceptive or misleading to any reasonable person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offers to provide a service which the health maintenance organization is unable to provide.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the availability of a service provided by the health maintenance organization, either directly or indirectly, including the availability of the service as to location.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE INFORMATION AND ADVERTISING GENERALLY.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, circulating, or placing before the public, or causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, or placed before the public:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a newspaper, magazine, or other publication;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the form of a notice, circular, pamphlet, letter, or poster;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Over any radio or television station; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any other way,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">an advertisement, announcement, or statement containing any assertion, representation, or statement with respect to the business of the health maintenance organization which is untrue, deceptive, or misleading.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFAMATION.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating, directly or indirectly, or aiding, abetting, or encouraging the making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating of, any oral or written statement, or any pamphlet, circular, article, or literature, which is false or maliciously critical of any person and which is calculated to injure such person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE STATEMENTS AND ENTRIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing with any supervisory or other public official,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delivering to any person,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing before the public, or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, or delivered to any person, or place before the public,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">any material false statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly making any false entry of a material fact in any book, report, or statement of any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNFAIR CLAIM SETTLEMENT PRACTICES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to settle claims on the basis of an application or any other material document which was altered without notice to, or knowledge or consent of, the subscriber or group of subscribers to a health maintenance organization;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a material misrepresentation to the subscriber for the purpose and with the intent of effecting settlement of claims, loss, or damage under a health maintenance contract on less favorable terms than those provided in, and contemplated by, the contract; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing or performing with such frequency as to indicate a general business practice any of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to adopt and implement standards for the proper investigation of claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresenting pertinent facts or contract provisions relating to coverage at issue;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to acknowledge and act promptly upon communications with respect to claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denying of claims without conducting reasonable investigations based upon available information;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to affirm or deny coverage of claims upon written request of the subscriber within a reasonable time not to exceed 30 days after a claim or proof-of-loss statements have been completed and documents pertinent to the claim have been requested in a timely manner and received by the health maintenance organization;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to promptly provide a reasonable explanation in writing to the subscriber of the basis in the health maintenance contract in relation to the facts or applicable law for denial of a claim or for the offer of a compromise settlement;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to provide, upon written request of a subscriber, itemized statements verifying that services and supplies were furnished, where such statement is necessary for the submission of other insurance claims covered by individual specified disease or limited benefit policies, provided that the organization may receive from the subscriber a reasonable administrative charge for the cost of preparing such statement;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to provide any subscriber with services, care, or treatment contracted for pursuant to any health maintenance contract without a reasonable basis to believe that a legitimate defense exists for not providing such services, care, or treatment. To the extent that a national disaster, war, riot, civil insurrection, epidemic, or any other emergency or similar event not within the control of the health maintenance organization results in the inability of the facilities, personnel, or financial resources of the health maintenance organization to provide or arrange for provision of a health service in accordance with requirements of this part, the health maintenance organization is required only to make a good faith effort to provide or arrange for provision of the service, taking into account the impact of the event. For the purposes of this paragraph, an event is not within the control of the health maintenance organization if the health maintenance organization cannot exercise influence or dominion over its occurrence; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systematic downcoding with the intent to deny reimbursement otherwise due.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAILURE TO MAINTAIN COMPLAINT-HANDLING PROCEDURES.<EmDash />Failure of any person to maintain a complete record of all the complaints received since the date of the most recent examination of the health maintenance organization by the office. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “complaint” means any written communication primarily expressing a grievance and requesting a remedy to the grievance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPERATION WITHOUT A SUBSISTING CERTIFICATE OF AUTHORITY.<EmDash />Operation of a health maintenance organization by any person or entity without a subsisting certificate of authority therefor or renewal, issuance, or delivery of any health maintenance contract by a health maintenance organization, person, or entity without a subsisting certificate of authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION IN HEALTH MAINTENANCE ORGANIZATION APPLICATIONS.<EmDash />Knowingly making false or fraudulent statements or representations on, or relative to, an application for a health maintenance contract for the purpose of obtaining a fee, commission, money, or other benefits from any health maintenance organization; agent; or representative, broker, or individual.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TWISTING.<EmDash />Knowingly making any misleading representations or incomplete or fraudulent comparisons of any health maintenance contracts or health maintenance organizations or of any insurance policies or insurers for the purpose of inducing, or intending to induce, any person to lapse, forfeit, surrender, terminate, retain, pledge, assign, borrow on, or convert any insurance policy or health maintenance contract or to take out a health maintenance contract or policy of insurance in another health maintenance organization or insurer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ILLEGAL DEALINGS IN PREMIUMS; EXCESS OR REDUCED CHARGES FOR HEALTH MAINTENANCE COVERAGE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly collecting any sum as a premium or charge for health maintenance coverage which is not then provided or is not in due course to be provided, subject to acceptance of the risk by the health maintenance organization, by a health maintenance contract issued by a health maintenance organization as permitted by this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly collecting as a premium or charge for health maintenance coverage any sum in excess of or less than the premium or charge applicable to health maintenance coverage, in accordance with the applicable classifications and rates as filed with the office, and as specified in the health maintenance contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE CLAIMS; OBTAINING OR RETAINING MONEY DISHONESTLY.<EmDash />Any agent or representative, physician, claimant, or other person who causes to be presented to any health maintenance organization a false claim for payment knowing the same to be false.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROHIBITED DISCRIMINATORY PRACTICES.<EmDash />A health maintenance organization may not:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage or attempt to engage in discriminatory practices that discourage participation on the basis of actual or perceived health status of Medicaid recipients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse to provide services or care to a subscriber solely because medical services may be or have been sought for injuries resulting from an assault, battery, sexual assault, sexual battery, or any other offense by a family or household member, as defined in s. 741.28, or by another who is or was residing in the same dwelling unit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION IN HEALTH MAINTENANCE ORGANIZATION; AVAILABILITY OF PROVIDERS.<EmDash />Knowingly misleading potential enrollees as to the availability of providers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADVERSE ACTION AGAINST A PROVIDER.<EmDash />Any retaliatory action by a health maintenance organization against a contracted provider, including, but not limited to, termination of a contract with the provider, on the basis that the provider communicated information to the provider’s patient regarding medical care or treatment options for the patient when the provider deems knowledge of such information by the patient to be in the best interest of the patient.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTICIPATION IN A WELLNESS OR HEALTH IMPROVEMENT PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Authorization to offer rewards or incentives for participation.</Font><EmDash />A health maintenance organization issuing a group or individual health benefit plan may offer a voluntary wellness or health improvement program and may encourage or reward participation in the program by authorizing rewards or incentives, including, but not limited to, merchandise, gift cards, debit cards, premium discounts, contributions to a member’s health savings account, or modifications to copayment, deductible, or coinsurance amounts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Verification of medical condition by nonparticipants due to medical condition.</Font><EmDash />A health maintenance organization may require a member of a health benefit plan to provide verification, such as an affirming statement from the member’s physician, that the member’s medical condition makes it unreasonably difficult or inadvisable to participate in the wellness or health improvement program in order for that nonparticipant to receive the reward or incentive.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Disclosure requirement.</Font><EmDash />A reward or incentive offered under this subsection shall be disclosed in the policy or certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Other incentives.</Font><EmDash />This subsection does not prohibit health maintenance organizations from offering other incentives or rewards for adherence to a wellness or health improvement program if otherwise authorized by state or federal law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 36, 47, ch. 85-177; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 28, ch. 96-199; s. 6, ch. 96-223; s. 1, ch. 99-264; s. 5, ch. 2000-252; s. 8, ch. 2002-55; s. 1591, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2011-167.</History>
</Section>