<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation or cancellation of certificate of authority; suspension of authority to enroll new subscribers; terms of suspension.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance of a valid and current Health Care Provider Certificate issued pursuant to part III of this chapter is a condition of the maintenance of a valid and current certificate of authority issued by the office to operate a prepaid health clinic. Revocation or nonrenewal of a Health Care Provider Certificate shall be deemed to be an automatic and immediate cancellation of a prepaid health clinic’s certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may suspend the authority of a clinic to enroll new subscribers or revoke any certificate of authority issued to a prepaid health clinic, or order compliance within 60 days, if the office finds that any of the following conditions exist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinic is not operating in compliance with this part or any rule promulgated under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan is no longer actuarially sound or the clinic does not have the minimum surplus as required by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existing contract rates are excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinic has advertised, merchandised, or attempted to merchandise its services in such a manner as to misrepresent its services or capacity for services or has engaged in deceptive, misleading, or unfair practices with respect to advertising or merchandising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization is insolvent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinic has not complied with the grievance procedures for subscribers that are set forth in any prepaid health clinic contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinic has not fully satisfied a judgment against the clinic within 10 days of the entry of the judgment by any court in the state or, in the case of an appeal from such judgment, has not fully satisfied the judgment within 60 days after affirmance of the judgment by the appellate court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall, in its order suspending the authority of a clinic to enroll new subscribers, specify the period during which the suspension is to be in effect and the conditions, if any, which must be met by the clinic prior to reinstatement of its authority to enroll new subscribers. The order of suspension is subject to rescission or modification by further order of the office prior to the expiration of the suspension period. Reinstatement shall not be made unless requested by the clinic; however, the office shall not grant reinstatement if it finds that the circumstances for which the suspension occurred still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 11, ch. 84-313; s. 18, ch. 87-236; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 49, ch. 95-211; s. 1619, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>