<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health maintenance contracts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity issued a certificate and otherwise in compliance with this part may enter into contracts in this state to provide an agreed-upon set of comprehensive health care services to subscribers in exchange for a prepaid per capita sum or a prepaid aggregate fixed sum. Each subscriber shall be given a copy of the applicable health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook. Whichever document is provided to a subscriber shall contain all of the provisions and disclosures required by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rates charged by any health maintenance organization to its subscribers shall not be excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory or follow a rating methodology that is inconsistent, indeterminate, or ambiguous or encourages misrepresentation or misunderstanding. A law restricting or limiting deductibles, coinsurance, copayments, or annual or lifetime maximum payments shall not apply to any health maintenance organization contract that provides coverage as described in s. 641.31071(5)(a)2., offered or delivered to an individual or a group of 51 or more persons. The commission, in accordance with generally accepted actuarial practice as applied to health maintenance organizations, may define by rule what constitutes excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory rates and may require whatever information it deems necessary to determine that a rate or proposed rate meets the requirements of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a health maintenance organization desires to amend any contract with its subscribers or any certificate or member handbook, or desires to change any basic health maintenance contract, certificate, grievance procedure, or member handbook form, or application form where written application is required and is to be made a part of the contract, or printed amendment, addendum, rider, or endorsement form or form of renewal certificate, it may do so, upon filing with the office the proposed change or amendment. Any proposed change shall be effective immediately, subject to disapproval by the office. Following receipt of notice of such disapproval or withdrawal of approval, no health maintenance organization shall issue or use any form disapproved by the office or as to which the office has withdrawn approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in the rate is subject to paragraph (d) and requires at least 30 days’ advance written notice to the subscriber. In the case of a group member, there may be a contractual agreement with the health maintenance organization to have the employer provide the required notice to the individual members of the group.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall disapprove any form filed under this subsection, or withdraw any previous approval thereof, if the form:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in any respect in violation of, or does not comply with, any provision of this part or rule adopted thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains or incorporates by reference, where such incorporation is otherwise permissible, any inconsistent, ambiguous, or misleading clauses or exceptions and conditions which deceptively affect the risk purported to be assumed in the general coverage of the contract.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has any title, heading, or other indication of its provisions which is misleading.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is printed or otherwise reproduced in such a manner as to render any material provision of the form substantially illegible.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains provisions which are unfair, inequitable, or contrary to the public policy of this state or which encourage misrepresentation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Excludes coverage for human immunodeficiency virus infection or acquired immune deficiency syndrome or contains limitations in the benefits payable, or in the terms or conditions of such contract, for human immunodeficiency virus infection or acquired immune deficiency syndrome which are different than those which apply to any other sickness or medical condition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in rates charged for the contract must be filed with the office not less than 30 days in advance of the effective date. At the expiration of such 30 days, the rate filing shall be deemed approved unless prior to such time the filing has been affirmatively approved or disapproved by order of the office. The approval of the filing by the office constitutes a waiver of any unexpired portion of such waiting period. The office may extend by not more than an additional 15 days the period within which it may so affirmatively approve or disapprove any such filing, by giving notice of such extension before expiration of the initial 30-day period. At the expiration of any such period as so extended, and in the absence of such prior affirmative approval or disapproval, any such filing shall be deemed approved. This paragraph does not apply to group health contracts effectuated and delivered in this state, insuring groups of 51 or more persons, except for Medicare supplement insurance, long-term care insurance, and any coverage under which the increase in claims costs over the lifetime of the contract due to advancing age or duration is prefunded in the premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not the intent of this subsection to restrict unduly the right to modify rates in the exercise of reasonable business judgment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook shall clearly state all of the services to which a subscriber is entitled under the contract and must include a clear and understandable statement of any limitations on the services or kinds of services to be provided, including any copayment feature or schedule of benefits required by the contract or by any insurer or entity which is underwriting any of the services offered by the health maintenance organization. The contract, certificate, or member handbook shall also state where and in what manner the comprehensive health care services may be obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every subscriber shall receive a clear and understandable description of the method of the health maintenance organization for resolving subscriber grievances, and the method shall be set forth in the contract, certificate, and member handbook. The organization shall also furnish, at the time of initial enrollment and when necessary due to substantial changes to the grievance process a separate and additional communication prepared or approved by the office notifying the contract holder of a group contract or subscriber of an individual contract of their rights and responsibilities under the grievance process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate of payment for a health maintenance contract shall be a part of the contract and shall be stated in individual contracts issued to subscribers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization is entitled to coordinate benefits on the same basis as an insurer under s. 627.4235.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization providing medical benefits or payments to a subscriber who suffers injury, disease, or illness by virtue of the negligent act or omission of a third party is entitled to reimbursement from the subscriber in accordance with s. 768.76(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts that provide coverage, benefits, or services for a member of the family of the subscriber must, as to such family member’s coverage, benefits, or services, provide also that the coverage, benefits, or services applicable for children must be provided with respect to a newborn child of the subscriber, or covered family member of the subscriber, from the moment of birth. However, with respect to a newborn child of a covered family member other than the spouse of the insured or subscriber, the coverage for the newborn child terminates 18 months after the birth of the newborn child. The coverage, benefits, or services for newborn children must consist of coverage for injury or sickness, including the necessary care or treatment of medically diagnosed congenital defects, birth abnormalities, or prematurity, and transportation costs of the newborn to and from the nearest appropriate facility appropriately staffed and equipped to treat the newborn’s condition, when such transportation is certified by the attending physician as medically necessary to protect the health and safety of the newborn child.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract may require the subscriber to notify the plan of the birth of a child within a time period, as specified in the contract, of not less than 30 days after the birth, or a contract may require the preenrollment of a newborn prior to birth. However, if timely notice is given, a plan may not charge an additional premium for additional coverage of the newborn child for not less than 30 days after the birth of the child. If timely notice is not given, the plan may charge an additional premium from the date of birth. If notice is given within 60 days of the birth of the child, the contract may not deny coverage of the child due to failure of the subscriber to timely notify the plan of the birth of the child or to preenroll the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the contract does not require the subscriber to notify the plan of the birth of a child within a specified time period, the plan may not deny coverage of the child nor may it retroactively charge the subscriber an additional premium for the child; however, the contract may prospectively charge the member an additional premium for the child if the plan provides at least 45 days’ notice of the additional charge.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No alteration of any written application for any health maintenance contract shall be made by any person other than the applicant without his or her written consent, except that insertions may be made by the health maintenance organization, for administrative purposes only, in such manner as to indicate clearly that such insertions are not to be ascribed to the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No contract shall contain any waiver of rights or benefits provided to or available to subscribers under the provisions of any law or rule applicable to health maintenance organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook shall state that emergency services and care shall be provided to subscribers in emergency situations not permitting treatment through the health maintenance organization’s providers, without prior notification to and approval of the organization. Not less than 75 percent of the reasonable charges for covered services and supplies shall be paid by the organization, up to the subscriber contract benefit limits. Payment also may be subject to additional applicable copayment provisions, not to exceed $100 per claim. The health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook shall contain the definitions of “emergency services and care” and “emergency medical condition” as specified in s. 641.19(6) and (7), shall describe procedures for determination by the health maintenance organization of whether the services qualify for reimbursement as emergency services and care, and shall contain specific examples of what does constitute an emergency. In providing for emergency services and care as a covered service, a health maintenance organization shall be governed by s. 641.513.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of this section, with respect to a person who is entitled to have payments for health care costs made under Medicare, Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (“Medicare”), parts A and/or B:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health maintenance organization shall mail or deliver notification to the Medicare beneficiary of the date of enrollment in the health maintenance organization within 10 days after receiving notification of enrollment approval from the United States Department of Health and Human Services, Health Care Financing Administration. When a Medicare beneficiary who is a subscriber of the health maintenance organization requests disenrollment from the organization, the organization shall mail or deliver to the beneficiary notice of the effective date of the disenrollment within 10 days after receipt of the written disenrollment request. The health maintenance organization shall forward the disenrollment request to the United States Department of Health and Human Services, Health Care Financing Administration, in a timely manner so as to effectuate the next available disenrollment date, as prescribed by such federal agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health maintenance contract, certificate, or member handbook shall be delivered to the subscriber no later than the earlier of 10 working days after the health maintenance organization and the Health Care Financing Administration of the United States Department of Health and Human Services approve the subscriber’s enrollment application or the effective date of coverage of the subscriber under the health maintenance contract. However, if notice from the Health Care Financing Administration of its approval of the subscriber’s enrollment application is received by the health maintenance organization after the effective coverage date prescribed by the Health Care Financing Administration, the health maintenance organization shall deliver the contract, certificate, or member handbook to the subscriber within 10 days after receiving such notice. When a Medicare recipient is enrolled in a health maintenance organization program, the contract, certificate, or member handbook shall be accompanied by a health maintenance organization identification sticker with instruction to the Medicare beneficiary to place the sticker on the Medicare identification card.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a subscriber of a health maintenance organization is also a Medicaid recipient, the health maintenance organization’s coverage shall be primary to the recipient’s Medicaid benefits and the organization shall be a third party subject to the provisions of s. 409.910(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts, certificates, and member handbooks shall contain the following provision:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">“Grace Period: This contract has a (insert a number not less than 10) day grace period. This provision means that if any required premium is not paid on or before the date it is due, it may be paid during the following grace period. During the grace period, the contract will stay in force.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The required provision of paragraph (a) shall not apply to certificates or member handbooks delivered to individual subscribers under a group health maintenance contract when the employer or other person who will hold the contract on behalf of the subscriber group pays the entire premium for the individual subscribers. However, such required provision shall apply to the group health maintenance contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contracts must clearly disclose the intent of the health maintenance organization as to the applicability or nonapplicability of coverage to preexisting conditions. If coverage of the contract is not to be applicable to preexisting conditions, the contract shall specify, in substance, that coverage pertains solely to accidental bodily injuries resulting from accidents occurring after the effective date of coverage and that sicknesses are limited to those which first manifest themselves subsequent to the effective date of coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts that provide coverage for a member of the family of the subscriber, shall, as to such family member’s coverage, provide that coverage, benefits, or services applicable for children shall be provided with respect to an adopted child of the subscriber, which child is placed in compliance with chapter 63, from the moment of placement in the residence of the subscriber. Such contracts may not exclude coverage for any preexisting condition of the child. In the case of a newborn child, coverage shall begin from the moment of birth if a written agreement to adopt such child has been entered into by the subscriber prior to the birth of the child, whether or not such agreement is enforceable. However, coverage for such child shall not be required in the event that the child is not ultimately placed in the residence of the subscriber in compliance with chapter 63.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health maintenance contracts that provide coverage, benefits, or services for maternity care must provide, as an option to the subscriber, the services of nurse-midwives and midwives licensed pursuant to chapter 467, and the services of birth centers licensed pursuant to ss. 383.30-383.335, if such services are available within the service area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health maintenance contract that provides maternity or newborn coverage may not limit coverage for the length of a maternity or newborn stay in a hospital or for followup care outside of a hospital to any time period that is less than that determined to be medically necessary, in accordance with prevailing medical standards and consistent with guidelines for perinatal care of the American Academy of Pediatrics or the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, by the treating obstetrical care provider or the pediatric care provider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect any agreement between a health maintenance organization and a hospital or other health care provider with respect to reimbursement for health care services provided, rate negotiations with providers, or capitation of providers, and this section does not prohibit appropriate utilization review or case management by a health maintenance organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health maintenance contract that provides coverage, benefits, or services for maternity or newborn care must provide coverage for postdelivery care for a mother and her newborn infant. The postdelivery care must include a postpartum assessment and newborn assessment and may be provided at the hospital, at the attending physician’s office, at an outpatient maternity center, or in the home by a qualified licensed health care professional trained in mother and baby care. The services must include physical assessment of the newborn and mother, and the performance of any medically necessary clinical tests and immunizations in keeping with prevailing medical standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subject to paragraph (b) shall communicate active case questions and concerns regarding postdelivery care directly to the treating physician or hospital in written form, in addition to other forms of communication. Such organization shall also use a process that includes a written protocol for utilization review and quality assurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health maintenance organization subject to paragraph (b) may not:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deny to a mother or her newborn infant eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the contract for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide monetary payments or rebates to a mother to encourage the mother to accept less than the minimum protections available under this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of an attending provider solely because the attending provider provided care to an individual participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide incentives, monetary or otherwise, to an attending provider solely to induce the provider to provide care to an individual participant or beneficiary in a manner inconsistent with this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to paragraph (i), restrict benefits for any portion of a period within a hospital length of stay required under paragraph (b) in a manner that is less favorable than the benefits provided for any preceding portion of such stay.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not require a mother who is a participant or beneficiary to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give birth in a hospital.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stay in the hospital for a fixed period of time following the birth of her infant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply with respect to any coverage offered by a health maintenance organization that does not provide benefits for hospital lengths of stay in connection with childbirth for a mother or her newborn infant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prevent a health maintenance organization from imposing deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost sharing in relation to benefits for hospital lengths of stay in connection with childbirth for a mother or her newborn infant under the contract or under health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan, except that such coinsurance or other cost sharing for any portion of a period within a hospital length of stay required under paragraph (b) may not be greater than such coinsurance or cost sharing for any preceding portion of such stay.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, health maintenance policies or contracts which provide coverage, benefits, or services as described in s. 463.002(5), shall offer to the subscriber the services of an optometrist licensed pursuant to chapter 463.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, health maintenance policies or contracts which provide coverage, benefits, or services which are performed by physicians who are ophthalmologists, licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459, shall offer the subscriber the services of an ophthalmologist. For purposes of this subsection, ophthalmologists are physicians specializing in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases and injuries of the eye.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, health maintenance policies or contracts which provide anesthesia coverage, benefits, or services shall offer to the subscriber, if requested and available, the services of a certified registered nurse anesthetist licensed pursuant to part I of chapter 464.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance organization that offers a group plan within this state must have at least one open enrollment period of not less than 30 days every 18 months. Such open enrollment periods are required for as long as the group exists unless the health maintenance organization and the employer mutually agree to a shorter period of time than 18 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall include the following provision:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">“Time limit on certain defenses: Relative to a misstatement in the application, after 2 years from the issue date, only fraudulent misstatements in the application may be used to void the policy or deny any claim for loss incurred or disability starting after the 2-year period.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance organization that provides for inpatient and outpatient services by allopathic hospitals shall provide as an option of the subscriber similar inpatient and outpatient services by hospitals accredited by the American Osteopathic Association when such services are available in the same service area of the HMO and the osteopathic hospital agrees to provide the services as specified herein. As a condition precedent to providing osteopathic inpatient and outpatient services through an osteopathic hospital that has not entered into a written contract with the HMO, the HMO may require the subscriber or any other person receiving osteopathic services to release the HMO from any liability arising from any act of omission or commission constituting malpractice in the delivery of osteopathic care from that hospital. The osteopathic hospital providing the inpatient and outpatient services for the HMO shall charge rates that do not exceed the osteopathic hospital’s usual and customary rates less the average discount provided by allopathic hospitals providing the HMO services in the same service area of the HMO.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a subscriber is a resident of a continuing care facility certified under chapter 651 or a retirement facility consisting of a nursing home or assisted living facility and residential apartments, the subscriber’s primary care physician must refer the subscriber to that facility’s skilled nursing unit or assisted living facility if requested by the subscriber and agreed to by the facility; if the primary care physician finds that such care is medically necessary; if the facility agrees to be reimbursed at the health maintenance organization’s contract rate negotiated with similar providers for the same services and supplies; and if the facility meets all guidelines established by the health maintenance organization related to quality of care, utilization, referral authorization, risk assumption, use of the health maintenance organization’s network, and other criteria applicable to providers under contract for the same services and supplies. If a health maintenance organization enrolls a new subscriber who already resides in a continuing care facility or a retirement facility as described in this subsection, the health maintenance organization must provide in writing a disclosure of the subscriber’s rights under this subsection. If a subscriber’s request to be referred to the skilled nursing unit or assisted living facility that is part of the subscriber’s place of residence is not honored, the subscriber may use the grievance process provided in s. 641.511.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health maintenance organization and prepaid health plan shall provide coverage for all medically appropriate and necessary equipment, supplies, and services used to treat diabetes, including outpatient self-management training and educational services, if the patient’s primary care physician, or the physician to whom the patient has been referred who specializes in treating diabetes, certifies that the equipment, supplies, or services are necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract may require that diabetes outpatient self-management training and educational services be provided under the direct supervision of a certified diabetes educator or a board-certified endocrinologist under contract with or designated by the health maintenance organization or prepaid health plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall adopt standards for outpatient self-management training and educational services, taking into consideration standards approved by the American Diabetes Association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health maintenance contract that covers a resident of this state and that is issued, amended, delivered, or renewed in this state after October 1, 1996, must provide coverage for the medically necessary diagnosis and treatment of osteoporosis for high-risk individuals, including, but not limited to, estrogen-deficient individuals who are at clinical risk for osteoporosis, individuals who have vertebral abnormalities, individuals who are receiving long-term glucocorticoid (steroid) therapy, individuals who have primary hyperparathyroidism, and individuals who have a family history of osteoporosis. This subsection shall not apply to the state employee health insurance program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization may not discriminate against or fail to contract with a hospital, based solely on the fact that the hospital’s medical staff is comprised of physicians licensed under chapter 459. Nothing in this subsection shall mandate that a health maintenance organization contract with a hospital.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a health maintenance contract provides that coverage of a dependent child of the subscriber will terminate upon attainment of the limiting age for dependent children which is specified in the contract, the contract must also provide in substance that attainment of the limiting age does not terminate the coverage of the child while the child continues to be both:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incapable of self-sustaining employment by reason of mental retardation or physical handicap, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chiefly dependent upon the employee or member for support and maintenance.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the claim is denied under a contract for the stated reason that the child has attained the limiting age for dependent children specified in the contract, the notice or denial must state that the subscriber has the burden of establishing that the child continues to meet the criteria specified in paragraphs (a) and (b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts which provide coverage, benefits, or services for a member of the family of the subscriber must, as to such family member’s coverage, benefits, or services, also provide that the benefits applicable for children include coverage for child health supervision services from the moment of birth to age 16 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “child health supervision services” means physician-delivered or physician-supervised services that include, at a minimum, services delivered at the intervals and scope stated in this subsection.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Child health supervision services must include periodic visits which shall include a history, a physical examination, a developmental assessment and anticipatory guidance, and appropriate immunizations and laboratory tests. Such services and periodic visits shall be provided in accordance with prevailing medical standards consistent with the Recommendations for Preventive Pediatric Health Care of the American Academy of Pediatrics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimum benefits may be limited to one visit payable to one provider for all of the services provided at each visit cited in this subsection.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="31"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health maintenance contracts that provide coverage, benefits, or services for breast cancer treatment may not limit inpatient hospital coverage for mastectomies to any period that is less than that determined by the treating physician under contract with the health maintenance organization to be medically necessary in accordance with prevailing medical standards and after consultation with the covered patient. Such contract must also provide coverage for outpatient postsurgical followup care in keeping with prevailing medical standards by a licensed health care professional under contract with the health maintenance organization qualified to provide postsurgical mastectomy care. The treating physician under contract with the health maintenance organization, after consultation with the covered patient, may choose that the outpatient care be provided at the most medically appropriate setting, which may include the hospital, treating physician’s office, outpatient center, or home of the covered patient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization subject to this subsection may not:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deny to a covered person eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or to renew coverage under the terms of the contract for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this subsection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide monetary payments or rebates to a covered patient to accept less than the minimum protections available under this subsection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of an attending provider solely because the attending provider provided care to a covered patient under this subsection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide incentives, monetary or otherwise, to an attending provider solely to induce the provider to provide care to a covered patient in a manner inconsistent with this subsection; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the other provisions of this subsection, restrict benefits for any portion of a period within a hospital length of stay or outpatient care as required by this subsection in a manner that is less than favorable than the benefits provided for any preceding portion of such stay.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not require a covered patient to have the mastectomy in the hospital or stay in the hospital for a fixed period of time following the mastectomy.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prevent a contract from imposing deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost sharing in relation to benefits pursuant to this subsection, except that such cost sharing shall not exceed cost sharing with other benefits.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (b), this subsection does not affect any agreement between a health maintenance organization and a hospital or other health care provider with respect to reimbursement for health care services provided, rate negotiations with providers, or capitation of providers, and does not prohibit appropriate utilization review or case management by the health maintenance organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “mastectomy” means the removal of all or part of the breast for medically necessary reasons as determined by a licensed physician.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="32"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance contract that provides coverage for mastectomies must also provide coverage for prosthetic devices and breast reconstructive surgery incident to the mastectomy. As used in this subsection, the term “breast reconstructive surgery” means surgery to reestablish symmetry between the two breasts. Such surgery must be in a manner chosen by the treating physician under contract with the health maintenance organization, consistent with prevailing medical standards, and in consultation with the patient. The health maintenance organization may charge an appropriate additional premium for the coverage required by this subsection. The coverage for prosthetic devices and breast reconstructive surgery shall be subject to any deductible and coinsurance conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="33"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this section to the contrary, a health maintenance organization which offers dermatological services shall provide direct patient access, for office visits and minor procedures and testing, to a dermatologist who is under contract with the health maintenance organization. The term “direct patient access” means the ability of a subscriber to obtain such services without a referral or other authorization before receiving services. The health maintenance organization shall, by July 1, 1997, develop criteria for compliance with the provisions of this subsection which do not impede or inhibit access to dermatological services for policyholders of the health maintenance organization. The criteria may include a maximum of five office visits to a dermatologist without prior authorization for a dermatologic problem within a 12-month period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="34"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, dental treatment or surgery shall be considered necessary when the dental condition is likely to result in a medical condition if left untreated. Any health maintenance organization contract which provides coverage for general anesthesia and hospitalization services to a covered person shall not preclude such coverage in assuring the safe delivery of necessary dental care provided to a covered person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is under 8 years of age and is determined by a licensed dentist, and the child’s physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, to require necessary dental treatment in a hospital or ambulatory surgical center due to a significantly complex dental condition or a developmental disability in which patient management in the dental office has proved to be ineffective; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has one or more medical conditions that would create significant or undue medical risk for the individual in the course of delivery of any necessary dental treatment or surgery if not rendered in a hospital or ambulatory surgical center.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">As provided herein, all terms and conditions of the covered person’s health maintenance organization contract shall apply to such services, and this section does not require coverage for the diagnosis or treatment of dental disease. A health maintenance organization may require prior authorization for general anesthesia and hospital services required under this section in the same manner the organization requires prior authorization for hospitalization for other covered services. This subsection shall not apply to Medicare supplement, long-term care, disability, limited benefit, accident only, or specified disease policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="35"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance contract that covers a child under the age of 18 must provide coverage for treatment of cleft lip and cleft palate for the child. The coverage must include medical, dental, speech therapy, audiology, and nutrition services only if such services are prescribed by the primary care physician or physician to whom the child is referred and such physician certifies that such services are medically necessary and consequent to treatment of the cleft lip or cleft palate. The coverage required by this section is subject to terms and conditions applicable to other benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="36"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization may increase the copayment for any benefit, or delete, amend, or limit any of the benefits to which a subscriber is entitled under the group contract only, upon written notice to the contract holder at least 45 days in advance of the time of coverage renewal. The health maintenance organization may amend the contract with the contract holder, with such amendment to be effective immediately at the time of coverage renewal. The written notice to the contract holder shall specifically identify any deletions, amendments, or limitations to any of the benefits provided in the group contract during the current contract period which will be included in the group contract upon renewal. This subsection does not apply to any increases in benefits. The 45-day notice requirement shall not apply if benefits are amended, deleted, or limited at the request of the contract holder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="37"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts that provide coverage for massage must also cover the services of persons licensed to practice massage pursuant to chapter 480 if the massage is prescribed by a contracted physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461 as medically necessary and the prescription specifies the number of treatments. Such massage services are subject to the same terms, conditions, and limitations as those of other covered services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="38"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, a health maintenance organization that meets the requirements of paragraph (b) may, through a point-of-service rider to its contract providing comprehensive health care services, include a point-of-service benefit. Under such a rider, a subscriber or other covered person of the health maintenance organization may choose, at the time of covered service, a provider with whom the health maintenance organization does not have a health maintenance organization provider contract. The rider may not require a referral from the health maintenance organization for the point-of-service benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization offering a point-of-service rider under this subsection must have a valid certificate of authority issued under the provisions of the chapter, must have been licensed under this chapter for a minimum of 3 years, and must at all times that it has riders in effect maintain a minimum surplus of $5 million. A health maintenance organization offering a point-of-service rider to its contract providing comprehensive health care services may offer the rider to employers who have employees living and working outside the health maintenance organization’s approved geographic service area without having to obtain a health care provider certificate, as long as the master group contract is issued to an employer that maintains its primary place of business within the health maintenance organization’s approved service area. Any member or subscriber that lives and works outside the health maintenance organization’s service area and elects coverage under the health maintenance organization’s point-of-service rider must provide a statement to the health maintenance organization that indicates the member or subscriber understands the limitations of his or her policy and that only those benefits under the point-of-service rider will be covered when services are provided outside the service area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums paid in for the point-of-service riders may not exceed 15 percent of total premiums for all health plan products sold by the health maintenance organization offering the rider. If the premiums paid for point-of-service riders exceed 15 percent, the health maintenance organization must notify the office and, once this fact is known, must immediately cease offering such a rider until it is in compliance with the rider premium cap.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the limitations of deductibles and copayment provisions in this part, a point-of-service rider may require the subscriber to pay a reasonable copayment for each visit for services provided by a noncontracted provider chosen at the time of the service. The copayment by the subscriber may either be a specific dollar amount or a percentage of the reimbursable provider charges covered by the contract and must be paid by the subscriber to the noncontracted provider upon receipt of covered services. The point-of-service rider may require that a reasonable annual deductible for the expenses associated with the point-of-service rider be met and may include a lifetime maximum benefit amount. The rider must include the language required by s. 627.6044 and must comply with copayment limits described in s. 627.6471. Section 641.3154 does not apply to a point-of-service rider authorized under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The point-of-service rider must contain provisions that comply with s. 627.6044.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “point of service” may not be used by a health maintenance organization except with riders permitted under this section or with forms approved by the office in which a point-of-service product is offered with an indemnity carrier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A point-of-service rider must be filed and approved under ss. 627.410 and 627.411.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="39"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization contract may not prohibit or restrict a subscriber from receiving inpatient services in a contracted hospital from a contracted primary care or admitting physician if such services are determined by the organization to be medically necessary and covered services under the organization’s contract with the contract holder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="40"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any group rate, rating schedule, or rating manual for a health maintenance organization policy, which provides creditable coverage as defined in s. 627.6561(5), filed with the office shall provide for an appropriate rebate of premiums paid in the last policy year, contract year, or calendar year when the majority of members of a health plan are enrolled in and have maintained participation in any health wellness, maintenance, or improvement program offered by the group contract holder. The group must provide evidence of demonstrative maintenance or improvement of his or her health status as determined by assessments of agreed-upon health status indicators between the group and the health insurer, including, but not limited to, reduction in weight, body mass index, and smoking cessation. Any rebate provided by the health maintenance organization is presumed to be appropriate unless credible data demonstrates otherwise, or unless the rebate program requires the insured to incur costs to qualify for the rebate which equals or exceeds the value of the rebate but the rebate may not exceed 10 percent of paid premiums.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premium rebate authorized by this section shall be effective for a subscriber on an annual basis, unless the number of participating members on the contract renewal anniversary becomes fewer than the majority of the members eligible for participation in the wellness program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization that issues individual contracts may offer a premium rebate, as provided under this section, for a healthy lifestyle program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="41"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health maintenance contracts providing coverage for a member of the subscriber’s family must comply with the provisions of s. 627.6562.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="42"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract, certificate, or member handbook must be accompanied by an identification card that contains, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the organization offering the contract or name of the organization administering the contract, whichever applies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the subscriber.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the health plan is a health maintenance organization. Only a health plan with a certificate of authority issued under this chapter may be identified as a health maintenance organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The member identification number, contract number, and group number, if applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contact phone number or electronic address for authorizations and admission certifications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A phone number or electronic address whereby the covered person or hospital, physician, or other person rendering services covered by the contract may obtain benefits verification and information in order to estimate patient financial responsibility, in compliance with privacy rules under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The national plan identifier, in accordance with the compliance date set forth by the federal Department of Health and Human Services.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The identification card must present the information in a readily identifiable manner or, alternatively, the information may be embedded on the card and available through magnetic stripe or smart card. The information may also be provided through other electronic technology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="43"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever, in any health maintenance organization claim form, a subscriber specifically authorizes payment of benefits directly to any contracted hospital, ambulance provider, physician, or dentist, the health maintenance organization shall make such payment to the designated provider of such services if any benefits are due to the subscriber under the terms of the agreement between the subscriber and the health maintenance organization. The health maintenance organization contract may not prohibit, and claims forms must provide an option for, the payment of benefits directly to a licensed hospital, ambulance provider, physician, or dentist for covered services provided, for services provided pursuant to s. 395.1041, and for ambulance transport and treatment provided pursuant to part III of chapter 401. The attestation of assignment of benefits may be in written or electronic form. Payment to the provider from the health maintenance organization may not be more than the amount that the insurer would otherwise have paid without the assignment. This subsection does not affect the applicability of ss. 641.3154 and 641.513 with respect to services provided and payment for such services provided pursuant to the subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 72-264; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 794, 804, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 11, ch. 83-198; s. 9, ch. 84-313; s. 21, ch. 85-177; ss. 2, 11, ch. 87-236; s. 2, ch. 87-273; s. 3, ch. 88-269; s. 52, ch. 88-380; s. 14, ch. 88-388; s. 4, ch. 89-190; s. 1, ch. 89-357; s. 9, ch. 90-232; s. 38, ch. 90-295; ss. 121, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 61, ch. 91-110; s. 3, ch. 91-185; s. 69, ch. 91-282; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-245; s. 27, ch. 95-418; s. 3, ch. 96-195; s. 25, ch. 96-199; ss. 3, 5, ch. 96-279; s. 4, ch. 96-282; s. 12, ch. 97-48; s. 1752, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 97-166; s. 2, ch. 97-171; s. 23, ch. 97-179; s. 5, ch. 98-66; s. 23, ch. 98-159; s. 4, ch. 98-312; s. 5, ch. 99-264; s. 3, ch. 99-275; s. 4, ch. 99-393; s. 13, ch. 2000-252; s. 23, ch. 2000-256; s. 142, ch. 2000-318; s. 4, ch. 2003-139; s. 1578, ch. 2003-261; s. 135, ch. 2004-5; s. 34, ch. 2004-297; s. 10, ch. 2005-231; s. 98, ch. 2006-1; s. 1, ch. 2007-215; s. 10, ch. 2008-32; s. 4, ch. 2008-119; s. 7, ch. 2008-212.</History></Section>