<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Language used in contracts and advertisements; translations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All prepaid health clinic contracts or forms shall be printed in English.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the negotiations by a prepaid health clinic with a subscriber leading up to the effectuation of a prepaid health clinic contract are conducted in a language other than English, the prepaid health clinic shall supply to the subscriber a written translation of the contract, which translation accurately reflects the substance of the contract and is in the language used to negotiate the contract. Any such translation shall be furnished to the office as part of the filing of the prepaid health clinic contract form and shall be approved by the office prior to use. No translation of a prepaid health clinic contract form shall be approved by the office unless the translation accurately reflects the substance of the prepaid health clinic contract form in translation. When a translation of a prepaid health clinic contract is used, the translation shall clearly and conspicuously state on its face and in the language of the translation:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">READ THIS FIRST</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">This is a translation of the document that you are about to sign.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All advertisements by a prepaid health clinic, if printed or broadcast in a language other than English, also shall be available in English and shall be furnished to the office upon request. As used in this subsection, the term “advertisement” means any advertisement, circular, pamphlet, brochure, or other printed material disclosing or disseminating advertising material or information by a clinic to prospective or existing subscribers and includes any radio or television transmittal of an advertisement or information.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 11, ch. 84-313; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1610, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>