<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination by the department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall examine the affairs, transactions, accounts, business records, and assets of any health maintenance organization as often as it deems it expedient for the protection of the people of this state, but not less frequently than once every 5 years. However, except when the medical records are requested and copies furnished pursuant to s. 456.057, medical records of individuals and records of physicians providing service under contract to the health maintenance organization shall not be subject to audit, although they may be subject to subpoena by court order upon a showing of good cause. For the purpose of examinations, the office may administer oaths to and examine the officers and agents of a health maintenance organization concerning its business and affairs. The examination of each health maintenance organization by the office shall be subject to the same terms and conditions as apply to insurers under chapter 624. In no event shall expenses of all examinations exceed a maximum of $50,000 for any 1-year period. Any rehabilitation, liquidation, conservation, or dissolution of a health maintenance organization shall be conducted under the supervision of the department, which shall have all power with respect thereto granted to it under the laws governing the rehabilitation, liquidation, reorganization, conservation, or dissolution of life insurance companies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may contract, at reasonable fees for work performed, with qualified, impartial outside sources to perform audits or examinations or portions thereof pertaining to the qualification of an entity for issuance of a certificate of authority or to determine continued compliance with the requirements of this part, in which case the payment must be made directly to the contracted examiner by the health maintenance organization examined, in accordance with the rates and terms agreed to by the office and the examiner. Any contracted assistance shall be under the direct supervision of the office. The results of any contracted assistance shall be subject to the review of, and approval, disapproval, or modification by, the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 72-264; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 789, 804, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 8, ch. 83-198; s. 14, ch. 85-177; s. 9, ch. 87-236; s. 12, ch. 88-388; ss. 117, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 161, ch. 98-166; s. 222, ch. 2000-160; s. 73, ch. 2000-318; s. 1570, ch. 2003-261; s. 9, ch. 2005-231.</History></Section>