<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.3108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of cancellation of contract.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for nonpayment of premium or termination of eligibility, no health maintenance organization may cancel or otherwise terminate or fail to renew a health maintenance contract without giving the subscriber at least 45 days’ notice in writing of the cancellation, termination, or nonrenewal of the contract. The written notice shall state the reason or reasons for the cancellation, termination, or nonrenewal. All health maintenance contracts shall contain a clause which requires that this notice be given.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If cancellation is due to nonpayment of premium, the health maintenance organization may not retroactively cancel the contract to a date prior to the date that notice of cancellation was provided to the subscriber unless the organization mails notice of cancellation to the subscriber prior to 45 days after the date the premium was due. Such notice must be mailed to the subscriber’s last address as shown by the records of the organization and may provide for a retroactive date of cancellation no earlier than midnight of the date that the premium was due.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a health maintenance contract issued to an employer or person holding the contract on behalf of the subscriber group, the health maintenance organization may make the notification through the employer or group contract holder, and, if the health maintenance organization elects to take this action through the employer or group contract holder, the organization shall be deemed to have complied with the provisions of this section upon notifying the employer or group contract holder of the requirements of this section and requesting the employer or group contract holder to forward to all subscribers the notice required herein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 30, 47, ch. 85-177; ss. 122, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 14, ch. 99-204; s. 8, ch. 99-275; s. 13, ch. 99-393.</History></Section>