<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Declaration of legislative intent, findings, and purposes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Faced with the continuation of mounting costs of health care, coupled with the state’s interest in high-quality care, the Legislature has determined that there is a need to explore alternative methods for the delivery of health care services, with a view toward achieving greater efficiency and economy in providing these services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health maintenance organizations, consisting of prepaid health care plans, hereinafter referred to as “plans,” are developing rapidly in many communities. Through these organizations, structured in various forms, health care services are provided directly to a group of people who make regular premium payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">These plans, when properly operated, emphasize effective cost and quality controls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the policy of this state to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate legal barriers to the organization, promotion, and expansion of comprehensive prepaid health care plans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that prepaid comprehensive health care plans shall be exempt from operation of the insurance laws of this state except in the manner and to the extent set forth in this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that comprehensive prepaid health care plans deliver high-quality health care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Although it is the intent of this act to provide an opportunity for the development of health maintenance organizations, there is no intent to impair the present system for the delivery of health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature has determined that the operation of a health maintenance organization without a subsisting certificate of authority or the renewal, issuance, or delivery of a health maintenance contract without a subsisting certificate of authority constitutes a danger to the citizens of this state and exposes any subscriber to immediate and irreparable injury, loss, or damage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 72-264; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 779, 804, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 5, ch. 85-177; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>