<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.3111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Extension of benefits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every group health maintenance contract shall provide that termination of the contract shall be without prejudice to any continuous loss which commenced while the contract was in force, but any extension of benefits beyond the period the contract was in force may be predicated upon the continuous total disability of the subscriber and may be limited to payment for the treatment of a specific accident or illness incurred while the subscriber was a member. Such extension of benefits may be limited to the occurrence of the earliest of the following events:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expiration of 12 months.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such time as the member is no longer totally disabled.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A succeeding carrier elects to provide replacement coverage without limitation as to the disability condition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum benefits payable under the contract have been paid.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, an individual is totally disabled if the individual has a condition resulting from an illness or injury which prevents an individual from engaging in any employment or occupation for which the individual is or may become qualified by reason of education, training, or experience, and the individual is under the regular care of a physician.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of maternity coverage, when not covered by the succeeding carrier, a reasonable extension of benefits or accrued liability provision is required, which provision provides for continuation of the contract benefits in connection with maternity expenses for a pregnancy that commenced while the policy was in effect. The extension shall be for the period of that pregnancy and shall not be based upon total disability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (1), no subscriber is entitled to an extension of benefits if the termination of the contract by the health maintenance organization is based upon any event referred to in s. 641.3922(7)(a), (b), or (e).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 16, 24, ch. 88-388; ss. 124, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 25, ch. 98-159.</History></Section>