<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0641.31098" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for individuals with developmental disabilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section and s. 627.6686 may be cited as the “Steven A. Geller Autism Coverage Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applied behavior analysis” means the design, implementation, and evaluation of environmental modifications, using behavioral stimuli and consequences, to produce socially significant improvement in human behavior, including, but not limited to, the use of direct observation, measurement, and functional analysis of the relations between environment and behavior.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Autism spectrum disorder” means any of the following disorders as defined in the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders of the American Psychiatric Association:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Autistic disorder.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Asperger’s syndrome.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible individual” means an individual under 18 years of age or an individual 18 years of age or older who is in high school who has been diagnosed as having a developmental disability at 8 years of age or younger.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health maintenance contract” means a group health maintenance contract offered by a health maintenance organization. This term does not include a health maintenance contract offered in the individual market, a health maintenance contract that is individually underwritten, or a health maintenance contract provided to a small employer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance contract issued or renewed on or after April 1, 2009, shall provide coverage to an eligible individual for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Well-baby and well-child screening for diagnosing the presence of autism spectrum disorder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Treatment of autism spectrum disorder through speech therapy, occupational therapy, physical therapy, and applied behavior analysis services. Applied behavior analysis services shall be provided by an individual certified pursuant to s. 393.17 or an individual licensed under chapter 490 or chapter 491.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coverage required pursuant to subsection (3) is subject to the following requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage shall be limited to treatment that is prescribed by the subscriber’s treating physician in accordance with a treatment plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage for the services described in subsection (3) shall be limited to $36,000 annually and may not exceed $200,000 in total benefits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage may not be denied on the basis that provided services are habilitative in nature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage may be subject to general exclusions and limitations of the subscriber’s contract, including, but not limited to, coordination of benefits, participating provider requirements, and utilization review of health care services, including the review of medical necessity, case management, and other managed care provisions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coverage required pursuant to subsection (3) may not be subject to dollar limits, deductibles, or coinsurance provisions that are less favorable to a subscriber than the dollar limits, deductibles, or coinsurance provisions that apply to physical illnesses that are generally covered under the subscriber’s contract, except as otherwise provided in subsection (3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health maintenance organization may not deny or refuse to issue coverage for medically necessary services, refuse to contract with, or refuse to renew or reissue or otherwise terminate or restrict coverage for an individual solely because the individual is diagnosed as having a developmental disability.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment plan required pursuant to subsection (4) shall include, but is not limited to, a diagnosis, the proposed treatment by type, the frequency and duration of treatment, the anticipated outcomes stated as goals, the frequency with which the treatment plan will be updated, and the signature of the treating physician.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 2011, the maximum benefit under paragraph (4)(b) shall be adjusted annually on January 1 of each calendar year to reflect any change from the previous year in the medical component of the then current Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2008-30; s. 14, ch. 2012-27.</History>
</Section>