<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0641.401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Declaration of legislative intent, findings, and purposes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Faced with the continuation of mounting health care costs, coupled with the interest of the state in high-quality care, the Legislature has determined that there is a need to explore intermediate or limited levels of delivery of prepaid health care services, with a view toward achieving greater efficiency and economy in the provision of these services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepaid health clinics, referred to in this part as “clinics,” are developing rapidly in communities in the state. Through these organizations, structured in various forms, basic services are provided directly to groups of people who make regular premium payments as a condition upon their participation. These plans, when properly operated, emphasize effective cost and quality controls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this part to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimize legal barriers to the organization, promotion, and expansion of prepaid health clinics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize an exemption for prepaid health clinics, when operating under a subsisting certificate of authority issued pursuant to this part, from the operation of the Florida Insurance Code, as defined in s. 624.01, except in the manner and to the extent set forth in this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Although it is the intent of this part to provide an opportunity for the development of prepaid health clinics, there is no intent to impair the present system for the delivery of health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature has determined that the operation of a prepaid health clinic, or the issuance, delivery, or renewal of a prepaid health clinic contract, without a subsisting certificate of authority constitutes a danger to the citizens of this state and exposes a subscriber to immediate and irreparable injury, loss, or damage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 11, ch. 84-313; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>