<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0665.0335" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Supervisory case; emergency conversion, reorganization, merger; consolidation; acquisition of assets.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may determine that a state or federal association is a supervisory case if it finds that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association is in an impaired condition; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association is in imminent danger of being in an impaired condition.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any such finding by the office shall be based upon reports furnished to it by a state or federal savings and loan association examiner or upon other evidence from which it is reasonable to conclude that the association is a supervisory case.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or chapter 120, if the office finds that immediate action is necessary to protect the interests of depositors and reduce the potential for claims against the insurance fund, or in order to prevent the probable failure of a state or federal association which is a supervisory case, the office may, with the concurrence of the appropriate federal regulatory agency in the case of any association the deposits of which are federally insured, issue an emergency order authorizing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conversion of such association from a state to a federal charter, or vice versa, without change of business form;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reorganization, merger, or consolidation of such state or federal association with another state or federal association;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conversion of such state or federal association into a state or federal capital stock association; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any state or federal association to acquire the assets of, and assume the liabilities of, such failing association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 36, 46, ch. 82-214; s. 2, ch. 86-278; s. 25, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 180, ch. 92-303; s. 1860, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>