<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0665.074" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Loan expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every association may require borrowers to pay all reasonable expenses incurred in connection with the making, closing, disbursing, extending, readjusting, or renewing of real estate loans. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, such expenses may include appraisal, attorney, abstract, recording, and registration fees; title examination; title insurance; mortgage loan insurance; credit report; survey; drawing of papers; escrow services; loan closing costs; and taxes or charges imposed upon or in connection with the making and recording of any loan. Every association also may require borrowers to pay the cost of all other necessary and incidental services rendered by the association or by others in connection with real estate and other loans in such reasonable amounts as may be fixed by the board of directors. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, such costs may include the costs of services of inspectors, engineers, and architects. Such initial charges may be collected by the association from the borrower and paid to any person, including any director, officer, or employee of the association rendering such services, or paid directly by the borrower. In lieu of such initial charges to cover such expenses and costs, an association may make a reasonable charge, part or all of which may be retained by the association which renders such service or part or all of which may be paid to others who render such services. The fees and charges authorized by this chapter shall be in addition to interest authorized by law and shall not be deemed to be a part of the interest collected or agreed to be paid on such loans within the meaning of any law of this state which limits the rate of interest which may be exacted in any transaction. No director, officer, or employee of an association shall receive any fee or other compensation of any kind in connection with procuring any loan for an association, except for services actually rendered as above provided.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 69-39; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 40, 57, 58, ch. 80-257; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 184, ch. 92-303.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 665.401.</Text></Note></Section>