<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0665.0315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reorganization, merger, or consolidation with a foreign association.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An association shall have power to reorganize or merge or consolidate with a foreign association, as defined in s. 665.1001, subject to the approval of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resulting or surviving association is to be a foreign association, the office shall not approve the proposed transaction unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The laws of the state in which the foreign association has its principal place of business permit associations in that state to reorganize, merge, or consolidate with Florida associations in transactions in which the resulting or surviving association is a Florida association; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The constituent Florida association has been in existence and continuously operating for more than 2 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposed transaction in which the resulting or surviving association is to be a foreign association shall be subject to any conditions, restrictions, and requirements that would apply in the state where the foreign association has its principal place of business if the resulting or surviving association were to be a Florida association, which conditions, restrictions, and requirements would not apply to a reorganization, merger, or consolidation of associations all of which are located in that state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign association which is the resulting or surviving association in a reorganization, merger, or consolidation with a Florida association shall not be considered a Florida association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for reorganization, merger, or consolidation with a foreign association shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable filing fee as provided in s. 658.73(2)(g).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 7, ch. 86-58; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 178, ch. 92-303; s. 1858, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>