<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0589.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of Florida Forest Service.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service shall cooperate with federal, state, and local governmental agencies, nonprofit organizations, and other persons to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and encourage forest fire protection, forest environmental education, forest land stewardship, good forest management, tree planting and care, forest recreation, and the proper management of public lands.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply for, solicit, and receive grants, funds, services, equipment, and supplies from those agencies, organizations, firms, and individuals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All grant proceeds and funds received for these purposes shall be deposited in the Incidental Trust Fund. Expenditures of these funds shall be for the purposes established in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service shall provide direction for the multiple-use management of forest lands owned by the state; serve as the lead management agency for state-owned land primarily suited for forest resource management; and provide to other state agencies having land management responsibilities technical guidance and management plan development for managing the forest resources on state-owned lands managed for other objectives. Multiple-purpose use shall include, but is not limited to, water-resource protection, forest-ecosystems protection, natural-resource-based low-impact recreation, and sustainable timber management for forest products.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service shall begin immediately an aggressive program to reforest and afforest, with appropriate tree species, lands over which the Florida Forest Service has forest resource management responsibility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 12283, 1927; CGL 4151(4); ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 80, ch. 93-169; s. 9, ch. 95-372; s. 21, ch. 96-231; s. 4, ch. 98-332; s. 26, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>