<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1005.35" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commission for Independent Education shall annually establish a fee schedule to generate, from fees, the amount of revenue appropriated for its operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall include, as a part of its legislative budget request, a proposed fee schedule to generate the appropriated fee revenue required in the General Appropriations Act. The commission may adjust the fee amounts to generate the fee revenue required in the General Appropriations Act but may not add fee categories without the Legislature’s approval. The fee schedule proposed in the legislative budget request takes effect unless the Legislature requires changes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall charge each licensed institution a base fee to cover the cost of routine services, such as data collection and dissemination. The base fee may be higher for institutions with a large enrollment but may not exceed one-half of 1 percent of the amount appropriated for the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall assess workload fees to institutions for specific services that relate to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual reviews.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special reviews.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Site visits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resolution of complaints.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approval to use the term “college” or “university.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the Student Protection Fund established pursuant to s. 1005.37.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other workload activities as allowed by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may assess late fees for an institution’s failure to timely submit required materials.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees shall be submitted through the Department of Education to the Chief Financial Officer, to be deposited in the Institutional Assessment Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees authorized in this section are administrative fees and are not refundable unless paid in error. The commission may deduct from an institution’s future fee collection any unintentional overpayment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 258, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>