<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1005.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold meetings as necessary to administer its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually select a chairperson and a vice chairperson, appoint and review an executive director, and authorize the executive director to appoint employees of the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and use an official seal in the authentication of its acts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make rules for its own governance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the provisions of this chapter. To this end, the commission has the following administrative powers and responsibilities:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 for the operation and establishment of independent postsecondary educational institutions. The commission shall submit the rules to the State Board of Education for approval or disapproval. If the state board does not act on a rule within 60 days after receiving it, the rule shall be filed immediately with the Department of State.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall submit an annual budget to the State Board of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall transmit all fees, donations, and other receipts of money to the Institutional Assessment Trust Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall expend funds as necessary to assist in the application and enforcement of its powers and duties. The Chief Financial Officer shall pay out all moneys and funds as directed under this chapter upon vouchers approved by the Department of Education for all lawful purposes necessary to administering this chapter. The commission shall make annual reports to the State Board of Education showing in detail amounts received and all expenditures. The commission shall include in its annual report to the State Board of Education a statement of its major activities during the period covered by the report.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a record of its proceedings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with other state and federal agencies and other nongovernmental agencies in administering its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause to be investigated criminal justice information, as defined in s. 943.045, for each owner, administrator, and agent employed by an institution applying for licensure from the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a central agency for collecting and distributing current information regarding institutions licensed by the commission. The commission shall collect, and all institutions licensed by the commission shall report, student-level data for each student who receives state funds. At a minimum, data shall be reported annually and include retention rates, transfer rates, completion rates, graduation rates, employment and placement rates, and earnings of graduates.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform independent postsecondary educational institutions of laws adopted by the Legislature and rules adopted by the State Board of Education and the commission and of their responsibility to follow those laws and rules.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and publicize the procedures for receiving and responding to complaints from students, faculty, and others concerning institutions or programs under the purview of the commission, and keep records of such complaints in order to determine the frequency and nature of complaints with respect to specific institutions of higher education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide annually to the Office of Student Financial Assistance of the Department of Education information and documentation that can be used to determine an institution’s eligibility to participate in state student financial assistance programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate and convey annual reports to the Commissioner of Education relating to campus crime statistics, the assessment of physical plant safety, and the antihazing policies of nonpublic postsecondary educational institutions eligible to receive state-funded student assistance, as required by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and report to the Office of Student Financial Assistance the accrediting associations recognized by the United States Department of Education which have standards that are comparable to the minimum standards required to operate an institution at that level in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assure that an institution is not required to operate without a current license because of the schedule of commission meetings or application procedures, if the institution has met the commission’s requirements for licensure or license renewal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue or be sued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts with the Federal Government, with other departments of the state, or with individuals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive bequests and gifts, subject to any restrictions upon which the commission and the donor agree.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint standing or special committees to assist it in carrying out its responsibilities. Committees may include members who are not commission members or representatives of licensed postsecondary institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the Governor, the Legislature, the State Board of Education, and the Commissioner of Education on issues relating to private postsecondary education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegate to the chairperson of the commission the responsibility for signing final orders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist independent postsecondary educational institutions in formulating articulation agreements with public and other independent institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and operate additional offices in the central and southern part of the state if the concentration of licensed institutions renders such an office economically feasible.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and administer the Student Protection Fund pursuant to s. 1005.37.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 252, ch. 2002-387; s. 104, ch. 2007-217; s. 8, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>