<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1005.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designation “college” or “university”.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of the designation “college” or “university” in combination with any series of letters, numbers, or words is restricted in this state to colleges or universities as defined in s. 1005.02 that offer degrees as defined in s. 1005.02 and fall into at least one of the following categories:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida public college.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida or out-of-state college that has been in active operation and using the designation “college” or “university” since April 1, 1970.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A college for which the commission has issued a license pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A college that is under the jurisdiction of the Department of Education, eligible to participate in the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program and that is a nonprofit independent college or university located and chartered in this state and accredited by the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools to grant baccalaureate degrees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A college that meets the description of either s. 1005.06(1)(e) or (f).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a college is approved under subsection (1) to use the designation “college” or “university,” a branch or extension of that college may use the name of the parent college, but shall include an indication of the location of the branch or extension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity offering postsecondary educational courses or programs of study in Florida, whether or not college credit is awarded, shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entity shall not use the designation “college” or “university” in its name in Florida without approval by the commission, unless the commission determines that its name is clearly and accurately descriptive of the services provided by the entity and is not one that may mislead the public.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 246, ch. 2002-387; s. 102, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>