<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1005.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fair consumer practices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every institution that is under the jurisdiction of the commission or is exempt from the jurisdiction or purview of the commission pursuant to s. 1005.06(1)(c) or (f) and that either directly or indirectly solicits for enrollment any student shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose to each prospective student a statement of the purpose of such institution, its educational programs and curricula, a description of its physical facilities, its status regarding licensure, its fee schedule and policies regarding retaining student fees if a student withdraws, and a statement regarding the transferability of credits to and from other institutions. The institution shall make the required disclosures in writing at least 1 week prior to enrollment or collection of any tuition from the prospective student. The required disclosures may be made in the institution’s current catalog;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use a reliable method to assess, before accepting a student into a program, the student’s ability to complete successfully the course of study for which he or she has applied;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform each student accurately about financial assistance and obligations for repayment of loans; describe any employment placement services provided and the limitations thereof; and refrain from promising or implying guaranteed placement, market availability, or salary amounts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to prospective and enrolled students accurate information regarding the relationship of its programs to state licensure requirements for practicing related occupations and professions in Florida;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that all advertisements are accurate and not misleading;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publish and follow an equitable prorated refund policy for all students, and follow both the federal refund guidelines for students receiving federal financial assistance and the minimum refund guidelines set by commission rule;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Follow the requirements of state and federal laws that require annual reporting with respect to crime statistics and physical plant safety and make those reports available to the public; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publish and follow procedures for handling student complaints, disciplinary actions, and appeals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, institutions that are required to be licensed by the commission shall disclose to prospective students that additional information regarding the institution may be obtained by contacting the Commission for Independent Education, Department of Education, Tallahassee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 247, ch. 2002-387; s. 45, ch. 2004-41.</History></Section>