<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1005.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purpose.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature encourages privately supported higher education and intends to aid in protecting the health, education, and welfare of persons who receive educational services from independent postsecondary educational institutions in this state; to aid in protecting employers and others who depend upon people whose educational credentials are from independent postsecondary educational institutions in this state; and to aid in protecting independent postsecondary educational institutions that currently operate or intend to begin operating in this state. The Legislature finds that both individuals and independent postsecondary educational institutions benefit from a state system that assures that all institutions satisfactorily meet minimum educational standards. The Legislature further recognizes the role of federally recognized accrediting associations in setting standards for independent postsecondary educational institutions and encourages the use of recognized accreditation standards as general guidelines for the licensure of independent postsecondary educational institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that a degree, diploma, or other educational credential serves several purposes. Employers rely upon a person’s educational credentials in judging that person’s qualifications for employment. Educators rely upon a person’s educational credentials to assess the adequacy of that person’s preparation for the pursuit of further education. Therefore, the Legislature intends that the provisions of this chapter aid in protecting the integrity of degrees, diplomas, and other educational credentials offered by independent postsecondary educational institutions by providing for the evaluation of minimum educational requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature intends to prohibit the granting of false or misleading educational credentials and to prohibit misleading literature, advertising, solicitation, or representations by independent postsecondary educational institutions or their agents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 244, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>