<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0034.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Method of prosecution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons tried in the county court on any criminal charge shall be tried upon indictment by the grand jury, upon information filed by the prosecuting attorney, or upon affidavit or complaint.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the finding of indictments by the grand jury for crimes cognizable by the county court, the clerk of the court, without any order therefor, shall docket the same on the trial docket of the county court on or before the first day of its next succeeding term.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney is authorized to sign affidavits before the judge of the county court when the state attorney has evidence to support such affidavit for a criminal charge over which such court has jurisdiction. The judge shall issue arrest warrants upon such affidavit as is done in all other cases. This procedure shall be cumulative to all other practice and procedure before such courts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon complaint made on affidavit to any county court that any misdemeanor has been committed, the county court judge may issue a warrant on the usual form, making it returnable before himself or herself or another county court judge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Municipal prosecutors may prosecute violations of municipal ordinances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any circuit court clerk acting as clerk of the county court, or any deputy county court clerk appointed for the sole purpose of issuing arrest warrants, or any county court clerk, may, at municipal expense, administer an oath to and take affidavit of any person charging another person with a violation of a municipal ordinance and may issue a warrant on the usual form, making it returnable to the appropriate county court judge. The authority granted to a clerk or deputy clerk under this section shall be subordinate to that of any state judge.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 3730, 1887; RS 2837; GS 3894; RGS 5989; CGL 8283; s. 13, ch. 72-404; s. 2, ch. 73-297; s. 197, ch. 95-147; s. 53, ch. 2003-402.</History></Section>