<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0034.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power of clerk to appoint deputies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the concurrence of the chief circuit judge of the circuit, the clerk of the circuit court, in his or her capacity as clerk of the county court, may appoint a deputy clerk or clerks of the county court, for whose acts the clerk shall be liable, and the said deputies shall have and exercise each and every power of whatsoever nature and kind as the clerk may exercise as clerk of the county court, except the power to appoint a deputy or deputies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any deputy county court clerk appointed for the sole purpose of issuing arrest warrants for violation of chapter 316 or county or municipal ordinances triable in the county courts shall have and exercise only those powers of the clerk which are required to achieve such limited purpose, and those arrest warrants issued for violation of county or municipal ordinances shall be funded by the county or municipality which approved the ordinance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipal clerk or deputy municipal clerk appointed as a deputy clerk of the county court shall receive no additional compensation from the state or from any county but may be compensated for such warrant-issuing duties by his or her employing municipality. The limited appointment of any municipal clerk or deputy municipal clerk as a deputy clerk of the county court under this section shall not constitute any appointment to a new office, but rather shall be the conferring of additional powers and duties upon a municipal officer in order to implement revised Art. V of the State Constitution wherein the jurisdiction of municipal courts is transferred to the county courts. It is the expressed intent of the Legislature that the designation of any deputy clerk of the county court herein shall not create any new office but rather shall enlarge the duties and powers of municipal clerks and deputy municipal clerks as provided herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall limit the power to appoint under s. 28.06.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-297; s. 195, ch. 95-147; s. 51, ch. 2003-402.</History></Section>