<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0951.231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">County residential probation program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any prisoner who has been sentenced under s. 921.18 to serve a sentence in a county residential probation center as described in s. 951.23 shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reside at the center at all times other than during employment hours and reasonable travel time to and from his or her place of employment, except that supervisory personnel at a county residential probation center may extend the limits of confinement to include, but not be limited to, probation, community control, or other appropriate supervisory techniques.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek and obtain employment on an 8-hours-a-day basis and retain employment throughout the period of time he or she is housed at the center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in and complete the program required by s. 958.045, if required by the supervisor of the center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in the education program provided at the center, if required by the supervisor of the center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in the drug treatment program provided at the center, if required by the supervisor of the center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center participating in the county residential probation program must provide or contract to provide for the programs established under subsection (1) as well as provide or contract to provide for necessary health care for the period of time the prisoner is housed at the center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government having an existing Department of Corrections probation and restitution center within its boundaries with current available capacity may contract with the Department of Corrections to house prisoners sentenced in accordance with s. 921.18.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government having an existing Department of Corrections probation and restitution center within its boundaries without current available capacity, or a local government not having an existing Department of Corrections probation and restitution center within its boundaries, may provide facilities either through construction, purchase, or lease of new facilities or purchase, renovation, or lease of existing facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments participating in this program may apply to the Department of Corrections for funding. The department shall allocate the funding for this program to the extent authorized in the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 79, ch. 88-122; s. 1701, ch. 97-102; s. 48, ch. 2010-117.</History>
</Section>