<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0951.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public safety coordinating councils.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of county commissioners shall establish a county public safety coordinating council for the county or shall join with a consortium of one or more other counties to establish a public safety coordinating council for the geographic area represented by the member counties.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public safety coordinating council for a county shall consist of:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney, or an assistant state attorney designated by the state attorney.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public defender, or an assistant public defender designated by the public defender.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief circuit judge, or another circuit judge designated by the chief circuit judge.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief county judge, or another county judge designated by the chief county judge.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief correctional officer.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff, or a member designated by the sheriff, if the sheriff is not the chief correctional officer.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state probation circuit administrator, or a member designated by the state probation circuit administrator, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chairperson of the board of county commissioners, or another county commissioner as designee.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the county has such program available, the director of any county probation or pretrial intervention program, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of a local substance abuse treatment program, or a member designated by the director, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives from county and state jobs programs and other community groups who work with offenders and victims, appointed by the chairperson of the board of county commissioners to 4-year terms.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chairperson of the board of county commissioners, or another county commissioner as designee, shall serve as the chairperson of the council until the council elects a chairperson from the membership of the council.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public safety coordinating council for a consortium of two or more counties shall consist of the following members, appointed with the approval of each board of county commissioners within the consortium:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chief circuit judge, or a circuit judge designated by a chief circuit judge.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chief county judge, or a county judge designated by a chief county judge.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state attorney, or an assistant state attorney designated by a state attorney.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public defender, or an assistant public defender designated by a public defender.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state probation circuit administrator, or a member designated by a state probation circuit administrator, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician who practices in the area of alcohol and substance abuse, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mental health professional who practices in the area of alcohol and substance abuse, to be appointed to a 4-year term.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sheriff or a jail administrator for a county within the consortium.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chief of police for a municipality within the geographic area of the consortium.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county commissioner from each member county of the consortium.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An elected member of the governing body of the most populous municipality within the geographic area of the consortium.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="l">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An elected member of a school board within the geographic area of the consortium.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the public safety coordinating council shall elect a chairperson from among its members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet at the call of the chairperson for the purpose of assessing the population status of all detention or correctional facilities owned or contracted by the county, or the county consortium, and formulating recommendations to ensure that the capacities of such facilities are not exceeded. Such recommendations shall include an assessment of the availability of pretrial intervention or probation programs, work-release programs, substance abuse programs, gain-time schedules, applicable bail bond schedules, and the confinement status of the inmates housed within each facility owned or contracted by the county, or the county consortium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council may also develop a local public safety plan for future construction needs. The plan must cover at least a 5-year period. The plan may be submitted for consideration to the local planning agency for the county, or the planning agency for each county within the consortium, at least 120 days before the adoption of or amendment to the comprehensive plan for the county by the local planning agency pursuant to part II of chapter 163.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county, or county consortium, that contracts to receive community corrections funds for its community corrections programs under s. 948.51 shall require the public safety coordinating council to develop a comprehensive public safety plan as described therein which includes the future public safety construction needs as described in paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council may also develop a comprehensive local reentry plan that is designed to assist offenders released from incarceration to successfully reenter the community. The plan should cover at least a 5-year period. In developing the plan, the council shall coordinate with public safety officials and local community organizations who can provide offenders with reentry services, such as assistance with housing, health care, education, substance abuse treatment, and employment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All meetings of a public safety coordinating council, as well as its records, books, documents, and papers, are open and available to the public in accordance with ss. 119.07 and 286.011.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 87-340; s. 90, ch. 88-122; s. 16, ch. 91-225; s. 35, ch. 92-310; s. 7, ch. 93-204; s. 44, ch. 95-283; s. 32, ch. 96-312; s. 1881, ch. 97-102; s. 22, ch. 2010-64.</History>
</Section>