<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0951.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment of correctional officers; duties; salary.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county commissioners shall designate a chief correctional officer and such correctional officers as they deem necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All chief correctional officers of prisoners shall see that all rules and regulations prescribed by law or the department are fully observed and complied with; enforce discipline among the prisoners in and about the camps; and administer punishment to prisoners, when in their judgment the same is necessary in order to enforce proper discipline, conforming always to the law and rules and regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All boards of county commissioners shall immediately discharge any correctional officer who shall be guilty of gross negligence or cruel and inhuman treatment of prisoners under their control and their action shall be final.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The salaries of correctional officers provided for in this chapter shall be fixed by the board of county commissioners, and the chief correctional officer shall be furnished means of transportation over the roads of the county when necessary, the upkeep and operation of which shall be furnished by the county; however, the county shall not in any case be required to furnish a driver of such conveyance where such services are required to be paid for.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All salaries contemplated by this chapter shall be paid from the general revenue fund of the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 6537, 1913; RGS 6218; s. 2, ch. 9203, 1923; CGL 8550; s. 44, ch. 57-121; ss. 1, 2, ch. 61-198; s. 18, ch. 61-530; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-441; s. 94, ch. 77-120; s. 113, ch. 79-3; s. 2, ch. 86-183; s. 29, ch. 96-312.</History></Section>