<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0951.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contractual arrangements for operation and maintenance of county detention facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After consultation with the sheriff and upon adoption of an ordinance by vote of a majority plus one, the governing body of the county may enter into a contract with a private entity for the provision of the operation and maintenance of a county detention facility as defined in s. 951.23(1)(a) and the supervision of county prisoners. The contract may designate a representative from a private entity as the chief correctional officer pursuant to s. 951.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract term shall be determined by the negotiating parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any private entity entering into a contract with the board of county commissioners pursuant to the provisions of s. 951.061 shall be liable in tort with respect to the care and custody of county prisoners under its supervision and for any breach of contract with the board of county commissioners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any private entity entering into a contract with the board of county commissioners pursuant to the provisions of s. 951.061 shall allow law enforcement officers access to persons detained within the county detention facility for the purpose of conducting criminal investigations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a county prisoner’s willful failure to remain within the supervisory control of the private entity, such action shall constitute an escape, punishable as provided in s. 944.40.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private correctional officers responsible for supervising inmates within the facility shall meet the requirements necessary for certification by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission pursuant to s. 943.1395. However, expenses for such training shall be the responsibility of the private entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After consultation with the sheriff, the county shall appoint a contract monitor who shall be responsible for documenting adherence to the contract and compliance with rules, policies, procedures, and performance standards established by the local governing body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall require an annual audit of the private entity’s operation of the county detention facility or facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a county enters into a contract for the operation and maintenance of county detention facilities, the sheriff of such county shall cease to be liable for actions arising out of the operation and maintenance of the facilities under contract, except as to any acts he or she commits personally.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 86-183; s. 6, ch. 91-225; s. 2, ch. 94-168; s. 1696, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>