<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0951.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial responsibility for medical expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county detention facility or municipal detention facility incurring expenses for providing medical care, treatment, hospitalization, or transportation may seek reimbursement for the expenses incurred in the following order:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From the prisoner or person receiving medical care, treatment, hospitalization, or transportation by deducting the cost from the prisoner’s cash account on deposit with the detention facility. If the prisoner’s cash account does not contain sufficient funds to cover medical care, treatment, hospitalization, or transportation, then the detention facility may place a lien against the prisoner’s cash account or other personal property, to provide payment in the event sufficient funds become available at a later time. Any existing lien may be carried over to future incarceration of the same prisoner as long as the future incarceration takes place within the county originating the lien and the future incarceration takes place within 3 years of the date the lien was placed against the prisoner’s account or other personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From an insurance company, health care corporation, or other source if the prisoner or person is covered by an insurance policy or subscribes to a health care corporation or other source for those expenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prisoner who receives medical care, treatment, hospitalization, or transportation shall cooperate with the county detention facility or municipal detention facility in seeking reimbursement under paragraphs(1)(a) and (b) for expenses incurred by the facility for the prisoner. A prisoner who willfully refuses to cooperate with the reimbursement efforts of the detention facility may have a lien placed against the prisoner’s cash account or other personal property and may not receive gain-time as provided by s. 951.21.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-189; s. 45, ch. 95-283.</History></Section>