<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0344.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Depositories and investments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received by the Chief Financial Officer as treasurer of the State Board of Administration, a body corporate under s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution, shall be deposited by the treasurer in a solvent bank or banks, to be approved and accepted for such purposes by the board. In making such deposits, he or she shall follow the method for the deposit of state funds. Each bank receiving any portion of such funds shall be required to deposit with such treasurer satisfactory bonds or treasury certificates of the United States; bonds of the several states; special tax school district bonds; bonds of any municipality eligible to secure state deposits as provided by law; bonds of any county or special road and bridge district of this state entitled to participate under the provisions of s. 16, Art. IX of the State Constitution of 1885, as adopted by the 1968 revised constitution, and of s. 9, Art. XII of that revision; bonds issued under the provisions of s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885, as adopted by s. 9, Art. XII of the 1968 revised constitution; or bonds, notes, or certificates issued by the Florida State Improvement Commission or its successors, the Florida Development Commission and the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration, which contain a pledge of the 80-percent surplus 2-cent constitutional gasoline tax accruing under s. 16, Art. IX of the State Constitution of 1885, as adopted by the 1968 revised constitution, and under s. 9, Art. XII of that revision, which shall be equal to the amount deposited with such bank. Such security shall be in the possession of such treasurer; or the treasurer is authorized to accept, in lieu of the actual depositing with him or her of such security, trust or safekeeping receipts issued by any Federal Reserve Bank, or member bank thereof, or by any bank incorporated under the laws of the United States; provided the member bank or bank incorporated under the laws of the United States has been previously approved and accepted for such purposes by the State Board of Administration and the trust or safekeeping receipts are in substantially the same form as that which the Chief Financial Officer is authorized to accept in lieu of securities given to cover deposits of state funds.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 14486, 1929; CGL 1936 Supp. 2470(17); s. 1, ch. 17889, 1937; s. 2, ch. 20302, 1941; s. 1, ch. 20946, 1941; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 2, ch. 57-749; ss. 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 18, ch. 69-216; s. 44, ch. 83-3; s. 286, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 510, ch. 95-148; s. 376, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>