<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0344.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition of excess funds in county accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in any case in which a levy of ad valorem taxes has been or may hereafter be laid and collected by or for any county or special road and bridge district, or other taxing district in this state, for the servicing of road and bridge bonded indebtedness being administered by the State Board of Administration, and the proceeds of which have been remitted to the State Board of Administration, or if on account of profits realized from investments by the State Board of Administration or its predecessor, the statutory Board of Administration, or if on account of tax redemption funds collected and remitted to the State Board of Administration or its predecessor, the statutory Board of Administration, there has been or shall hereafter be created an amount of funds in excess of the requirements for which such tax levies were or may be laid and upon which such tax redemptions may be based, or of the account for which such profits upon investments have been or may be realized, all such excess funds shall be transferred and applied as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If created for countywide bonds or obligations, to the credit of the county, and applied by the State Board of Administration as gasoline and other fuel tax funds are applied, as required by s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If created for special road and bridge district or other special taxing district bonds or obligations, to the credit of the interest and sinking funds of the respective districts, and applied to other district bonds or obligations being administered by the State Board of Administration; provided, that if there are no such other bonds or obligations of districts, then and in that event, such excess funds shall be transferred to the credit of the county in which such district is located, and applied as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds transferred under the provisions of this section shall be under the control and supervision of the State Board of Administration, as are all other funds made available to and administered by it under s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 21640, 1943; s. 18, ch. 69-216.</History></Section>