<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0532.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment by direct deposit of funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">None of the provisions of this chapter shall be deemed or construed to prohibit the payor of wages or salary from causing the amount of such wages or salary to be deposited directly to the account of the payee in a financial institution by electronic or other medium if such direct deposit has been authorized in writing by the payee and if the payee has designated in writing the financial institution of her or his choice in which such deposit is to be made. However, at the time the order for payment of such direct deposit is received by the drawee, the payor of such wages or salary must have sufficient funds or credit or an arrangement or understanding with the drawee for payment thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No employer or payor of wages or salary shall terminate the employment of any employee or payee solely for refusing to authorize such direct deposit of wages or salary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee or payee of wages or salary may bring a civil action against any person violating subsection (2). Upon rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against the person violating subsection (2) and in favor of the employee or payee of wages or salary, the trial court, or, in event of an appeal in which the employee or payee prevails, the appellate court, shall adjudge or decree against the person violating subsection (2) and in favor of the employee or payee a reasonable sum as fees for the employee’s or payee’s attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. The court may, in its discretion, provide such equitable relief as it deems necessary or proper, including enjoining the defendant from further violation of subsection (2). If it appears to the court that the suit brought by the plaintiff was ill-founded or brought for purposes of harassment, the plaintiff shall be liable for reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the defendant. When so awarded, attorney’s fees shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-296; s. 733, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>