<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.913" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is obligated to the extent of the full amount of the covered claims:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing before the adjudication of insolvency and arising within 30 days after the determination of insolvency;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing before the policy expiration date if less than 30 days after the determination of insolvency; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing before the insured replaces the policy or causes its cancellation, if the insured does so within 30 days after the determination of insolvency.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding such criteria, the corporation’s obligation for a covered claim for the return of unearned premium shall not exceed $50,000 per policy. In addition, the corporation is not obligated to a policyholder or claimant in an amount in excess of the obligation of the insolvent insurer under the policy from which the claim arises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is considered to be the insurer to the extent of its obligation on the covered claims, and, to such extent, has all rights, duties, and obligations of the insolvent insurer as if the insurer had not become insolvent. The corporation is not liable for any penalties or interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ or retain such persons as are necessary to handle claims and perform other duties of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow funds necessary to effect the purposes of this part in accordance with the plan of operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue or be sued. Service of process in such legal actions must be made upon the person registered with the department as agent for the receipt of service of process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into such contracts as are necessary to carry out the purpose of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may assist and advise the department, when appropriate, concerning rehabilitation, payment of claims, continuance of coverage, or the performance of other contractual obligations of any impaired or insolvent insurer. The corporation may also assist and advise departments of insurance of other states; other guaranty associations; and conservators, rehabilitators, and receivers appointed or acting in regard to any member insured wherever located, for the purpose of developing plans to coordinate protection of policyholders. Costs of such activities may be charged against the Florida Workers’ Compensation Insurance Guaranty Association Account at the discretion of the board of directors, notwithstanding any other provision of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall have standing to appear before any court in this state which has jurisdiction over an impaired or insolvent insurer to which the corporation is or may become obligated under this act. Such standing shall extend to all matters germane to the powers and duties of the corporation, including but not limited to, proposals for reinsuring or guaranteeing the covered policies of the impaired or insolvent insurer and the determination of the covered policies and contractual obligations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State funds may not be allocated or paid to the corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 97-262; s. 5, ch. 2003-267.</History></Section>