<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.399" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Receiver’s right to recover distributions made to affiliate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an order for liquidation or rehabilitation of an insurer domiciled in this state has been entered, the receiver appointed under such order has a right to recover on behalf of the insurer, from any affiliate, the amount or value of distributions, other than stock dividends paid by the insurer on its capital stock, made at any time during the 5 years preceding the petition for liquidation or rehabilitation, subject to the limitations of subsections (2), (3), and (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The distributions shall be recoverable unless the affiliate shows that the distributions were lawful and reasonable and that the insurer did not know and could not reasonably have known that the distributions might adversely affect the ability of the insurer to fulfill its contractual obligations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any affiliate at the time the distributions were made is liable up to the amount or value of distributions it received.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum amount recoverable under this section is the amount needed in excess of all other available assets of the insolvent insurer to pay the contractual obligations of the insolvent insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any affiliate liable under subsection (3) is insolvent, all of its affiliates are jointly and severally liable for any resulting deficiency in the amount recovered from the insolvent affiliate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 79-189; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 29, ch. 83-38; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 631.732.</Text></Note></Section>