<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.62" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prevention of insolvencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To aid in the detection and prevention of insurer insolvencies:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the board of directors, upon majority vote, to notify the office of any information indicating any member insurer may be insolvent or in a financial condition hazardous to the policyholders or the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may, upon majority vote, request that the office order an examination of any member insurer which the board in good faith believes may be in a financial condition hazardous to the policyholders or the public. Within 30 days of the receipt of such request, the office shall begin such examination. The examination may be conducted as a National Association of Insurance Commissioners examination or may be conducted by such persons as the office designates. The cost of such examination shall be paid by the association and the examination report shall be treated as are other examination reports pursuant to s. 624.319. In no event shall such examination report be released to the board of directors prior to its release to the public. The office shall notify the board of directors when the examination is completed. The request for an examination shall be kept on file by the office; such request is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until the examination report is released to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may, upon majority vote, make reports and recommendations to the department or office upon any matter germane to the solvency, liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation of any member insurer. Such reports and recommendations are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until the termination of a delinquency proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may, upon majority vote, make recommendations to the office for the detection and prevention of insurer insolvencies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 70-20; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 32, ch. 83-38; s. 38, ch. 87-226; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-118; s. 386, ch. 96-406; s. 1357, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>