<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.156" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigation by the department; scope of authority; sharing of materials.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, under the direction and supervision of the receivership court, conduct an investigation to determine the causes of the insolvency, including whether false statements filed with the department contributed to the insolvency and if any laws of this state, any other state, or the Federal Government relating to the solvency of the insurer were violated; to discover assets for recovery; and to determine the location of assets and their manner of recovery. The department may take statements under oath and examine and review the books, records, and documents of the insurer or any affiliate, controlling person, officer, director, manager, trustee, agent, adjuster, employee, or independent contractor of any insurer or affiliate and any other person possessing any executive authority over, or exercising or having exercised any control over, any segment of the affairs of the insurer or affiliate. Contracts of reinsurance between an insurer and a reinsurer do not constitute the exercise of control by the reinsurer over the insurer for purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide documents, books, and records; other investigative products, work product, and analysis; and copies of any or all of such materials to the Division of Insurance Fraud or any other appropriate government agency. The sharing of these materials shall not waive any work product or other privilege otherwise applicable under law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The receivership court, upon motion of the department, shall enter an order expediting compliance with the requirements of subsection (1). The court may impose appropriate penalties and sanctions for noncompliance with such order, including penalties and sanctions for the loss, destruction, or spoliation of any evidence that occurs after entry of such order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2002-25.</History></Section>