<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offsets.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all cases of mutual debts or mutual credits between the insurer and another person in connection with any action or proceeding under this chapter, such credits and debts shall be set off and the balance only shall be allowed or paid, except as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No offset shall be allowed in favor of any such person where:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligation of the insurer to such person would not at the date of the entry of any liquidation order or otherwise, as provided in s. 631.251, entitle her or him to share as a claimant in the assets of the insurer. Any such obligation must be fully vested and mature as of the date of the order of liquidation and in no way contingent upon any future event or condition precedent to allow an offset. In the case of a reinsurance agreement, the insurer’s obligation must be incurred as of the date of the order of liquidation to allow an offset.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligation of the insurer to such person was purchased by or transferred to such person with a view of its being used as an offset.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligation of such person is to pay an assessment levied against the members of a mutual insurer, or against the subscribers of a reciprocal insurer, or is to pay a balance upon the subscription to the capital stock of a stock insurer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent who voluntarily pays the unearned portion of a premium to a policyholder shall succeed to the interest of the policyholder as an assignee of the policyholder’s claim against the receiver for the unearned portion of the premium as of the effective date of cancellation of the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No claim of offset shall operate to create a secured claim.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 744, ch. 59-205; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 22, ch. 83-38; s. 41, ch. 88-166; s. 7, ch. 90-248; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 406, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>