<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.715" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a nonprofit legal entity to be known as the Florida Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association. All member insurers shall be and remain members of the association as a condition of their authority to transact insurance in this state, and, further, as a condition of such authority, an insurer shall agree to reimburse the association for all claim payments the association makes on said insurer’s behalf if such insurer is subsequently rehabilitated. The association shall perform its functions under the plan of operation established and approved under the provisions of s. 631.721 and shall exercise its powers through a board of directors established under the provisions of s. 631.716.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of administration and assessment, the association shall maintain three accounts:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health insurance account;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The life insurance account; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annuity account.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrowing between accounts for payment of policyholder and contract holder claims and other obligations of the association is authorized at the discretion of the board of directors, provided that the amounts so borrowed are restored to the appropriate accounts not less than annually.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association shall come under the immediate supervision of the department and shall be subject to the applicable provisions of the insurance laws of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 79-189; s. 433, ch. 81-259; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 15, ch. 89-360; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 92-328.</History></Section>