<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0631.59" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties and powers of department and office.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall notify the association of the existence of an insolvent insurer not later than 3 days after it receives notice of the determination of the insolvency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require that the association notify the insureds of the insolvent insurer and any other interested parties of the determination of insolvency and of their rights under this part. Such notification shall be by mail at their last known addresses, when available, but if sufficient information for notification by mail is not available, notice by e-mail or telephone shall be sufficient.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall, upon request of the board of directors, provide the association with a statement of the net direct written premiums of each member insurer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspend or revoke the certificate of authority to transact insurance in this state of any member insurer which fails to pay an assessment when due or fails to comply with the plan of operation. As an alternative, the office may levy a fine on any member insurer which fails to pay an assessment when due. Such fine may not exceed 5 percent of the unpaid assessment per month, except that no fine shall be less than $100 per month.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revoke the designation of any servicing facility if it finds claims are being handled unsatisfactorily.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 70-20; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1356, ch. 2003-261; s. 20, ch. 2012-212.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>