<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.911" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of the Florida Workers’ Compensation Insurance Guaranty Association, Incorporated; merger; effect of merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Self-Insurance Fund Guaranty Association established in former part V of chapter 631 and the workers’ compensation insurance account, which includes excess workers’ compensation insurance, established in former s. 631.55(2)(a) shall be merged, in accordance with the plan of operation adopted by the interim board of directors. The successor nonprofit corporation shall be known as the “Florida Workers’ Compensation Insurance Guaranty Association, Incorporated.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the effective date of the merger:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Self-Insurance Fund Guaranty Association and the workers’ compensation insurance account within the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association cease to exist and are succeeded by the Florida Workers’ Compensation Insurance Guaranty Association.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to all assets of any description, all real estate and other property, or any interest therein, owned by each party to the merger is vested in the successor corporation without reversion or impairment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The successor corporation shall be responsible and liable for all the liabilities and obligations of each party to the merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any claim existing or action or proceeding pending by or against any party to the merger may be continued as if the merger did not occur or the successor corporation may be substituted in the proceeding for the corporation or account which ceased existence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the rights of creditors nor any liens upon the property of any party to the merger shall be impaired by such merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Outstanding assessments levied by the Florida Self-Insurance Guaranty Association or the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association on behalf of the workers’ compensation insurance account remain in full force and effect and shall be paid when due.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All insurers must be members of the corporation as a condition of their authority to offer workers’ compensation coverage in this state. An insurer must reimburse the corporation for all funds advanced to the insurer and all claim payments the insurer makes on the insured’s behalf if the insurer, having been placed in rehabilitation receivership, is subsequently rehabilitated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall perform its functions under a plan of operation and shall exercise its powers through a board of directors. Upon adoption of a plan of operation for the corporation, the board shall manage the Florida Workers’ Compensation Insurance Guaranty Association Account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation has all powers granted or allowed to not-for-profit corporations under chapter 617, in addition to other powers granted in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 97-262; s. 84, ch. 2000-154; s. 69, ch. 2001-63; s. 1372, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>