<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plan of operation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association shall submit to the department a proposed plan of operation and any amendments thereto necessary or suitable to assure the fair, reasonable, and equitable administration of the association. The plan of operation and any amendments thereto shall become effective upon approval in writing by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the association fails to submit a suitable proposed plan of operation by December 30, 1970, or if at any time thereafter the association fails to submit suitable amendments to the plan, the department shall adopt and promulgate such reasonable rules as are necessary or advisable to effectuate the provisions of this part. Such rules shall continue in force until modified by the department or superseded by a plan submitted by the association and approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All member insurers shall comply with the plan of operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of operation shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the procedures whereby all the powers and duties of the association under s. 631.57 will be performed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for handling assets of the association;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the amount and method of reimbursing members of the board of directors under s. 631.56;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures by which claims may be filed with the association and acceptable forms of proof of covered claims. Notice of claims to the receiver or liquidator of the insolvent insurer shall be deemed notice to the association or its agent, and a list of such claims shall be periodically submitted to the association or similar organization in another state by the receiver or liquidator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish regular places and times for meetings of the board of directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for records to be kept of all financial transactions of the association, its agents, and the board of directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that any member insurer aggrieved by any final action or decision of the association may appeal to the department within 30 days after the action or decision;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the procedures whereby recommendations for the board of directors will be submitted to the department; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain additional provisions necessary or proper for the execution of the powers and duties of the association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of operation may provide that any or all powers and duties of the association, except those under s. 631.57(2)(b) and (c), are delegated to a corporation, association, or other organization which performs or will perform functions similar to those of this association or its equivalent in two or more states. Such a corporation, association, or organization shall be reimbursed as a servicing facility would be reimbursed and shall be paid for its performance of any other functions of the association. A delegation under this subsection shall take effect only with the approval of both the board of directors and the department, and may be made only to a corporation, association, or organization which extends protection not substantially less favorable and effective than that provided by this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 70-20; s. 163, ch. 71-355; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>