<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.391" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation of officers and employees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer, director, manager, trustee, agent, adjuster, employee, or independent contractor of any insurer or affiliate and any other person who possesses any executive authority over, or who exercises any control over, any segment of the affairs of the insurer or affiliate shall fully cooperate with the department and office in any proceeding under this chapter or any investigation preliminary or incidental to the proceeding. An order of rehabilitation or liquidation which results in the discharge or suspension of any of the persons listed above does not operate to release such person from the duty to cooperate with the department and office as set out herein. To “cooperate” includes, but is not limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reply promptly in writing to any inquiry from the department or office requesting such a reply;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promptly to make available and deliver to the department or office any books, accounts, documents, other records, information, data processing software, or property of or pertaining to the insurer and in her or his possession, custody, or control; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promptly to provide access to all data processing records in hard copy and in electronic form and to data processing facilities and services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall obstruct or interfere with the department or office in the conduct of any delinquency proceeding or any investigation preliminary or incidental thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit any person from seeking legal relief from a court when aggrieved by the petition for liquidation or other delinquency proceeding or by other orders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person referred to in subsection (1) who fails to cooperate with the department or office, or any other person who obstructs or interferes with the department or office, in the conduct of any delinquency proceeding or any investigation preliminary or incidental thereto, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or by fine of not more than $10,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal by any person referred to in subsection (1) to provide records upon the request of the department or office is grounds for revocation of any insurance-related license, including, but not limited to, agent and third-party administrator licenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person referred to in subsection (1) who refuses to cooperate in providing records upon the request of the department or office is liable for any penalties, fines, or other costs assessed against the guaranty association or the receiver that result from the refusal or delay to provide records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 70-27; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 655, ch. 71-136; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 26, ch. 83-38; s. 8, ch. 85-339; ss. 95, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 410, ch. 97-102; s. 14, ch. 97-262; s. 1349, ch. 2003-261; s. 7, ch. 2011-226.</History></Section>