<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of insolvency to policyholders by insurer, general agent, or agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The receiver shall, immediately after appointment in any delinquency proceeding against an insurer in which the policies have been canceled, give written notice of such proceeding to each general agent and licensed agent of the insurer in this state. Each general agent and licensed agent of the insurer in this state shall forthwith give written notice of such proceeding to all subagents, producing agents, brokers, and service representatives writing business through such general agent or licensed agent, whether or not such subagents, producing agents, brokers, and servicing representatives are licensed or permitted by the insurer and whether or not they are operating under a written agency contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless, within 15 days subsequent to the date of such notice, all agents referred to in subsection (1) have either replaced or reinsured in a solvent authorized insurer the insurance coverages placed by or through such agent in the delinquent insurer, such agents shall then, by registered or certified mail, send to the last known address of any policyholder a written notice of the insolvency of the delinquent insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license, permit, or certificate of authority of any person, firm, or corporation which fails to comply with the provisions of this section is subject to revocation as otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such person, firm, or corporation is not licensed or permitted or the holder of a certificate of authority under any section of this code, such person, firm, or corporation, or the officers and directors thereof, are, upon failure to comply with the provisions of this section, guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or by a fine of not more than $5,000.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 750, ch. 59-205; s. 15, ch. 70-27; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 24, ch. 83-38; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 68, ch. 2002-206.</History></Section>