<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.398" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prevention of insolvencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To aid in the detection and prevention of insurer insolvencies or impairments:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member insurer; agent, employee, or member of the board of directors; or representative of any insurance guaranty association may make reports and recommendations to the department or office upon any matter germane to the solvency, liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation of any member insurer or germane to the solvency of any company seeking to do an insurance business in this state. Such reports and recommendations are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until the termination of a delinquency proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the board of directors of the appropriate insurance guaranty association when it has reasonable cause to believe from any examination, whether completed or in process, of any member insurer that such insurer may be an impaired or insolvent insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek the advice and recommendations of the board of directors of the appropriate insurance guaranty association concerning any matter affecting the duties and responsibilities of the office in relation to the financial condition of member companies and companies seeking admission to transact insurance business in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, no later than the conclusion of any domestic insurer insolvency proceeding, prepare a summary report containing such information as is in its possession relating to the history and causes of such insolvency, including a statement of the business practices of such insurer which led to such insolvency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 28, 39, ch. 83-38; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 2, 6, ch. 93-118; s. 385, ch. 96-406; s. 1351, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>