<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.252" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuation of coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All insurance policies or similar contracts of coverage, other than coverages defined in s. 631.713 or health maintenance organization coverage under part IV, issued by the insurer shall be canceled upon the earliest to occur of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of entry of the liquidation or, if the court so provides in its order, the expiration of 30 days from the date of entry of the liquidation order;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The normal expiration of the policy or contract coverage;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The replacement of the coverage by the insured, or the replacement of the policy or contract of coverage, with a policy or contract acceptable to the insured by the receiver with another insurer; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The termination of the coverage by the insured.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim arising during continuation of coverage under paragraph (1)(a) shall be treated as if it arose immediately before the order of liquidation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 30-day coverage continuation period provided in paragraph (1)(a) may in no event be extended; and failure of actual notice to the policyholder of the insolvency of the insurer, of commencement of a delinquency proceeding, or of expiration of the extension period does not affect such expiration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Benefits under policies of life or health insurance or annuities and other coverages as defined in s. 631.713 shall continue in force for such period as provided for by s. 631.717 or any applicable law governing a foreign guaranty association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Benefits under membership in a health maintenance organization shall continue in force for such period as provided in part IV.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 70-27; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 19, ch. 83-38; s. 5, ch. 85-339; ss. 93, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>