<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Claims of residents against insurers domiciled in reciprocal states.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a liquidation proceeding in a reciprocal state against an insurer domiciled in that state, if a notice to file claims has been issued by the Florida receiver pursuant to s. 631.181(3), claimants against the insurer who reside within this state may file claims either with the ancillary receiver, if any, in this state or with the domiciliary receiver. Claims must be filed on or before the last date fixed for the filing of claims in the domiciliary liquidation proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a notice to file claims has been issued by the Florida receiver pursuant to s. 631.181(3), claims belonging to claimants residing in this state may be proved either in the domiciliary state under the law of that state or in the ancillary proceeding, if any, in this state. If a claimant elects to prove her or his claim in this state, the claimant shall file her or his claim with the receiver in the manner provided in s. 631.181(1) and (2). The ancillary receiver shall make its recommendation to the court as under s. 631.182(2), shall arrange a date for hearing if necessary under s. 631.182(1), and shall give notice to the liquidator in the domiciliary state, either by certified mail or by personal service at least 40 days prior to the date set for hearing. If the domiciliary liquidator, within 30 days after the giving of such notice, gives notice in writing to the ancillary receiver and to the claimant, either by certified mail or by personal service, of her or his intention to contest the claim, she or he is entitled to appear or to be represented in any proceeding in this state involving the adjudication of the claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a notice to file claims has not been issued by the Florida receiver pursuant to s. 631.181(3), claims shall be proved and filed before the domiciliary receiver.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The final allowance of the claim by the courts of this state shall be accepted as conclusive as to amount and as to priority against special deposits or other security located in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 733, ch. 59-205; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 10, ch. 83-38; s. 3, ch. 85-339; ss. 89, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 400, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>