<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.154" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Funds, assets, or other property in the possession of third person.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the receiver determines that funds, assets, or property in the possession of another person are rightfully the property of the estate, the receiver shall deliver to such person a written demand for immediate delivery of the funds, assets, or property to the receiver, referencing this section by number, referencing the court and docket number of the receivership action, and notifying the person that any claim of right to the funds, assets, or property by her or him must be presented to the court within 20 days after the date of the written demand. Any person who holds funds, assets, or other property belonging to an entity placed in receivership under this chapter shall deliver the funds, assets, or other property to the receiver on demand. Should the person allege any right to retain the funds, assets, or other property pursuant to s. 631.155, s. 631.191, s. 631.261, s. 631.262, s. 631.263, or s. 631.281, a pleading setting out the right shall be filed with the court within 20 days after the receipt of the receiver’s demand that the funds, assets, or property be delivered to the receiver. The person shall serve a copy of the pleading on the receiver. The pleading of the person shall inform the court as to the nature of the claim to the property, the alleged value of the assets or property, or the amount of funds held, and what action has been taken by the person to preserve and protect the assets or property or to preserve any funds pending determination of the dispute.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If requested by the receiver, a hearing shall be held to determine where and under what conditions the property, assets, or funds shall be held by the person pending determination of the dispute. The court may impose conditions as it may deem necessary or appropriate for the preservation of the property until the court can determine the validity of the person’s claim to the property, assets, or funds. If any property, assets, or funds are allowed to remain in the possession of the person after demand made by the receiver, that person shall be strictly liable for any waste, loss, or damage of the property, assets, or funds retained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person has filed a pleading alleging any right to retain funds, assets, or property, the court shall hold a subsequent hearing to determine entitlement to the funds, assets, or property claimed by the receiver.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person fails to file the pleading required by subsection (1) within the 20-day period, the court may, upon petition of the receiver and upon a copy of the petition being served by the petitioner to such person, issue its summary order directing the immediate delivery of the funds, assets, or property to the receiver and finding that the person has waived all claims of right to the funds, assets, or property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply to all proceedings brought by the receiver to recover funds, assets, or property believed by the receiver under this chapter to be assets of the entity subject to an order of conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation. The receiver shall be exempt from the provisions of s. 57.111.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should the receiver be successful in establishing its claim or any part thereof, the receiver shall be entitled to recover judgment for the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property or its cash value as of the date of the order of conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation, whichever is applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental for the use of the property to run from the date of the order of conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation, whichever is applicable, to the date the property is delivered to the receiver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of funds, interest at the statutory rate to run from the date of the order of conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation, whichever is applicable, to the date the funds are delivered to the receiver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All costs, investigative and other expenses, including, but not limited to, those for department staff, incurred in the recovery of the property, assets, or funds, and reasonable attorney’s fees. Department staff costs and expenses include staff salaries.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">It is the intent of this section that a person found to be holding receivership assets fully reimburse the receiver for any and all efforts made to recover those assets.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 89-360; s. 1, ch. 90-192; ss. 87, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 399, ch. 97-102; s. 10, ch. 2002-25.</History></Section>