<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.721" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plan of operation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association shall submit to the department a proposed plan of operation and any amendments thereto necessary or suitable to assure the fair, reasonable, and equitable administration of the association. The proposed plan of operation and any amendments thereto shall become effective upon approval in writing by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the association fails to submit a suitable proposed plan of operation within 180 days following October 1, 1979, or if at any time thereafter the association fails to submit suitable amendments to the plan, the department shall, after notice and hearing, adopt such reasonable rules as are necessary to effectuate the provisions of this part. Such rules shall continue in force until modified by the department or superseded by a proposed plan submitted by the association and approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All member insurers shall comply with the approved plan of operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of operation shall, in addition to requirements enumerated elsewhere in this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for handling the assets of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the amount and method of reimbursing members of the board of directors under s. 631.716.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish regular places and times for meetings of the board of directors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for keeping records of all financial transactions of the association, its agents, and the board of directors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures whereby selections for the board of directors shall be made and submitted to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish any additional procedures for assessments under s. 631.718.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain additional provisions necessary or proper for the execution of the powers and duties of the association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of operation may provide that any or all powers and duties of the association, except those under ss. 631.717(10)(c) and 631.718, are delegated to a corporation, association, or other organization which performs or will perform functions similar to those of this association, or its equivalent, in two or more states. Such a corporation, association, or organization shall be reimbursed for any payments made on behalf of the association and shall be paid for its performance of any function of the association. A delegation under this subsection shall take effect only with the approval of both the board of directors and the department and may be made only to a corporation, association, or organization which extends protection not substantially less favorable and effective than that provided by this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 79-189; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>