<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.917" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prevention of insolvencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To aid in the detection and prevention of insolvencies or impairments:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may make reasonable and lawful investigation into the practices of any third-party administrator or service company for a self-insurance fund declared insolvent by the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the results of an investigation reasonably lead to a finding that certain actions taken or not taken by those handling, processing, or preparing covered claims for payment or other benefit pursuant to any workers’ compensation insurance policy contributed to the insolvency of an insurer, such information may, in the discretion of the board, be provided to the department or office in an expedited manner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may make reports and recommendations to the department or office upon any matter germane to the solvency, liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation of any member insurer or germane to the solvency of any insurer seeking to do insurance business in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors, in its discretion, may notify the office of any information indicating that any member insurer may be an impaired or insolvent insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors, in its discretion, may request that the office order an examination of any member insurer which the board in good faith believes may be an impaired or insolvent insurer. Within 30 days after receipt of such a request, the office shall begin such an examination. The examination may be conducted as a National Association of Insurance Commissioners examination or may be conducted by such persons as the office designates. The cost of such examination shall be paid by the corporation, and the examination report shall be treated in a manner similar to other examination reports pursuant to s. 624.319. In no event may such examination report be released to the board of directors before its release to the public, but this requirement does not preclude the office from complying with s. 631.398(2). The office shall notify the board of directors when the examination is completed. The request for an examination shall be kept on file by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to assist and aid the department or office, in any manner consistent with existing laws and this chapter, in the department’s or office’s investigation or referral for prosecution of those whose action or inaction may have contributed to the impairment or insolvency of the insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may make recommendations to the office for the detection and prevention of insurer insolvencies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 97-262; s. 1374, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>