<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0631.152" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conduct of delinquency proceeding; foreign insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever under this chapter an ancillary receiver is to be appointed in a delinquency proceeding for an insurer not domiciled in this state, the court shall appoint the department as ancillary receiver. The department shall file a petition requesting the appointment on the grounds set forth in s. 631.091:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it finds that there are sufficient assets of the insurer located in this state to justify the appointment of an ancillary receiver;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If 10 or more persons resident in this state having claims against such insurer file a petition with the department or office requesting the appointment of such ancillary receiver; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it finds it is necessary to obtain records to adjudicate the covered claims of Florida policyholders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domiciliary receiver for the purpose of liquidating an insurer domiciled in a reciprocal state shall be vested by operation of law with the title to all of the property (except statutory deposits, special statutory deposits, and property located in this state subject to a security interest), contracts, and rights of action, and all of the books and records of the insurer located in this state, and it shall have the immediate right to recover balances due from local agents and to obtain possession of any books and records of the insurer found in this state. It shall also be entitled to recover the property subject to a security interest, statutory deposits, and special statutory deposits of the insurer located in this state, except that upon the appointment of an ancillary receiver in this state, the ancillary receiver shall during the ancillary receivership proceeding have the sole right to recover such other assets. The ancillary receiver shall, as soon as practicable, liquidate from their respective securities those special deposit claims and secured claims which are proved and allowed in the ancillary proceeding in this state, and shall pay the necessary expenses of the proceeding. All remaining assets it shall promptly transfer to the domiciliary receiver. Subject to the foregoing provisions, the ancillary receiver and its agents shall have the same powers and be subject to the same duties with respect to the administration of such assets as a receiver of an insurer domiciled in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domiciliary receiver of an insurer domiciled in a reciprocal state may sue in this state to recover any assets of such insurer to which it may be entitled under the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 631.141(7)(b) applies to ancillary delinquency proceedings opened for the purpose of obtaining records necessary to adjudicate the covered claims of Florida policyholders.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 731, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 86, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1346, ch. 2003-261; s. 5, ch. 2011-226.</History></Section>