<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0924.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appeal by state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state may appeal from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order dismissing an indictment or information or any count thereof or dismissing an affidavit charging the commission of a criminal offense, the violation of probation, the violation of community control, or the violation of any supervised correctional release.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order granting a new trial.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order arresting judgment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A ruling on a question of law when the defendant is convicted and appeals from the judgment. Once the state’s cross-appeal is instituted, the appellate court shall review and rule upon the question raised by the state regardless of the disposition of the defendant’s appeal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sentence, on the ground that it is illegal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judgment discharging a prisoner on habeas corpus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order adjudicating a defendant insane under the Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other pretrial orders, except that it may not take more than one appeal under this subsection in any case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sentence imposed below the lowest permissible sentence established by the Criminal Punishment Code under chapter 921.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A ruling granting a motion for judgment of acquittal after a jury verdict.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order denying restitution under s. 775.089.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order or ruling suppressing evidence or evidence in limine at trial.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order withholding adjudication of guilt in violation of s. 775.08435.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appeal under this section must embody all assignments of error in each pretrial order that the state seeks to have reviewed. The state shall pay all costs of the appeal except for the defendant’s attorney’s fee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 286, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(296); s. 1, ch. 69-15; s. 148, ch. 70-339; s. 4, ch. 83-87; s. 46, ch. 87-243; s. 1, ch. 90-239; s. 14, ch. 93-37; s. 7, ch. 93-406; s. 7, ch. 96-248; s. 28, ch. 97-194; s. 14, ch. 98-204; s. 2, ch. 2004-60.</History></Section>