<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0924.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appeal by defendant.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant may appeal from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final judgment of conviction when probation has not been granted under chapter 948, except as provided in subsection (3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order granting probation under chapter 948;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order revoking probation under chapter 948;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sentence, on the ground that it is illegal; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sentence imposed under s. 921.0024 of the Criminal Punishment Code which exceeds the statutory maximum penalty provided in s. 775.082 for an offense at conviction, or the consecutive statutory maximums for offenses at conviction, unless otherwise provided by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appeal of an order granting probation shall proceed in the same manner and have the same effect as an appeal of a judgment of conviction. An appeal of an order revoking probation may review only proceedings after the order of probation. If a judgment of conviction preceded an order of probation, the defendant may appeal from the order or the judgment or both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant who pleads guilty with no express reservation of the right to appeal a legally dispositive issue, or a defendant who pleads nolo contendere with no express reservation of the right to appeal a legally dispositive issue, shall have no right to a direct appeal.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 285, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(295); s. 22, ch. 20519, 1941; s. 3, ch. 59-130; s. 147, ch. 70-339; s. 7, ch. 76-274; s. 3, ch. 83-87; s. 6, ch. 93-406; s. 5, ch. 96-248; s. 27, ch. 97-194; s. 13, ch. 98-204.</History></Section>