<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0518.115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power of fiduciary or custodian to deposit securities in a central depository.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any fiduciary, as defined in s. 518.10, holding securities, as defined in <Reference Number="1" />s. 678.102(1), in its fiduciary capacity, and any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary, is authorized to deposit or arrange for the deposit of such securities in a clearing corporation, as defined in <Reference Number="1" />s. 678.102(3). When such securities are so deposited, certificates representing securities of the same class of the same issuer may be merged and held in bulk in the name of the nominee of such clearing corporation with any other such securities deposited in such clearing corporation by any person, regardless of the ownership of such securities, and certificates of small denomination may be merged into one or more certificates of larger denomination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank or a trust company so depositing securities with a clearing corporation shall be subject to such rules and regulations with respect to the making and maintenance of such deposit as, in the case of state-chartered institutions, the Financial Services Commission and, in the case of national banking associations, the Comptroller of the Currency may from time to time issue.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, ownership of, and other interests in, the securities credited to such account may be transferred by entries on the books of said clearing corporation without physical delivery of any securities. The records of such fiduciary and the records of such bank or trust company acting as custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary shall at all times show the name of the party for whose account the securities are so deposited. A bank or trust company acting as custodian for a fiduciary shall, on demand by the fiduciary, certify in writing to the fiduciary the securities so deposited by such bank or trust company in such clearing corporation for the account of such fiduciary. A fiduciary shall, on demand by any party to a judicial proceeding for the settlement of such fiduciary’s account or on demand by the attorney for such party, certify in writing to such party the securities deposited by such fiduciary in such clearing corporation for its account as such fiduciary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply to any fiduciary holding securities in its fiduciary capacity, and to any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary, acting on June 18, 1974, or who thereafter may act regardless of the date of the agreement, instrument, or court order by which it is appointed and regardless of whether or not such fiduciary, custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary owns capital stock of such clearing corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-224; s. 613, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 25, ch. 98-11.</Text></Note></Section>