<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0518.116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power of certain fiduciaries and custodians to deposit United States Government and agency securities with a Federal Reserve bank.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any fiduciary, as defined in s. 518.10, which is a bank or trust company holding securities in its fiduciary capacity, and any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary, is authorized to deposit or arrange for the deposit with the Federal Reserve Bank in its district of any securities, the principal and interest of which the United States Government or any department, agency, or instrumentality thereof has agreed to pay or has guaranteed payment, to be credited to one or more accounts on the books of said Federal Reserve Bank in the name of such bank or trust company to be designated fiduciary or safekeeping accounts, to which account other similar securities may be credited.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank or trust company so depositing securities with a Federal Reserve Bank shall be subject to such rules and regulations with respect to the making and maintenance of such deposits as, in the case of state-chartered institutions, the Financial Services Commission and, in the case of national banking associations, the Comptroller of the Currency may from time to time issue. The records of such bank or trust company shall at all times show the ownership of the securities held in such account.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, ownership of, and other interests in, the securities credited to such account may be transferred by entries on the books of said Federal Reserve Bank without physical delivery of any securities. The records of such fiduciary and the records of such bank or trust company acting as custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary shall at all times show the name of the party for whose account the securities are so deposited. A bank or a trust company acting as custodian for a fiduciary shall, on demand by the fiduciary, certify in writing to the fiduciary the securities so deposited by such bank or trust company with such Federal Reserve Bank for the account of such fiduciary. A fiduciary shall, on demand by any party to a judicial proceeding for the settlement of such fiduciary’s account or on demand by the attorney for such party, certify in writing to such party the securities deposited by such fiduciary with such Federal Reserve bank for its account as such fiduciary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply to any fiduciary and to any bank or trust company holding securities as custodian, managing agent, or custodian for a fiduciary, acting on June 18, 1974, or who thereafter may act regardless of the date of the instrument or court order by which it is appointed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-224; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 614, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>