<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0518.152" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Puerto Rican bonds or obligations, legal investments and securities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any restrictions on investments contained in any law of this state, all public officers and public bodies of the state, counties, municipal corporations, and other political subdivisions; all banks, bankers, trust companies, savings banks, building and loan associations, savings and loan associations, investment companies, and other persons carrying on a banking business; all insurance companies, insurance associations and other persons carrying on an insurance business; all persons holding in trust any pension, health and welfare, and vacation funds; all administrators, executors, guardians, trustees, and other fiduciaries of any public, quasi-public, or private fund or estate; and all other persons authorized to invest in bonds or other obligations may legally invest any sinking funds, moneys, or other funds belonging to them or within their control in bonds or other obligations issued by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, its agencies, authorities, instrumentalities, municipalities, or political subdivisions, provided such agency, authority, instrumentality, municipality, or political subdivision has not, within 5 years prior to the making of such investment, defaulted for more than 90 days in the payment of any part of the principal or interest of its bonded indebtedness. Such bonds or obligations shall be authorized security for all public deposits, including, but not restricted to, deposits as authorized in s. 17.57, it being the purpose of this section to authorize any person, firm, corporation, association, political subdivision, body, and officer, public or private, to use any funds owned or controlled by them, including, but not limited to, sinking, insurance, investment, retirement, compensation, pension and trust funds, and funds held on deposit, for the purchase of any such bonds or obligations up to the amount as authorized by law to be invested in any type of security, including United States Government Bonds. However, nothing contained in this section shall be construed as relieving any person from any duty of exercising reasonable care in selecting securities.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-136; s. 617, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>