<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0097.0535" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special requirements for certain applicants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant who registers by mail and who has never previously voted in the state and who the department has verified has not been issued a current and valid Florida driver’s license, Florida identification card, or social security number shall be required to provide a copy of a current and valid identification, as provided in subsection (3), or indicate that he or she is exempt from the requirements prior to voting. Such identification or indication may be provided at the time of registering, or at any time prior to voting for the first time in the state. If the voter registration application clearly provides information from which a voter registration official can determine that the applicant meets at least one of the exemptions in subsection (4), the voter registration official shall make the notation on the registration records of the statewide voter registration system and the applicant shall not be required to provide the identification required by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The voter registration official shall, upon accepting the voter registration application submitted pursuant to subsection (1), determine if the applicant provided the required identification at the time of registering. If the required identification was not provided, the supervisor shall notify the applicant that he or she must provide the identification prior to voting the first time in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following forms of identification shall be considered current and valid if they contain the name and photograph of the applicant and have not expired:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">United States passport.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Debit or credit card.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Military identification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student identification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retirement center identification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neighborhood association identification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public assistance identification.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following forms of identification shall be considered current and valid if they contain the name and current residence address of the applicant:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Utility bill.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bank statement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Government check.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paycheck.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other government document (excluding voter identification card).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons are exempt from the identification requirements of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons 65 years of age or older.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons with a temporary or permanent physical disability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the uniformed service on active duty who, by reason of such active duty, are absent from the county on election day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the Merchant Marine who, by reason of service in the Merchant Marine, are absent from the county on election day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The spouse or dependent of a member referred to in paragraph (c) or paragraph (d) who, by reason of the active duty or service of the member, is absent from the county on election day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons currently residing outside the United States who are eligible to vote in Florida.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2003-415; s. 7, ch. 2005-278; s. 4, ch. 2008-95.</History></Section>