<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0097.052" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform statewide voter registration application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe by rule a uniform statewide voter registration application for use in this state.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uniform statewide voter registration application must be accepted for any one or more of the following purposes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial registration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change of address.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change of party affiliation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change of name.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Replacement of a voter information card.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signature update.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is responsible for printing the uniform statewide voter registration application and the voter registration application form prescribed by the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to federal law. The applications and forms must be distributed, upon request, to the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals seeking to register to vote or update a voter registration record.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals or groups conducting voter registration programs. A charge of 1 cent per application shall be assessed on requests for 10,000 or more applications.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Voter registration agencies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Armed forces recruitment offices.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifying educational institutions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervisors, who must make the applications and forms available in the following manner:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By distributing the applications and forms in their offices to any individual or group.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By distributing the applications and forms at other locations designated by each supervisor.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By mailing the applications and forms to applicants upon the request of the applicant.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uniform statewide voter registration application may be reproduced by any private individual or group, provided the reproduced application is in the same format as the application prescribed by rule under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uniform statewide voter registration application must be designed to elicit the following information from the applicant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Last, first, and middle name, including any suffix.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date of birth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address of legal residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mailing address, if different.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County of legal residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Race or ethnicity that best describes the applicant:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">American Indian or Alaskan Native.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Asian or Pacific Islander.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Black, not Hispanic.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">White, not Hispanic.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hispanic.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or country of birth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sex.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Party affiliation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the applicant needs assistance in voting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address where last registered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Last four digits of the applicant’s social security number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida driver’s license number or the identification number from a Florida identification card issued under s. 322.051.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An indication, if applicable, that the applicant has not been issued a Florida driver’s license, a Florida identification card, or a social security number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Telephone number (optional).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signature of applicant under penalty for false swearing pursuant to s. 104.011, by which the person subscribes to the oath required by s. 3, Art. VI of the State Constitution and s. 97.051, and swears or affirms that the information contained in the registration application is true.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the application is being used for initial registration, to update a voter registration record, or to request a replacement voter information card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the applicant is a citizen of the United States by asking the question “Are you a citizen of the United States of America?” and providing boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether the applicant is or is not a citizen of the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the applicant has been convicted of a felony, and, if convicted, has had his or her civil rights restored by including the statement “I affirm I am not a convicted felon, or, if I am, my rights relating to voting have been restored.” and providing a box for the applicant to check to affirm the statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the applicant has been adjudicated mentally incapacitated with respect to voting or, if so adjudicated, has had his or her right to vote restored by including the statement “I affirm I have not been adjudicated mentally incapacitated with respect to voting, or, if I have, my competency has been restored.” and providing a box for the applicant to check to affirm the statement.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The registration application must be in plain language and designed so that convicted felons whose civil rights have been restored and persons who have been adjudicated mentally incapacitated and have had their voting rights restored are not required to reveal their prior conviction or adjudication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uniform statewide voter registration application must also contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The oath required by s. 3, Art. VI of the State Constitution and s. 97.051.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement specifying each eligibility requirement under s. 97.041.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalties provided in s. 104.011 for false swearing in connection with voter registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that, if an applicant declines to register to vote, the fact that the applicant has declined to register will remain confidential and may be used only for voter registration purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that informs the applicant who chooses to register to vote or update a voter registration record that the office at which the applicant submits a voter registration application or updates a voter registration record will remain confidential and may be used only for voter registration purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement informing an applicant who has not been issued a Florida driver’s license, a Florida identification card, or a social security number that if the application is submitted by mail and the applicant is registering for the first time in this state, the applicant will be required to provide identification prior to voting the first time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A supervisor may produce a voter registration application that has the supervisor’s direct mailing address if the department has reviewed the application and determined that it is substantially the same as the uniform statewide voter registration application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The voter registration application form prescribed by the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to federal law or the federal postcard application must be accepted as an application for registration in this state if the completed application or postcard application contains the information required by the constitution and laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a voter registration applicant fails to provide any of the required information on the voter registration application form, the supervisor shall notify the applicant of the failure by mail within 5 business days after the supervisor has the information available in the voter registration system. The applicant shall have an opportunity to complete the application form to vote in the next election up until the book closing for that next election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 25391, 1949; s. 2, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 1, ch. 59-231; s. 8, ch. 65-134; s. 1, ch. 67-170; s. 8, ch. 69-377; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 72-63; s. 5, ch. 77-175; s. 23, ch. 84-302; s. 6, ch. 89-338; s. 10, ch. 94-224; s. 2, ch. 96-327; s. 26, ch. 97-13; s. 4, ch. 98-129; ss. 1, 7, ch. 2002-189; s. 3, ch. 2003-415; s. 4, ch. 2005-277; s. 5, ch. 2005-278.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 97.05; s. 98.111.</Text></Note></Section>