<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0097.058" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voter registration agencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each voter registration agency must provide each applicant the opportunity to register to vote or to update a voter registration record, at the time the applicant applies for services or assistance from that agency, for renewal of such services or assistance, or for a change of address required with respect to the services or assistance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each voter registration agency, other than a public library, must develop and provide each applicant with a form approved by the department containing all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The questions:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“If you are not registered to vote where you live now, would you like to apply to register to vote today?”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“If you are registered to vote where you live now, would you like to update your voter registration record?”</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For agencies providing public assistance, the statement, “Applying to register or declining to register to vote will not affect the amount of assistance that you will be provided by this agency.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boxes for the applicant to check which indicate that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant would like to register to vote or update a current voter registration;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant would like to decline to register to vote; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is already registered to vote and does not need to update the voter registration,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">together with the statement, “If you do not check any box, you will be considered to have decided not to register to vote or update a voter registration at this time.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statement, “If you would like help in filling out the voter registration application, we will help you. The decision whether to seek or accept help is yours. You may fill out the voter registration application in private.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statement, “If you believe that someone has interfered with your right to register or to decline to register to vote, your right to privacy in deciding whether to register or in applying to register to vote, or your right to choose your own political party or other political preference, you may file a complaint with the Secretary of State.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address and telephone number of the appropriate office in the department where a complaint may be filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that all declinations will remain confidential and may be used only for voter registration purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that informs the applicant who chooses to register to vote or update a voter registration record that the office at which the applicant submits a voter registration application or updates a voter registration record will remain confidential and may be used only for voter registration purposes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency may use the uniform statewide voter registration application or may create and use a voter registration application that meets the requirements of s. 97.052, with the approval of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency must provide to each applicant under subsection (1) the voter registration application that the agency decides to use pursuant to paragraph (a). An applicant who indicates a desire to register to vote or update a voter registration record must be provided the same degree of assistance with regard to the completion of that voter registration application as is provided by the agency with regard to the completion of its own forms, unless the applicant refuses that assistance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a voter registration agency provides services to a person with a disability at the person’s home, the agency must also provide voter registration services at the person’s home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency must establish procedures for providing voter registration services to applicants who apply by telephone.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency must forward all completed and incomplete voter registration applications within 5 days after receipt to the supervisor of the county where the agency that processed or received that application is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency must retain declinations for a period of 2 years, during which time the declinations are not considered a record of the client pursuant to the laws governing the agency’s records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person providing voter registration services for a voter registration agency may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek to influence an applicant’s political preference or party registration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display any political preference or party allegiance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to lead the applicant to believe that a decision to register or not to register has any bearing on the availability of services or benefits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to discourage the applicant from registering to vote; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose any applicant’s voter registration information except as needed for the administration of voter registrations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter registration agency must collect data determined necessary by the department, as provided by rule, for program evaluation and reporting to the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to federal law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency which contracts with a private provider that is also a voter registration agency as defined in s. 97.021 is responsible for contracting for voter registration services with that provider and for ensuring that the private provider complies with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each voter registration agency must ensure that all voter registration services provided by its offices are in compliance with the Voting Rights Act of 1965.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 94-224; s. 3, ch. 2002-189; s. 10, ch. 2005-278.</History></Section>