<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0024.118" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Other prohibited acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNLAWFUL EXTENSIONS OF CREDIT.<EmDash />Any retailer who extends credit or lends money to a person for the purchase of a lottery ticket is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. This subsection shall not be construed to prohibit the purchase of a lottery ticket through the use of a credit or charge card or other instrument issued by a bank, savings association, credit union, or charge card company or by a retailer pursuant to part II of chapter 520, provided that any such purchase from a retailer shall be in addition to the purchase of goods and services other than lottery tickets having a cost of no less than $20.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNLAWFUL ASSIGNMENT OR TRANSFER OF RIGHT TO CLAIM PRIZE.<EmDash />Any person who induces another to assign or transfer his or her right to claim a prize, who offers for sale his or her right to claim a prize, or who offers for compensation to claim the prize of another is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNTERFEIT OR ALTERED TICKETS.<EmDash />Any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly presents a counterfeit or altered state lottery ticket;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly transfers a counterfeit or altered state lottery ticket to another to present for payment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With intent to defraud, falsely makes, alters, forges, passes, or counterfeits a state lottery ticket; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Files with the department a claim for payment based upon facts alleged by the claimant which facts are untrue and known by the claimant to be untrue when the claim is made;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BREACH OF CONFIDENTIALITY.<EmDash />Any person who, with intent to defraud or with intent to provide a financial or other advantage to himself, herself, or another, knowingly and willfully discloses any information relating to the lottery designated as confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) pursuant to this act is guilty of a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNLAWFUL REPRESENTATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who uses point-of-sale materials issued by the department or otherwise holds himself or herself out as a retailer without being authorized by the department to act as a retailer is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who without being authorized by the department in writing uses the term “Florida Lottery,” “State Lottery,” “Florida State Lottery,” or any similar term in the title or name of any charitable or commercial enterprise, product, or service is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 87-65; s. 4, ch. 89-208; s. 6, ch. 90-360; s. 92, ch. 95-147; s. 9, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>