<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0024.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bank deposits and control of lottery transactions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received by each retailer from the operation of the state lottery, including, but not limited to, all ticket sales, interest, gifts, and donations, less the amount retained as compensation for the sale of the tickets and the amount paid out as prizes, shall be remitted to the department or deposited in a qualified public depository, as defined in s. 280.02, as directed by the department. The department shall have the responsibility for all administrative functions related to the receipt of funds. The department may also require each retailer to file with the department reports of the retailer’s receipts and transactions in the sale of lottery tickets in such form and containing such information as the department may require. The department may require any person, including a qualified public depository, to perform any function, activity, or service in connection with the operation of the lottery as it may deem advisable pursuant to this act and rules of the department, and such functions, activities, or services shall constitute lawful functions, activities, and services of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require retailers to establish separate electronic funds transfer accounts for the purpose of receiving moneys from ticket sales, making payments to the department, and receiving payments from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each retailer is liable to the department for any and all tickets accepted or generated by any employee or representative of that retailer, and the tickets shall be deemed to have been purchased by the retailer unless returned to the department within the time and in the manner prescribed by the department. All moneys received by retailers from the sale of lottery tickets, less the amount retained as compensation for the sale of tickets and the amount paid out as prizes by the retailer, shall be held in trust prior to delivery to the department or electronic transfer to the Operating Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 87-65; s. 10, ch. 2006-79.</History></Section>