<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.555" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of consumer collection agencies; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person required to register as a consumer collection agency shall furnish to the office the registration fee and information as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registrant shall pay to the office a registration fee in the amount of $200. All amounts collected shall be deposited by the office to the credit of the Regulatory Trust Fund of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each registrant shall provide to the office the business name or trade name, the current mailing address, the current business location which constitutes its principal place of business, and the full name of each individual who is a principal of the registrant. “Principal of a registrant” means the registrant’s owners if a partnership or sole proprietorship, corporate officers, corporate directors other than directors of a not-for-profit corporation organized pursuant to chapter 617 and Florida resident agent if a corporate registrant. The registration information shall include a statement clearly identifying and explaining any occasion on which any professional license or state registration held by the registrant, by any principal of the registrant, or by any business entity in which any principal of the registrant was the owner of 10 percent or more of such business, was the subject of any suspension or revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Renewal of registration shall be made between October 1 and December 31 of each year. There shall be no proration of the fee for any registration.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 13, ch. 93-275; s. 679, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>