<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.553" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of consumer collection agencies required; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After January 1, 1994, no person shall engage in business in this state as a consumer collection agency or continue to do business in this state as a consumer collection agency without first registering in accordance with this part, and thereafter maintaining a valid registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each consumer collection agency doing business in this state shall register with the office and renew such registration annually as set forth in s. 559.555.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prospective registrant shall be entitled to be registered when registration information is complete on its face and the applicable registration fee has been paid; however, the office may reject a registration submitted by a prospective registrant if the registrant or any principal of the registrant previously has held any professional license or state registration which was the subject of any suspension or revocation which has not been explained by the prospective registrant to the satisfaction of the office either in the registration information submitted initially or upon the subsequent written request of the office. In the event that an attempted registration is rejected by the office the prospective registrant shall be informed of the basis for rejection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any original creditor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of The Florida Bar.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any financial institution authorized to do business in this state and any wholly owned subsidiary and affiliate thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensed real estate broker.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurance company authorized to do business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any consumer finance company and any wholly owned subsidiary and affiliate thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed pursuant to chapter 520.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any out-of-state consumer debt collector who does not solicit consumer debt accounts for collection from credit grantors who have a business presence in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any FDIC-insured institution or subsidiary or affiliate thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any out-of-state consumer debt collector as defined in s. 559.55(8) who is not exempt from registration by application of subsection (4) and who fails to register in accordance with this part shall be subject to an enforcement action by the state as specified in s. 559.565.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 13, ch. 93-275; s. 678, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>