<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.921" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any customer injured by a violation of this part may bring an action in the appropriate court for relief. The prevailing party in that action may be entitled to damages plus court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees. The customer may also bring an action for injunctive relief in the circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall process consumer complaints according to ss. 570.07 and 570.544.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All motor vehicle repair shops shall allow department personnel to enter their place of business to ascertain whether the registration certificate is current. If department personnel are refused entry or access to the premises, the department may seek injunctive relief in circuit court in order to obtain compliance with this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter an order imposing one or more of the penalties set forth in paragraph (b) if the department finds that a motor vehicle repair shop:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violated or is operating in violation of any of the provisions of this part or of the rules adopted or orders issued thereunder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made a material false statement in any application, document, or record required to be submitted or retained under this part;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refused or failed, or any of its principal officers have refused or failed, after notice, to produce any document or record or disclose any information required to be produced or disclosed under this part or the rules of the department;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made a material false statement in response to any request or investigation by the department, the Department of Legal Affairs, or the state attorney; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has intentionally defrauded the public through dishonest or deceptive means.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a finding as set forth in paragraph (a), the department may enter an order doing one or more of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuing a notice of noncompliance pursuant to s. 120.695.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposing an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 per violation for each act which constitutes a violation of this part or a rule or order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directing that the motor vehicle repair shop cease and desist specified activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to register or revoking or suspending a registration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing the registrant on probation for a period of time, subject to such conditions as the department may specify.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative proceedings which could result in the entry of an order imposing any of the penalties specified in paragraph (b) shall be conducted in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the state attorney, if a violation of this part occurs in his or her judicial circuit, shall be the enforcing authority for purposes of this part and may bring a civil action in circuit court for temporary or permanent injunctive relief and may seek other appropriate civil relief, including a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000 for each violation, restitution and damages for injured customers, court costs, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enforcing authority may terminate any investigation or action upon agreement by the offender to pay a stipulated civil penalty, to make restitution or pay damages to customers, or to satisfy any other relief authorized herein and requested by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall have exclusive authority to impose the remedies in subsection (4) for motor vehicle and recreational vehicle dealers licensed under chapter 320. The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and the state attorney shall have exclusive authority to impose the remedies in subsection (5) for motor vehicle and recreational vehicle dealers licensed under chapter 320. Upon receipt of a final order from the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for suspension or revocation of a motor vehicle repair shop registration, the department shall suspend or revoke the registration according to the order. Rules adopted by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to enforce the provisions of this part shall be consistent with the rules of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in any proceeding brought pursuant to this part, it is determined that the repairs and costs thereof were in fact authorized, orally or in writing, the repairs were completed in a proper manner, and the consumer benefited therefrom, then the enforcing authority may consider such factors in assessing penalties or damages and may award the reasonable value of such repairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remedies provided for in this section shall be in addition to any other remedy provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-139; s. 12, ch. 93-219; s. 829, ch. 97-103; s. 28, ch. 97-250; s. 45, ch. 2001-279; ss. 64, 65, ch. 2003-399.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.923.</Text></Note></Section>