<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.920" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts and practices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be a violation of this act for any motor vehicle repair shop or employee thereof to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage or attempt to engage in repair work for compensation of any type without first being registered with or having submitted an affidavit of exemption to the department;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or charge for repairs which have not been expressly or impliedly authorized by the customer;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent that repairs have been made to a motor vehicle;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent that certain parts and repairs are necessary to repair a vehicle;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent that the vehicle being inspected or diagnosed is in a dangerous condition or that the customer’s continued use of the vehicle may be harmful or cause great damage to the vehicle;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulently alter any customer contract, estimate, invoice, or other document;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulently misuse any customer’s credit card;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or authorize in any manner or by any means whatever any written or oral statement which is untrue, deceptive or misleading, and which is known, or which by the exercise of reasonable care should be known, to be untrue, deceptive or misleading;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make false promises of a character likely to influence, persuade, or induce a customer to authorize the repair, service, or maintenance of a motor vehicle;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute used, rebuilt, salvaged, or straightened parts for new replacement parts without notice to the motor vehicle owner and to her or his insurer if the cost of repair is to be paid pursuant to an insurance policy and the identity of the insurer or its claims adjuster is disclosed to the motor vehicle repair shop;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause or allow a customer to sign any work order that does not state the repairs requested by the customer or the automobile’s odometer reading at the time of repair;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail or refuse to give to a customer a copy of any document requiring the customer’s signature upon completion or cancellation of the repair work;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully depart from or disregard accepted practices and professional standards;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have repair work subcontracted without the knowledge or consent of the customer unless the motor vehicle repair shop or employee thereof demonstrates that the customer could not reasonably have been notified;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct the business of motor vehicle repair in a location other than that stated on the registration certificate;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rebuild or restore a rebuilt vehicle without the knowledge of the owner in such a manner that it does not conform to the original vehicle manufacturer’s established repair procedures or specifications and allowable tolerances for the particular model and year; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform any other act that is a violation of this part or that constitutes fraud or misrepresentation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 93-219; s. 828, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>