<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0559.904" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motor vehicle repair shop registration; application; exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each motor vehicle repair shop engaged or attempting to engage in the business of motor vehicle repair work must register with the department prior to doing business in this state. The application for registration must be on a form provided by the department and must include at least the following information:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name under which the applicant is doing business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business address at which the applicant performs repair work or in the case of a mobile motor vehicle repair shop, the home address of the owner, if different from the business address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of all licenses, permits, and certifications obtained by the applicant or employees of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of employees which the applicant intends to employ or which are currently employed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle repair shop maintaining more than one place of business may file a single application biennially, which, along with the other information required by this part, clearly indicates the location of and the individual in charge of each facility or in the case of a mobile motor vehicle repair shop, the home address of the owner, if different from the business address. In such case, fees shall be paid for each place of business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for registration must be accompanied by a registration fee calculated on a per-year basis as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the place of business has 1 to 5 employees: $50.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the place of business has 6 to 10 employees: $150.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the place of business has 11 or more employees: $300.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each initial application for registration must be accompanied by copies of the applicant’s estimate and invoice forms. Each renewal application for registration must be accompanied by copies of the applicant’s estimate and invoice forms only if the original forms filed by the applicant are changed, altered, or revised. Such forms must comply with the applicable provisions of this act before a registration may be issued.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No biennial registration fee is required for any motor vehicle repair shop which has a local municipal or county license issued pursuant to an ordinance containing standards which the department determines are at least equal to the requirements of this part, or for any motor vehicle dealer licensed pursuant to chapter 320.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue to each applicant a registration certificate in the form and size as prescribed by the department in accordance with s. 120.60. In the case of an applicant with more than one place of business, the department shall issue a registration certificate for each place of business. The certificate must show at least the name and address of the motor vehicle repair shop and the registration number for that place of business. In the case of a mobile motor vehicle repair shop, the certificate must show the home address of the owner, if different from the business address.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person applying for or renewing a local business tax receipt to engage in business as a motor vehicle repair shop must exhibit an active registration certificate from the department before the local business tax receipt may be issued or renewed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each registration must be renewed biennially on or before the expiration date of the current registration. A late fee of $25 shall be paid, in addition to the registration fee or any other penalty, for any registration renewal application that is received by the department after the expiration date of the current registration. The department may not issue the registration until all fees are paid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No registration application or fee is required for an individual with no employees and no established place of business. In the case of a mobile motor vehicle repair shop, the established place of business shall be considered the home address of the owner, if different than the business address.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, revoke, or refuse to renew the registration of a motor vehicle repair shop based upon a determination that the motor vehicle repair shop, or any of its directors, officers, owners, or general partners:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have failed to meet the requirements for registration as provided in this part;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have not satisfied a civil fine, administrative fine, or other penalty arising out of any administrative or enforcement action brought by any governmental agency based upon conduct involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any violation of this part;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have had against them any civil, criminal, or administrative adjudication in any jurisdiction, based upon conduct involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any violation of this part; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have had a judgment entered against them in any action brought by the department or the state attorney pursuant to ss. 501.201-501.213 or this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall post a prominent “Closed by Order of the Department” sign on any motor vehicle repair shop that has had its registration suspended or revoked. The department shall also post a sign on any motor vehicle repair shop that has been judicially or administratively determined to be operating without a registration. It is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any person to deface such sign or remove such sign without written authorization by the department or for any motor vehicle repair shop to open for operation without a registration or to open for operation as a motor vehicle repair shop while its registration is suspended or revoked. The department may impose administrative sanctions provided for in s. 559.921(4) for violations of this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 93-219; s. 6, ch. 94-298; s. 26, ch. 97-250; s. 10, ch. 98-299; s. 14, ch. 99-307; s. 17, ch. 2001-214; s. 9, ch. 2003-132; s. 16, ch. 2006-2; s. 35, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>