<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.932" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vacation certificate disclosure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any seller of travel to fail to provide each person solicited with a contract which shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A space for the date, name, address, and signature of the purchaser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expiration date of the vacation certificate and the terms and conditions of its extension or renewal, if available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and business address of any seller of travel who may solicit vacation certificate purchasers for further purchases, and a full and complete statement as to the nature and method of that solicitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total financial obligation of the purchaser which shall include the initial purchase price and any additional charges to which the purchaser may be subject, including, but not limited to, any per diem, seasonal, reservation, or recreational charge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of any person who has the right to alter, amend, or add to the charges to which the purchaser may be subject and the terms and conditions under which such charges may be imposed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any accommodation or facility which a purchaser acquires the right to use pursuant to the vacation certificate is not completed at the time the certificate is offered for sale, the date of availability of each component of the accommodation or facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By means of a section entitled “terms and conditions”:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All eligibility requirements for use of the vacation certificate, including, but not limited to, age, sex, marital status, group association, residency, or geographic limitations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All eligibility requirements for use of any discount or complimentary coupon or ticket.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether transportation and meals are provided pursuant to use of the certificate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any room deposit requirement, including all conditions for its return or refund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which reservation requests are to be made and the method by which they are to be confirmed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any identification, credential, or other means by which a purchaser must establish her or his entitlement to the rights, benefits, or privileges of the vacation certificate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any restriction or limitation upon transfer of the vacation certificate or any right, benefit, or privilege thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other term, limitation, condition, or requirement material to use of the vacation certificate or any right, benefit, or privilege thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In immediate proximity to the space reserved in the contract for the date and the name, address, and signature of the purchaser, the following statement in boldfaced type of a size of 10 points:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">“YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHOUT ANY PENALTY OR OBLIGATION WITHIN 30 DAYS FROM THE DATE OF PURCHASE OR RECEIPT OF THE VACATION CERTIFICATE, WHICHEVER OCCURS LATER.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“YOU MAY ALSO CANCEL THIS CONTRACT IF ACCOMMODATIONS OR FACILITIES ARE NOT AVAILABLE PURSUANT TO A REQUEST FOR USE AS PROVIDED IN THE CONTRACT.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">“IF YOU DECIDE TO CANCEL, YOU MUST NOTIFY THE SELLER IN WRITING OF YOUR INTENT TO CANCEL BY RETURNING THE CERTIFICATE AND SENDING NOTICE TO: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(NAME OF SELLER)</Directions> AT <Directions xml:space="preserve">(SELLER’S ADDRESS)</Directions>.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In immediate proximity to the statement required in paragraph (h), the following statement in boldfaced type of a size of 10 points:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">“NO PURCHASER SHOULD RELY UPON REPRESENTATIONS OTHER THAN THOSE INCLUDED IN THIS CONTRACT.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">However, inclusion of this statement shall not impair any purchaser’s right to bring legal action based on verbal statements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In immediate proximity to the statement required in paragraph (i), the following statement:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“This contract is for the purchase of a vacation certificate and puts all assignees on notice of the consumer’s right to cancel under section 559.933, Florida Statutes.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a sale or agreement to purchase a vacation certificate is completed over the telephone, the seller shall inform the purchaser over the telephone that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser may cancel the contract without any penalty or obligation within 30 days from the date of purchase or receipt of the vacation certificate, whichever occurs later.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser may also cancel the contract if accommodations or facilities are not available upon request for use as provided in the contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 93-107; s. 5, ch. 95-314; s. 834, ch. 97-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.927(7).</Text></Note></Section>