<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business opportunity sellers shall not:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent, by failure to disclose or otherwise, the known required total investment for such business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent or fail to disclose efforts to sell or establish more franchises or distributorships than it is reasonable to expect the market or market area for the particular business opportunity to sustain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the quantity or the quality of the products to be sold or distributed through the business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the training and management assistance available to the business opportunity purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the amount of profits, net or gross, which the franchisee can expect from the operation of the business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent, by failure to disclose or otherwise, the termination, transfer, or renewal provision of a business opportunity agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsely claim or imply that a primary marketer or trademark of products or services sponsors or participates directly or indirectly in the business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assign a so-called “exclusive territory” encompassing the same area to more than one business opportunity purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide vending locations for which written authorizations have not been granted by the property owners or lessees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide machines or displays of a brand or kind substantially different from and inferior to those promised by the business opportunity seller.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to provide the purchaser a written contract as provided in s. 559.811.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent their ability or the ability of a person or entity providing services as defined in s. 559.801(1)(a) to provide locations or assist the purchaser in finding locations expected to have a positive impact on the success of the business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent a material fact or create a false or misleading impression in the sale of a business opportunity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to provide or deliver the products, equipment, supplies, or services as specified in the written contract required under s. 559.811.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-374; s. 6, ch. 93-244; s. 32, ch. 97-98; s. 14, ch. 2001-214.</History></Section>