<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0559.9232" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; exclusion of rental-purchase agreements from certain regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cash price” means the price at which the lessor, in the ordinary course of business, would offer to sell for cash the property or service that is the subject of the rental-purchase agreement. The term “cash price” may include the price of accessories, services related to the agreement, and taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lessee” means a natural person who rents personal property pursuant to a rental-purchase agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lessor” means a person or corporation who, in the ordinary course of business, regularly offers to rent personal property, or arranges for personal property to be rented, pursuant to a rental-purchase agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal property” means any property that is not real property under the laws of the state where it is located and which is offered or made available for lease under a rental-purchase agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rental-purchase agreement” means an agreement for the use of personal property by a natural person primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, for an initial period of 4 months or less, that is automatically renewed with each rental payment after the initial period and that permits the lessee to acquire ownership of the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Services” means work, labor, or other personal services furnished pursuant to a rental-purchase agreement, including, but not limited to, the delivery, installation, servicing, repair, or improvement of rental property and excluding the provision of such property and associated services to the lessee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rental-purchase agreement that complies with this act shall not be construed to be, nor be governed by, any of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lease or agreement that constitutes a credit sale as defined in 12 C.F.R. s. 226.2(a)(16) and s. 1602(g) of the federal Truth in Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1601 et seq.;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lease that constitutes a “consumer lease” as defined in 12 C.F.R. s. 213.2(a)(6);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lease for agricultural, business, or commercial purposes;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lease made to an organization;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lease or agreement that constitutes a “retail installment contract” or “retail installment transaction” as those terms are defined in s. 520.31; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest as defined in s. 671.201(38).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-69; s. 51, ch. 95-144; s. 20, ch. 99-164; s. 685, ch. 2003-261; s. 52, ch. 2006-213; s. 20, ch. 2007-134; s. 1, ch. 2010-131.</History>
</Section>