<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definition; “budget planning.”</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “budget planning” as used in this part shall mean the act of entering into a contract by any person, firm, corporation, or association with a particular debtor by the terms of which contract the debtor agrees to deposit periodically with such person, firm, corporation, or association a specified sum of money and said person, firm, corporation, or association agrees to distribute said sum of money among specified creditors of the debtor in accordance with an agreed plan for which service the debtor agrees to pay a valuable consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “budget planning” does not include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The act of entering into a contract for services by any person, firm, corporation, or association with a particular mortgagor by the terms of which contract the mortgagor agrees to periodically deposit with such person, firm, corporation, or association, a specified sum of money and said person, firm, corporation, or association agrees to utilize said deposits to accelerate payments on a single mortgage loan of the mortgagor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other activities defined by rule of the Financial Services Commission as not within the prohibition of this part, provided such rule is adopted after a finding that consumers are adequately protected in the activity and that its prohibition is not required in the public interest.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Financial Services Commission may adopt rules as necessary to implement and enforce this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-345; s. 5, ch. 90-104; s. 671, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>