<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.802" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Franchises; exemption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of a franchise is exempt from this part if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The franchise meets the definition of that term as defined by the Federal Trade Commission regulations entitled, “Disclosure Requirements and Prohibitions Concerning Franchising and Business Opportunity Ventures,” as set forth in 16 C.F.R. ss. 436.1 et seq.; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before offering for sale or selling a franchise to be located in this state or to a resident of this state, the franchisor files a notice with the department stating that the franchisor is in substantial compliance with the requirements of the Federal Trade Commission rule, and pays a fee in an amount set by the department, not exceeding $100.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial exemption granted under this section is for a period of 1 year after the date of filing the notice, and it may be renewed each year for an additional 1-year period upon filing a notice for renewal and paying a renewal fee in an amount set by the department, not exceeding $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require only the name of the applicant, the name of the franchise and the name under which the applicant intends to, or does, transact business, if different, the applicant’s principal business address, and the applicant’s federal employer identification number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-244.</History></Section>