<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0559.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Regulation of sales.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not publish or conduct any sale of the type herein defined without a permit therefor. Such permit shall be issued by the tax collector, upon written application and verified by the person who, or by an officer of the corporation which intends to conduct such sale. Such application shall contain a description of the place where such sale is to be held, the nature of the occupancy, and whether by lease or sublease and the effective date of termination of such occupancy, the means to be employed in publishing such sale. Such application shall further contain, as part thereof, an itemized list of the goods, wares, and merchandise to be offered for sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of such application and payment of the fee prescribed in s. 559.23, the tax collector shall examine the same, and may make such investigation as she or he may deem proper. The tax collector shall determine if the person or corporation that intends to conduct the sale owes any taxes with respect to the goods to be offered for sale. The tax collector may not issue a permit to such person or corporation until all delinquent taxes on such goods have been paid. If after such investigation she or he is satisfied as to the truth of the statements contained in such application, the tax collector may issue a license permitting the publication and conduct of such sale on the following terms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permit shall authorize the sale described in the application for a period of not more than 60 consecutive days, counting Sundays and legal holidays following the issuance thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permit shall authorize only the one type of sale described in the application at the location named therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permit shall authorize only the sale of goods described in the inventory attached to the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon being issued a permit hereunder for a going-out-of-business sale, the permittee shall surrender to the tax collector all other business licenses she or he may hold at that time applicable to the location and goods covered by the application for a permit under this part, which license or licenses shall be transmitted by the tax collector to the licensing authority for cancellation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any permit herein provided for shall not be assignable or transferable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-292; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 198, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 93-82; s. 37, ch. 95-312; s. 811, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>