<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.079" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary guidelines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall adopt by rule and periodically review the disciplinary guidelines applicable to each ground for disciplinary action which may be imposed by the board, or the department if there is no board, pursuant to this chapter, the respective practice acts, and any rule of the board or department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disciplinary guidelines shall specify a meaningful range of designated penalties based upon the severity and repetition of specific offenses, it being the legislative intent that minor violations be distinguished from those which endanger the public health, safety, or welfare; that such guidelines provide reasonable and meaningful notice to the public of likely penalties which may be imposed for proscribed conduct; and that such penalties be consistently applied by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific finding in the final order of mitigating or aggravating circumstances shall allow the board to impose a penalty other than that provided for in such guidelines. If applicable, the board, or the department if there is no board, shall adopt by rule disciplinary guidelines to designate possible mitigating and aggravating circumstances and the variation and range of penalties permitted for such circumstances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must review such disciplinary guidelines for compliance with the legislative intent as set forth herein to determine whether the guidelines establish a meaningful range of penalties and may also challenge such rules pursuant to s. 120.56.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative law judge, in recommending penalties in any recommended order, must follow the penalty guidelines established by the board or department and must state in writing the mitigating or aggravating circumstances upon which the recommended penalty is based.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 70, ch. 97-261; s. 97, ch. 2000-160; s. 16, ch. 2001-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.627.</Text></Note></Section>