<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Treatment of Medicare beneficiaries; refusal, emergencies, consulting physicians.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective as of January 1, 1993, as used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a physician licensed under chapter 458, an osteopathic physician licensed under chapter 459, a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460, a podiatric physician licensed under chapter 461, or an optometrist licensed under chapter 463.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beneficiary” means a beneficiary of health insurance under Title XVIII of the federal Social Security Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consulting physician” means any physician to whom a primary physician refers a Medicare beneficiary for treatment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician may refuse to treat a beneficiary. However, nothing contained in this section shall be construed to limit a physician’s obligation under state or federal law to treat a patient for an emergency medical condition, regardless of the patient’s ability to pay.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If treatment is provided to a beneficiary for an emergency medical condition as defined in <Reference Number="1" />s. 395.0142(2)(c), the physician must accept Medicare assignment provided that the requirement to accept Medicare assignment for an emergency medical condition shall not apply to treatment rendered after the patient is stabilized, or the treatment is unrelated to the original emergency medical condition. For the purpose of this subsection “stabilized” is defined to mean with respect to an emergency medical condition, that no material deterioration of the condition is likely within reasonable medical probability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If treatment provided to a beneficiary is not for such emergency medical condition, and the primary physician accepts assignment, all consulting physicians must accept assignment unless the patient agrees in writing, before receiving the treatment, that the physician need not accept assignment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any attempt by a primary physician or a consulting physician to collect from a Medicare beneficiary any amount of charges for medical services in excess of those authorized under this section, other than the unmet deductible and the 20 percent of charges that Medicare does not pay, shall be deemed null, void, and of no merit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-118; s. 160, ch. 92-149; s. 89, ch. 97-261; ss. 192, 265, ch. 98-166; s. 78, ch. 2000-160.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency medical condition” is no longer defined in s. 395.0142, which was amended and transferred to s. 395.1041 by s. 24, ch. 92-289.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.2455; s. 455.691.</Text></Note></Section>