<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign-trained professionals; special examination and license provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When not otherwise provided by law, within its jurisdiction, the department shall by rule provide procedures under which exiled professionals may be examined within each practice act. A person shall be eligible for such examination if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immigrated to the United States after leaving the person’s home country because of political reasons, provided such country is located in the Western Hemisphere and lacks diplomatic relations with the United States;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applies to the department and submits a fee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was a Florida resident immediately preceding the person’s application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrates to the department, through submission of documentation verified by the applicant’s respective professional association in exile, that the applicant was graduated with an appropriate professional or occupational degree from a college or university; however, the department may not require receipt of any documentation from the Republic of Cuba as a condition of eligibility under this section;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lawfully practiced the profession for at least 3 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to 1980, successfully completed an approved course of study pursuant to chapters 74-105 and 75-177, Laws of Florida; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presents a certificate demonstrating the successful completion of a continuing education program which offers a course of study that will prepare the applicant for the examination offered under subsection (2). The department shall develop rules for the approval of such programs for its boards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of a person who meets the requirements of subsection (1) and submits an examination fee, the department, for its boards, shall provide a written practical examination which tests the person’s current ability to practice the profession competently in accordance with the actual practice of the profession. Evidence of meeting the requirements of subsection (1) shall be treated by the department as evidence of the applicant’s preparation in the academic and preprofessional fundamentals necessary for successful professional practice, and the applicant shall not be examined by the department on such fundamentals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees charged for the examinations offered under subsection (2) shall be established by the department, for its boards, by rule and shall be sufficient to develop or to contract for the development of the examination and its administration, grading, and grade reviews.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall examine any applicant who meets the requirements of subsections (1) and (2). Upon passing the examination and the issuance of the license, a licensee is subject to the administrative requirements of this chapter and the respective practice act under which the license is issued. Each applicant so licensed is subject to all provisions of this chapter and the respective practice act under which the license was issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a request by an applicant otherwise qualified under this section, the examinations offered under subsection (2) may be given in the applicant’s native language, provided that any translation costs are borne by the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, for its boards, shall not issue an initial license to, or renew a license of, any applicant or licensee who is under investigation or prosecution in any jurisdiction for an action which would constitute a violation of this chapter or the professional practice acts administered by the department and the boards until such time as the investigation or prosecution is complete, at which time the provisions of the professional practice acts shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 97-261; s. 52, ch. 2000-160.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.581.</Text></Note></Section>