<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that, absent a threat to the health, safety, and welfare of the public, the use of retired professionals in good standing to serve the indigent, underserved, or critical need populations of this state should be encouraged. To that end, the board, or the department when there is no board, may adopt rules to permit practice by retired professionals as limited licensees under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to obtain a limited license, when permitted by rule, shall submit to the board, or the department when there is no board, an application and fee, not to exceed $300, and an affidavit stating that the applicant has been licensed to practice in any jurisdiction in the United States for at least 10 years in the profession for which the applicant seeks a limited license. The affidavit shall also state that the applicant has retired or intends to retire from the practice of that profession and intends to practice only pursuant to the restrictions of the limited license granted pursuant to this section. If the applicant for a limited license submits a notarized statement from the employer stating that the applicant will not receive monetary compensation for any service involving the practice of her or his profession, the application and all licensure fees shall be waived.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department when there is no board, may deny limited licensure to an applicant who has committed, or is under investigation or prosecution for, any act which would constitute the basis for discipline pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or the applicable practice act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recipient of a limited license may practice only in the employ of public agencies or institutions or nonprofit agencies or institutions which meet the requirements of s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, and which provide professional liability coverage for acts or omissions of the limited licensee. A limited licensee may provide services only to the indigent, underserved, or critical need populations within the state. The standard for determining indigency shall be that recognized by the Federal Poverty Income Guidelines produced by the United States Department of Health and Human Services. The board, or the department when there is no board, may adopt rules to define underserved and critical need areas and to ensure implementation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board, or the department when there is no board, may provide by rule for supervision of limited licensees to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant granted a limited license is subject to all the provisions of this chapter and the respective practice act under which the limited license is issued which are not in conflict with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 50, ch. 97-261; s. 22, ch. 99-7; s. 47, ch. 2000-160.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.561.</Text></Note></Section>