<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0456.036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licenses; active and inactive status; delinquency.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee may practice a profession only if the licensee has an active status license. A licensee who practices a profession with an inactive status license, a retired status license, or a delinquent license is in violation of this section and s. 456.072, and the board, or the department if there is no board, may impose discipline on the licensee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall permit a licensee to choose, at the time of licensure renewal, an active, inactive, or retired status.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall by rule impose a fee for renewal of an active or inactive status license. The renewal fee for an inactive status license may not exceed the fee for an active status license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, a licensee may change licensure status at any time.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Active status licensees choosing inactive status at the time of license renewal must pay the inactive status renewal fee, and, if applicable, the delinquency fee and the fee to change licensure status. Active status licensees choosing inactive status at any other time than at the time of license renewal must pay the fee to change licensure status.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active status licensee or an inactive status licensee who chooses retired status at the time of license renewal must pay the retired status fee, which may not exceed $50 as established by rule of the board or the department if there is no board. An active status licensee or inactive status licensee who chooses retired status at any time other than at the time of license renewal must pay the retired status fee plus a change-of-status fee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inactive status licensee may change to active status at any time, if the licensee meets all requirements for active status. Inactive status licensees choosing active status at the time of license renewal must pay the active status renewal fee, any applicable reactivation fees as set by the board, or the department if there is no board, and, if applicable, the delinquency fee and the fee to change licensure status. Inactive status licensees choosing active status at any other time than at the time of license renewal must pay the difference between the inactive status renewal fee and the active status renewal fee, if any exists, any applicable reactivation fees as set by the board, or the department if there is no board, and the fee to change licensure status.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee must apply with a complete application, as defined by rule of the board, or the department if there is no board, to renew an active or inactive status license before the license expires. If a licensee fails to renew before the license expires, the license becomes delinquent in the license cycle following expiration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A delinquent licensee must affirmatively apply with a complete application, as defined by rule of the board, or the department if there is no board, for active or inactive status during the licensure cycle in which a licensee becomes delinquent. Failure by a delinquent licensee to become active or inactive before the expiration of the current licensure cycle renders the license null without any further action by the board or the department. Any subsequent licensure shall be as a result of applying for and meeting all requirements imposed on an applicant for new licensure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall by rule impose an additional delinquency fee, not to exceed the biennial renewal fee for an active status license, on a delinquent licensee when such licensee applies for active or inactive status.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall by rule impose an additional fee, not to exceed the biennial renewal fee for an active status license, for processing a licensee’s request to change licensure status at any time other than at the beginning of a licensure cycle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, may by rule impose reasonable conditions, excluding full reexamination but including part of a national examination or a special purpose examination to assess current competency, necessary to ensure that a licensee who has been on inactive status for more than two consecutive biennial licensure cycles and who applies for active status can practice with the care and skill sufficient to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the public. Reactivation requirements may differ depending on the length of time licensees are inactive. The costs to meet reactivation requirements shall be borne by licensees requesting reactivation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board, or the department if there is no board, may by rule impose reasonable conditions, including full reexamination to assess current competency, in order to ensure that a licensee who has been on retired status for more than 5 years, or a licensee from another state who has not been in active practice within the past 5 years, and who applies for active status is able to practice with the care and skill sufficient to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the public. Requirements for reactivation of a license may differ depending on the length of time a licensee has been retired.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before reactivation, an inactive status licensee or a delinquent licensee who was inactive prior to becoming delinquent must meet the same continuing education requirements, if any, imposed on an active status licensee for all biennial licensure periods in which the licensee was inactive or delinquent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the license of a retired status licensee is reactivated, the licensee must meet the same requirements for continuing education, if any, and pay any renewal fees imposed on an active status licensee for all biennial licensure periods during which the licensee was on retired status.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status or a change in status of a licensee does not alter in any way the right of the board, or of the department if there is no board, to impose discipline or to enforce discipline previously imposed on a licensee for acts or omissions committed by the licensee while holding a license, whether active, inactive, retired, or delinquent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been denied renewal of licensure, certification, or registration under s. 456.0635(3) may regain licensure, certification, or registration only by meeting the qualifications and completing the application process for initial licensure as defined by the board, or the department if there is no board. However, a person who was denied renewal of licensure, certification, or registration under s. 24, chapter 2009-223, Laws of Florida, between July 1, 2009, and June 30, 2012, is not required to retake and pass examinations applicable for initial licensure, certification, or registration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a business establishment registered, permitted, or licensed by the department to do business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department when there is no board, may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 as necessary to implement this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 95, ch. 97-261; s. 63, ch. 2000-160; s. 31, ch. 2000-318; s. 3, ch. 2005-62; s. 2, ch. 2012-64.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.711.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>