<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0456.039" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designated health care professionals; information required for licensure.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who applies for initial licensure as a physician under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461, except a person applying for registration pursuant to ss. 458.345 and 459.021, must, at the time of application, and each physician who applies for license renewal under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461, except a person registered pursuant to ss. 458.345 and 459.021, must, in conjunction with the renewal of such license and under procedures adopted by the Department of Health, and in addition to any other information that may be required from the applicant, furnish the following information to the Department of Health:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each medical school that the applicant has attended, with the dates of attendance and the date of graduation, and a description of all graduate medical education completed by the applicant, excluding any coursework taken to satisfy medical licensure continuing education requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each hospital at which the applicant has privileges.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address at which the applicant will primarily conduct his or her practice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any certification that the applicant has received from a specialty board that is recognized by the board to which the applicant is applying.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The year that the applicant began practicing medicine.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any appointment to the faculty of a medical school which the applicant currently holds and an indication as to whether the applicant has had the responsibility for graduate medical education within the most recent 10 years.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any criminal offense of which the applicant has been found guilty, regardless of whether adjudication of guilt was withheld, or to which the applicant has pled guilty or nolo contendere. A criminal offense committed in another jurisdiction which would have been a felony or misdemeanor if committed in this state must be reported. If the applicant indicates that a criminal offense is under appeal and submits a copy of the notice for appeal of that criminal offense, the department must state that the criminal offense is under appeal if the criminal offense is reported in the applicant’s profile. If the applicant indicates to the department that a criminal offense is under appeal, the applicant must, upon disposition of the appeal, submit to the department a copy of the final written order of disposition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any final disciplinary action taken within the previous 10 years against the applicant by the agency regulating the profession that the applicant is or has been licensed to practice, whether in this state or in any other jurisdiction, by a specialty board that is recognized by the American Board of Medical Specialties, the American Osteopathic Association, or a similar national organization, or by a licensed hospital, health maintenance organization, prepaid health clinic, ambulatory surgical center, or nursing home. Disciplinary action includes resignation from or nonrenewal of medical staff membership or the restriction of privileges at a licensed hospital, health maintenance organization, prepaid health clinic, ambulatory surgical center, or nursing home taken in lieu of or in settlement of a pending disciplinary case related to competence or character. If the applicant indicates that the disciplinary action is under appeal and submits a copy of the document initiating an appeal of the disciplinary action, the department must state that the disciplinary action is under appeal if the disciplinary action is reported in the applicant’s profile.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relevant professional qualifications as defined by the applicable board.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the information required under paragraph (a), each applicant who seeks licensure under chapter 458, chapter 459, or chapter 461, and who has practiced previously in this state or in another jurisdiction or a foreign country must provide the information required of licensees under those chapters pursuant to s. 456.049. An applicant for licensure under chapter 460 who has practiced previously in this state or in another jurisdiction or a foreign country must provide the same information as is required of licensees under chapter 458, pursuant to s. 456.049.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the issuance of the licensure renewal notice required by s. 456.038, the Department of Health shall send a notice to each person licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461, at the licensee’s last known address of record with the department, regarding the requirements for information to be submitted by those practitioners pursuant to this section in conjunction with the renewal of such license and under procedures adopted by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who has submitted information pursuant to subsection (1) must update that information in writing by notifying the Department of Health within 45 days after the occurrence of an event or the attainment of a status that is required to be reported by subsection (1). Failure to comply with the requirements of this subsection to update and submit information constitutes a ground for disciplinary action under each respective licensing chapter and s. 456.072(1)(k). For failure to comply with the requirements of this subsection to update and submit information, the department or board, as appropriate, may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse to issue a license to any person applying for initial licensure who fails to submit and update the required information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a citation to any licensee who fails to submit and update the required information and may fine the licensee up to $50 for each day that the licensee is not in compliance with this subsection. The citation must clearly state that the licensee may choose, in lieu of accepting the citation, to follow the procedure under s. 456.073. If the licensee disputes the matter in the citation, the procedures set forth in s. 456.073 must be followed. However, if the licensee does not dispute the matter in the citation with the department within 30 days after the citation is served, the citation becomes a final order and constitutes discipline. Service of a citation may be made by personal service or certified mail, restricted delivery, to the subject at the licensee’s last known address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for initial licensure must submit a set of fingerprints to the Department of Health in accordance with s. 458.311, s. 458.3115, s. 458.3124, s. 458.313, s. 459.0055, s. 460.406, or s. 461.006.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for renewed licensure must submit a set of fingerprints for the initial renewal of his or her license after January 1, 2000, to the agency regulating that profession in accordance with procedures established under s. 458.319, s. 459.008, s. 460.407, or s. 461.007.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall submit the fingerprints provided by an applicant for initial licensure to the Florida Department of Law Enforcement for a statewide criminal history check, and the Florida Department of Law Enforcement shall forward the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history check of the applicant. The department shall submit the fingerprints provided by an applicant for a renewed license to the Florida Department of Law Enforcement for a statewide criminal history check, and the Florida Department of Law Enforcement shall forward the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history check for the initial renewal of the applicant’s license after January 1, 2000; for any subsequent renewal of the applicant’s license, the department shall submit the required information for a statewide criminal history check of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who is required to submit information pursuant to this section may submit additional information. Such information may include, but is not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information regarding publications in peer-reviewed medical literature within the previous 10 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information regarding professional or community service activities or awards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Languages, other than English, used by the applicant to communicate with patients and identification of any translating service that may be available at the place where the applicant primarily conducts his or her practice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An indication of whether the person participates in the Medicaid program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 127, ch. 97-237; s. 3, ch. 97-273; ss. 8, 34, ch. 98-166; s. 60, ch. 99-397; s. 66, ch. 2000-160; s. 21, ch. 2000-318; s. 74, ch. 2001-62; s. 13, ch. 2003-416; s. 57, ch. 2010-114.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.565.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>