<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlicensed practice of a health care profession; intent; cease and desist notice; penalties; enforcement; citations; fees; allocation and disposition of moneys collected.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that vigorous enforcement of licensure regulation for all health care professions is a state priority in order to protect Florida residents and visitors from the potentially serious and dangerous consequences of receiving medical and health care services from unlicensed persons whose professional education and training and other relevant qualifications have not been approved through the issuance of a license by the appropriate regulatory board or the department when there is no board. The unlicensed practice of a health care profession or the performance or delivery of medical or health care services to patients in this state without a valid, active license to practice that profession, regardless of the means of the performance or delivery of such services, is strictly prohibited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalties for unlicensed practice of a health care profession shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department has probable cause to believe that any person not licensed by the department, or the appropriate regulatory board within the department, has violated any provision of this chapter or any statute that relates to the practice of a profession regulated by the department, or any rule adopted pursuant thereto, the department may issue and deliver to such person a notice to cease and desist from such violation. In addition, the department may issue and deliver a notice to cease and desist to any person who aids and abets the unlicensed practice of a profession by employing such unlicensed person. The issuance of a notice to cease and desist shall not constitute agency action for which a hearing under ss. 120.569 and 120.57 may be sought. For the purpose of enforcing a cease and desist order, the department may file a proceeding in the name of the state seeking issuance of an injunction or a writ of mandamus against any person who violates any provisions of such order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the remedies under paragraph (a), the department may impose by citation an administrative penalty not to exceed $5,000 per incident. The citation shall be issued to the subject and shall contain the subject’s name and any other information the department determines to be necessary to identify the subject, a brief factual statement, the sections of the law allegedly violated, and the penalty imposed. If the subject does not dispute the matter in the citation with the department within 30 days after the citation is served, the citation shall become a final order of the department. The department may adopt rules to implement this section. The penalty shall be a fine of not less than $500 nor more than $5,000 as established by rule of the department. Each day that the unlicensed practice continues after issuance of a notice to cease and desist constitutes a separate violation. The department shall be entitled to recover the costs of investigation and prosecution in addition to the fine levied pursuant to the citation. Service of a citation may be made by personal service or by mail to the subject at the subject’s last known address or place of practice. If the department is required to seek enforcement of the cease and desist or agency order, it shall be entitled to collect its attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to or in lieu of any other administrative remedy, the department may seek the imposition of a civil penalty through the circuit court for any violation for which the department may issue a notice to cease and desist. The civil penalty shall be no less than $500 and no more than $5,000 for each offense. The court may also award to the prevailing party court costs and reasonable attorney fees and, in the event the department prevails, may also award reasonable costs of investigation and prosecution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the administrative and civil remedies under paragraphs (b) and (c) and in addition to the criminal violations and penalties listed in the individual health care practice acts:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, to practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice a health care profession without an active, valid Florida license to practice that profession. Practicing without an active, valid license also includes practicing on a suspended, revoked, or void license, but does not include practicing, attempting to practice, or offering to practice with an inactive or delinquent license for a period of up to 12 months which is addressed in subparagraph 3. Applying for employment for a position that requires a license without notifying the employer that the person does not currently possess a valid, active license to practice that profession shall be deemed to be an attempt or offer to practice that health care profession without a license. Holding oneself out, regardless of the means of communication, as able to practice a health care profession or as able to provide services that require a health care license shall be deemed to be an attempt or offer to practice such profession without a license. The minimum penalty for violating this subparagraph shall be a fine of $1,000 and a minimum mandatory period of incarceration of 1 year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, to practice a health care profession without an active, valid Florida license to practice that profession when such practice results in serious bodily injury. For purposes of this section, “serious bodily injury” means death; brain or spinal damage; disfigurement; fracture or dislocation of bones or joints; limitation of neurological, physical, or sensory function; or any condition that required subsequent surgical repair. The minimum penalty for violating this subparagraph shall be a fine of $1,000 and a minimum mandatory period of incarceration of 1 year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, to practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice a health care profession with an inactive or delinquent license for any period of time up to 12 months. However, practicing, attempting to practice, or offering to practice a health care profession when that person’s license has been inactive or delinquent for a period of time of 12 months or more shall be a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. The minimum penalty for violating this subparagraph shall be a term of imprisonment of 30 days and a fine of $500.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because all enforcement costs should be covered by professions regulated by the department, the department shall impose, upon initial licensure and each licensure renewal, a special fee of $5 per licensee to fund efforts to combat unlicensed activity. Such fee shall be in addition to all other fees collected from each licensee. The department shall make direct charges to the Medical Quality Assurance Trust Fund by profession. The department shall seek board advice regarding enforcement methods and strategies. The department shall directly credit the Medical Quality Assurance Trust Fund, by profession, with the revenues received from the department’s efforts to enforce licensure provisions. The department shall include all financial and statistical data resulting from unlicensed activity enforcement as a separate category in the quarterly management report provided for in s. 456.025. For an unlicensed activity account, a balance which remains at the end of a renewal cycle may, with concurrence of the applicable board and the department, be transferred to the operating fund account of that profession. The department shall also use these funds to inform and educate consumers generally on the importance of using licensed health care practitioners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section apply only to health care professional practice acts administered by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein shall be construed to limit or restrict the sale, use, or recommendation of the use of a dietary supplement, as defined by the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, 21 U.S.C. s. 321, so long as the person selling, using, or recommending the dietary supplement does so in compliance with federal and state law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 73, ch. 97-261; s. 84, ch. 2000-160; s. 35, ch. 2000-318; s. 54, ch. 2001-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.637.</Text></Note></Section>