<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0456.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General background screening provisions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for initial licensure received on or after January 1, 2013, under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, chapter 464, or s. 465.022 shall include fingerprints pursuant to procedures established by the department through a vendor approved by the Department of Law Enforcement and fees imposed for the initial screening and retention of fingerprints. Fingerprints must be submitted electronically to the Department of Law Enforcement for state processing, and the Department of Law Enforcement shall forward the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for national processing. Each board, or the department if there is no board, shall screen the results to determine if an applicant meets licensure requirements. For any subsequent renewal of the applicant’s license that requires a national criminal history check, the department shall request the Department of Law Enforcement to forward the retained fingerprints of the applicant to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fingerprints submitted to the Department of Law Enforcement as required under subsection (1) shall be retained by the Department of Law Enforcement as provided under s. 943.05(2)(g) and (h) and (3). The department shall notify the Department of Law Enforcement regarding any person whose fingerprints have been retained but who is no longer licensed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of fingerprint processing, including the cost for retaining fingerprints, shall be borne by the applicant subject to the background screening.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2012-73.</History>
</Section>