<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Boards; organization; meetings; compensation and travel expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board within the department shall comply with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall annually elect from among its number a chairperson and vice chairperson.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall meet at least once annually and may meet as often as is necessary. Meetings shall be conducted through teleconferencing or other technological means, unless disciplinary hearings involving standard of care, sexual misconduct, fraud, impairment, or felony convictions; licensure denial hearings; or controversial rule hearings are being conducted; or unless otherwise approved in advance of the meeting by the director of the Division of Medical Quality Assurance. The chairperson or a quorum of the board shall have the authority to call meetings, except as provided above relating to in-person meetings. A quorum shall be necessary for the conduct of official business by the board or any committee thereof. Unless otherwise provided by law, 51 percent or more of the appointed members of the board or any committee, when applicable, shall constitute a quorum. The membership of committees of the board, except as otherwise authorized pursuant to this chapter or the applicable practice act, shall be composed of currently appointed members of the board. The vote of a majority of the members of the quorum shall be necessary for any official action by the board or committee. Three consecutive unexcused absences or absences constituting 50 percent or more of the board’s meetings within any 12-month period shall cause the board membership of the member in question to become void, and the position shall be considered vacant. The board, or the department when there is no board, shall, by rule, define unexcused absences.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided by law, a board member or former board member serving on a probable cause panel shall be compensated $50 for each day in attendance at an official meeting of the board and for each day of participation in any other business involving the board. Each board shall adopt rules defining the phrase “other business involving the board,” but the phrase may not routinely be defined to include telephone conference calls that last less than 4 hours. A board member also shall be entitled to reimbursement for expenses pursuant to s. 112.061. Travel out of state shall require the prior approval of the State Surgeon General.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When two or more boards have differences between them, the boards may elect to, or the State Surgeon General may request that the boards, establish a special committee to settle those differences. The special committee shall consist of three members designated by each board, who may be members of the designating board or other experts designated by the board, and of one additional person designated and agreed to by the members of the special committee. In the event the special committee cannot agree on the additional designee, upon request of the special committee, the State Surgeon General may select the designee. The committee shall recommend rules necessary to resolve the differences. If a rule adopted pursuant to this provision is challenged, the participating boards shall share the costs associated with defending the rule or rules. The department shall provide legal representation for any special committee established pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 43, ch. 97-261; s. 43, ch. 2000-160; s. 10, ch. 2001-277; s. 62, ch. 2008-6.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.534.</Text></Note></Section>