<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.063" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexual misconduct; disqualification for license, certificate, or registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual misconduct in the practice of a health care profession means violation of the professional relationship through which the health care practitioner uses such relationship to engage or attempt to engage the patient or client, or an immediate family member, guardian, or representative of the patient or client in, or to induce or attempt to induce such person to engage in, verbal or physical sexual activity outside the scope of the professional practice of such health care profession. Sexual misconduct in the practice of a health care profession is prohibited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board within the jurisdiction of the department, or the department if there is no board, shall refuse to admit a candidate to any examination and refuse to issue a license, certificate, or registration to any applicant if the candidate or applicant has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Had any license, certificate, or registration to practice any profession or occupation revoked or surrendered based on a violation of sexual misconduct in the practice of that profession under the laws of any other state or any territory or possession of the United States and has not had that license, certificate, or registration reinstated by the licensing authority of the jurisdiction that revoked the license, certificate, or registration; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committed any act in any other state or any territory or possession of the United States which if committed in this state would constitute sexual misconduct.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this subsection, a licensing authority’s acceptance of a candidate’s relinquishment of a license which is offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of administrative charges against the candidate’s license constitutes the surrender of the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed health care practitioners shall report allegations of sexual misconduct to the department, regardless of the practice setting in which the alleged sexual misconduct occurred.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-183; s. 52, ch. 97-261; s. 78, ch. 99-397; s. 82, ch. 2000-160; s. 25, ch. 2000-318; s. 70, ch. 2001-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.2142; s. 455.567.</Text></Note></Section>