<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0456.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practitioner disclosure of confidential information; immunity from civil or criminal liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practitioner regulated through the Division of Medical Quality Assurance of the department shall not be civilly or criminally liable for the disclosure of otherwise confidential information to a sexual partner or a needle-sharing partner under the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a patient of the practitioner who has tested positive for human immunodeficiency virus discloses to the practitioner the identity of a sexual partner or a needle-sharing partner;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practitioner recommends the patient notify the sexual partner or the needle-sharing partner of the positive test and refrain from engaging in sexual or drug activity in a manner likely to transmit the virus and the patient refuses, and the practitioner informs the patient of his or her intent to inform the sexual partner or needle-sharing partner; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If pursuant to a perceived civil duty or the ethical guidelines of the profession, the practitioner reasonably and in good faith advises the sexual partner or the needle-sharing partner of the patient of the positive test and facts concerning the transmission of the virus.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, any notification of a sexual partner or a needle-sharing partner pursuant to this section shall be done in accordance with protocols developed pursuant to rule of the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the foregoing, a practitioner regulated through the Division of Medical Quality Assurance of the department shall not be civilly or criminally liable for failure to disclose information relating to a positive test result for human immunodeficiency virus of a patient to a sexual partner or a needle-sharing partner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 43, ch. 88-380; s. 12, ch. 89-350; s. 191, ch. 97-103; s. 84, ch. 97-261; s. 220, ch. 99-8; s. 82, ch. 2000-160.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.2416; s. 455.674.</Text></Note></Section>