<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0456.037" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Business establishments; requirements for active status licenses; delinquency; discipline; applicability.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A business establishment regulated by the Division of Medical Quality Assurance pursuant to this chapter may provide regulated services only if the business establishment has an active status license. A business establishment that provides regulated services without an active status license is in violation of this section and s. 456.072, and the board, or the department if there is no board, may impose discipline on the business establishment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A business establishment must apply with a complete application, as defined by rule of the board, or the department if there is no board, to renew an active status license before the license expires. If a business establishment fails to renew before the license expires, the license becomes delinquent, except as otherwise provided in statute, in the license cycle following expiration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A delinquent business establishment must apply with a complete application, as defined by rule of the board, or the department if there is no board, for active status within 6 months after becoming delinquent. Failure of a delinquent business establishment to renew the license within the 6 months after the expiration date of the license renders the license null without any further action by the board or the department. Any subsequent licensure shall be as a result of applying for and meeting all requirements imposed on a business establishment for new licensure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status or a change in status of a business establishment license does not alter in any way the right of the board, or of the department if there is no board, to impose discipline or to enforce discipline previously imposed on a business establishment for acts or omissions committed by the business establishment while holding a license, whether active or null.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to any business establishment registered, permitted, or licensed by the department to do business. Business establishments include, but are not limited to, dental laboratories, electrology facilities, massage establishments, pharmacies, and pain-management clinics required to be registered under s. 458.3265 or s. 459.0137.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 89, ch. 99-397; s. 64, ch. 2000-160; s. 27, ch. 2000-318; s. 102, ch. 2000-349; s. 1, ch. 2010-211.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 455.712.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>