<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0273.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition of state-owned tangible personal property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified surplus property shall not be sold, transferred, cannibalized, scrapped, warehoused, or destroyed without prior written authority from the custodian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Custodians shall maintain records to identify each property item as to disposition. Such records shall comply with rules issued by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Custodians may dispose of property certified as surplus by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling or transferring the property to any other governmental entity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling or donating the property to any private nonprofit agency;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling the property through a sale open to the public; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entering into contractual agreements with other entities, including, but not limited to, other governmental agencies or private vendors, which facilitate the final disposition of the property. Such agreements may include, but are not limited to, the leasing of storage space or arrangements for the disposal of scrap property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each custodian shall adopt guidelines or administrative rules and regulations pursuant to chapter 120 providing for, but not limited to, transferring, warehousing, bidding, destroying, scrapping, or other disposing of state-owned tangible personal property. However, the approval of the Department of Management Services is required prior to the disposal of motor vehicles, watercraft, or aircraft pursuant to ss. 287.15 and 287.16.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received from the disposition of state-owned tangible personal property or from any agreement entered into under this chapter must be retained by the custodian and may be disbursed for the acquisition of exchange and surplus property and for all necessary operating expenditures. The custodian shall maintain records of the accounts into which the money is deposited.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 73-233; s. 52, ch. 79-190; s. 1, ch. 81-300; s. 217, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 28, ch. 94-226; s. 14, ch. 94-265; s. 57, ch. 98-279; s. 28, ch. 99-399; s. 40, ch. 2006-122.</History></Section>