<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0418.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing of ordinance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any ordinance creating or amending the charter of a recreation district, upon being finally adopted, shall be filed in the minutes of the governing body of the municipality or county, and certified copies thereof shall be filed with the county clerk of the county in which said district is located and with the property appraiser of said county. The charter of a recreation district may contain findings by the governing body of the municipality or county:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the creation of such district is the best alternative available for delivering recreational service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That such district is amenable to separate special district government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all of the territory in the district will be benefited by proposed improvements to be made by said district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, for recreation districts created for exclusive use by a condominium established pursuant to chapter 718 or a cooperative established under chapter 719, based upon the number of residents, potential for proliferation of crime, automobile traffic flow, district development, availability of other recreational facilities outside the district, excessive noise levels, or other factors applicable to the particular district, a valid and paramount public purpose will be served by making the recreational facilities available exclusively for district residents and property owners.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If such charter contains any one or more such findings, each such finding may be reviewed by a court only as part of any review of the ordinance making such finding.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 78-237; s. 26, ch. 94-350.</History></Section>