<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0418.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of recreation districts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The charter of a recreation district may grant to the recreation district the following powers and all further or additional powers as the governing body of the municipality or county establishing the district may deem necessary or useful in order to exercise the powers for which provision is hereinafter made. The powers which may be granted by such charter include the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued and to have a corporate seal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract and be contracted with.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire, purchase, construct, improve, and equip recreational facilities of all types, including real and personal property, within the boundaries of the district; such acquisition may be by purchase, lease, gift, or exercise of the power of eminent domain. If the governing body of the municipality or county that created the recreation district for exclusive use by a condominium established under chapter 718 or a cooperative established under chapter 719 makes the finding described in s. 418.24(4), the governing body of the district may make the recreational facilities available exclusively for district residents and property owners, and may restrict any access to recreational facilities by nonresidents by rules adopted by the governing body of the district. Prior to any vote of the electors in the district adopting or amending a charter pursuant to s. 418.20, the governing body shall decide whether the criteria in s. 418.24(4) apply and whether the recreation district shall be available exclusively for the district residents. The recreation district may construct and maintain security buildings and other structures needed to regulate access to, and provide security for, the recreational facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue bonds, secured by ad valorem taxes or by pledge of both such taxes and other revenues of the district, if approved at a referendum held in such district, and to levy and collect ad valorem taxes, without limitation or with such limitation as may be imposed by charter, on all real property subject to city taxation within such district in order to pay the principal of and interest on such bonds as the same respectively fall due or to accumulate a sinking fund for the payment of principal and interest. The referendum required by this section may be held on the same day as any other referendum related to the district; provided that such bonds shall bear interest at a rate pursuant to s. 215.84 and be sold at public sale. In the event an offer of an issue of bonds at public sale produces no bid, or in the event all bids received are rejected, the district is authorized to negotiate for the sale of such bonds under such rates and terms as are acceptable; provided that no such bonds shall be sold or delivered on terms less favorable than the terms contained in any bids rejected at the public sale thereof or the terms contained in the notice of public sale if no bids were received at such public sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To operate and maintain recreational facilities or to enter into arrangements with others for such operation and maintenance pursuant to contract, lease, or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish, charge, and collect fees for admission to or use of recreational facilities and to apply such fees to the operation, maintenance, improvement, enlargement, or acquisition of recreational facilities or to the payment of bonds or revenue bonds of the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue revenue bonds payable solely from the revenues to be derived from recreational facilities owned or operated by such district if approved at a referendum held in such district; provided that such bonds shall bear interest at a rate pursuant to s. 215.84 and be sold at public sale. In the event an offer of an issue of bonds at public sale produces no bid, or in the event all bids received are rejected, the district is authorized to negotiate for the sale of such bonds under such rates and terms as are acceptable; provided that no such bonds shall be so sold or delivered on terms less favorable than the terms contained in any bids rejected at the public sale thereof or the terms contained in the notice of public sale if no bids were received at such public sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt and enforce rules for the use of the recreational facilities owned or operated by the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To employ all personnel deemed necessary for the operation and maintenance of the facilities of the district.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 78-237; s. 29, ch. 83-215; s. 25, ch. 94-350.</History></Section>