<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0910.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer from county for plea and sentence.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INDICTMENT OR INFORMATION PENDING.<EmDash />A defendant arrested or held in a county other than that in which an indictment or information is pending against him or her may state in writing that he or she wishes to plead guilty or nolo contendere, to waive trial in the county in which the indictment or information is pending, and to consent to disposition of the case in the county in which the defendant was arrested or is held, subject to the approval of the prosecuting attorney of the court in which the indictment or information is pending. Upon receipt of the defendant’s statement and the written approval of the prosecuting attorney, the clerk of the court in which the indictment or information is pending shall transmit the papers in the proceeding, or certified copies thereof, to the clerk of the court of competent jurisdiction for the county in which the defendant is held, and the prosecution shall continue in that county upon the information or indictment originally filed. In the event a fine is imposed upon the defendant in that county, two-thirds thereof shall be returned to the county in which the indictment or information was originally filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INDICTMENT OR INFORMATION NOT PENDING.<EmDash />A defendant arrested on a warrant issued upon a complaint in a county other than the county of arrest may state in writing that he or she wishes to plead guilty or nolo contendere, to waive trial in the county in which the warrant was issued, and to consent to disposition of the case in the county in which the defendant was arrested, subject to the approval of the prosecuting attorney of the court in which the indictment or information is pending. Upon receipt of the defendant’s statement and the written approval of the prosecuting attorney, and upon the filing of an information or the return of an indictment, the clerk of the court from which the warrant was issued shall transmit the papers in the proceeding, or certified copies thereof, to the clerk of the court of competent jurisdiction in the county in which the defendant was arrested, and the prosecution shall continue in that county upon the information or indictment originally filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EFFECT OF NOT GUILTY PLEA.<EmDash />If, after the proceeding has been transferred pursuant to subsection (1) or subsection (2), the defendant pleads not guilty, the clerk shall return the papers to the court in which the prosecution was commenced, and the proceeding shall be restored to the docket of that court. The defendant’s statement that he or she wishes to plead guilty or nolo contendere shall not be used against the defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPEARANCE IN RESPONSE TO A SUMMONS.<EmDash />For the purpose of initiating a transfer under this section, a person who appears in response to a summons shall be treated as if he or she had been arrested on a warrant in the county of such appearance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person eligible for participation in a drug court treatment program pursuant to s. 948.08(6) may be eligible to have the case transferred to a county other than that in which the charge arose if the drug court program agrees and if the following conditions are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authorized representative of the drug court program of the county requesting to transfer the case shall consult with the authorized representative of the drug court program in the county to which transfer is desired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If approval for transfer is received from all parties, the trial court shall accept a plea of nolo contendere and enter a transfer order directing the clerk to transfer the case to the county which has accepted the defendant into its drug court program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer order shall include a copy of the probable cause affidavit; any charging documents in the case; all reports, witness statements, test results, evidence lists, and other documents in the case; the defendant’s mailing address and phone number; and the defendant’s written consent to abide by the rules and procedures of the receiving county’s drug court program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the transfer takes place, the clerk shall set the matter for a hearing before the drug court program judge and the court shall ensure the defendant’s entry into the drug court program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon successful completion of the drug court program, the jurisdiction to which the case has been transferred shall dispose of the case pursuant to s. 948.08(6). If the defendant does not complete the drug court program successfully, the jurisdiction to which the case has been transferred shall dispose of the case within the guidelines of the Criminal Punishment Code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-45; s. 1514, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 2001-48; s. 7, ch. 2006-97.</History></Section>