<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Beach management; funding; repair and maintenance strategy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to such appropriations as the Legislature may make therefor from time to time, disbursements from the Ecosystem Management and Restoration Trust Fund may be made by the department in order to carry out the proper state responsibilities in a comprehensive, long-range, statewide beach management plan for erosion control; beach preservation, restoration, and nourishment; and storm and hurricane protection. Legislative intent in appropriating such funds is for the implementation of those projects that contribute most significantly to addressing the state’s beach erosion problems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a multiyear repair and maintenance strategy that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourages regional approaches to ensure the geographic coordination and sequencing of prioritized projects;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduces equipment mobilization and demobilization costs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maximizes the infusion of beach-quality sand into the system;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extends the life of beach nourishment projects and reduces the frequency of nourishment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promotes inlet sand bypassing to replicate the natural flow of sand interrupted by improved, modified, or altered inlets and ports.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with the intent expressed in s. 161.088 and the legislative finding that erosion of the beaches of this state is detrimental to tourism, the state’s major industry, further exposes the state’s highly developed coastline to severe storm damage, and threatens beach-related jobs, which, if not stopped, may significantly reduce state sales tax revenues, funds deposited into the State Treasury to the credit of the Ecosystem Management and Restoration Trust Fund, in the annual amounts provided in s. 201.15, shall be used, for a period of not less than 15 years, to fund the development, implementation, and administration of the state’s beach management plan, as provided in ss. 161.091-161.212, prior to the use of such funds deposited pursuant to s. 201.15 in that trust fund for any other purpose.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-408; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-182; s. 1, ch. 72-170; ss. 1-3, ch. 74-102; s. 1, ch. 75-288; s. 1, ch. 77-379; s. 6, ch. 78-257; s. 5, ch. 80-183; s. 4, ch. 86-138; ss. 16, 23, ch. 87-97; s. 1, ch. 91-79; s. 4, ch. 96-321; s. 1, ch. 97-187; s. 2, ch. 98-311; s. 5, ch. 99-247; s. 8, ch. 2000-346; s. 2, ch. 2008-114.</History></Section>