<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coastal construction serving no public purpose, endangering human life, health, or welfare, or becoming unnecessary or undesirable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any coastal construction, or any structure including groins, jetties, moles, breakwaters, seawalls, revetments, or other structures if of a solid or highly impermeable design upon sovereignty lands of Florida, below the mean high-water line of any tidal water of the state, regardless of date of construction or whether a permit has been issued in accordance with this part, which serves no public purpose, which is dangerous to or in any way endangers human life, health, or welfare, or which proves to be undesirable or becomes unnecessary, as determined by the department, shall be adjusted, altered, or removed by the abutting upland property owner after written notice by the division. Request for hearing must be filed by the owner with the department within 15 days after such notice. Adjustments, alterations, or removals required by this section shall be accomplished at no cost to the state. The decision of the department as to whether to adjust, alter, or remove such coastal construction or structure shall be final, and the department shall set a reasonable time within which the adjustment, alteration, or removal shall be accomplished.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the upland property owner does not adjust, alter, or remove any coastal construction, or other structure including groins, jetties, moles, breakwaters, seawalls, revetments, or other structures if of a solid or highly impermeable design upon sovereignty lands of Florida, below the mean high-water line, when requested or directed by the department in accordance with subsection (1) of this section, the department may alter, adjust, or remove such coastal construction or structures at its own expense, and the costs thereof shall become a lien upon the property of said abutting upland property owner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-408; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 23, ch. 78-95; s. 23, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>