<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.38" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners, for and on behalf of each or any district created in accordance with this part, is authorized to provide from time to time for the issuance of bonds to obtain funds to meet the costs of the beach and shore preservation program; provided, however, that such issuance shall have first been approved at a duly conducted referendum election by freeholders within the subject district as provided for by law. The bonds of each issue shall be dated, shall bear interest at rates not to exceed 7.5 percent which mature at such time not to exceed 40 years from the date of issuance as determined by the board of county commissioners, and at the option of the board of county commissioners may be made redeemable before maturity under such terms and conditions and at such prices as fixed by the board of county commissioners prior to issuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners shall determine the form of such bonds, including any interest coupons to be attached thereto, the denomination of the bonds, and the place of payment of principal and interest which may be at any bank or trust company within or without the state.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resolution authorizing the issue may further provide that such bonds may be executed manually or by engraved, lithographed or facsimile signature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate seal may be affixed or lithographed, engraved or otherwise reproduced in facsimile on such bonds and shall be attested by the manual or facsimile signature of the county clerk; provided, however, that at least one of the signatures of executing officials on the bonds shall be manual. Signatures, manual or facsimile, of executing officials shall continue to be valid for all purposes whatsoever regardless of whether or not signing officials are still in office at the time bonds are actually delivered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be issued in coupon or registered form as the board of county commissioners may decide and provision may be made for the registration of any coupon bonds as to principal alone or as to principal and interest, and for the reconversion of coupon bonds or any bond registered as to principal and interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No sale of bonds shall be made at a price so low as to require the payment of interest on money received therefor at a rate in excess of 6 percent per annum, computed with relation to the absolute maturity of the bonds in accordance with standard tables of bond values, excluding from such computation, however, the amount of any premium to be paid for the redemption of any bonds prior to maturity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the preparation or issuance of definitive bonds, the board of county commissioners may under like restrictions issue interim receipts or temporary notes or other forms of such temporary obligations with or without coupons, exchangeable for definitive bonds when such bonds have been executed and are available for delivery. Such bonds may be issued under the provisions of this part without obtaining the consent of any commission, board, bureau or agency of this state, and without any other proceeding or happening than specifically required by this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All bonds issued under this part shall constitute, and have all the qualities and incidents of, negotiable instruments under the law merchant and the negotiable instruments law of Florida, and shall not be invalid for any irregularity or defect in the proceedings for the issuance and sale thereof and shall be incontestable in the hands of bona fide purchasers for value.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this part shall constitute an irrevocable contract between the board of county commissioners and the holders of such bonds or coupons thereof issued pursuant to the provisions hereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder of such bonds issued under the provisions of this part, and the trustee under any trustee agreement, except to the extent the rights herein given may be restricted by such trust agreement, may either at law or in equity, by suit, action, or mandamus, force and compel the performance of the duties required by this part or of any of the officers or persons herein mentioned in relation to said bonds, or the levy, assessment, collection and enforcement and application of the taxes pledged for the principal and interest thereof as provided for in s. 161.37.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued under the provisions of this part shall not be subject to the consent or approval of any state board, commission, or agency, but such bonds shall be validated in accordance with the provisions of chapter 75.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-408; s. 11, ch. 73-302; s. 5, ch. 80-98.</History></Section>