<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.57" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coastal properties disclosure statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that it is necessary to ensure that the purchasers of interests in real property located in coastal areas partially or totally seaward of the coastal construction control line as defined in s. 161.053 are fully apprised of the character of the regulation of the real property in such coastal areas and, in particular, that such lands are subject to frequent and severe fluctuations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At or prior to the time a seller and a purchaser both execute a contract for sale and purchase of any interest in real property located partially or totally seaward of the coastal construction control line as defined in s. 161.053, the seller must give a written disclosure statement in the following form to the prospective purchaser which may be set forth in the contract or in a separate writing:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The property being purchased may be subject to coastal erosion and to federal, state, or local regulations that govern coastal property, including the delineation of the coastal construction control line, rigid coastal protection structures, beach nourishment, and the protection of marine turtles. Additional information can be obtained from the Florida Department of Environmental Protection, including whether there are significant erosion conditions associated with the shoreline of the property being purchased.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise waived in writing by the purchaser, at or prior to the closing of any transaction where an interest in real property located either partially or totally seaward of the coastal construction control line as defined in s. 161.053 is being transferred, the seller shall provide to the purchaser an affidavit, or a survey meeting the requirements of chapter 472, delineating the location of the coastal construction control line on the property being transferred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A seller’s failure to deliver the disclosure, affidavit, or survey required by this section does not impair the enforceability of the sale and purchase contract by either party, create any right of rescission by the purchaser, or impair the title to any such real property conveyed by the seller to the purchaser.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 85-55; s. 22, ch. 87-224; s. 1, ch. 2006-273.</History></Section>