<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.088" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Declaration of public policy respecting beach erosion control and beach restoration and nourishment projects.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because beach erosion is a serious menace to the economy and general welfare of the people of this state and has advanced to emergency proportions, it is hereby declared to be a necessary governmental responsibility to properly manage and protect Florida beaches fronting on the Atlantic Ocean, Gulf of Mexico, and Straits of Florida from erosion and that the Legislature make provision for beach restoration and nourishment projects, including inlet management projects that cost-effectively provide beach-quality material for adjacent critically eroded beaches. The Legislature declares that such beach restoration and nourishment projects, as approved pursuant to s. 161.161, are in the public interest; must be in an area designated as critically eroded shoreline, or benefit an adjacent critically eroded shoreline; must have a clearly identifiable beach management benefit consistent with the state’s beach management plan; and must be designed to reduce potential upland damage or mitigate adverse impacts caused by improved, modified, or altered inlets, coastal armoring, or existing upland development. Given the extent of the problem of critically eroded beaches, it is also declared that beach restoration and nourishment projects shall be funded in a manner that encourages all cost-saving strategies, fosters regional coordination of projects, improves the performance of projects, and provides long-term solutions. The Legislature further declares that nothing herein is intended to reduce or amend the beach protection programs otherwise established in this chapter or to result in local governments altering the coastal management elements of their local government comprehensive plans pursuant to chapter 163.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-138; s. 1, ch. 98-311; s. 7, ch. 2000-346.</History></Section>