<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0161.212" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial review relating to permits and licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any official, officer, commission, authority, council, committee, department, division, bureau, board, section, or other unit or entity of state government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permit” means any permit or license required by this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person substantially affected by a final action of any agency with respect to a permit may seek review within 90 days of the rendering of such decision and request monetary damages and other relief in the circuit court in the judicial circuit in which the affected property is located; however, circuit court review shall be confined solely to determining whether final agency action is an unreasonable exercise of the state’s police power constituting a taking without just compensation. Review of final agency action for the purpose of determining whether the action is in accordance with existing statutes or rules and based on competent substantial evidence shall proceed in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court determines the decision reviewed is an unreasonable exercise of the state’s police power constituting a taking without just compensation, the court shall remand the matter to the agency which shall, within a reasonable time:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree to issue the permit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree to pay appropriate monetary damages; however, in determining the amount of compensation to be paid, consideration shall be given by the court to any enhancement to the value of the land attributable to governmental action; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree to modify its decision to avoid an unreasonable exercise of police power.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall submit a statement of its agreed-upon action to the court in the form of a proposed order. If the action is a reasonable exercise of police power, the court shall enter its final order approving the proposed order. If the agency fails to submit a proposed order within a reasonable time not to exceed 90 days which specifies an action that is a reasonable exercise of police power, the court may order the agency to perform any of the alternatives specified in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs to the agency or substantially affected person, whichever prevails.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are cumulative and shall not be deemed to abrogate any other remedies provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 78-85.</History></Section>