<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Domicile” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 631.011, the “domicile” of an insurer means:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to Canadian insurers, Canada and the province under the laws of which the insurer was formed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to other alien insurers authorized to transact insurance in one or more states, the state designated by the insurer in writing filed with the office at the time of admission to this state or within 6 months after the effective date of this code, whichever date is the later, and may be any of the following states:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That in which the insurer was first authorized to transact insurance if the insurer is still so authorized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That in which is located the insurer’s principal place of business in the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That in which is held the larger deposit of trusteed assets of the insurer for the protection of its policyholders and creditors in the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the insurer makes no such designation, its domicile shall be deemed to be that state in which is located its principal place of business in the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to alien insurers not authorized to transact insurance in one or more states, the country under the laws of which the insurer was formed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to all other insurers, the state under the laws of which the insurer was formed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 15, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 2, ch. 82-386; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 752, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>