<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.444" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension, revocation of approval.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall deny, suspend, or revoke an arrangement’s certificate of authority if it finds that the arrangement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is insolvent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is using such methods and practices in the conduct of its business as to render its further transaction of business in this state hazardous or injurious to its participating employers, covered employees and dependents, or to the public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to pay any final judgment rendered against it in this state within 60 days after the judgment became final;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in violation of any provision of this chapter, including any requirements for the granting of a certificate of authority;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is no longer actuarially sound or the arrangement does not have the minimum surplus required by this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existing contract rates are inadequate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in its discretion, deny, suspend, or revoke the certificate of authority of any arrangement if it finds that the arrangement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any lawful order or rule of the office or commission or any applicable provision of the Florida Insurance Code; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has refused to be examined or to produce its accounts, records, and files for examination, or if any of its officers have refused to give information with respect to its affairs or to perform any other legal obligation as to such examination, when required by the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the financial condition of the arrangement is such that, if not modified or corrected, its continued operation would result in impairment or insolvency, the department may order the arrangement to file with the office and implement a corrective action plan designed to do one or more of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the total amount of present potential liability for benefits by reinsurance or other means.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the volume of new business being accepted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the expenses of the arrangement by specified methods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspend or limit the writing of new business for a specified period of time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require an increase in the arrangement’s net worth.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the arrangement fails to submit a plan within 30 days after the office’s order, or if the plan submitted is insufficient to correct the arrangement’s financial condition, the office may order the arrangement to implement one or more of the corrective actions specified in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any order to suspend the authority of an arrangement to enroll new subscribers, the office shall specify the period during which the suspension is to be in effect and the conditions, if any, which must be met by the arrangement prior to reinstatement of its authority to enroll new subscribers. The order of suspension is subject to rescission or modification by further order of the office prior to the expiration of the suspension period. An arrangement’s authority to enroll new subscribers shall not be reinstated unless it requests reinstatement, and shall not be reinstated if the office finds that the circumstances that gave rise to the suspension still exist.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 85-212; s. 1, ch. 86-286; ss. 38, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 820, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>