<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0624.4095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Premiums written; restrictions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever an insurer’s ratio of actual or projected annual written premiums as adjusted in accordance with subsection (4) to current or projected surplus as to policyholders as adjusted in accordance with subsection (6) exceeds 10 to 1 for gross written premiums or exceeds 4 to 1 for net written premiums, the office shall suspend the insurer’s certificate of authority or establish by order maximum gross or net annual premiums to be written by the insurer consistent with maintaining the ratios specified herein unless the insurer demonstrates to the office’s satisfaction that exceeding the ratios of this section does not endanger the financial condition of the insurer or endanger the interests of the insurer’s policyholders.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projected annual net or gross premiums shall be based on the actual writings to date for the insurer’s current calendar year or the insurer’s writings for the previous calendar year or both. Ratios shall be computed on an annualized basis.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, gross premiums written means direct premiums written and reinsurance assumed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, for the calendar year ending December 31, 1990, and each subsequent year, premiums shall be calculated as the product of the actual or projected premiums and the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For property insurance, 0.90.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For casualty insurance, 1.25.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For health insurance, 0.80.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other kinds of insurance, 1.00.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life insurance written by life or life and health insurers; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life and health insurers which have a surplus as to policyholders greater than $40 million and which have written health insurance during each of the immediately preceding five calendar years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, surplus as to policyholders for life and health insurers shall be calculated as follows: (actual or projected surplus as to policyholders) minus (surplus as to policyholders required to be maintained under s. 624.408 for liabilities relating to life insurance).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of ss. 624.407 and 624.408 and this section, with regard to capital and surplus required, gross written premiums for federal multiple-peril crop insurance that is ceded to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and authorized reinsurers shall not be included when calculating the insurer’s gross writing ratio. The liabilities for ceded reinsurance premiums payable for federal multiple-peril crop insurance ceded to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and authorized reinsurers shall be netted against the asset for amounts recoverable from reinsurers. Each insurer that writes other insurance products together with federal multiple-peril crop insurance shall disclose in the notes to the annual and quarterly financial statement, or file a supplement to the financial statement that discloses, a breakout of the gross written premiums for federal multiple-peril crop insurance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 85-245; s. 1, ch. 86-286; s. 27, ch. 89-360; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 788, ch. 2003-261; ss. 7, 9, ch. 2011-7; HJR 7103, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
</Section>