<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.472" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Member’s liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The liability of each member other than a governmental entity for the obligations of the commercial self-insurance fund unrelated to governmental entities shall be individual, several, and proportionate, but not joint, except as provided in this section and s. 624.474. Nothing herein shall preclude a governmental entity from being a member of a fund established pursuant to this part. However, the liability of each governmental entity member shall be limited to the obligations of the commercial self-insurance fund related to governmental entities only and shall be individual, several, and proportionate, but not joint, except as provided in this section and s. 624.474.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the limitations of subsection (1), each member shall have a contingent assessment liability for payment of actual losses and expenses incurred while her or his policy was in force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each policy issued by the fund shall contain a statement of the contingent liability. Both the application for insurance and the policy shall contain, in contrasting color and in not less than 10-point type, the following statements: “This is a fully assessable policy. In the event the fund is unable to pay its obligations, policyholders will be required to contribute on a pro rata earned premium basis the money necessary to meet any unfilled obligations.” In lieu of the notice provided for above, a fund with governmental entity members shall provide the following notice to members other than governmental entities: “This is a fully assessable policy. In the event the fund is unable to pay its obligations related to members which are not governmental entities, the policyholders which are not governmental entities will be required to contribute on a pro rata earned premium basis the money necessary to meet any such unfilled obligations.” A fund with governmental entity members shall provide the following notice to governmental entity members: “This is a fully assessable policy. In the event the fund is unable to pay its obligations related to governmental entity members, governmental entity policyholders will be required to contribute on a pro rata earned premium basis the money necessary to meet any such unfilled obligations.” If the application is signed by the applicant, it must be conclusively presumed that there was an informed, knowing acceptance of the assessment liability that exists as a result of participation in the fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 86-160; s. 1, ch. 89-247; s. 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 92-328; s. 189, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>