<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.4094" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bail bond premiums.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that a significant portion of bail bond premiums is retained by the licensed bail bond agents or licensed managing general agents. For purposes of reporting in financial statements required to be filed with the office pursuant to s. 624.424, direct written premiums for bail bonds by a domestic insurer in this state shall be reported net of any amounts retained by licensed bail bond agents or licensed managing general agents. However, in no case shall the direct written premiums for bail bonds be less than 6.5 percent of the total consideration received by the agent for all bail bonds written by the agent. This subsection also applies to any determination of compliance with s. 624.4095.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums assumed by a domestic insurer shall be reported consistent with subsections (1) and (4) for purposes of filing financial statements with the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic bail bond insurer shall keep complete and accurate records of the total consideration paid for all bail bonds written by such insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic bail bond insurer shall disclose the following information in the notes to the financial statement in the insurer’s annual statement filed with the office.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gross bail bond premiums written in each state by agents for the company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of premium taxes incurred by the company in each state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total consideration withheld by agents and not reported as an expense by the insurer in financial statements filed with the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of bail bond premium included on the surety line of the annual statement filed with the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the reporting or payment of insurance premium taxes under ss. 624.509, 624.5091, and 624.5092, and the insurance premium tax and related excise taxes shall continue to be calculated using gross bail bond premiums.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-126; s. 787, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>