<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.1265" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonprofit religious organization exemption; authority; notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonprofit religious organization is not subject to the requirements of the Florida Insurance Code if the nonprofit religious organization qualifies under Title 26, s. 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended; limits its participants to members of the same religion; acts as an organizational clearinghouse for information between participants who have financial, physical, or medical needs and participants who have the ability to pay for the benefit of those participants who have financial, physical, or medical needs; provides for the financial or medical needs of a participant through payments directly from one participant to another participant; and suggests amounts that participants may voluntarily give with no assumption of risk or promise to pay among the participants or between the participants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prevent the organization described in subsection (1) from establishing qualifications of participation relating to the health of a prospective participant, does not prevent a participant from limiting the financial or medical needs that may be eligible for payment, and does not prevent the organization from canceling the membership of a participant when such participant indicates his or her unwillingness to participate by failing to make a payment to another participant for a period in excess of 60 days.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The religious organization described in subsection (1) shall provide each prospective participant in the organizational clearinghouse written notice that the organization is not an insurance company, that membership is not offered through an insurance company, and that the organization is not subject to the regulatory requirements or consumer protections of the Florida Insurance Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2008-32.</History></Section>