<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority of Department of Law Enforcement to accept fingerprints of, and exchange criminal history records with respect to, certain persons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement may accept fingerprints of organizers, incorporators, subscribers, officers, stockholders, directors, or any other persons involved, directly or indirectly, in the organization, operation, or management of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer or proposed insurer transacting or proposing to transact insurance in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other entity which is examined or investigated or which is eligible to be examined or investigated under the provisions of the Florida Insurance Code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement may accept fingerprints of individuals who apply for a license as an agent, customer representative, adjuster, service representative, or managing general agent or the fingerprints of the majority owner, sole proprietor, partners, officers, and directors of a corporation or other legal entity that applies for licensure with the department or office under the provisions of the Florida Insurance Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement may, to the extent provided for by federal law, exchange state, multistate, and federal criminal history records with the department or office for the purpose of the issuance, denial, suspension, or revocation of a certificate of authority, certification, or license to operate in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement may accept fingerprints of any other person required by statute or rule to submit fingerprints to the department or office or any applicant or licensee regulated by the department or office who is required to demonstrate that he or she has not been convicted of or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a misdemeanor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall, upon receipt of fingerprints from the department or office, submit the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation to check federal criminal history records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Statewide criminal records obtained through the Department of Law Enforcement, federal criminal records obtained through the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and local criminal records obtained through local law enforcement agencies shall be used by the department and office for the purpose of issuance, denial, suspension, or revocation of certificates of authority, certifications, or licenses issued to operate in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-131; s. 1, ch. 86-286; s. 3, ch. 88-166; s. 191, ch. 90-363; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 780, ch. 2003-261; s. 15, ch. 2003-267; s. 8, ch. 2003-281.</History></Section>