<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.416" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuance, expiration, reinstatement, and amendment of certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of authority issued under this code shall continue in force as long as the insurer is entitled thereto under this code and until suspended, revoked, or terminated at the request of the insurer; subject, however, to continuance of the certificate by the insurer each year by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment prior to June 1 of the annual license tax provided for in s. 624.501(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Due filing by the insurer of its annual statement for the calendar year preceding as required under s. 624.424; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment by the insurer of applicable taxes with respect to the preceding calendar year as required under this code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If not so continued by the insurer, its certificate of authority shall expire at midnight on the May 31 next following such failure of the insurer so to continue it in force. The office shall promptly notify the insurer of the occurrence of any failure resulting in impending expiration of its certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in its discretion, reinstate a certificate of authority which the insurer has inadvertently permitted to expire, after the insurer has fully cured all its failures which resulted in the expiration, and upon payment by the insurer of the fee for reinstatement, in the amount provided in s. 624.501(1)(b). Otherwise, the insurer shall be granted another certificate of authority only after filing application therefor and meeting all other requirements as for an original certificate of authority in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may amend a certificate of authority at any time to accord with changes in the insurer’s charter or insuring powers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 60, ch. 59-205; s. 1, ch. 63-149; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 51, 64, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 19, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 796, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>