<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.468" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuing requirements for certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After issuance of its initial certificate of authority a commercial self-insurance fund shall thereafter meet the following requirements as a condition of maintaining its certificate of authority:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of competent and trustworthy persons to service the program, as further specified in s. 624.466(7). Written notice shall be provided to the office before changing the fund’s method of fulfilling its servicing requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of a risk management program as further specified in s. 624.466(6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of a deposit of cash or securities in the amount of $100,000, or a surety bond in lieu thereof, as further specified in s. 624.466(9).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of excess insurance in accordance with sound actuarial principles, unless waived by the office, as further specified in s. 624.466(10).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of a fidelity bond, as further specified in s. 624.466(11).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of appropriate funded loss reserves determined in accordance with sound actuarial principles satisfactory to the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any self-insurance fund which holds a certificate of authority on or after January 1, 1998, shall maintain surplus to policyholders in a positive amount.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each fund shall have and maintain its principal place of business in this state and shall therein make available to the office upon reasonable notice complete records of its assets, transactions, and affairs in accordance with such methods and systems as are customary for, or suitable to, the kind or kinds of business transacted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fund shall file such reports with the office as are required by s. 624.470.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fund shall report to the office within 15 days of a determination that the actual premiums written or liability assumed or any other factor which substantially contributes to the financial condition of the plan deviates by more than 25 percent from the projections used in the most recent annual report, as required by s. 624.470 or, if the first annual report has not yet been filed, projections used in the initial plan of operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of the annual license tax provided for in s. 624.501(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fund shall maintain records which will confirm that membership in the fund is in accordance with the constitution or bylaws of the association as required by s. 624.462(3). The office may request from the fund, not more than annually, a certification which confirms that all members of the fund are members of the association and are in compliance with the constitution or bylaws of the association and may require that the fund submit a plan, acceptable to the office, to eliminate membership that does not comply with s. 624.462(3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 86-160; s. 15, ch. 90-249; s. 5, ch. 90-366; s. 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 12, ch. 95-211; s. 5, ch. 97-262; s. 828, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>