<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.413" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To apply for a certificate of authority, an insurer shall file its application therefor with the office, upon a form adopted by the commission and furnished by the office, showing its name; location of its home office and, if an alien insurer, its principal office in the United States; kinds of insurance to be transacted; state or country of domicile; and such additional information as the commission reasonably requires, together with the following documents:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One copy of its corporate charter, articles of incorporation, existing and proposed nonfacultative reinsurance contracts, declaration of trust, or other charter documents, with all amendments thereto, certified by the public official with whom the originals are on file in the state or country of domicile.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mutual insurer, a copy of its bylaws, as amended, certified by its secretary or other officer having custody thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign or alien reciprocal insurer, a copy of the power of attorney of its attorney in fact and of its subscribers’ agreement, if any, certified by the attorney in fact; and, if a domestic reciprocal insurer, the declaration provided for in s. 629.081.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of its financial statement as of December 31 next preceding, containing information generally included in insurer financial statements prepared in accordance with generally accepted insurance accounting principles and practices and in a form generally utilized by insurers for financial statements, sworn to by at least two executive officers of the insurer, or certified by the public official having supervision of insurance in the insurer’s state of domicile or of entry into the United States. To facilitate uniformity in financial statements, the commission may by rule adopt the form for financial statements approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners in 2002, and may adopt subsequent amendments thereto if the form remains substantially consistent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supplemental quarterly financial statements for each calendar quarter since the beginning of the year of its application for the certificate of authority, sworn to by at least two of its executive officers. To facilitate uniformity in financial statements, the commission may by rule adopt the form for quarterly financial statements approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners in 2002, and may adopt subsequent amendments thereto if the form remains substantially consistent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign or alien insurer, a copy of the report of the most recent examination of the insurer certified by the public official having supervision of insurance in its state of domicile or of entry into the United States. The end of the most recent year covered by the examination must be within the 3-year period preceding the date of application. In lieu of the certified examination report, the office may accept an audited certified public accountant’s report prepared on a basis consistent with the insurance laws of the insurer’s state of domicile, certified by the public official having supervision of insurance in its state of domicile or of entry into the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign or alien insurer, a certificate of compliance from the public official having supervision of insurance in its state or country of domicile showing that it is duly organized and authorized to transact insurance therein and the kinds of insurance it is so authorized to transact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign or alien insurer, a certificate of the public official having custody of any deposit maintained by the insurer in another state in lieu of a deposit or part thereof required in this state under s. 624.411 or s. 624.412, showing the amount of such deposit and the assets or securities of which comprised.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a life insurer, a certificate of valuation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an alien insurer, a copy of the appointment and authority of its United States manager, certified by its officer having custody of its records.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be accompanied by the applicable fees and license tax as specified in s. 624.501.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 49, 64, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 6, ch. 85-245; s. 30, ch. 89-360; ss. 18, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 792, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>