<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.5092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of taxes; payments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall administer, audit, and enforce the assessment and collection of those taxes to which this section is applicable. The office and department may share information with the Department of Revenue as necessary to verify premium tax or other tax liability arising under such taxes and credits which may apply thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Installments of the taxes to which this section is applicable shall be due and payable on April 15, June 15, and October 15 in each year, based upon the estimated gross amount of receipts of insurance premiums or assessments received during the immediately preceding calendar quarter. A final payment of tax due for the year shall be made at the time the taxpayer files her or his return for such year. On or before March 1 in each year, an annual return shall be filed showing, by quarters, the gross amount of receipts taxable for the preceding year and the installment payments made during that year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any taxpayer who fails to report and timely pay any installment of tax, who estimates any installment of tax to be less than 90 percent of the amount finally shown to be due in any quarter, or who fails to report and timely pay any tax due with the final return is in violation of this section and is subject to a penalty of 10 percent on any underpayment of taxes or delinquent taxes due and payable for that quarter or on any delinquent taxes due and payable with the final return. Any taxpayer paying, for each installment required in this section, 27 percent of the amount of the net tax due as reported on her or his return for the preceding year shall not be subject to the penalty provided by this section for underpayment of estimated taxes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any taxpayer fails to pay any amount due under this section, or any portion thereof, on or before the day when such tax or installment of tax is required by law to be paid, there shall be added to the amount due interest at the rate of 12 percent per year from the date due until paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All penalties and interest imposed on those taxes to which this section is applicable shall be payable to and collectible by the Department of Revenue in the same manner as if they were a part of the tax imposed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may settle or compromise any such interest or penalties imposed on those taxes to which this section is applicable pursuant to s. 213.21.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is applicable to taxes imposed by ss. 624.4621, 624.475, 624.509-624.515, 627.357, 629.5011, and 636.066.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 89-167; s. 45, ch. 90-132; s. 4, ch. 92-318; s. 4, ch. 93-128; s. 55, ch. 93-148; s. 22, ch. 93-233; s. 15, ch. 95-211; s. 196, ch. 97-102; s. 16, ch. 99-3; s. 845, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>