<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records; reproductions; destruction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, the department, commission, and office shall each preserve in permanent form records of its proceedings, hearings, investigations, and examinations and shall file such records in its office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records of insurance claim negotiations of any state agency or political subdivision are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) until termination of all litigation and settlement of all claims arising out of the same incident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, commission, and office may each photograph, microphotograph, or reproduce on film, or maintain in an electronic recordkeeping system, all financial records, financial statements of domestic insurers, reports of business transacted in this state by foreign insurers and alien insurers, reports of examination of domestic insurers, and such other records and documents on file in its office as it may in its discretion select.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate the efficient use of floor space and filing equipment in its offices, the department, commission, and office may each destroy the following records and documents pursuant to chapter 257:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General closed correspondence files over 3 years old;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agent, adjuster, and similar license files, including license files of the Division of State Fire Marshal, over 2 years old; except that the department or office shall preserve by reproduction or otherwise a copy of the original records upon the basis of which each such licensee qualified for her or his initial license, except a competency examination, and of any disciplinary proceeding affecting the licensee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All agent, adjuster, and similar license files and records, including original license qualification records and records of disciplinary proceedings 5 years after a licensee has ceased to be qualified for a license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurer certificate of authority files over 2 years old, except that the office shall preserve by reproduction or otherwise a copy of the initial certificate of authority of each insurer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All documents and records which have been photographed or otherwise reproduced as provided in subsection (3), if such reproductions have been filed and an audit of the department or office has been completed for the period embracing the dates of such documents and records; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other records, documents, and files not expressly provided for in paragraphs (a)-(e).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 79-52; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 23, 37, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 41, ch. 83-215; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-78; s. 10, ch. 95-211; s. 364, ch. 96-406; s. 1720, ch. 97-102; s. 44, ch. 2002-206; s. 765, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2004-335.</History></Section>