<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.317" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigation of agents, adjusters, administrators, service companies, and others.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating any provision of this code, or upon the written complaint signed by any interested person indicating that any such violation may exist:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct such investigation as it deems necessary of the accounts, records, documents, and transactions pertaining to or affecting the insurance affairs of any general agent, surplus lines agent, adjuster, managing general agent, insurance agent, insurance agency, customer representative, service representative, or other person subject to its jurisdiction, subject to the requirements of s. 626.601.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall conduct such investigation as it deems necessary of the accounts, records, documents, and transactions pertaining to or affecting the insurance affairs of any:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrator, service company, or other person subject to its jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Person having a contract or power of attorney under which she or he enjoys in fact the exclusive or dominant right to manage or control an insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Person engaged in or proposing to be engaged in the promotion or formation of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic insurer;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurance holding corporation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation to finance a domestic insurer or in the production of the domestic insurer’s business.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-55; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 27, 37, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 1, ch. 83-203; ss. 10, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 179, ch. 97-102; s. 72, ch. 2003-1; s. 772, ch. 2003-261; s. 14, ch. 2003-267; s. 7, ch. 2003-281; s. 16, ch. 2004-390; s. 1, ch. 2005-257.</History></Section>