<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.129" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain location and recovery services; exemption from code.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may, in exchange for fees, dues, charges, or other consideration, not exceeding $300 annually (adjusted for increases in the Consumer Price Index after 1994) for each covered individual, provide services involving the registration of natural persons and related services identified in this section concerning the location and recovery of natural persons who are lost, missing, or abducted, without being deemed an insurer and without being subject to the provisions of this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the following shall be considered services related to the registration of natural persons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining, compiling, storing, and retrieving biographical, statistical, pictorial, and similar information regarding natural persons desiring such services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing educational, preventive, or remedial information or assistance relating to the possibility of natural persons being or becoming missing, lost, or abducted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contacting, assisting, or obtaining assistance from law enforcement officials, organizations concerned with missing persons, or the media regarding the search for and location and recovery of a natural person reported missing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing or arranging to provide investigative, psychological, or social services and assistance in connection with the search for and location and recovery of a natural person reported missing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the discretion of the provider and as part of its investigative or search methods, offering a reward (but not a ransom) for information leading to the location or recovery of a natural person who is lost, missing, or abducted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written agreement or enrollment form used by the provider of such services for subscribers in this state shall contain a conspicuous legend to the effect that the services are not regulated by either the department or the office as insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person soliciting, offering, providing, entering into, issuing, or delivering an agreement for services under this section, without being deemed an insurer and without being subject to this code pursuant to subsection (1), shall, as to any such agreement, be subject to the provisions of the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act, part II of chapter 501.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 95-335; s. 756, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>