<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department; annual report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As early as reasonably possible, the office, with such assistance from the department as requested, shall annually prepare a report to the Speaker and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the President and Minority Leader of the Senate, the chairs of the legislative committees with jurisdiction over matters of insurance, and the Governor showing, with respect to the preceding calendar year:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Names of the authorized insurers transacting insurance in this state, with abstracts of their financial statements including assets, liabilities, and net worth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Names of insurers whose business was closed during the year, the cause thereof, and amounts of assets and liabilities as ascertainable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Names of insurers against which delinquency or similar proceedings were instituted, and a concise statement of the circumstances and results of each such proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The receipts and estimated expenses of the office for the year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other pertinent information and matters as the office deems to be in the public interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually after each regular session of the Legislature, a compilation of the laws of this state relating to insurance. Any such publication may be printed, revised, or reprinted upon the basis of the original low bid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis and summary report of the state of the insurance industry in this state evaluated as of the end of the most recent calendar year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall maintain the following information and make such information available upon request:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calendar year profitability, including investment income from policyholders’ unearned premium and loss reserves (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aggregate Florida loss reserves.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums written (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums earned (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incurred losses (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paid losses (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allocated Florida loss adjustment expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Renewal ratio (countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Variation of premiums charged by the industry as compared to rates promulgated by the Insurance Services Office (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of policy size limits (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insureds’ selection of claims-made versus occurrence coverage (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subreport on the involuntary market in Florida encompassing such joint underwriting plans and assigned risk plans operating in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subreport providing information relevant to emerging markets and alternate marketing mechanisms, such as self-insured trusts, risk retention groups, purchasing groups, and the excess-surplus lines market.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trends; emerging trends as exemplified by the percentage change in frequency and severity of both paid and incurred claims, and pure premium (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fast track loss ratios as defined and assimilated by the Insurance Services Office (Florida and countrywide).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may contract with outside vendors, in accordance with chapter 287, to compile data in an electronic data processing format that is compatible with the systems of the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 13, ch. 77-468; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 37, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 5, ch. 82-386; s. 1, ch. 88-390; s. 1, ch. 90-119; ss. 7, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 178, ch. 97-102; s. 769, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>