<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.609" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limit of risk.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No insurer shall retain any risk on any one subject of insurance, either as the direct insurer or the reinsurer, whether located or to be performed in this state or elsewhere, in an amount exceeding 10 percent of its surplus to policyholders, except as provided in subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “subject of insurance” for the purposes of this section, as to insurance against fire and hazards other than windstorm, earthquake, or other catastrophic hazards, includes all properties insured by the same insurer which are customarily considered by underwriters to be subject to loss or damage from the same fire or the same occurrence of such other hazard insured against.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reinsurance ceded as authorized by s. 624.610 shall be deducted in determining risk retained. As to surety risks, a deduction shall also be made of the amount assumed by any established incorporated cosurety and the value of any security deposited, pledged, or held subject to the surety’s consent and for the surety’s protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to alien insurers, other than insurers domiciled in Canada, this section relates only to risks and surplus to policyholders of the insurer’s United States branch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to fire insurance covering risks adequately protected by automatic sprinklers or risks principally of noncombustible construction and occupancy, the insurer may retain risk as to any one such subject of insurance in an amount not exceeding 25 percent of the sum of its unearned premium reserve applicable to property insurance policies and its surplus to policyholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surplus to policyholders” for the purposes of this section, in addition to the insurer’s capital and surplus, shall be deemed to include any voluntary reserves which are not required pursuant to law and shall be determined from the last sworn statement of the insurer on file with the office, or by the last report of examination of the insurer, whichever is the more recent at time of assumption of risk.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to life insurance, health insurance, annuity contracts, title insurance, insurance of wet marine and transportation insurance risks, workers’ compensation insurance, or employers’ liability coverages or to any policy or type of coverage as to which the maximum possible loss to the insurer is not readily ascertainable on issuance of the policy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 107, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 85, ch. 79-40; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 84, 86, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 36, ch. 89-360; ss. 184, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 854, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>