<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.322" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Testimony compelled; immunity from prosecution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any natural person asks to be excused from attending or testifying or from producing any books, papers, records, contracts, documents, or other evidence in connection with any examination, hearing, or investigation being conducted by the department, commission, or office or its examiner, on the ground that the testimony or evidence required of her or him may tend to incriminate the person or subject her or him to a penalty or forfeiture, and shall notwithstanding be directed to give such testimony or produce such evidence, the person must, if so directed by the department, commission, or office and the Department of Legal Affairs, nonetheless comply with such direction; but she or he shall not thereafter be prosecuted or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture for or on account of any transaction, matter, or thing concerning which she or he may have so testified or produced evidence; and no testimony so given or evidence produced shall be received against the person upon any criminal action, investigation, or proceeding. However, no such person so testifying shall be exempt from prosecution or punishment for any perjury committed by her or him in such testimony, and the testimony or evidence so given or produced shall be admissible against her or him upon any criminal action, investigation, or proceeding concerning such perjury. No license or permit conferred or to be conferred to such person shall be refused, suspended, or revoked based upon the use of such testimony.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such individual may execute, acknowledge, and file with the department, commission, or office, as appropriate, a statement expressly waiving such immunity or privilege in respect to any transaction, matter, or thing specified in such statement; and thereupon the testimony of such individual or such evidence in relation to such transaction, matter, or thing may be received or produced before any judge or justice, court, tribunal, grand jury, or otherwise; and, if so received or produced, such individual shall not be entitled to any immunity or privileges on account of any testimony she or he may so give or evidence so produced.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 59-205; ss. 11, 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 32, 37, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 182, ch. 97-102; s. 777, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>