<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.606" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Surety insurance” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surety insurance” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract bond, including a bid, payment, or maintenance bond, or a performance bond, which guarantees the execution of a contract other than a contract of indebtedness or other monetary obligation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An indemnity bond for the benefit of a public body, railroad, or charitable organization or a lost security or utility payment bond;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Becoming surety on, or guaranteeing the performance of, any lawful contract where the bond is guaranteeing the execution of a contract other than a contract of indebtedness or other monetary obligation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Becoming surety on, or guaranteeing the performance of, bonds and undertakings required or permitted in a judicial proceeding or otherwise allowed by law, including surety bonds accepted by states and municipal authorities in lieu of deposits as security for the performance of insurance contracts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fidelity insurance as defined in s. 624.6065 for the purposes of the Florida Insurance Code other than part XX of chapter 627; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residual value insurance as defined in s. 624.6081.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surety insurance” does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mortgage guaranty insurance, as defined in s. 635.011;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial guaranty insurance, as defined in s. 627.971; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any reinsurance contract authorized pursuant to s. 624.610.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 104, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 86, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 3, ch. 88-87; ss. 184, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 1, ch. 91-110; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 17, ch. 95-211.</History></Section>