<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.482" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Making and use of rates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to all classes of insurance which a self-insurance fund underwrites, the rates must not be excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory. In determining what rates, including credits and surcharges, are excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory, the office shall apply the same standards applicable to other insurers regulated by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rate shall be held to be excessive if the expense factors associated with the rate are not justified or are not reasonable for the benefits and services provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rates shall be deemed inadequate if they are clearly insufficient, together with the investment income attributable to them, to sustain projected losses and expenses in the class of business to which they apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rate shall be deemed inadequate as to the premium charged to a risk or group of risks if discounts or credits are allowed which exceed a reasonable reflection of expense savings and reasonably expected loss experience from the risk or group of risks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office determines that the continued use of a rate for a coverage endangers the solvency of the fund, it may issue an order requiring the rate to be increased or requiring the fund to limit or cease writing the coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fund shall have the burden of proving that a rate filed is adequate if, during the first 5 years of issuing policies, the fund files a rate that is below the rate for loss and loss adjustment expenses for the same type and classification of insurance that has been filed by the Insurance Services Office and approved by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit the office from examining a fund pursuant to s. 624.3161.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A self-insurance fund shall file its rates, including credits and surcharge schedules, with the office for approval pursuant to the standards of this section and the procedures of s. 624.480(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any self-insurance fund may subscribe to, or be a member of, a rating organization as prescribed in s. 627.231. A rating organization may not discriminate against a self-insurance fund as to conditions of subscription or membership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any self-insurance fund that writes workers’ compensation insurance and employer’s liability insurance is subject to, and shall make all rate filings for workers’ compensation insurance and employer’s liability insurance in accordance with, ss. 627.091, 627.101, 627.111, 627.141, 627.151, 627.171, 627.191, and 627.211.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 86-160; s. 1, ch. 87-124; s. 8, ch. 91-106; ss. 42, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 87, ch. 93-415; s. 835, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>