<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil remedy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may bring a civil action against an insurer when such person is damaged:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a violation of any of the following provisions by the insurer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 626.9541(1)(i), (o), or (x);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 626.9551;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 626.9705;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 626.9706;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 626.9707; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 627.7283.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the commission of any of the following acts by the insurer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not attempting in good faith to settle claims when, under all the circumstances, it could and should have done so, had it acted fairly and honestly toward its insured and with due regard for her or his interests;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making claims payments to insureds or beneficiaries not accompanied by a statement setting forth the coverage under which payments are being made; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as to liability coverages, failing to promptly settle claims, when the obligation to settle a claim has become reasonably clear, under one portion of the insurance policy coverage in order to influence settlements under other portions of the insurance policy coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding the provisions of the above to the contrary, a person pursuing a remedy under this section need not prove that such act was committed or performed with such frequency as to indicate a general business practice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any party may bring a civil action against an unauthorized insurer if such party is damaged by a violation of s. 624.401 by the unauthorized insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition precedent to bringing an action under this section, the department and the authorized insurer must have been given 60 days’ written notice of the violation. If the department returns a notice for lack of specificity, the 60-day time period shall not begin until a proper notice is filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be on a form provided by the department and shall state with specificity the following information, and such other information as the department may require:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statutory provision, including the specific language of the statute, which the authorized insurer allegedly violated.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facts and circumstances giving rise to the violation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of any individual involved in the violation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reference to specific policy language that is relevant to the violation, if any. If the person bringing the civil action is a third party claimant, she or he shall not be required to reference the specific policy language if the authorized insurer has not provided a copy of the policy to the third party claimant pursuant to written request.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the notice is given in order to perfect the right to pursue the civil remedy authorized by this section.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 20 days of receipt of the notice, the department may return any notice that does not provide the specific information required by this section, and the department shall indicate the specific deficiencies contained in the notice. A determination by the department to return a notice for lack of specificity shall be exempt from the requirements of chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action shall lie if, within 60 days after filing notice, the damages are paid or the circumstances giving rise to the violation are corrected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authorized insurer that is the recipient of a notice filed pursuant to this section shall report to the department on the disposition of the alleged violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicable statute of limitations for an action under this section shall be tolled for a period of 65 days by the mailing of the notice required by this subsection or the mailing of a subsequent notice required by this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon adverse adjudication at trial or upon appeal, the authorized insurer shall be liable for damages, together with court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the plaintiff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No punitive damages shall be awarded under this section unless the acts giving rise to the violation occur with such frequency as to indicate a general business practice and these acts are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful, wanton, and malicious;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In reckless disregard for the rights of any insured; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In reckless disregard for the rights of a beneficiary under a life insurance contract.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who pursues a claim under this subsection shall post in advance the costs of discovery. Such costs shall be awarded to the authorized insurer if no punitive damages are awarded to the plaintiff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed to authorize a class action suit against an authorized insurer or a civil action against the commission, the office, or the department or any of their employees, or to create a cause of action when an authorized health insurer refuses to pay a claim for reimbursement on the ground that the charge for a service was unreasonably high or that the service provided was not medically necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of expressed language to the contrary, this section shall not be construed to authorize a civil action or create a cause of action against an authorized insurer or its employees who, in good faith, release information about an insured or an insurance policy to a law enforcement agency in furtherance of an investigation of a criminal or fraudulent act relating to a motor vehicle theft or a motor vehicle insurance claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The civil remedy specified in this section does not preempt any other remedy or cause of action provided for pursuant to any other statute or pursuant to the common law of this state. Any person may obtain a judgment under either the common-law remedy of bad faith or this statutory remedy, but shall not be entitled to a judgment under both remedies. This section shall not be construed to create a common-law cause of action. The damages recoverable pursuant to this section shall include those damages which are a reasonably foreseeable result of a specified violation of this section by the authorized insurer and may include an award or judgment in an amount that exceeds the policy limits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A surety issuing a payment or performance bond on the construction or maintenance of a building or roadway project is not an insurer for purposes of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 78, ch. 83-216; s. 2, ch. 83-288; s. 2, ch. 86-262; s. 1, ch. 87-278; s. 1, ch. 88-166; s. 30, ch. 90-119; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 176, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 2003-148; s. 757, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2005-218.</History></Section>