<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Fire Marshal regulatory assessment and surcharge; levy and amount.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other license or excise tax now or hereafter imposed, and such taxes as may be imposed under other statutes, there is hereby assessed and imposed upon every domestic, foreign, and alien insurer authorized to engage in this state in the business of issuing policies of fire insurance, a regulatory assessment in an amount equal to 1 percent of the gross amount of premiums collected by each such insurer on policies of fire insurance issued by it and insuring property in this state. The assessment shall be payable annually on or before March 1 to the Department of Revenue by the insurer on such premiums collected by it during the preceding calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When it is impractical, due to the nature of the business practices within the insurance industry, to determine the percentage of fire insurance contained within a line of insurance written by an insurer on risks located or resident in Florida, the Department of Revenue may establish by rule such percentages for the industry. The Department of Revenue may also amend the percentages as the insurance industry changes its practices concerning the portion of fire insurance within a line of insurance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every insurer authorized to transact insurance in this state shall collect, in addition to the applicable premium charge, an annual surcharge from each holder of a policy of fire, allied lines, or multiperil insurance insuring commercial property located in this state. The surcharge shall be imposed at a rate of .1 percent on the gross direct premium written on commercial property located in this state. The surcharge shall be remitted by the insurer to the Department of Revenue pursuant to s. 624.5092.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “fire insurance” means the insurance of structures or other property at fixed locations against loss or damage to such structures or other described properties from the risks of fire and lightning; and the terms “policies” and “premiums” respectively mean and include those policies or other contracts or agreements effecting and evidencing insurance, and premiums and other considerations for such policies, of the same character as described in and contemplated by the provisions of ss. 624.509 and 624.510. As used in this section, “allied lines” means the insurance of structures or other property against loss or damage to such structures or other properties from the risks of tornado, windstorm, hail, sprinkler or water damage, explosion, riot or civil commotion, flood, rain, and damage from aircraft or vehicle. The amount of such premiums upon which the regulatory assessment shall be computed by each such insurer shall be the amount thereof remaining after deducting therefrom those items described in and permitted by s. 624.509(1) relating to the premium receipts tax thereby imposed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 87, ch. 59-205; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-207; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-237; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 12, ch. 89-233; s. 8, ch. 92-324; s. 28, ch. 98-342; s. 2, ch. 2000-333.</History></Section>