<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0624.91" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “William G. ‘Doc’ Myers Healthy Kids Corporation Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that increased access to health care services could improve children’s health and reduce the incidence and costs of childhood illness and disabilities among children in this state. Many children do not have comprehensive, affordable health care services available. It is the intent of the Legislature that the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation provide comprehensive health insurance coverage to such children. The corporation is encouraged to cooperate with any existing health service programs funded by the public or the private sector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation serve as one of several providers of services to children eligible for medical assistance under Title XXI of the Social Security Act. Although the corporation may serve other children, the Legislature intends the primary recipients of services provided through the corporation be school-age children with a family income below 200 percent of the federal poverty level, who do not qualify for Medicaid. It is also the intent of the Legislature that state and local government Florida Healthy Kids funds be used to continue coverage, subject to specific appropriations in the General Appropriations Act, to children not eligible for federal matching funds under Title XXI.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY FOR STATE-FUNDED ASSISTANCE.<EmDash />Only the following individuals are eligible for state-funded assistance in paying Florida Healthy Kids premiums:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residents of this state who are eligible for the Florida Kidcare program pursuant to s. 409.814.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 409.814, legal aliens who are enrolled in the Florida Healthy Kids program as of January 31, 2004, who do not qualify for Title XXI federal funds because they are not qualified aliens as defined in s. 409.811.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NONENTITLEMENT.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed as providing an individual with an entitlement to health care services. No cause of action shall arise against the state, the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, or a unit of local government for failure to make health services available under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CORPORATION AUTHORIZATION, DUTIES, POWERS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, a not-for-profit corporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrange for the collection of any family, local contributions, or employer payment or premium, in an amount to be determined by the board of directors, to provide for payment of premiums for comprehensive insurance coverage and for the actual or estimated administrative expenses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrange for the collection of any voluntary contributions to provide for payment of Florida Kidcare program premiums for children who are not eligible for medical assistance under Title XIX or Title XXI of the Social Security Act.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of s. 409.8134, accept voluntary supplemental local match contributions that comply with the requirements of Title XXI of the Social Security Act for the purpose of providing additional Florida Kidcare coverage in contributing counties under Title XXI.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the administrative and accounting procedures for the operation of the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish, with consultation from appropriate professional organizations, standards for preventive health services and providers and comprehensive insurance benefits appropriate to children, provided that such standards for rural areas shall not limit primary care providers to board-certified pediatricians.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine eligibility for children seeking to participate in the Title XXI-funded components of the Florida Kidcare program consistent with the requirements specified in s. 409.814, as well as the non-Title-XXI-eligible children as provided in subsection (3).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures under which providers of local match to, applicants to and participants in the program may have grievances reviewed by an impartial body and reported to the board of directors of the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish participation criteria and, if appropriate, contract with an authorized insurer, health maintenance organization, or third-party administrator to provide administrative services to the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish enrollment criteria that include penalties or waiting periods of 30 days for reinstatement of coverage upon voluntary cancellation for nonpayment of family premiums.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with authorized insurers or any provider of health care services, meeting standards established by the corporation, for the provision of comprehensive insurance coverage to participants. Such standards shall include criteria under which the corporation may contract with more than one provider of health care services in program sites. Health plans shall be selected through a competitive bid process. The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall purchase goods and services in the most cost-effective manner consistent with the delivery of quality medical care. The maximum administrative cost for a Florida Healthy Kids Corporation contract shall be 15 percent. For health care contracts, the minimum medical loss ratio for a Florida Healthy Kids Corporation contract shall be 85 percent. For dental contracts, the remaining compensation to be paid to the authorized insurer or provider under a Florida Healthy Kids Corporation contract shall be no less than an amount which is 85 percent of premium; to the extent any contract provision does not provide for this minimum compensation, this section shall prevail. The health plan selection criteria and scoring system, and the scoring results, shall be available upon request for inspection after the bids have been awarded.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish disenrollment criteria in the event local matching funds are insufficient to cover enrollments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement a plan to publicize the Florida Kidcare program, the eligibility requirements of the program, and the procedures for enrollment in the program and to maintain public awareness of the corporation and the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure staff necessary to properly administer the corporation. Staff costs shall be funded from state and local matching funds and such other private or public funds as become available. The board of directors shall determine the number of staff members necessary to administer the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consultation with the partner agencies, provide a report on the Florida Kidcare program annually to the Governor, the Chief Financial Officer, the Commissioner of Education, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Minority Leaders of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information on a quarterly basis to the Legislature and the Governor which compares the costs and utilization of the full-pay enrolled population and the Title XXI-subsidized enrolled population in the Florida Kidcare program. The information, at a minimum, must include:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The monthly enrollment and expenditure for full-pay enrollees in the Medikids and Florida Healthy Kids programs compared to the Title XXI-subsidized enrolled population; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs and utilization by service of the full-pay enrollees in the Medikids and Florida Healthy Kids programs and the Title XXI-subsidized enrolled population.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">By February 1, 2010, the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall provide a study to the Legislature and the Governor on premium impacts to the subsidized portion of the program from the inclusion of the full-pay program, which shall include recommendations on how to eliminate or mitigate possible impacts to the subsidized premiums.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish benefit packages that conform to the provisions of the Florida Kidcare program, as created in ss. 409.810-409.821.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage under the corporation’s program is secondary to any other available private coverage held by, or applicable to, the participant child or family member. Insurers under contract with the corporation are the payors of last resort and must coordinate benefits with any other third-party payor that may be liable for the participant’s medical care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall be a private corporation not for profit, organized pursuant to chapter 617, and shall have all powers necessary to carry out the purposes of this act, including, but not limited to, the power to receive and accept grants, loans, or advances of funds from any public or private agency and to receive and accept from any source contributions of money, property, labor, or any other thing of value, to be held, used, and applied for the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD OF DIRECTORS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall operate subject to the supervision and approval of a board of directors chaired by the Chief Financial Officer or her or his designee, and composed of 12 other members selected for 3-year terms of office as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration, or his or her designee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member appointed by the Commissioner of Education from the Office of School Health Programs of the Florida Department of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member appointed by the Chief Financial Officer from among three members nominated by the Florida Pediatric Society.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Governor, who represents the Children’s Medical Services Program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member appointed by the Chief Financial Officer from among three members nominated by the Florida Hospital Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Governor, who is an expert on child health policy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Chief Financial Officer, from among three members nominated by the Florida Academy of Family Physicians.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Governor, who represents the state Medicaid program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Chief Financial Officer, from among three members nominated by the Florida Association of Counties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Health Officer or her or his designee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Children and Family Services, or his or her designee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member, appointed by the Governor, from among three members nominated by the Florida Dental Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the board of directors may be removed by the official who appointed that member. The board shall appoint an executive director, who is responsible for other staff authorized by the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members are entitled to receive, from funds of the corporation, reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided by s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no cause of action shall arise against, any member of the board of directors, or its employees or agents, for any action they take in the performance of their powers and duties under this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSING NOT REQUIRED; FISCAL OPERATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall not be deemed an insurer. The officers, directors, and employees of the corporation shall not be deemed to be agents of an insurer. Neither the corporation nor any officer, director, or employee of the corporation is subject to the licensing requirements of the insurance code or the rules of the Department of Financial Services. However, any marketing representative utilized and compensated by the corporation must be appointed as a representative of the insurers or health services providers with which the corporation contracts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board has complete fiscal control over the corporation and is responsible for all corporate operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Financial Services shall supervise any liquidation or dissolution of the corporation and shall have, with respect to such liquidation or dissolution, all power granted to it pursuant to the insurance code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-199; s. 1, ch. 91-188; s. 30, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 93-78; s. 21, ch. 93-129; s. 1, ch. 96-337; s. 368, ch. 96-406; s. 28, ch. 96-418; s. 9, ch. 96-420; s. 1722, ch. 97-102; s. 8, ch. 97-153; s. 54, ch. 98-288; s. 5, ch. 99-357; s. 20, ch. 2001-377; s. 32, ch. 2002-400; s. 14, ch. 2002-404; s. 21, ch. 2003-405; s. 6, ch. 2004-1; s. 20, ch. 2004-270; s. 84, ch. 2006-1; s. 18, ch. 2006-2; s. 23, ch. 2006-28; s. 7, ch. 2008-32; s. 3, ch. 2008-146; s. 1, ch. 2009-41; s. 13, ch. 2009-113; s. 119, ch. 2010-5; s. 1, ch. 2012-42.</History>
</Section>