<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.470" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every self-insurance fund shall, annually within 3 months of the end of the fiscal year, file a financial statement of the fund, including its balance sheet and a statement of operations for the preceding year, verified by the oath of a member of the board of trustees or by an administrative executive appointed by the board. An entry for future investment income, reported on or after January 1, 1998, may only be reflected as an aggregate write-in asset on the balance sheet of the annual and quarterly financial statements. Future investment income shall be calculated as the sum of the admitted asset value of Line 1 (Bonds) plus the admitted asset value of Line 6 (Cash and Short-Term Investments) as reported on page 2 in the annual or quarterly financial statement, times the 3-year treasury note yield as of the date of the financial statement, times 3.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For financial statements filed on or after January 1, 1998, future investment income may only be reported as an admitted asset by an Assessable Mutual or Self-Insurance Fund which reported future investment income in financial statements filed with the <Reference Number="1" />Department of Insurance prior to January 1, 1998.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every fund shall, annually within 6 months of the end of the fiscal year, file a report with the office verified by the oath of a member of the board of trustees or by an administrative executive appointed by the board, containing the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial statement of the fund, including its balance sheet and a statement of operations for the preceding year certified by an independent certified public accountant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report prepared by an actuary who is a member of the American Academy of Actuaries as to the actuarial soundness of the fund. The report shall consist of, but shall not be limited to, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequacy of premiums or contributions in paying claims and changes, if any, needed in the contribution rates to achieve or preserve a level of funding deemed adequate, which shall include a valuation of present assets, based on statement value, and prospective assets and liabilities of the plan and the extent of any unfunded accrued liabilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan to amortize any unfunded liabilities and a description of actions taken to reduce unfunded liabilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description and explanation of actuarial assumptions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A schedule illustrating the amortization of any unfunded liabilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A comparative review illustrating the level of funds available to the commercial self-insurance fund from rates, investment income, and other sources realized over the period covered by the report, indicating the assumptions used.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A projection of the following year’s plan of operation, including additional number of members, gross premiums to be written, and projected liabilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by the actuary that the report is complete and accurate and that in her or his opinion the techniques and assumptions used are reasonable and meet the requirements of this subsection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other factors or statements as may be reasonably required by the office or commission in order to determine the actuarial soundness of the plan.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any changes in the constitution, bylaws, or trust agreement of the fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 86-160; s. 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 188, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 97-262; s. 829, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duties of the Department of Insurance were transferred to the Department of Financial Services or the Financial Services Commission by ch. 2002-404, and s. 20.13, creating the Department of Insurance, was repealed by s. 3, ch. 2003-1.</Text></Note></Section>