<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insurer” means and includes every person as defined in s. 624.03 as limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any domestic or commercially domiciled insurer who is doing business as an insurer, or has transacted insurance in this state, and against whom claims arising from that transaction may exist now or in the future.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any specialty insurer as that term is defined in s. 628.4615.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any domestic or commercially domiciled fraternal benefit society which is subject to the provisions of chapter 632.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unsound condition” means that the office has determined that one or more of the following conditions exist with respect to an insurer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer’s required surplus, capital, or capital stock is impaired to an extent prohibited by law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer continues to write new business when it has not maintained the required surplus or capital;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer attempts to dissolve or liquidate without first having made provisions, satisfactory to the office, for liabilities arising from insurance policies issued by the insurer; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer meets one or more of the grounds in s. 631.051 for the appointment of the department as receiver.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exceeded its powers” means the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer has refused to permit examination by the office of its books, papers, accounts, records, or business practices;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer organized in this state has unlawfully removed from this state books, papers, accounts, or records necessary for an examination of the insurer by the office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer has failed to promptly comply with the applicable financial reporting statutes and office requests relating thereto;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer has neglected or refused to observe an order of the office to correct a deficiency in its capital or surplus; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer has unlawfully or in violation of an office order:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Totally reinsured its entire outstanding business; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Merged or consolidated substantially its entire property or business with another insurer.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consent” means authorized written agreement to supervision by the insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercially domiciled insurer” means and includes any foreign or alien insurer which, during its 3 preceding fiscal years taken together, or during any lesser period of time if not authorized to do business in this state or if it has been licensed to transact its business in this state only for the lesser period of time, has written an average of 25 percent or more direct premiums in this state than it has written in its state of domicile during the same period, or the direct premiums written in this state constitute more than 55 percent of its total direct premiums written everywhere in the United States during its 3 preceding fiscal years taken together, or during any lesser period of time if not authorized to do business in this state or if it has been authorized to transact its business in this state only for the lesser period of time, as reported in its most recent applicable annual or quarterly statements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 71, 72, ch. 89-360; s. 46, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 2002-247; s. 856, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>