<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.607" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Marine insurance,” “wet marine and transportation insurance,” and “inland marine insurance” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marine insurance” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance against any kinds of loss or damage to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vessels, craft, aircraft, cars, automobiles, and vehicles of every kind, as well as all goods, freights, cargoes, merchandise, effects, disbursements, profits, moneys, bullion, precious stones, securities, choses in action, evidences of debt, valuable papers, bottomry and respondentia interests and all other kinds of property and interests therein, in respect to, appertaining to, or in connection with any and all risks or perils of navigation, transit, or transportation, including war risks, on or under any seas or other waters, on land or in the air, or while being assembled, packed, crated, baled, compressed, or similarly prepared for shipment or while awaiting the same or during any delays, storage, transshipment, or reshipment incident thereto, including marine builder’s risks and all personal property floater risks; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Person or property in connection with or appertaining to a marine, inland marine, transit, or transportation insurance, including liability for loss of or damage to either, arising out of or in connection with the construction, repair, operation, maintenance, or use of the subject matter of such insurance, but not including life insurance or surety bonds nor insurance against loss by reason of bodily injury to the person arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of automobiles; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Precious stones, jewels, jewelry, gold, silver, and other precious metals, whether used in business or trade or otherwise and whether the same be in course of transportation or otherwise; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bridges, tunnels, and other instrumentalities of transportation and communication (excluding buildings, their furniture and furnishings, fixed contents, and supplies held in storage) unless fire, tornado, sprinkler leakage, hail, explosion, earthquake, riot, and/or civil commotion are the only hazards to be covered; piers, wharves, docks, and slips, excluding the risks of fire, tornado, sprinkler leakage, hail, explosion, earthquake, riot, and/or civil commotion; and other aids to navigation and transportation, including dry docks and marine railways, against all risks.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marine protection and indemnity insurance, meaning insurance against, or against legal liability of the insured for, loss, damage, or expense arising out of, or incident to, the ownership, operation, chartering, maintenance, use, repair, or construction of any vessel, craft, or instrumentality in use in ocean or inland waterways, including liability of the insured for personal injury, illness, or death or for loss of or damage to the property of another person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this code, “wet marine and transportation insurance” is that part of marine insurance which includes only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance upon vessels, crafts, and hulls and of interests therein or with relation thereto;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance of marine builders’ risks, marine war risks, and contracts of marine protection and indemnity insurance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance of freights and disbursements pertaining to a subject of insurance coming within this definition; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance of personal property and interests therein, in course of exportation from or importation into any country, or in course of transportation coastwise or on inland waters, including transportation by land, water, or air from point of origin to final destination, in respect to, appertaining to, or in connection with any and all risks or perils of navigation, transit, or transportation, and while being prepared for and while awaiting shipment, and during any delays, storage, transshipment, or reshipment incident thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this code, “inland marine insurance” is as established by general custom of the insurance business and promulgated by rule of the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 105, 417, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 80, 86, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 853, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of s. 624.607 and former s. 627.071.</Text></Note></Section>