<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain motor vehicle service agreements; exemption from code.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may, in exchange for fees, charges, or other consideration, solicit, offer, provide, enter into, issue, or deliver a motor vehicle service agreement indemnifying the service agreement holder against loss caused by the failure of any mechanical or component part or parts of a motor vehicle listed in the agreement arising out of the ownership, operation, and use of such motor vehicle when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premium charged for the motor vehicle service agreement does not exceed a total of $50 annually or $50 for the term of the agreement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The difference in the price of substantially similar parts, or service connected therewith, sold with and without the agreement does not exceed a total of $50 annually or $50 for the term of the agreement;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement is entered into incidentally to the sale of the part or parts or to the service connected therewith by the person soliciting, offering, providing, entering into, issuing, or delivering the motor vehicle service agreement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No other agreements are solicited, offered, provided, entered into, issued, or delivered by such person at any time on any other mechanical or component part or parts or service connected therewith on the same motor vehicle where the total of all payments exceeds $50 annually or $50 for the term of the agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">without being deemed an insurer and without being subject to the provisions of this code, provided that the agreement is not renewable or subject to extension or extendible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person soliciting, offering, providing, entering into, issuing, or delivering a motor vehicle service agreement without being deemed an insurer and without being subject to this code pursuant to subsection (1) shall, as to any such agreement, be subject to the provisions of the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act, part II of chapter 501.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 50, ch. 85-321; ss. 4, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>