<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.4626" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electric cooperative self-insurance fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any two or more electric cooperatives organized pursuant to chapter 425 may operate a self-insurance fund for the purpose of pooling and spreading liabilities of its group members in securing the payment of benefits under chapter 440. A self-insurance fund established under this section must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that every member of the fund is jointly and severally liable for the obligations of the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a continuing program of excess insurance coverage and reserve evaluation to protect the financial stability of the fund in an amount and manner determined by a qualified and independent actuary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subscribe to, or be a member of, a rating organization as prescribed in s. 627.231.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ an independent certified public accountant to complete an audit of its fiscal year-end financial statement within 6 months after the end of the fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a governing body comprised of a representative from each member of the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limit membership in the fund to electric cooperatives that operate in this state, their subsidiaries, and the current members of the Florida Rural Electric Self-Insurer’s Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At renewal, provide the members of the fund with a disclosure statement that notifies the members that the fund is not regulated by the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A self-insurance fund that meets the requirements of this section is subject to the assessments set forth in ss. 440.49(9), 440.51(1), and 624.4621(7), but is not subject to any other provision of s. 624.4621 and is not required to file any report with the department under s. 440.38(2)(b) which is uniquely required of group self-insurer funds qualified under s. 624.4621.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2009-116.</History></Section>