<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0624.474" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustees of a self-insurance fund operating as a trust, or the corporate directors of a self-insurance fund operating as a corporation, may assess from time to time members of a self-insurance fund liable therefor under the terms of their policies and pursuant to this section, or the department may assess the members in the event of liquidation of the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the limitations of s. 624.472(1), each member’s share of a deficiency for which an assessment is made shall be computed by applying to the premium earned on the member’s policy or policies during the period to be covered by the assessment the ratio of the total deficiency to the total premiums earned during such period upon all policies subject to the assessment. In the event one or more members fail to pay an assessment, the other members are liable on a proportionate basis for an additional assessment. The fund, acting on behalf of all members who paid the additional assessment, shall institute legal action when necessary and appropriate to recover the assessment from members who failed to pay it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In computing the earned premiums for the purposes of this section, the gross premium received by the fund for the policy shall be used as a base, deducting therefrom solely charges not recurring upon the renewal or extension of the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No member shall have an offset against any assessment for which she or he is liable on account of any claim for unearned premium or losses payable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 86-160; s. 2, ch. 89-247; ss. 41, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 83, ch. 93-415; s. 190, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>