<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0624.5105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community contribution tax credit; authorization; limitations; eligibility and application requirements; administration; definitions; expiration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZATION TO GRANT TAX CREDITS; LIMITATIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be allowed a credit of 50 percent of a community contribution against any tax due for a calendar year under s. 624.509 or s. 624.510.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No insurer shall receive more than $200,000 in annual tax credits for all approved community contributions made in any one year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of tax credit which may be granted for all programs approved under this section and ss. 212.08(5)(p) and 220.183 is $10.5 million annually for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) and $3.5 million annually for all other projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each proposal for the granting of such tax credit requires the prior approval of the director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the credit granted pursuant to this section is not fully used in any one year because of insufficient tax liability on the part of the insurer, the unused amount may be carried forward for a period not to exceed 5 years. The carryover credit may be used in a subsequent year when the tax imposed by s. 624.509 or s. 624.510 for such year exceeds the credit under this section for such year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer that claims a credit against premium-tax liability earned by making a community contribution under this section need not pay any additional retaliatory tax levied under s. 624.5091 as a result of claiming such a credit. Section 624.5091 does not limit such a credit in any manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each community contribution by an insurer must be in a form specified in subsection (5).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each community contribution must be reserved exclusively for use in a project as defined in s. 220.03(1)(t).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project must be undertaken by an “eligible sponsor,” as defined in s. 220.183(2)(c). In no event shall a contributing insurer have a financial interest in the eligible sponsor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project shall be located in an area designated as an enterprise zone or a Front Porch Community. Any project designed to construct or rehabilitate housing for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) is exempt from the area requirement of this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for less than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant tax credits for those applications and shall grant remaining tax credits on a first-come, first-served basis for any subsequent eligible applications received before the end of the state fiscal year. If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for more than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant the tax credits for those applications as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If tax credit applications submitted for approved projects of an eligible sponsor do not exceed $200,000 in total, the credits shall be granted in full if the tax credit applications are approved.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If tax credit applications submitted for approved projects of an eligible sponsor exceed $200,000 in total, the amount of tax credits granted under sub-subparagraph a. shall be subtracted from the amount of available tax credits, and the remaining credits shall be granted to each approved tax credit application on a pro rata basis.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects other than those that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for less than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant tax credits for those applications and shall grant remaining tax credits on a first-come, first-served basis for any subsequent eligible applications received before the end of the state fiscal year. If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects other than those that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for more than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant the tax credits for those applications on a pro rata basis.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any eligible sponsor wishing to participate in this program must submit a proposal to the Department of Economic Opportunity which sets forth the sponsor, the project, the area in which the project is located, and such supporting information as may be prescribed by rule. The proposal shall also contain a resolution from the local governmental unit in which the proposed project is located certifying that the project is consistent with local plans and regulations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer wishing to participate in this program must submit an application for tax credit to the Department of Economic Opportunity which sets forth the sponsor; the project; and the type, value, and purpose of the contribution. The sponsor must verify, in writing, the terms of the application and indicate its willingness to receive the contribution, which verification must accompany the application for tax credit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer must submit a separate application for tax credit for each individual contribution which it proposes to contribute to each individual project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity may adopt rules to administer this section, including rules for the approval or disapproval of proposals by insurers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision of the director shall be in writing, and, if approved, the proposal shall state the maximum credit allowable to the insurer. A copy of the decision shall be transmitted to the executive director of the Department of Revenue, who shall apply such credit to the tax liability of the insurer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall monitor all projects periodically, in a manner consistent with available resources to ensure that resources are utilized in accordance with this section; however, each project shall be reviewed no less frequently than once every 2 years.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall, in consultation with the Florida Housing Finance Corporation and the statewide and regional housing and financial intermediaries, market the availability of the community contribution tax credit program to community-based organizations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall adopt any rules necessary to ensure the orderly implementation and administration of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community contribution” means the grant by an insurer of any of the following items:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash or other liquid assets.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Goods or inventory.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other physical resources which are identified by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the director of the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means any county or incorporated municipality in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project” means an activity as defined in s. 220.03(1)(t).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXPIRATION.<EmDash />The provisions of this section, except paragraph (1)(e), shall expire and be void on June 30, 2015.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 84-356; s. 124, ch. 91-112; s. 54, ch. 94-136; s. 149, ch. 96-320; s. 2, ch. 98-219; s. 2, ch. 99-265; s. 41, ch. 2000-210; s. 32, ch. 2001-201; s. 25, ch. 2004-243; s. 4, ch. 2005-282; s. 3, ch. 2006-78; s. 136, ch. 2007-5; s. 36, ch. 2008-153; s. 20, ch. 2010-4; s. 429, ch. 2011-142; s. 77, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>