<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0010.00001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Official census for apportionment; definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 8(a), Art. X of the State Constitution, the United States Decennial Census of 2000 is the official census of the state for the purposes of this joint resolution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following delineation of areas to be included in each representative district employs the official census county divisions, tracts, block numbering areas, block groups, and blocks used by the United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census, in compiling the United States Decennial Census of 2000 in this state. The populations within these census geographic units are the population figures reported in the counts of the United States Decennial Census of 2000 provided to the state in accordance with Pub. L. No. 94-171.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this joint resolution, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Block” means the smallest geographic unit for which population was ascertained in taking the 2000 census.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Block group” means the combination of blocks within a single tract or block numbering area the numbers of which begin with the same digit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tract” means the combination of blocks within a county which is delineated as a tract by local committee according to Census Bureau guidelines.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Block numbering area” or “BNA” means the combination of blocks within a county which are not included in a tract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Census county division” means an administrative division of a county which contains tracts or block numbering areas.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, HJR 1987, 2002 Regular Session.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Superseded by s. 10.11, created by s. 1, Committee Substitute for Senate Joint Resolution 1176, 2012 Regular Session.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>