<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0162.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notices.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All notices required by this part must be provided to the alleged violator by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified mail to the address listed in the tax collector’s office for tax notices, or to any other address provided by the property owner in writing to the local government for the purpose of receiving notices. For property owned by a corporation, notices may be provided by certified mail to the registered agent of the corporation. If any notice sent by certified mail is not signed as received within 30 days after the date of mailing, notice may be provided by posting as described in subparagraphs (2)(b)1. and 2.;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hand delivery by the sheriff or other law enforcement officer, code inspector, or other person designated by the local governing body;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leaving the notice at the violator’s usual place of residence with any person residing therein who is above 15 years of age and informing such person of the contents of the notice; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of commercial premises, leaving the notice with the manager or other person in charge.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to providing notice as set forth in subsection (1), at the option of the code enforcement board, notice may also be served by publication or posting, as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such notice shall be published once during each week for 4 consecutive weeks (four publications being sufficient) in a newspaper of general circulation in the county where the code enforcement board is located. The newspaper shall meet such requirements as are prescribed under chapter 50 for legal and official advertisements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of publication shall be made as provided in ss. 50.041 and 50.051.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of publication as described in paragraph (a), such notice may be posted at least 10 days prior to the hearing, or prior to the expiration of any deadline contained in the notice, in at least two locations, one of which shall be the property upon which the violation is alleged to exist and the other of which shall be, in the case of municipalities, at the primary municipal government office, and in the case of counties, at the front door of the courthouse or the main county governmental center in said county.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of posting shall be by affidavit of the person posting the notice, which affidavit shall include a copy of the notice posted and the date and places of its posting.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice by publication or posting may run concurrently with, or may follow, an attempt or attempts to provide notice by hand delivery or by mail as required under subsection (1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Evidence that an attempt has been made to hand deliver or mail notice as provided in subsection (1), together with proof of publication or posting as provided in subsection (2), shall be sufficient to show that the notice requirements of this part have been met, without regard to whether or not the alleged violator actually received such notice.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-300; s. 11, ch. 86-201; s. 3, ch. 87-391; s. 10, ch. 89-268; s. 6, ch. 94-291; s. 6, ch. 99-360; s. 3, ch. 2000-125; s. 1, ch. 2012-13.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 166.062.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>