<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0162.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local government code enforcement boards; organization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local governing body may appoint one or more code enforcement boards and legal counsel for the enforcement boards. The local governing body of a county or a municipality that has a population of less than 5,000 persons may appoint five-member or seven-member code enforcement boards. The local governing body of a county or a municipality that has a population equal to or greater than 5,000 persons must appoint seven-member code enforcement boards. The local governing body may appoint up to two alternate members for each code enforcement board to serve on the board in the absence of board members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the enforcement boards shall be residents of the municipality, in the case of municipal enforcement boards, or residents of the county, in the case of county enforcement boards. Appointments shall be made in accordance with applicable law and ordinances on the basis of experience or interest in the subject matter jurisdiction of the respective code enforcement board, in the sole discretion of the local governing body. The membership of each enforcement board shall, whenever possible, include an architect, a businessperson, an engineer, a general contractor, a subcontractor, and a realtor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial appointments to a seven-member code enforcement board shall be as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members appointed for a term of 1 year each.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members appointed for a term of 2 years each.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members appointed for a term of 3 years each.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial appointments to a five-member code enforcement board shall be as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member appointed for a term of 1 year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members appointed for a term of 2 years each.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members appointed for a term of 3 years each.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Thereafter, any appointment shall be made for a term of 3 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local governing body of a county or a municipality that has a population of less than 5,000 persons may reduce a seven-member code enforcement board to five members upon the simultaneous expiration of the terms of office of two members of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member may be reappointed upon approval of the local governing body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appointment to fill any vacancy on an enforcement board shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. If any member fails to attend two of three successive meetings without cause and without prior approval of the chair, the enforcement board shall declare the member’s office vacant, and the local governing body shall promptly fill such vacancy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members shall serve in accordance with ordinances of the local governing body and may be suspended and removed for cause as provided in such ordinances for removal of members of boards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of an enforcement board shall elect a chair, who shall be a voting member, from among the members of the board. The presence of four or more members shall constitute a quorum of any seven-member enforcement board, and the presence of three or more members shall constitute a quorum of any five-member enforcement board. Members shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for such travel, mileage, and per diem expenses as may be authorized by the local governing body or as are otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local governing body attorney shall either be counsel to an enforcement board or shall represent the municipality or county by presenting cases before the enforcement board, but in no case shall the local governing body attorney serve in both capacities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-300; s. 5, ch. 82-37; s. 4, ch. 86-201; s. 2, ch. 87-129; s. 4, ch. 89-268; s. 1, ch. 94-291; s. 1441, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 166.055.</Text></Note></Section>