<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0162.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the code inspector to initiate enforcement proceedings of the various codes; however, no member of a board shall have the power to initiate such enforcement proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsections (3) and (4), if a violation of the codes is found, the code inspector shall notify the violator and give him or her a reasonable time to correct the violation. Should the violation continue beyond the time specified for correction, the code inspector shall notify an enforcement board and request a hearing. The code enforcement board, through its clerical staff, shall schedule a hearing, and written notice of such hearing shall be hand delivered or mailed as provided in s. 162.12 to said violator. At the option of the code enforcement board, notice may additionally be served by publication or posting as provided in s. 162.12. If the violation is corrected and then recurs or if the violation is not corrected by the time specified for correction by the code inspector, the case may be presented to the enforcement board even if the violation has been corrected prior to the board hearing, and the notice shall so state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a repeat violation is found, the code inspector shall notify the violator but is not required to give the violator a reasonable time to correct the violation. The code inspector, upon notifying the violator of a repeat violation, shall notify an enforcement board and request a hearing. The code enforcement board, through its clerical staff, shall schedule a hearing and shall provide notice pursuant to s. 162.12. The case may be presented to the enforcement board even if the repeat violation has been corrected prior to the board hearing, and the notice shall so state. If the repeat violation has been corrected, the code enforcement board retains the right to schedule a hearing to determine costs and impose the payment of reasonable enforcement fees upon the repeat violator. The repeat violator may choose to waive his or her rights to this hearing and pay said costs as determined by the code enforcement board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the code inspector has reason to believe a violation or the condition causing the violation presents a serious threat to the public health, safety, and welfare or if the violation is irreparable or irreversible in nature, the code inspector shall make a reasonable effort to notify the violator and may immediately notify the enforcement board and request a hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the owner of property that is subject to an enforcement proceeding before an enforcement board, special magistrate, or court transfers ownership of such property between the time the initial pleading was served and the time of the hearing, such owner shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose, in writing, the existence and the nature of the proceeding to the prospective transferee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver to the prospective transferee a copy of the pleadings, notices, and other materials relating to the code enforcement proceeding received by the transferor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose, in writing, to the prospective transferee that the new owner will be responsible for compliance with the applicable code and with orders issued in the code enforcement proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File a notice with the code enforcement official of the transfer of the property, with the identity and address of the new owner and copies of the disclosures made to the new owner, within 5 days after the date of the transfer.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A failure to make the disclosures described in paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) before the transfer creates a rebuttable presumption of fraud. If the property is transferred before the hearing, the proceeding shall not be dismissed, but the new owner shall be provided a reasonable period of time to correct the violation before the hearing is held.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-300; s. 5, ch. 86-201; s. 1, ch. 87-391; s. 5, ch. 89-268; s. 2, ch. 94-291; s. 1442, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 96-385; s. 4, ch. 99-360; s. 64, ch. 2004-11.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 166.056.</Text></Note></Section>