<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1009.90" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of the Department of Education.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the department shall include:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of this part and rules adopted by the State Board of Education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of federal funding, insurance, or reinsurance in full compliance with applicable federal laws and regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of written administrative procedures and controls for the administration of each financial aid program conducted by the office, maintenance of program records and documents, timely collection and remittance of insurance premiums, and timely assignment of defaulted loans to collection agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual compilation of sources of financial aid available to students in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Biennial analysis of the amount of available financial aid moneys and the effect of such moneys on student access to postsecondary institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Biennial internal evaluation of the administrative efficiency and effectiveness of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual assessment of the accuracy of eligibility information from a random sample of award recipients.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual review of procedures for the distribution of state financial aid funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development and submission of a report, annually, to the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, which shall include, but not be limited to, recommendations for the distribution of state financial aid funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development and evaluation of a comprehensive, long-range program of all sources of student financial aid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dissemination of information on available financial aid programs to district school superintendents and other persons who request such information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calculation of the amount of need-based student financial aid required to offset fee increases recommended by the State Board of Education and the Board of Governors and inclusion of such amount within the legislative budget request for student assistance grant programs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 473, ch. 2002-387; s. 139, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>