<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1009.93" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Student financial aid planning and development.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer a student financial aid planning and development program. It is the intent of the Legislature that a specific sum of funds be allocated each year for the purpose of sponsoring the design, development, and implementation of a comprehensive program of student financial aid and of initiating activities of inservice training for student financial aid administrators and activities to encourage maximum lender participation in guaranteed loans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The objective of a state program is the maintenance of a state student financial aid program to supplement a basic national program which will provide equal access to postsecondary education to citizens of this state who have the ability and motivation to benefit from a postsecondary education. In the development of a state program to achieve this objective, it shall be the policy that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State student financial aid be provided primarily on the basis of financial need;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students receiving need-based financial aid be expected to contribute toward their cost of education through self-help resources such as savings, work, and loans;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student financial aid be available to state residents for attendance at accredited public or private institutions of higher education in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student financial aid be provided for all levels of postsecondary education; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State student financial aid be administered by a central state agency.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Planning and development must be in accordance with the foregoing objective and policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The planning and development procedures shall provide for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The review of public policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of performance objectives;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of alternate approaches;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The evaluation of performance; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The participation and involvement in the planning process of representatives of the groups affected by a state program of student financial aid.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules providing for the verification of the independent status of state financial aid recipients.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall encourage industry and education linkages through the development of temporary employment opportunities for students attending postsecondary institutions in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 476, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>