<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1009.534" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Academic Scholars award.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student is eligible for a Florida Academic Scholars award if the student meets the general eligibility requirements for the Florida Bright Futures Scholarship Program and the student:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has achieved a 3.5 weighted grade point average as calculated pursuant to s. 1009.531, or its equivalent, in high school courses that are designated by the State Board of Education as college-preparatory academic courses; and has attained at least the score pursuant to s. 1009.531(6)(a) on the combined verbal and quantitative parts of the Scholastic Aptitude Test, the Scholastic Assessment Test, or the recentered Scholastic Assessment Test of the College Entrance Examination, or an equivalent score on the ACT Assessment Program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has attended a home education program according to s. 1002.41 during grades 11 and 12 or has completed the International Baccalaureate curriculum but failed to earn the International Baccalaureate Diploma or has completed the Advanced International Certificate of Education curriculum but failed to earn the Advanced International Certificate of Education Diploma, and has attained at least the score pursuant to s. 1009.531(6)(a) on the combined verbal and quantitative parts of the Scholastic Aptitude Test, the Scholastic Assessment Test, or the recentered Scholastic Assessment Test of the College Entrance Examination, or an equivalent score on the ACT Assessment Program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been awarded an International Baccalaureate Diploma from the International Baccalaureate Office or an Advanced International Certificate of Education Diploma from the University of Cambridge International Examinations Office;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been recognized by the merit or achievement programs of the National Merit Scholarship Corporation as a scholar or finalist; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been recognized by the National Hispanic Recognition Program as a scholar recipient.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A student must complete a program of community service work, as approved by the district school board, the administrators of a nonpublic school, or the Department of Education for home education program students, which shall include a minimum of 75 hours of service work for high school students graduating in the 2010-2011 academic year and 100 hours of service work for high school students graduating in the 2011-2012 academic year and thereafter, and must identify a social problem that interests him or her, develop a plan for his or her personal involvement in addressing the problem, and, through papers or other presentations, evaluate and reflect upon his or her experience.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida Academic Scholar who is enrolled in a certificate, diploma, associate, or baccalaureate degree program at a public or nonpublic postsecondary education institution is eligible for an award equal to the amount specified in the General Appropriations Act to assist with the payment of educational expenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for a renewal award as a Florida Academic Scholar, a student must maintain the equivalent of a cumulative grade point average of 3.0 on a 4.0 scale with an opportunity for restoration one time as provided in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each school district, the Florida Academic Scholar with the highest academic ranking shall receive an additional award equal to the amount specified in the General Appropriations Act for college-related expenses. This award must be funded from the Florida Bright Futures Scholarship Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 426, ch. 2002-387; s. 56, ch. 2004-41; s. 8, ch. 2005-196; s. 3, ch. 2007-330; s. 15, ch. 2009-60; s. 15, ch. 2010-155; s. 18, ch. 2011-63; s. 17, ch. 2011-177; s. 27, ch. 2012-134.</History>
</Section>