<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1009.89" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">The William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grants.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that independent nonprofit colleges and universities eligible to participate in the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program are an integral part of the higher education system in this state and that a significant number of state residents choose this form of higher education. The Legislature further finds that a strong and viable system of independent nonprofit colleges and universities reduces the tax burden on the citizens of the state. Because the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program is not related to a student’s financial need or other criteria upon which financial aid programs are based, it is the intent of the Legislature that the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program not be considered a financial aid program but rather a tuition assistance program for its citizens.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program shall be administered by the Department of Education. The State Board of Education shall adopt rules for the administration of the program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue through the program a William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant to any full-time degree-seeking undergraduate student registered at an independent nonprofit college or university which is located in and chartered by the state; which is accredited by the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools; which grants baccalaureate degrees; which is not a state university or Florida College System institution; and which has a secular purpose, so long as the receipt of state aid by students at the institution would not have the primary effect of advancing or impeding religion or result in an excessive entanglement between the state and any religious sect. Any independent college or university that was eligible to receive tuition vouchers on January 1, 1989, and which continues to meet the criteria under which its eligibility was established, shall remain eligible to receive William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant payments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is eligible to receive such William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">He or she meets the general requirements, including residency, for student eligibility as provided in s. 1009.40, except as otherwise provided in this section; </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">He or she is enrolled as a full-time undergraduate student at an eligible college or university;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">He or she is not enrolled in a program of study leading to a degree in theology or divinity; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">He or she is making satisfactory academic progress as defined by the college or university in which he or she is enrolled; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">He or she submits a Free Application for Federal Student Aid which is complete and error free prior to disbursement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program for eligible institutions shall be as provided in the General Appropriations Act. The William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant may be paid on a prorated basis in advance of the registration period. The department shall make such payments to the college or university in which the student is enrolled for credit to the student’s account for payment of tuition and fees. Institutions shall certify to the department the amount of funds disbursed to each student and shall remit to the department any undisbursed advances or refunds within 60 days of the end of regular registration. A student is not eligible to receive the award for more than 9 semesters or 14 quarters, except as otherwise provided in s. 1009.40(3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the combined amount of the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant issued pursuant to this act and all other scholarships and grants for tuition or fees exceeds the amount charged to the student for tuition and fees, the department shall reduce the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida resident access grant issued pursuant to this act by an amount equal to such excess.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the number of eligible students exceeds the total authorized in the General Appropriations Act, an institution may use its own resources to assure that each eligible student receives the full benefit of the grant amount authorized.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 471, ch. 2002-387; s. 8, ch. 2005-56; s. 143, ch. 2011-5; s. 31, ch. 2011-63.</History>
</Section>