<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1009.95" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delinquent accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education is directed to exert every lawful and reasonable effort to collect all delinquent unpaid and uncanceled scholarship loan notes, student loan notes, and defaulted guaranteed loan notes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish a recovery account into which unpaid and uncanceled scholarship loan note, student loan note, and defaulted guaranteed loan note accounts may be transferred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may settle any delinquent unpaid and uncanceled scholarship loan notes, student loan notes, and defaulted guaranteed loan notes and employ the service of a collection agent when deemed advisable in collecting delinquent or defaulted accounts. However, no collection agent may be paid a commission in excess of 35 percent of the amount collected. Any expense incurred by the department in enforcing the collection of a loan note may be borne by the signer of the note and may be added to the amount of the principal of such note.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may charge off unpaid and uncanceled scholarship loan notes and student loan notes which are at least 3 years delinquent and which prove uncollectible after good faith collection efforts. However, a delinquent account with a past due balance of $25 or less may be charged off as uncollectible when it becomes 6 months past due and the cost of further collection effort or assignment to a collection agent would not be warranted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No individual borrower who has been determined to be in default in making legally required scholarship loan, student loan, or guaranteed loan repayments shall be furnished with his or her academic transcripts or other student records until such time as the loan is paid in full or the default status has been removed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may charge an individual borrower who has been determined to be in default in making legally required loan repayments the maximum interest rate authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt such rules as are necessary to regulate the collection, settlement, and charging off of delinquent unpaid and uncanceled scholarship loan notes, student loan notes, and defaulted guaranteed loan notes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 478, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>