<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1009.286" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional student payment for hours exceeding baccalaureate degree program completion requirements at state universities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to encourage each undergraduate student who enrolls in a state university to complete the student’s respective baccalaureate degree program in the most efficient way possible while providing for access to additional college coursework. Therefore, the Legislature intends to enact a policy that provides incentives for efficient baccalaureate degree completion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State universities shall require a student to pay an excess hour surcharge for each credit hour in excess of the number of credit hours required to complete the baccalaureate degree program in which the student is enrolled. The excess hour surcharge shall become effective for students who enter a state university for the first time and maintain continuous enrollment as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2009-2010 and 2010-2011 academic years, an excess hour surcharge equal to 50 percent of the tuition rate for each credit hour in excess of 120 percent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2011-2012 academic year, an excess hour surcharge equal to 100 percent of the tuition rate for each credit hour in excess of 115 percent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2012-2013 academic year and thereafter, an excess hour surcharge equal to 100 percent of the tuition rate for each credit hour in excess of 110 percent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law and for purposes of this section, the following credit hours shall be included when calculating the number of hours taken by a student:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All credit hours for courses taken at the state university from which the student is seeking a baccalaureate degree, including:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed courses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses that are dropped after the university’s advertised last day of the drop and add period.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses from which a student withdraws, except as provided in subsection (4).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repeated courses, except repeated courses for which the student has paid the full cost of instruction as provided in s. 1009.285.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All credit hours earned at another institution and accepted for transfer by the state university and applied toward the student’s baccalaureate degree program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, credit hours earned under the following circumstances are not calculated as hours required to earn a baccalaureate degree:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">College credits earned through an articulated accelerated mechanism identified in s. 1007.27.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours earned through internship programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours required for certification, recertification, or certificate programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours in courses from which a student must withdraw due to reasons of medical or personal hardship.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours taken by active-duty military personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours required to achieve a dual major taken while pursuing a baccalaureate degree.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remedial and English as a Second Language credit hours.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit hours earned in military science courses that are part of the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps (ROTC) program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state university and Florida College System institution shall implement a process for notifying students regarding the provisions of this section. Notice must be provided by a state university or a Florida College System institution upon a student’s initial enrollment in the institution. Such notice must be provided a second time by a state university when a student has earned the credit hours required to complete the baccalaureate degree program in which the student is enrolled. The notice must include a recommendation that each student who intends to earn credit hours at the institution in excess of the credit hours required for the baccalaureate degree program in which the student is enrolled meet with his or her academic advisor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “state university” includes the institutions identified in s. 1000.21(6) and the term “Florida College System institution” includes the institutions identified in s. 1000.21(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2009-60; s. 125, ch. 2011-5; s. 16, ch. 2011-63; s. 24, ch. 2012-134.</History>
</Section>