<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1009.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Fund for Minority Teachers, Inc.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida Fund for Minority Teachers, Inc., which is a not-for-profit statutory corporation housed in the College of Education at the University of Florida. The corporation shall administer and manage the minority teacher education scholars program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall submit an annual budget projection to the Department of Education to be included in the annual legislative budget request. The projection must be based on the cost to award up to 350 scholarships to new scholars in the junior year and up to 350 renewal scholarships to the 350 rising seniors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall report to the Department of Education, by the date established by the department, the eligible students to whom scholarship moneys are disbursed each academic term, the annual balance of the corporation’s assets and cash reserves, and any other information requested by the department in accordance with s. 1009.94. By June 30 of each fiscal year, the corporation shall remit to the department any appropriated funds that were not distributed for scholarships, less the 5 percent for administration, including administration of the required training program, authorized pursuant to subsection (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of directors shall administer the corporation. The Governor shall appoint to the board at least 15 but not more than 25 members, who shall serve terms of 3 years, except that 4 of the initial members shall serve 1-year terms and 4 shall serve 2-year terms. At least 4 members must be employed by Florida College System institutions and at least 11 members must be employed by public or private postsecondary institutions that operate colleges of education. At least one member must be a financial aid officer employed by a postsecondary education institution operating in Florida. Administrative costs for support of the Board of Directors and the Florida Fund for Minority Teachers may not exceed 5 percent of funds allocated for the program. The board shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold meetings to implement this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select a chairperson annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make rules for its own government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint an executive director to serve at its pleasure. The executive director shall be the chief administrative officer and agent of the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a record of its proceedings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegate to the chairperson the responsibility for signing final orders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out the training program as required for the minority teacher education scholars program. No more than 5 percent of the funds appropriated and up to $100,000 from other available funds for the minority teacher education scholars program may be expended annually for administration, including administration of the required training program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 439, ch. 2002-387; s. 24, ch. 2009-60; s. 137, ch. 2011-5; s. 9, ch. 2011-63; s. 31, ch. 2012-134.</History>
</Section>