<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1009.533" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Bright Futures Scholarship Program; eligible postsecondary education institutions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student is eligible for an award or the renewal of an award from the Florida Bright Futures Scholarship Program if the student meets the requirements for the program as described in this act and is enrolled in a postsecondary education institution that meets the description in any one of the following subsections:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida public university, Florida College System institution, or career center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An independent Florida college or university that is accredited by an accrediting association whose standards are comparable to the minimum standards required to operate an institution at that level in Florida, as determined by rules of the Commission for Independent Education, and which has operated in the state for at least 3 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An independent Florida postsecondary education institution that is licensed by the Commission for Independent Education and that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is authorized to grant degrees;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shows evidence of sound financial condition; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has operated in the state for at least 3 years without having its approval, accreditation, or license placed on probation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida independent postsecondary education institution that offers a nursing diploma approved by the Board of Nursing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida independent postsecondary education institution that is licensed by the Commission for Independent Education and which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is authorized to award certificates, diplomas, or credentials other than degrees;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a program completion and placement rate of at least the rate required by the current Florida Statutes, the Florida Administrative Code, or the Department of Education for an institution at its level; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shows evidence of sound financial condition; and either:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is accredited at the institutional level by an accrediting agency recognized by the United States Department of Education and has operated in the state for at least 3 years during which there has been no complaint for which probable cause has been found; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has operated in Florida for 5 years during which there has been no complaint for which probable cause has been found.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 425, ch. 2002-387; s. 121, ch. 2004-357; s. 132, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>