<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1009.61" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Teacher/Quest Scholarship Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Teacher/Quest Scholarship Program is created for the purpose of providing teachers with the opportunity to enhance their knowledge of science, mathematics, and computer applications in business, industry, and government. A school district or lab school may propose that one or more teachers be granted a Teacher/Quest Scholarship by submitting to the Department of Education:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A project proposal specifying activities a teacher will carry out to improve his or her:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Understanding of mathematical, scientific, or computing concepts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ability to apply and demonstrate such concepts through instruction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowledge of career requirements for competency in mathematics, science, and computing; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ability to integrate and apply technological concepts from all three fields; and</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contractual agreement with a private corporation or governmental agency that implements the project proposal and guarantees employment to the teacher during a summer or other period when schools are out of session. The agreement must stipulate a salary rate that does not exceed regular rates of pay and a gross salary amount consistent with applicable statutory and contractual provisions for the teacher’s employment. The teacher’s compensation shall be provided for on an equally matched basis by funds from the employing corporation or agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 440, ch. 2002-387; s. 60, ch. 2004-41; s. 124, ch. 2004-357.</History></Section>