<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.514" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification for registered contractors; grandfathering provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall, upon receipt of a completed application, appropriate fee, and proof of compliance with the provisions of this section, issue:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an applying registered electrical contractor, a certificate as an electrical contractor, as defined in s. 489.505(12); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an applying registered alarm system contractor, a certificate in the matching alarm system contractor category, as defined in s. 489.505(2)(a) or (b); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an applying registered electrical specialty contractor, a certificate in the matching electrical specialty contractor category, as defined in s. 489.505(19).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contractor registered under this part who makes application under this section to the board shall meet each of the following requirements for certification:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Currently holds a valid registered local license in the category of electrical contractor, alarm system contractor, or electrical specialty contractor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has, for that category, passed a written, proctored examination that the board finds to be substantially similar to the examination required to be licensed as a certified contractor under this part. For purposes of this subsection, a written, proctored examination such as that produced by the National Assessment Institute, Block and Associates, NAI/Block, Experior Assessments, Professional Testing, Inc., or Assessment Systems, Inc., shall be considered to be substantially similar to the examination required to be licensed as a certified contractor. The board may not impose or make any requirements regarding the nature or content of these cited examinations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has at least 5 years of experience as a contractor in that contracting category, or as an inspector or building administrator with oversight over that category, at the time of application. For contractors, only time periods in which the contractor license is active and the contractor is not on probation shall count toward the 5 years required under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not had his or her contractor’s license revoked at any time, had his or her contractor’s license suspended in the last 5 years, or been assessed a fine in excess of $500 in the last 5 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in compliance with the insurance and financial responsibility requirements in s. 489.515(1)(b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant must make application by November 1, 2004, to be licensed pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 99-254; s. 39, ch. 2000-372.</History></Section>