<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0489.518" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alarm system agents.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed electrical or alarm system contractor may not employ a person to perform the duties of a burglar alarm system agent unless the person:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age or has evidence of a court-approved declaration of emancipation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed a minimum of 14 hours of training, to include basic alarm system electronics in addition to related training including CCTV and access control training, with at least 2 hours of training in the prevention of false alarms. Such training shall be from a board-approved provider, and the employee or applicant for employment shall provide proof of successful completion to the licensed employer. The board shall by rule establish criteria for the approval of training courses and providers and may by rule establish criteria for accepting alternative nonclassroom education on an hour-for-hour basis. The board shall approve providers that conduct training in other than the English language. The board shall establish a fee for the approval of training providers or courses, not to exceed $60. Qualified employers may conduct training classes for their employees, with board approval.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been convicted within the last 3 years of a crime that directly relates to the business for which employment is being sought. Although the employee is barred from operating as an alarm system agent for 3 years subsequent to his or her conviction, the employer shall be supplied the information regarding any convictions occurring prior to that time, and the employer may at his or her discretion consider an earlier conviction to be a bar to employment as an alarm system agent. To ensure that this requirement has been met, a licensed electrical or alarm contractor must obtain from the Florida Department of Law Enforcement a completed fingerprint and criminal background check for each applicant for employment as a burglar alarm system agent or for each individual currently employed on the effective date of this act as a burglar alarm system agent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been committed for controlled substance abuse or been found guilty of a crime under chapter 893 or a similar law relating to controlled substances in any other state within the 3-year period immediately preceding the date of application for employment, or the effective date of this act for an individual employed as a burglar alarm system agent on that date, unless he or she establishes that he or she is not currently abusing any controlled substance and has successfully completed a rehabilitation course.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who perform only monitoring are not required to complete the training required for burglar alarm system agents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who perform only monitoring at an out-of-state location are not required to comply with background check requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who perform proprietary burglar alarm system agent duties for only a single employer, and who do not offer alarm system contracting services to the public, are not required to comply with background check requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state-certified electrical contractor, a state-certified alarm system contractor, a state-registered alarm system contractor, a journeyman electrician licensed by any local jurisdiction, or an alarm technician licensed by a local jurisdiction that requires an examination and experience or training as licensure qualifications, is not required to complete the training required for burglar alarm system agents. A state-registered electrical contractor is not required to complete the training required for burglar alarm system agents, so long as he or she is only doing electrical work up to the alarm panel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonsupervising employee working as a helper or apprentice under the direct, onsite, continuous supervision of a state-certified electrical contractor, a state-registered electrical contractor, a state-certified alarm system contractor, a state-registered alarm system contractor, a journeyman electrician licensed by any local jurisdiction, an alarm technician licensed by a local jurisdiction that requires an examination and experience or training as licensure qualifications, or a qualified alarm system agent is not required to complete the training otherwise required and is not required to be 18 years of age or older.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for employment as an alarm system agent, or an individual employed as a burglar alarm system agent on the effective date of this act, may commence or continue employment pending the completion of the required training and the results of the background check required by this section for a period not to exceed 90 days after the date of application for employment, or 90 days after the effective date of this act for individuals currently employed as burglar alarm system agents. However, the person must work under the direction and control of a sponsoring licensed electrical or burglar alarm system contractor pending the completion of the training and the criminal background check. If an applicant or an individual employed on the effective date of this act does not complete the training or receive a satisfactory criminal background check within the 90-day period, the employment must be terminated immediately.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed electrical or alarm system contractor shall furnish each of its burglar alarm system agents with an identification card.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification card shall be designed in a board-approved format. The card must include a picture of the agent, must specify at least the name of the holder of the card and the name and license number of the contractor, and must be signed by the contractor and by the holder of the card. Each identification card is valid for a period of 2 years after the date of issuance. The identification card must be in the possession of each burglar alarm system agent while engaged in burglar alarm system agent duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person to whom an identification card has been issued shall be responsible for the safekeeping thereof and shall not loan, or allow any other person to use or display, the identification card.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each identification card must be renewed every 2 years and in a board-approved format to show compliance with the 6 hours of continuing education necessary to maintain certification as a burglar alarm system agent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed electrical or alarm system contractor must obtain an updated criminal background check from the Department of Law Enforcement for each burglar alarm system agent who renews certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each burglar alarm system agent must receive 6 hours of continuing education on burglar alarm system installation and repair and false alarm prevention every 2 years from a board-approved sponsor of training and through a board-approved training course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with any of the provisions of this section shall be a disciplinable offense against the contractor pursuant to s. 489.533.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 96-298; s. 2, ch. 97-122; s. 46, ch. 98-419; s. 28, ch. 99-7; s. 22, ch. 2000-332; s. 2, ch. 2004-76.</History>
</Section>