<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.1402" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Homeowners’ Construction Recovery Fund; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following definitions apply to ss. 489.140-489.144:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Arbitration” means alternative dispute resolution entered into between a claimant and a contractor either pursuant to a construction contract that contains a mandatory arbitration clause or through any binding arbitration under the Florida Arbitration Code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Construction Industry Licensing Board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Claimant” means a homeowner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contractor” means a Division I contractor performing services described in s. 489.105(3)(a)-(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court of competent jurisdiction” means a civil or criminal court in the State of Florida, or a bankruptcy court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Homeowner” means the owner of an owner-occupied residence, including a trustee based upon a trust instrument granting a person a beneficial interest for life in the residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means a contractor, financially responsible officer, or business organization licensed under this part at the time the violation was committed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Notice” means service as described in s. 455.275.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residence” means an individual residential condominium or cooperative unit or a residential building containing not more than two residential units in which the owner contracting for the improvement is residing or will reside 6 months or more each calendar year upon completion of the improvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recovery fund” means the Florida Homeowners’ Construction Recovery Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Same transaction” means a contract, or any series of contracts, between a claimant and a contractor or qualified business, when such contract or contracts involve the same property or contiguous properties and are entered into either at one time or serially.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Valid and current license,” for the purpose of s. 489.141(2)(d), means any license issued pursuant to this part to a licensee, including a license in an active, inactive, delinquent, or suspended status.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following definitions apply to claims made prior to July 1, 2007, when the contract was executed and the violation occurred on or before January 1, 2005.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Claimant” means a natural person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means a contractor, financially responsible officer, or business organization licensed under this part at the time the violation was committed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2004-84.</History></Section>