<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.1425" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duty of contractor to notify residential property owner of recovery fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agreement or contract for repair, restoration, improvement, or construction to residential real property must contain a written statement explaining the consumer’s rights under the recovery fund, except where the value of all labor and materials does not exceed $2,500. The written statement must be substantially in the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">FLORIDA HOMEOWNERS’ CONSTRUCTION<NewLine />RECOVERY FUND</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">PAYMENT MAY BE AVAILABLE FROM THE FLORIDA HOMEOWNERS’ CONSTRUCTION RECOVERY FUND IF YOU LOSE MONEY ON A PROJECT PERFORMED UNDER CONTRACT, WHERE THE LOSS RESULTS FROM SPECIFIED VIOLATIONS OF FLORIDA LAW BY A LICENSED CONTRACTOR. FOR INFORMATION ABOUT THE RECOVERY FUND AND FILING A CLAIM, CONTACT THE FLORIDA CONSTRUCTION INDUSTRY LICENSING BOARD AT THE FOLLOWING TELEPHONE NUMBER AND ADDRESS:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The statement shall be immediately followed by the board’s address and telephone number as established by board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon finding a first violation of subsection (1), the board may fine the contractor up to $500, and the moneys must be deposited into the recovery fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon finding a second or subsequent violation of subsection (1), the board shall fine the contractor $1,000 per violation, and the moneys must be deposited into the recovery fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 95-240; s. 11, ch. 96-298; s. 73, ch. 96-388; s. 6, ch. 2004-84.</History></Section>