<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.5185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fire alarm system agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified unlimited electrical contractor or licensed fire alarm contractor may not employ a person to perform the duties of a fire alarm system agent unless the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age or has evidence of a court-approved declaration of emancipation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed a minimum of 14 hours of initial training, to include basic fire alarm system technology in addition to related training in National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) codes and standards and access control training, with at least 2 hours of training in the prevention of false alarms. Such training must be from a board-approved provider, and the employee or applicant for employment must provide proof of successful completion to the licensed employer. The board, by rule, shall establish criteria for the approval of training courses and providers. The board shall approve qualified providers that conduct training in other than the English language. The board shall establish a fee for the approval of training providers, not to exceed $200, and a fee for the approval of courses at $25 per credit hour, not to exceed $100 per course.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been convicted within the last 3 years of a crime that directly relates to the business for which employment is being sought. Although the employee is barred from operating as a fire alarm system agent for 3 years subsequent to his or her conviction, the employer shall be supplied the information regarding any convictions occurring prior to that time, and the employer may at his or her discretion consider an earlier conviction to be a bar to employment as a fire alarm system agent. To ensure that this requirement has been met, a certified unlimited electrical contractor or licensed fire alarm contractor must obtain from the Department of Law Enforcement a completed fingerprint and criminal background check for each applicant for employment as a fire alarm system agent or for each individual currently employed on the effective date of this act as a fire alarm system agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been committed for controlled substance abuse or been found guilty of a crime under chapter 893 or any similar law relating to controlled substances in any other state within the 3-year period immediately preceding the date of application for employment, or immediately preceding the effective date of this act for an individual employed as a fire alarm system agent on that date, unless the person establishes that he or she is not currently abusing any controlled substance and has successfully completed a rehabilitation course.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any applicant for employment as a fire alarm system agent, or any individual employed as a fire alarm system agent on the effective date of this act, who has completed alarm system agent or burglar alarm system agent training prior to the effective date of this act in a board-certified program is not required to take additional training in order to comply with the initial training requirements of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state-certified electrical contractor, a state-certified fire alarm system contractor, a state-registered fire alarm system contractor, a journeyman electrician licensed by any local jurisdiction, or an alarm technician licensed by a local jurisdiction that requires an examination and experience or training as licensure qualifications is not required to complete the training required for fire alarm system agents. A state-registered electrical contractor is not required to complete the training required for fire alarm system agents, so long as he or she is only doing electrical work up to the alarm panel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonsupervising employee working as a helper or apprentice under the direct, onsite, continuous supervision of a state-certified electrical contractor, a state-registered electrical contractor, a state-certified fire alarm system contractor, a state-registered fire alarm system contractor, a journeyman electrician licensed by any local jurisdiction, an alarm technician licensed by a local jurisdiction that requires an examination and experience or training as licensure qualifications, or a qualified fire alarm system agent is not required to complete the training otherwise required and is not required to be 18 years of age or older.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A burglar alarm system agent employed by a licensed fire alarm contractor or certified unlimited electrical contractor who has fulfilled all requirements of s. 489.518 prior to the effective date of this act is not required to complete the initial training required by this section for fire alarm system agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who perform only monitoring are not required to complete the training required for fire alarm system agents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for employment as a fire alarm system agent may commence employment, or an individual employed as a fire alarm system agent on the effective date of this act may continue employment, pending completion of both the training and the fingerprint and criminal background checks required by this section, for a period not to exceed 90 days after the date of application for employment or 90 days after the effective date of this act for individuals employed as fire alarm system agents on that date. However, the person must work under the direction and control of a sponsoring certified unlimited electrical contractor or licensed fire alarm contractor until completion of both the training and the fingerprint and criminal background checks. If an applicant or an individual employed on the effective date of this act does not complete the training or receive satisfactory fingerprint and criminal background checks within the 90-day period, the employment must be terminated immediately.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified unlimited electrical contractor or licensed fire alarm contractor must furnish each of his or her fire alarm system agents with an identification card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The card shall follow a board-approved format, to include a picture of the agent; shall specify at least the name of the holder of the card and the name and license number of the certified unlimited electrical contractor or licensed fire alarm contractor; and shall be signed by both the contractor and the holder of the card. Each identification card shall be valid for a period of 2 years after the date of issuance. The identification card must be in the possession of the fire alarm system agent while engaged in fire alarm system agent duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person to whom an identification card has been issued is responsible for the safekeeping thereof, and may not loan, or allow any other person to use or display, the identification card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each identification card must be renewed every 2 years and in a board-approved format to show compliance with the 6 hours of continuing education necessary to maintain certification as a fire alarm system agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed electrical or alarm system contractor must obtain an updated criminal background check from the Department of Law Enforcement for each fire alarm system agent who renews certification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each fire alarm system agent must receive 6 hours of continuing education on fire alarm system installation and repair and false alarm prevention every 2 years from a board-approved sponsor of training and through a board-approved training course.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with any of the provisions of this section shall be grounds for disciplinary action against the contractor pursuant to s. 489.533.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 98-170; s. 50, ch. 98-419; s. 40, ch. 2000-372; s. 3, ch. 2004-76.</History></Section>