<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.554" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration renewal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe by rule the method for approving continuing education courses, for renewing annual registration, for approving inactive status for the late filing of a renewal application, for allowing a contractor to hold a registration in inactive status for a specified period, and for reactivating a registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a minimum, annual renewal shall include continuing education requirements of not less than 12 classroom hours annually for septic tank contractors and not less than 18 classroom hours annually for master septic tank contractors. The 18 classroom hours of continuing education required for master septic tank contractors may include the 12 classroom hours required for septic tank contractors, but at a minimum must include 6 classroom hours of approved master septic tank contractor coursework.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of registration becomes inactive when a renewal application is not filed in a timely manner. A certificate that has become inactive may be reactivated under this section by application to the department. A licensed contractor may apply to the department for voluntary inactive status at any time during the period of registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A master septic tank contractor may elect to revert to the status of a registered septic tank contractor at any time during the period of registration. The department shall prescribe by rule the method for a master septic tank contractor who has reverted to the status of a registered septic tank contractor to apply for status as a master septic tank contractor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny an application for renewal if the applicant has failed to pay any administrative penalty imposed by the department if the penalty is final agency action and all judicial reviews have been exhausted.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 10, ch. 87-310; s. 55, ch. 91-297; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 8, ch. 96-303; s. 5, ch. 98-420; s. 47, ch. 2004-350; s. 7, ch. 2006-252.</History></Section>