<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.117" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration; specialty contractors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person engaged in the business of a contractor as defined in s. 489.105(3)(a)-(o) must be registered before engaging in business as a contractor in this state, unless he or she is certified. To be initially registered, the applicant shall submit the required fee and file evidence of successful compliance with the local examination and licensing requirements, if any, in the area for which registration is desired. An examination is not required for registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration allows the registrant to engage in contracting only in the counties, municipalities, or development districts where he or she has complied with all local licensing requirements and only for the type of work covered by the registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each registrant shall report to the board each local jurisdiction and each category of registration in which the registrant holds a certificate of competency or license, or where the registrant has been granted a certificate of competency or license by reciprocal agreement, for which registration is required by this part, within 30 days after obtaining such certificate or license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No new registration may be issued by the board after July 1, 1993, based on any certificate of competency or license for a category of contractor defined in s. 489.105(3)(a)-(o) which is issued by a municipal or county government that does not exercise disciplinary control and oversight over such locally licensed contractors, including forwarding a recommended order in each action to the board as provided in s. 489.131(7). For purposes of this subsection and s. 489.131(10), the board shall determine the adequacy of such disciplinary control by reviewing the local government’s ability to process and investigate complaints and to take disciplinary action against locally licensed contractors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon findings of fact supporting the need therefor, the board may grant a limited nonrenewable registration to a contractor not domiciled in the state, for one project. During the period of such registration the board may require compliance with this and any other statute of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for a temporary registration shall constitute appointment of the Department of State as an agent of the applicant for service of process in any action or proceeding against the applicant arising out of any transaction or operation connected with or incidental to the practice of contracting for which the temporary license was issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person holding a local license whose job scope does not substantially correspond to either the job scope of one of the contractor categories defined in s. 489.105(3)(a)-(o), or the job scope of one of the certified specialty contractor categories established by board rule, is not required to register with the board to perform contracting activities within the scope of such specialty license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local jurisdictions are responsible for providing the following information to the board within 30 days after licensure of, or any disciplinary action against, a locally licensed contractor who is registered under this part:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Code violation information pursuant to s. 553.781.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary information.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The board shall maintain such licensure and disciplinary information as it is provided to the board and shall make the information available through the automated information system provided pursuant to s. 455.2286.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing discipline to such locally licensed contractors is the responsibility of the local jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is not required to obtain registration or certification pursuant to s. 489.105(3)(d)-(o) may perform contracting services for the construction, remodeling, repair, or improvement of single-family residences, including a townhouse as defined in the Florida Building Code, without obtaining a local license if such person is under the supervision of a certified or registered general, building, or residential contractor. As used in this paragraph, supervision shall not be deemed to require the existence of a direct contract between the certified or registered general, building, or residential contractor and the person performing specialty contracting services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 17, ch. 79-200; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 9, 20, 21, ch. 88-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 92-55; s. 61, ch. 92-149; s. 3, ch. 93-154; s. 12, ch. 93-166; s. 262, ch. 94-119; s. 483, ch. 97-103; s. 22, ch. 98-287; s. 1, ch. 99-254; s. 5, ch. 2003-257; s. 30, ch. 2009-195.</History></Section>