<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.537" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application of this part.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part applies to any contractor performing work for the state or any county or municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope of electrical contracting shall apply to private and public property and shall include any excavation, paving, and other related work incidental thereto and shall include the work of all specialty electrical contractors. However, such electrical contractor shall subcontract the work of any other craft for which an examination for a certificate of competency or registration or a license is required, unless such contractor is certified or registered or holds a license for the respective trade category as required by the appropriate local authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered electrical contractor may bid on electrical contracts which include alarm systems contracting as a part of the contract, provided that the individual shall subcontract such alarm systems contracting, except raceway systems, to a properly certified or registered alarm system contractor. Registered electrical contractors may install raceways for alarm systems. However, if the registered electrical contractor is properly certified or registered as an alarm system contractor, the individual is not required to subcontract out the alarm system contracting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act limits the power of a municipality or county:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To regulate the quality and character of work performed by contractors through a system of permits, fees, and inspections which is designed to secure compliance with, and aid in the implementation of, state and local building laws or to enforce other local laws for the protection of the public health and safety. However, a certified alarm system contractor or certified electrical contractor is not subject to any additional certification or licensure requirements that are not required by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To collect fees for business tax receipts and inspections for engaging in contracting or examination fees from persons who are registered with the local boards pursuant to local examination requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt any system of permits requiring submission to and approval by the municipality or county of plans and specifications for work to be performed by contractors before commencement of the work.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require one bond for each electrical contractor in an amount not to exceed $5,000, which bond shall be conditioned only upon compliance with the Florida Building Code adopted pursuant to s. 553.73. Any such bond must be equally available to all electrical contractors without regard to the period of time an electrical contractor has been certified or registered and without regard to any financial responsibility requirements. Any such bonds shall be payable to the Governor and filed in each county or municipality in which a building permit is requested. Bond reciprocity shall be granted statewide. All such bonds shall be included in meeting any financial responsibility requirements imposed by any statute or rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refuse to issue permits or issue permits with specific conditions to a contractor who has committed multiple violations, when he or she has been disciplined for each of them by the board and when each disciplinary action has involved revocation or suspension of a license, imposition of an administrative fine of at least $1,000, or probation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue permits with specific conditions to a contractor who, within the previous 12 months, has had final action taken against him or her, by the department or by a local board or agency which licenses contractors and has reported the action pursuant to paragraph (5)(c), for engaging in the business or acting in the capacity of a contractor without a license.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require that one electrical journeyman, who is a graduate of the Institute of Applied Technology in Construction Excellence or licensed pursuant to s. 489.5335, be present on an industrial or commercial new construction site with a facility of 50,000 gross square feet or more when electrical work in excess of 77 volts is being performed in order to supervise or perform such work, except as provided in s. 489.503.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any official authorized to issue building or other related permits shall ascertain that the applicant contractor is certified or registered and duly qualified according to any local requirements in the area where the construction is to take place before issuing the permit. The evidence shall consist only of the exhibition to him or her of current evidence of proper certification or registration and local qualification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Municipalities or counties may continue to provide examinations for their territorial area, provided that no examination is given the holder of a certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To engage in contracting in the territorial area, an applicant shall also be registered with the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local board or agency which licenses contractors shall transmit monthly to the board a report of any disciplinary action taken against contractors and any administrative or disciplinary action taken against unlicensed persons for engaging in the business or acting in the capacity of a contractor, including any cease and desist order issued pursuant to s. 489.516(2)(b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to create local boards in the future by any municipality or county is preserved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope of work of a certified unlimited electrical contractor includes the work of a certified alarm system contractor as provided in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons licensed under this part are subject to ss. 205.0535(1) and 205.065, as applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered electrical contractor, an alarm system contractor II certificateholder, and a registered alarm system contractor II shall be allowed to install residential smoke detectors or residential heat detectors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 17, ch. 79-272; s. 374, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 87-152; ss. 10, 14, ch. 87-254; ss. 19, 21, 23, ch. 88-149; s. 8, ch. 91-119; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 284, ch. 94-119; s. 500, ch. 97-103; s. 31, ch. 98-287; s. 47, ch. 98-419; s. 26, ch. 99-254; s. 127, ch. 2000-141; s. 23, ch. 2000-332; s. 45, ch. 2000-372; ss. 20, 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372; s. 6, ch. 2005-147; s. 45, ch. 2009-195.</History></Section>