<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.522" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifying agents; responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualifying agent is a primary qualifying agent unless he or she is a secondary qualifying agent under this section. All primary qualifying agents for a business organization are jointly and equally responsible for supervision of all operations of the business organization; for all field work at all sites; and for financial matters, both for the organization in general and for each specific job.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a qualifying agent ceases to qualify a business, the qualifying agent must transfer the license to another business, qualify himself or herself as an individual, or place the license in an inactive status within 60 days after termination of the qualifying status with the business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One of the qualifying agents for a business organization that has more than one qualifying agent may be designated as the sole primary qualifying agent for the business organization by a joint agreement that is executed, on a form provided by the board, by all qualifying agents for the business organization. The joint agreement shall be submitted to the board for approval. If the board determines that the joint agreement is in good order, it shall approve the designation and immediately notify the qualifying agents of such approval. The designation made by the joint agreement is effective upon receipt of the notice by the qualifying agents. The qualifying agent designated for a business organization by a joint agreement is the sole primary qualifying agent for the business organization, and all other qualifying agents for the business organization are secondary qualifying agents.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designated sole primary qualifying agent has all the responsibilities and duties of a primary qualifying agent, notwithstanding that there are secondary qualifying agents for specified jobs. The designated sole primary qualifying agent is jointly and equally responsible with secondary qualifying agents for field work supervision.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secondary qualifying agent is responsible only for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervision of field work at sites where his or her license was used to obtain the building permit; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other work for which he or she accepts responsibility.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A secondary qualifying agent is not responsible for supervision of financial matters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A primary qualifying agent shall have approval authority for checks, payments, drafts, and contracts issued by or entered into by the business organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualifying agent who has been designated by a joint agreement as the sole primary qualifying agent for a business organization may terminate this status as such by giving actual notice to the business organization, to the board, and to all secondary qualifying agents of his or her intention to terminate this status. The notice to the board shall include proof satisfactory to the board that he or she has given the notice required in this paragraph. The status of the qualifying agent shall cease upon the designation of a new primary qualifying agent or 60 days after satisfactory notice of termination has been provided to the board, whichever first occurs. If no new primary qualifying agent has been designated within 60 days, all secondary qualifying agents for the business organization shall become primary qualifying agents, unless the joint agreement specifies that one or more of them shall become sole qualifying agents under such circumstances, in which case only they shall become sole qualifying agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in the status of a qualifying agent is prospective only. A qualifying agent is not responsible for his or her predecessor’s actions, but is responsible, even after a change in status, for matters for which he or she was responsible while in a particular status.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 23, ch. 88-149; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 281, ch. 94-119; s. 496, ch. 97-103; s. 41, ch. 2000-372.</History></Section>