<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who desires to be certified shall apply to the department in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall be eligible for licensure by examination if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of good moral character; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets eligibility requirements according to one of the following criteria:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a baccalaureate degree from an accredited 4-year college in the appropriate field of engineering, architecture, or building construction and has 1 year of proven experience in the category in which the person seeks to qualify. For the purpose of this part, a minimum of 2,000 person-hours shall be used in determining full-time equivalency.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a total of at least 4 years of active experience as a worker who has learned the trade by serving an apprenticeship as a skilled worker who is able to command the rate of a mechanic in the particular trade or as a foreman who is in charge of a group of workers and usually is responsible to a superintendent or a contractor or his or her equivalent, provided, however, that at least 1 year of active experience shall be as a foreman.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a combination of not less than 1 year of experience as a foreman and not less than 3 years of credits for any accredited college-level courses; has a combination of not less than 1 year of experience as a skilled worker, 1 year of experience as a foreman, and not less than 2 years of credits for any accredited college-level courses; or has a combination of not less than 2 years of experience as a skilled worker, 1 year of experience as a foreman, and not less than 1 year of credits for any accredited college-level courses. All junior college or community college-level courses shall be considered accredited college-level courses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified residential contractor is eligible to take the building contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 3 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified residential contractor is eligible to take the general contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 4 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified building contractor is eligible to take the general contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 4 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified air-conditioning Class C contractor is eligible to take the air-conditioning Class B contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 3 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified air-conditioning Class C contractor is eligible to take the air-conditioning Class A contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 4 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified air-conditioning Class B contractor is eligible to take the air-conditioning Class A contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 1 year of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified swimming pool servicing contractor is eligible to take the residential swimming pool contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 3 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified swimming pool servicing contractor is eligible to take the swimming pool commercial contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 4 years of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active certified residential swimming pool contractor is eligible to take the commercial swimming pool contractors’ examination if he or she possesses a minimum of 1 year of proven experience in the classification in which he or she is certified.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant is eligible to take the swimming pool/spa servicing contractors’ examination if he or she has satisfactorily completed 60 hours of instruction in courses related to the scope of work covered by that license and approved by the Construction Industry Licensing Board by rule and has at least 1 year of proven experience related to the scope of work of such a contractor.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to certify an applicant for failure to satisfy the requirement of good moral character only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a substantial connection between the lack of good moral character of the applicant and the professional responsibilities of a certified contractor; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The finding by the board of lack of good moral character is supported by clear and convincing evidence.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an applicant is found to be unqualified for a certificate because of a lack of good moral character, the board shall furnish the applicant a statement containing the findings of the board, a complete record of the evidence upon which the determination was based, and a notice of the rights of the applicant to a rehearing and appeal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure that a sensitivity review committee has been established including representatives of various ethnic/minority groups. No question found by this committee to be discriminatory against any ethnic/minority group shall be included in the examination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 17, ch. 79-200; s. 369, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 20, 21, ch. 88-156; s. 12, ch. 89-162; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 480, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 97-228; s. 1, ch. 2001-117; s. 7, ch. 2002-392.</History></Section>