<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0489.109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, shall establish reasonable fees to be paid for applications, certification and renewal, registration and renewal, and recordmaking and recordkeeping. The fees shall be established as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an applicant for a certificate, the initial application fee may not exceed $150, and, if an examination cost is included in the application fee, the combined amount may not exceed $350. The initial certification fee and the renewal fee may not exceed $250. However, any applicant who seeks certification under this part by taking a practical examination must pay as an examination fee the actual cost incurred by the department in developing, preparing, administering, scoring, score reporting, and evaluating the examination, if the examination is conducted by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an applicant for registration, the initial application fee may not exceed $100, and the initial registration fee and the renewal fee may not exceed $200.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, may establish delinquency fees, not to exceed the applicable renewal fee for renewal applications made after the expiration date of the certificate or registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an application for registration or certification to qualify a business organization, the initial application fee and the renewal fee shall be $50.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, shall impose a renewal fee for an inactive status certificate or registration, not to exceed the renewal fee for an active status certificate or registration. Neither the inactive certification fee nor the inactive registration fee may exceed $50. The board, by rule, may provide for a different fee for inactive status where such status is sought by a building code administrator, plans examiner, or inspector certified pursuant to part XII of chapter 468 who is employed by a local government and is not allowed by the terms of such employment to maintain a certificate on active status issued pursuant to this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, shall impose an additional late fee on a delinquent status certificateholder or registrant when such certificateholder or registrant applies for active or inactive status.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, shall impose an additional fee, not to exceed the applicable renewal fee, which reasonably reflects the costs of processing a certificateholder’s or registrant’s request to change licensure status at any time other than at the beginning of a licensure cycle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall establish fees that are adequate to ensure the continued operation of the board. Fees shall be based on department estimates of the revenue required to implement this part and the provisions of law with respect to the regulation of the construction industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the fees provided in subsection (1) for application and renewal for certification and registration, all certificateholders and registrants must pay a fee of $4 to the department at the time of application or renewal. The funds must be transferred at the end of each licensing period to the department to fund projects relating to the building construction industry or continuing education programs offered to persons engaged in the building construction industry in Florida, to be selected by the Florida Building Commission. The board shall, at the time the funds are transferred, advise the department on the most needed areas of research or continuing education based on significant changes in the industry’s practices or on changes in the state building code or on the most common types of consumer complaints or on problems costing the state or local governmental entities substantial waste. The board’s advice is not binding on the department. The department shall ensure the distribution of research reports and the availability of continuing education programs to all segments of the building construction industry to which they relate. The department shall report to the board in October of each year, summarizing the allocation of the funds by institution and summarizing the new projects funded and the status of previously funded projects.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 17, ch. 79-200; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 20, 21, ch. 88-156; s. 35, ch. 88-205; s. 1, ch. 89-5; s. 62, ch. 89-162; s. 31, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 58, ch. 92-149; s. 7, ch. 93-166; s. 258, ch. 94-119; s. 4, ch. 97-228; s. 12, ch. 99-254; s. 40, ch. 2000-141; s. 27, ch. 2009-195; s. 405, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>