<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0489.515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of certificates; registrations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a certificate to a person who the board certifies is qualified to become a certified contractor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify as qualified for certification any person who satisfies the requirements of s. 489.511 and who submits satisfactory evidence that he or she has obtained both workers’ compensation insurance or an acceptable exemption certificate issued by the department and public liability and property damage insurance for the health, safety, and welfare of the public in amounts determined by rule of the board, and furnishes evidence of financial responsibility, credit, and business reputation of either himself or herself or the business organization he or she desires to qualify.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon compliance with the provisions of this section and payment of the certification fee, the department shall issue the person a certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a registration to a person who is in compliance with the provisions of s. 489.513 and who the board certifies is qualified to be registered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a prerequisite to the initial issuance or the renewal of a certificate or registration, the applicant shall submit an affidavit on a form provided by the board attesting to the fact that the applicant has obtained both workers’ compensation insurance or an acceptable exemption certificate issued by the department and public liability and property damage insurance for the health, safety, and welfare of the public in amounts determined by rule of the board. The board shall by rule establish a procedure to verify the accuracy of such affidavits based upon a random audit method.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for initial issuance of a certificate or registration shall submit as a prerequisite to qualifying for an exemption from workers’ compensation coverage requirements under s. 440.05 an affidavit attesting to the fact that the applicant will obtain an exemption within 30 days after the date the initial certificate or registration is issued by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to certify any applicant who has violated any of the provisions of s. 489.533.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate or registration is not transferable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 17, ch. 79-272; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 7, 14, ch. 87-254; ss. 7, 21, 23, ch. 88-149; s. 6, ch. 91-119; s. 44, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 51, ch. 92-149; s. 275, ch. 94-119; s. 493, ch. 97-103; s. 47, ch. 2000-372; s. 33, ch. 2001-91; s. 32, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>