<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0361.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of eminent domain to coal pipeline companies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the purpose of adopting this section to provide eminent domain powers and related benefits to certain firms is to make available low-cost electric power to all residents of the state and that this section should be construed consistently with this public interest policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation, partnership, joint venture, association, or other legal entity organized under the laws of this state, or under the laws of any other state and qualified to do business in this state, for the purpose of supplying any electric utility or utilities; any city, town, or village or the inhabitants thereof; or any community with coal or its derivatives and any mixture and combination thereof by pipeline, and for the purpose of serving as a common carrier operating or proposing to operate a pipeline or pipelines for transporting or delivering coal or its derivatives or any mixture or combination thereof, shall have the right of eminent domain, for the purpose of acquiring title, easements, rights-of-way, or other rights or interests in property, necessary to acquire and take private property which is or may be needed for the construction, operation, maintenance, repair, or replacement of coal slurry and derivative plants, pipelines, pumping stations, and any other installations and works incident thereto. The procedure to condemn property or interest therein shall be exercised in the manner set forth in chapters 73 and 74. In any condemnation proceeding under this act, the circuit court shall restrict the exercise of the right of eminent domain in the following particulars:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of eminent domain shall be limited to the taking of property or an interest therein from the owner which results in the least property or interest therein being taken to effect the purpose of the condemning entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All takings shall be subject to the legal obligation (which shall become a restrictive covenant on the property or interest therein taken) on the part of the condemning authority and its successor in title or interest, jointly and severally, to convey the title or property interest taken to the condemnee or the condemnee’s heirs, successors, or assigns if the condemned property or interest therein is not used within a reasonable time after the taking, which time limit shall be fixed by the court in the condemnation proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the property or interest therein is conveyed to the condemnee or to the condemnee’s heirs, successors, or assigns, the grantee of such conveyance shall pay or cause to be paid to the condemning authority or to its successor in title or interest, as the case may be, consideration, in cash, which shall be equal to the value of the condemned property or interest therein being conveyed, as determined as of the time of the taking, discounted at a rate of 10 percent per year, compounded annually, from the date of the taking to the date of the conveyance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-236; s. 546, ch. 95-148; s. 9, ch. 2006-214.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 5, ch. 79-236, provides that “[t]his act shall take effect when every state in which the coal slurry pipeline will pass en route to Florida has enacted laws granting eminent domain authority to coal slurry pipeline companies or other entities operating or proposing to operate a coal slurry pipeline, and when the appropriate governmental authority has guaranteed in writing to the Public Service Commission that a continuous source of water shall be available for use in said coal slurry pipeline.”</Text></Note></Section>