<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0361.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project” means a joint electric power supply project and any and all facilities, including all equipment, structures, machinery, and tangible and intangible property, real and personal, for the joint generation or transmission of electrical energy, or both, including any fuel supply or source useful for such a project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electric utility” means any municipality, authority, commission, or other public body, investor-owned electric utility, or rural electric cooperative which owns, maintains, or operates an electrical energy generation, transmission, or distribution system within the state on June 25, 1975.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any natural person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States; any state; any municipality, political subdivision, or municipal corporation created by or pursuant to the laws of the United States or any state; or any board, corporation, or other entity or body declared by or pursuant to the laws of the United States or any state to be a department, agency, or instrumentality of any thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation, not-for-profit corporation, firm, partnership, cooperative association, electric cooperative, or business trust of any nature whatsoever organized and existing under the laws of the United States or any state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any foreign country; any political subdivision or governmental unit of a foreign country; or any corporation, not-for-profit corporation, firm, partnership, cooperative association, electric cooperative, or business trust of any nature whatsoever organized and existing under the laws of a foreign country or of a political subdivision or governmental unit of a foreign country.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign public utility” means any person, as defined in subsection (3), the principal location or principal place of business of which is not located within this state, which owns, maintains, or operates facilities for the generation, transmission, or distribution of electrical energy and which supplies electricity to retail or wholesale customers, or both, on a continuous, reliable, and dependable basis; or any affiliate or subsidiary of such person, the business of which is limited to the generation or transmission, or both, of electrical energy and activities reasonably incidental thereto.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 75-200; s. 3, ch. 82-53.</History></Section>