<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0768.1325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cardiac Arrest Survival Act; immunity from civil liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Cardiac Arrest Survival Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Perceived medical emergency” means circumstances in which the behavior of an individual leads a reasonable person to believe that the individual is experiencing a life-threatening medical condition that requires an immediate medical response regarding the heart or other cardiopulmonary functioning of the individual.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automated external defibrillator device” means a lifesaving defibrillator device that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is commercially distributed in accordance with the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is capable of recognizing the presence or absence of ventricular fibrillation, and is capable of determining without intervention by the user of the device whether defibrillation should be performed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determining that defibrillation should be performed, is able to deliver an electrical shock to an individual.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Harm” means damage or loss of any and all types, including, but not limited to, physical, nonphysical, economic, noneconomic, actual, compensatory, consequential, incidental, and punitive damages or losses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, and except as provided in subsection (4), any person who uses or attempts to use an automated external defibrillator device on a victim of a perceived medical emergency, without objection of the victim of the perceived medical emergency, is immune from civil liability for any harm resulting from the use or attempted use of such device. In addition, notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, and except as provided in subsection (4), any person who acquired the device and makes it available for use, including, but not limited to, a community association organized under chapter 617, chapter 718, chapter 719, chapter 720, chapter 721, or chapter 723, is immune from such liability, if the harm was not due to the failure of such person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Properly maintain and test the device; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide appropriate training in the use of the device to an employee or agent of the acquirer when the employee or agent was the person who used the device on the victim, except that such requirement of training does not apply if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The device is equipped with audible, visual, or written instructions on its use, including any such visual or written instructions posted on or adjacent to the device;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee or agent was not an employee or agent who would have been reasonably expected to use the device; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The period of time elapsing between the engagement of the person as an employee or agent and the occurrence of the harm, or between the acquisition of the device and the occurrence of the harm in any case in which the device was acquired after engagement of the employee or agent, was not a reasonably sufficient period in which to provide the training.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immunity under subsection (3) does not apply to a person if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The harm involved was caused by that person’s willful or criminal misconduct, gross negligence, reckless disregard or misconduct, or a conscious, flagrant indifference to the rights or safety of the victim who was harmed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is a licensed or certified health professional who used the automated external defibrillator device while acting within the scope of the license or certification of the professional and within the scope of the employment or agency of the professional;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is a hospital, clinic, or other entity whose primary purpose is providing health care directly to patients, and the harm was caused by an employee or agent of the entity who used the device while acting within the scope of the employment or agency of the employee or agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is an acquirer of the device who leased the device to a health care entity, or who otherwise provided the device to such entity for compensation without selling the device to the entity, and the harm was caused by an employee or agent of the entity who used the device while acting within the scope of the employment or agency of the employee or agent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is the manufacturer of the device.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not establish any cause of action. This section does not require that an automated external defibrillator device be placed at any building or other location or require an acquirer to make available on its premises one or more employees or agents trained in the use of the device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may not require an acquirer of an automated external defibrillator device which is a community association organized under chapter 617, chapter 718, chapter 719, chapter 720, chapter 721, or chapter 723 to purchase medical malpractice liability coverage as a condition of issuing any other coverage carried by the association, and an insurer may not exclude damages resulting from the use of an automated external defibrillator device from coverage under a general liability policy issued to an association.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-76; s. 3, ch. 2004-345; s. 3, ch. 2004-353; s. 3, ch. 2006-206; s. 2, ch. 2008-101.</History></Section>