<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0768.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Damages.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All potential beneficiaries of a recovery for wrongful death, including the decedent’s estate, shall be identified in the complaint, and their relationships to the decedent shall be alleged. Damages may be awarded as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each survivor may recover the value of lost support and services from the date of the decedent’s injury to her or his death, with interest, and future loss of support and services from the date of death and reduced to present value. In evaluating loss of support and services, the survivor’s relationship to the decedent, the amount of the decedent’s probable net income available for distribution to the particular survivor, and the replacement value of the decedent’s services to the survivor may be considered. In computing the duration of future losses, the joint life expectancies of the survivor and the decedent and the period of minority, in the case of healthy minor children, may be considered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surviving spouse may also recover for loss of the decedent’s companionship and protection and for mental pain and suffering from the date of injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minor children of the decedent, and all children of the decedent if there is no surviving spouse, may also recover for lost parental companionship, instruction, and guidance and for mental pain and suffering from the date of injury. For the purposes of this subsection, if both spouses die within 30 days of one another as a result of the same wrongful act or series of acts arising out of the same incident, each spouse is considered to have been predeceased by the other.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each parent of a deceased minor child may also recover for mental pain and suffering from the date of injury. Each parent of an adult child may also recover for mental pain and suffering if there are no other survivors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical or funeral expenses due to the decedent’s injury or death may be recovered by a survivor who has paid them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decedent’s personal representative may recover for the decedent’s estate the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss of earnings of the deceased from the date of injury to the date of death, less lost support of survivors excluding contributions in kind, with interest. Loss of the prospective net accumulations of an estate, which might reasonably have been expected but for the wrongful death, reduced to present money value, may also be recovered:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the decedent’s survivors include a surviving spouse or lineal descendants; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the decedent is not a minor child as defined in s. 768.18(2), there are no lost support and services recoverable under subsection (1), and there is a surviving parent.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical or funeral expenses due to the decedent’s injury or death that have become a charge against her or his estate or that were paid by or on behalf of decedent, excluding amounts recoverable under subsection (5).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of remarriage of the decedent’s spouse is admissible.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All awards for the decedent’s estate are subject to the claims of creditors who have complied with the requirements of probate law concerning claims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The damages specified in subsection (3) shall not be recoverable by adult children and the damages specified in subsection (4) shall not be recoverable by parents of an adult child with respect to claims for medical negligence as defined by s. 766.106(1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-35; s. 2, ch. 81-183; s. 1, ch. 85-260; s. 2, ch. 90-14; s. 1169, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 2002-44; s. 66, ch. 2003-416.</History></Section>