<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0768.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Volunteer team physicians; immunity.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A volunteer team physician is any person licensed to practice medicine pursuant to chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is acting in the capacity of a volunteer team physician in attendance at an athletic event sponsored by a public or private elementary or secondary school; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who gratuitously and in good faith prior to the athletic event agrees to render emergency care or treatment to any participant in such event in connection with an emergency arising during or as the result of such event, without objection of such participant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A volunteer team physician is not liable for any civil damages as a result of such care or treatment or as a result of any act or failure to act in providing or arranging further medical treatment unless the care or treatment was rendered in a wrongful manner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or s. 464.012 who gratuitously and in good faith conducts an evaluation pursuant to s. 1006.20(2)(c) is not liable for any civil damages arising from that evaluation unless the evaluation was conducted in a wrongful manner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “wrongful manner” means in bad faith or with malicious purpose or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property, and shall be construed in conformity with the standard set forth in s. 768.28(9)(a).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-263; s. 483, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 88-257; s. 15, ch. 2011-233.</History>
</Section>