<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0768.79" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offer of judgment and demand for judgment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil action for damages filed in the courts of this state, if a defendant files an offer of judgment which is not accepted by the plaintiff within 30 days, the defendant shall be entitled to recover reasonable costs and attorney’s fees incurred by her or him or on the defendant’s behalf pursuant to a policy of liability insurance or other contract from the date of filing of the offer if the judgment is one of no liability or the judgment obtained by the plaintiff is at least 25 percent less than such offer, and the court shall set off such costs and attorney’s fees against the award. Where such costs and attorney’s fees total more than the judgment, the court shall enter judgment for the defendant against the plaintiff for the amount of the costs and fees, less the amount of the plaintiff’s award. If a plaintiff files a demand for judgment which is not accepted by the defendant within 30 days and the plaintiff recovers a judgment in an amount at least 25 percent greater than the offer, she or he shall be entitled to recover reasonable costs and attorney’s fees incurred from the date of the filing of the demand. If rejected, neither an offer nor demand is admissible in subsequent litigation, except for pursuing the penalties of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making of an offer of settlement which is not accepted does not preclude the making of a subsequent offer. An offer must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be in writing and state that it is being made pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name the party making it and the party to whom it is being made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State with particularity the amount offered to settle a claim for punitive damages, if any.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State its total amount.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The offer shall be construed as including all damages which may be awarded in a final judgment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offer shall be served upon the party to whom it is made, but it shall not be filed unless it is accepted or unless filing is necessary to enforce the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offer shall be accepted by filing a written acceptance with the court within 30 days after service. Upon filing of both the offer and acceptance, the court has full jurisdiction to enforce the settlement agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offer may be withdrawn in writing which is served before the date a written acceptance is filed. Once withdrawn, an offer is void.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon motion made by the offeror within 30 days after the entry of judgment or after voluntary or involuntary dismissal, the court shall determine the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a defendant serves an offer which is not accepted by the plaintiff, and if the judgment obtained by the plaintiff is at least 25 percent less than the amount of the offer, the defendant shall be awarded reasonable costs, including investigative expenses, and attorney’s fees, calculated in accordance with the guidelines promulgated by the Supreme Court, incurred from the date the offer was served, and the court shall set off such costs in attorney’s fees against the award. When such costs and attorney’s fees total more than the amount of the judgment, the court shall enter judgment for the defendant against the plaintiff for the amount of the costs and fees, less the amount of the award to the plaintiff.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a plaintiff serves an offer which is not accepted by the defendant, and if the judgment obtained by the plaintiff is at least 25 percent more than the amount of the offer, the plaintiff shall be awarded reasonable costs, including investigative expenses, and attorney’s fees, calculated in accordance with the guidelines promulgated by the Supreme Court, incurred from the date the offer was served.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of the determination required by paragraph (a), the term “judgment obtained” means the amount of the net judgment entered, plus any postoffer collateral source payments received or due as of the date of the judgment, plus any postoffer settlement amounts by which the verdict was reduced. For purposes of the determination required by paragraph (b), the term “judgment obtained” means the amount of the net judgment entered, plus any postoffer settlement amounts by which the verdict was reduced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a party is entitled to costs and fees pursuant to the provisions of this section, the court may, in its discretion, determine that an offer was not made in good faith. In such case, the court may disallow an award of costs and attorney’s fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When determining the reasonableness of an award of attorney’s fees pursuant to this section, the court shall consider, along with all other relevant criteria, the following additional factors:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The then apparent merit or lack of merit in the claim.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and nature of offers made by the parties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The closeness of questions of fact and law at issue.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the person making the offer had unreasonably refused to furnish information necessary to evaluate the reasonableness of such offer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the suit was in the nature of a test case presenting questions of far-reaching importance affecting nonparties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the additional delay cost and expense that the person making the offer reasonably would be expected to incur if the litigation should be prolonged.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of an offer is admissible only in proceedings to enforce an accepted offer or to determine the imposition of sanctions under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 58, ch. 86-160; s. 48, ch. 90-119; s. 1175, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>