<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.1105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of a patient.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care provider or facility that refuses to comply with a patient’s advance directive, or the treatment decision of his or her surrogate, shall make reasonable efforts to transfer the patient to another health care provider or facility that will comply with the directive or treatment decision. This chapter does not require a health care provider or facility to commit any act which is contrary to the provider’s or facility’s moral or ethical beliefs, if the patient:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not in an emergency condition; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received written information upon admission informing the patient of the policies of the health care provider or facility regarding such moral or ethical beliefs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care provider or facility that is unwilling to carry out the wishes of the patient or the treatment decision of his or her surrogate because of moral or ethical beliefs must within 7 days either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transfer the patient to another health care provider or facility. The health care provider or facility shall pay the costs for transporting the patient to another health care provider or facility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the patient has not been transferred, carry out the wishes of the patient or the patient’s surrogate, unless the provisions of s. 765.105 apply.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 92-199; s. 11, ch. 94-183; s. 1148, ch. 97-102; s. 30, ch. 99-331.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 765.308.</Text></Note></Section>