<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designation of a health care surrogate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written document designating a surrogate to make health care decisions for a principal shall be signed by the principal in the presence of two subscribing adult witnesses. A principal unable to sign the instrument may, in the presence of witnesses, direct that another person sign the principal’s name as required herein. An exact copy of the instrument shall be provided to the surrogate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person designated as surrogate shall not act as witness to the execution of the document designating the health care surrogate. At least one person who acts as a witness shall be neither the principal’s spouse nor blood relative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A document designating a health care surrogate may also designate an alternate surrogate provided the designation is explicit. The alternate surrogate may assume his or her duties as surrogate for the principal if the original surrogate is unwilling or unable to perform his or her duties. The principal’s failure to designate an alternate surrogate shall not invalidate the designation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If neither the designated surrogate nor the designated alternate surrogate is able or willing to make health care decisions on behalf of the principal and in accordance with the principal’s instructions, the health care facility may seek the appointment of a proxy pursuant to part IV.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A principal may designate a separate surrogate to consent to mental health treatment in the event that the principal is determined by a court to be incompetent to consent to mental health treatment and a guardian advocate is appointed as provided under s. 394.4598. However, unless the document designating the health care surrogate expressly states otherwise, the court shall assume that the health care surrogate authorized to make health care decisions under this chapter is also the principal’s choice to make decisions regarding mental health treatment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the document states a time of termination, the designation shall remain in effect until revoked by the principal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written designation of a health care surrogate executed pursuant to this section establishes a rebuttable presumption of clear and convincing evidence of the principal’s designation of the surrogate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 92-199; s. 8, ch. 94-183; s. 49, ch. 96-169; s. 1797, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>