<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advance directive” means a witnessed written document or oral statement in which instructions are given by a principal or in which the principal’s desires are expressed concerning any aspect of the principal’s health care, and includes, but is not limited to, the designation of a health care surrogate, a living will, or an anatomical gift made pursuant to part V of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Attending physician” means the primary physician who has responsibility for the treatment and care of the patient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Close personal friend” means any person 18 years of age or older who has exhibited special care and concern for the patient, and who presents an affidavit to the health care facility or to the attending or treating physician stating that he or she is a friend of the patient; is willing and able to become involved in the patient’s health care; and has maintained such regular contact with the patient so as to be familiar with the patient’s activities, health, and religious or moral beliefs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“End-stage condition” means an irreversible condition that is caused by injury, disease, or illness which has resulted in progressively severe and permanent deterioration, and which, to a reasonable degree of medical probability, treatment of the condition would be ineffective.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care decision” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Informed consent, refusal of consent, or withdrawal of consent to any and all health care, including life-prolonging procedures and mental health treatment, unless otherwise stated in the advance directives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision to apply for private, public, government, or veterans’ benefits to defray the cost of health care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of access to all records of the principal reasonably necessary for a health care surrogate to make decisions involving health care and to apply for benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision to make an anatomical gift pursuant to part V of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care facility” means a hospital, nursing home, hospice, home health agency, or health maintenance organization licensed in this state, or any facility subject to part I of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care provider” or “provider” means any person licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized by law to administer health care in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Incapacity” or “incompetent” means the patient is physically or mentally unable to communicate a willful and knowing health care decision. For the purposes of making an anatomical gift, the term also includes a patient who is deceased.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Informed consent” means consent voluntarily given by a person after a sufficient explanation and disclosure of the subject matter involved to enable that person to have a general understanding of the treatment or procedure and the medically acceptable alternatives, including the substantial risks and hazards inherent in the proposed treatment or procedures, and to make a knowing health care decision without coercion or undue influence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Life-prolonging procedure” means any medical procedure, treatment, or intervention, including artificially provided sustenance and hydration, which sustains, restores, or supplants a spontaneous vital function. The term does not include the administration of medication or performance of medical procedure, when such medication or procedure is deemed necessary to provide comfort care or to alleviate pain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Living will” or “declaration” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A witnessed document in writing, voluntarily executed by the principal in accordance with s. 765.302; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A witnessed oral statement made by the principal expressing the principal’s instructions concerning life-prolonging procedures.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Persistent vegetative state” means a permanent and irreversible condition of unconsciousness in which there is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The absence of voluntary action or cognitive behavior of any kind.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inability to communicate or interact purposefully with the environment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a person licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Principal” means a competent adult executing an advance directive and on whose behalf health care decisions are to be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proxy” means a competent adult who has not been expressly designated to make health care decisions for a particular incapacitated individual, but who, nevertheless, is authorized pursuant to s. 765.401 to make health care decisions for such individual.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surrogate” means any competent adult expressly designated by a principal to make health care decisions on behalf of the principal upon the principal’s incapacity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Terminal condition” means a condition caused by injury, disease, or illness from which there is no reasonable medical probability of recovery and which, without treatment, can be expected to cause death.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 92-199; s. 3, ch. 94-183; s. 46, ch. 96-169; s. 16, ch. 99-331; s. 3, ch. 2001-250; s. 131, ch. 2001-277; s. 104, ch. 2006-1; s. 28, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>