<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.544" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees; organ and tissue donor education and procurement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or a certificateholder shall pay a fee for each application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The amount of the fee shall be as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An initial application fee of $1,000 from organ procurement organizations and tissue banks and $500 from eye banks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual fees to be used, in the following order of priority, for the certification program, the advisory board, maintenance of the donor registry, and the organ and tissue donor education program, which may not exceed $35,000 per organization:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each organ procurement organization shall pay the greater of $1,000 or 0.25 percent of its total revenues produced from procurement activity in this state by the certificateholder during its most recently completed fiscal or operational year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each tissue procurement organization shall pay the greater of $1,000 or 0.25 percent of its total revenues from procurement and processing activity in this state by the certificateholder during its most recently completed fiscal or operational year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each eye bank shall pay the greater of $500 or 0.25 percent of its total revenues produced from procurement activity in this state by the certificateholder during its most recently completed fiscal or operational year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall specify by rule the administrative penalties for the purpose of ensuring adherence to the standards of quality and practice required by this chapter, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules of the agency for continued certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceeds from fees, administrative penalties, and surcharges collected pursuant to this section must be deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys deposited in the trust fund pursuant to this section must be used exclusively for the implementation, administration, and operation of the certification program and the advisory board, for maintaining the donor registry, and for organ and tissue donor education.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “procurement activity in this state” includes the bringing into this state for processing, storage, distribution, or transplantation of organs or tissues that are initially procured in another state or country.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 91-271; s. 8, ch. 94-305; s. 32, ch. 96-418; ss. 3, 4, ch. 98-68; s. 54, ch. 2002-1; s. 33, ch. 2003-1; s. 203, ch. 2007-230; s. 19, ch. 2008-9; s. 16, ch. 2009-218.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.6024.</Text></Note></Section>