<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Organ Transplant Advisory Council; membership; responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statewide technical Organ Transplant Advisory Council is created within the agency, consisting of twelve members who are physicians licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, to represent the interests of the public and the clients of the Department of Health or the agency. A person employed by the agency may not be appointed as a member of the council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration shall appoint all members of the council to serve a term of 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration shall fill each vacancy on the council for the balance of the unexpired term. Priority consideration must be given to the appointment of an individual whose primary interest, experience, or expertise lies with clients of the Department of Health and the agency. If an appointment is not made within 120 days after a vacancy occurs on the council, the vacancy must be filled by the majority vote of the council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the council shall elect a chairperson. The term of the chairperson shall be for 2 years, and an individual may not serve as chairperson for more than two consecutive terms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall receive no compensation, but shall be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses by the agency in accordance with s. 112.061 while engaged in the performance of their duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The responsibilities of the council shall be to recommend to the agency indications for adult and pediatric organ transplants. The council shall also formulate guidelines and standards for organ transplants and for the development of End Stage Organ Disease and Tissue/Organ Transplant programs. The recommendations, guidelines, and standards developed by the council are applicable only to those health programs funded through the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet at least annually or upon the call of the chairperson or the Secretary of Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 86-208; ss. 88, 89, ch. 86-220; s. 3, ch. 87-50; s. 8, ch. 91-49; s. 52, ch. 91-297; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 94-305; s. 50, ch. 97-101; s. 1, ch. 99-299; s. 6, ch. 2000-305; s. 33, ch. 2003-1; s. 12, ch. 2009-218.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.602; s. 381.0602.</Text></Note></Section>