<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.521" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Donations as part of driver license or identification card process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency and the department shall develop and implement a program encouraging and allowing persons to make anatomical gifts as a part of the process of issuing identification cards and issuing and renewing driver licenses. The donor registration card distributed by the department shall include the information required by the uniform donor card under s. 765.514 and such additional information as determined necessary by the department. The department shall also develop and implement a program to identify donors which includes notations on identification cards, driver licenses, and driver records or such other methods as the department develops to clearly indicate the individual’s intent to make an anatomical gift. A notation on an individual’s driver license or identification card that the individual intends to make an anatomical gift satisfies all requirements for consent to organ or tissue donation. The agency shall provide the necessary supplies and forms from funds appropriated from general revenue or contributions from interested voluntary, nonprofit organizations. The department shall provide the necessary recordkeeping system from funds appropriated from general revenue. The department and the agency shall incur no liability in connection with the performance of any acts authorized herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, after consultation with and concurrence by the agency, shall adopt rules to implement the provisions of this section according to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds expended by the agency to carry out the intent of this section may not be taken from funds appropriated for patient care.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 75-71; s. 1, ch. 77-16; s. 463, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-134; s. 5, ch. 83-171; s. 10, ch. 95-423; s. 71, ch. 2001-226; s. 8, ch. 2008-223; s. 10, ch. 2009-218.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 732.921.</Text></Note></Section>