<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0765.110" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health care facilities and providers; discipline.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care facility, pursuant to Pub. L. No. 101-508, ss. 4206 and 4751, shall provide to each patient written information concerning the individual’s rights concerning advance directives and the health care facility’s policies respecting the implementation of such rights, and shall document in the patient’s medical records whether or not the individual has executed an advance directive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care provider or health care facility may not require a patient to execute an advance directive or to execute a new advance directive using the facility’s or provider’s forms. The patient’s advance directives shall travel with the patient as part of the patient’s medical record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care provider or health care facility shall be subject to professional discipline and revocation of license or certification, and a fine of not more than $1,000 per incident, or both, if the health care provider or health care facility, as a condition of treatment or admission, requires an individual to execute or waive an advance directive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs for hospices and, in consultation with the Department of Elderly Affairs, the Department of Health for health care providers; the Agency for Health Care Administration for hospitals, nursing homes, home health agencies, and health maintenance organizations; and the Department of Children and Family Services for facilities subject to part I of chapter 394 shall adopt rules to implement the provisions of the section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 92-199; s. 6, ch. 94-183; s. 243, ch. 94-218; s. 48, ch. 96-169; s. 284, ch. 99-8; s. 21, ch. 99-331.</History></Section>