<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0765.5155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Donor registry; education program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a shortage of organ and tissue donors in this state willing to provide the organs and tissue that could save lives or enhance the quality of life for many persons.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a need to encourage the various minority populations of this state to donate organs and tissue.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statewide donor registry having an online donor registration process coupled with an enhanced program of donor education will lead to an increase in the number of organ and tissue donors registered in this state, thus affording more persons who are awaiting organ or tissue transplants the opportunity for a full and productive life.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency and the department shall jointly contract for the operation of a donor registry and education program. The contractor shall be procured by competitive solicitation pursuant to chapter 287, notwithstanding any exemption in s. 287.057(3)(f). When awarding the contract, priority shall be given to existing nonprofit groups that are based within the state, have expertise working with procurement organizations, have expertise in conducting statewide organ and tissue donor public education campaigns, and represent the needs of the organ and tissue donation community in the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor shall be responsible for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development, implementation, and maintenance of an interactive web-based donor registry that, through electronic means, allows for online organ donor registration and the recording of organ and tissue donation records submitted through the driver’s license identification program or through other sources.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registry must be maintained in a manner that allows, through electronic and telephonic methods, immediate access to organ and tissue donation records 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Access to the registry must be through coded and secure means to protect the integrity of the data in the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A continuing program to educate and inform medical professionals, law enforcement agencies and officers, other state and local government employees, high school students, minorities, and the public about the laws of this state relating to anatomical gifts and the need for anatomical gifts.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing community resources, when available, must be used to support the program and volunteers may assist the program to the maximum extent possible.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor shall coordinate with the head of a state agency or other political subdivision of the state, or his or her designee, to establish convenient times, dates, and locations for educating that entity’s employees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparing and submitting an annual written report to the agency by December 31 of each year. The report must include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of donors on the registry and an analysis of the registration rates by location and method of donation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The characteristics of donors as determined from registry information submitted directly by the donors or by the department;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual dollar amount of voluntary contributions received by the contractor;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the educational campaigns and initiatives implemented during the year and an evaluation of their effectiveness in increasing enrollment on the registry; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of Florida’s registry compared with other states’ donor registries.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Costs for the donor registry and education program shall be paid by the agency from the funds deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund pursuant to ss. 320.08047 and 322.08, which are designated for maintaining the donor registry and education program. In addition, the contractor may receive and use voluntary contributions to help support the registry and provide education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The donor registry established by this section is designated as the “Joshua Abbott Organ and Tissue Registry.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2008-223; s. 6, ch. 2009-218; s. 40, ch. 2010-151.</History>
</Section>