<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jury trial; compensation; severance damages; business damages.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the action is at issue, and only upon notice and hearing to set the cause for trial, the court shall impanel a jury of 12 persons as soon as practical considering the reasonable necessities of the court and of the parties, and giving preference to the trial of eminent domain cases over other civil actions, and submit the issue of compensation to them for determination, which issue shall be tried in the same manner as other issues of fact are tried in the circuit courts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of such compensation shall be determined as of the date of trial, or the date upon which title passes, whichever shall occur first.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jury shall determine solely the amount of compensation to be paid, which compensation shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of the property sought to be appropriated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where less than the entire property is sought to be appropriated, any damages to the remainder caused by the taking, including, when the action is by the Department of Transportation, county, municipality, board, district or other public body for the condemnation of a right-of-way, and the effect of the taking of the property involved may damage or destroy an established business of more than 4 years’ standing before January 1, 2005, or the effect of the taking of the property involved may damage or destroy an established business of more than 5 years’ standing on or after January 1, 2005, owned by the party whose lands are being so taken, located upon adjoining lands owned or held by such party, the probable damages to such business which the denial of the use of the property so taken may reasonably cause; any person claiming the right to recover such special damages shall set forth in his or her written defenses the nature and extent of such damages; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the appropriation is of property upon which a mobile home, other than a travel trailer as defined in s. 320.01, is located, whether or not the owner of the mobile home is an owner or lessee of the property involved, and the effect of the taking of the property involved requires the relocation of such mobile home, the reasonable removal or relocation expenses incurred by such mobile home owner, not to exceed the replacement value of such mobile home. The compensation paid to a mobile home owner under this paragraph shall preclude an award to a mobile home park owner for such expenses of removal or relocation. Any mobile home owner claiming the right to such removal or relocation expenses shall set forth in his or her written defenses the nature and extent of such expenses. This paragraph shall not apply to any governmental authority exercising its power of eminent domain when reasonable removal or relocation expenses must be paid to mobile home owners under other provisions of law or agency rule applicable to such exercise of power.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the action is by the Department of Transportation, county, municipality, board, district, or other public body for the condemnation of a road, canal, levee, or water control facility right-of-way, the enhancement, if any, in value of the remaining adjoining property of the defendant property owner by reason of the construction or improvement made or contemplated by the petitioner shall be offset against the damage, if any, resulting to such remaining adjoining property of the defendant property owner by reason of the construction or improvement. However, such enhancement in the value shall not be offset against the value of the property appropriated, and if such enhancement in value shall exceed the damage, if any, to the remaining adjoining property, there shall be no recovery over against such property owner for such excess.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any increase or decrease in the value of any property to be acquired which occurs after the scope of the project for which the property is being acquired is known in the market, and which is solely a result of the knowledge of the project location, shall not be considered in arriving at the value of the property acquired. For the purpose of this section, the scope of the project for which the property is being acquired shall be presumed to be known in the market on or after the condemnor executes a resolution which depicts the location of the project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jury shall view the subject property upon demand by any party or by order of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the jury cannot agree on a verdict the court shall discharge them, impanel a new jury, and proceed with the trial.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-369; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-283; s. 1, ch. 77-51; s. 19, ch. 79-400; s. 36, ch. 85-180; s. 361, ch. 95-147; ss. 58, 59, ch. 99-385; ss. 56, 57, ch. 2002-20.</History></Section>