<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Costs of the proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petitioner shall pay attorney’s fees as provided in s. 73.092 as well as all reasonable costs incurred in the defense of the proceedings in the circuit court, including, but not limited to, reasonable appraisal fees and, when business damages are compensable, a reasonable accountant’s fee, to be assessed by that court. No prejudgment interest shall be paid on costs or attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 30 days prior to a hearing to assess costs under this section, the condemnee’s attorney shall submit to the condemning authority for each expert witness complete time records and a detailed statement of services rendered by date, nature of services performed, time spent performing such services, and costs incurred, and a copy of any fee agreement which may exist between the expert and the condemnee or the condemnee’s attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In assessing costs, the court shall consider all factors relevant to the reasonableness of the costs, including, but not limited to, the fees paid to similar experts retained in the case by the condemning authority or other parties and the reasonable costs of similar services by similarly qualified persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In assessing costs to be paid by the petitioner, the court shall be guided by the amount the defendant would ordinarily have been expected to pay for the services rendered if the petitioner were not responsible for the costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall make specific findings that justify each sum awarded as an expert witness fee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-369; s. 2, ch. 87-148; s. 52, ch. 90-136; s. 1, ch. 90-303; s. 2, ch. 94-162; s. 60, ch. 99-385.</History></Section>