<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petition; contents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those having the right to exercise the power of eminent domain may file a petition therefor in the circuit court of the county wherein the property lies, which petition shall set forth:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority under which and the public use or purpose for which the property is to be acquired, and that the property is necessary for that public use or purpose;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description identifying the property sought to be acquired. The petitioners may join in the same action all properties involved in a planned project whether in the same or different ownership, or whether or not the property is sought for the same use;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estate or interest in the property which the petitioner intends to acquire;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names, places of residence, legal disabilities, if any, and interests in the property of all owners, lessees, mortgagees, judgment creditors, and lienholders, so far as ascertainable by diligent search, and all unknown persons having an interest in the property when the petitioner has been unable to ascertain the identity of such persons by diligent search and inquiry. If any interest in the property, or lien thereon, belongs to the unsettled estate of a decedent, the executor or administrator shall be made a defendant without joining the devisee or heir; if a trust estate, the trustee shall be made a defendant without joining the cestui que trust. The court may appoint an administrator ad litem to represent the estate of a deceased person whose estate is not being administered, and a guardian ad litem for all defendants who are infants or are under other legal disabilities; and for defendants whose names or addresses are unknown. A copy of the order of appointment shall be served on the guardian ad litem at least 10 days before trial unless he or she has entered an appearance;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether any mobile home is located on the property sought to be acquired and, if so, whether the removal of that mobile home will be required. If such removal shall be required, the petition shall name the owners of each such mobile home as defendants. This subsection shall not apply to any governmental authority exercising its power of eminent domain when reasonable relocation or removal expenses must be paid to mobile home owners under other provisions of law or agency rule applicable to such exercise of power;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the petitioner has surveyed and located its line or area of construction, and intends in good faith to construct the project on or over the described property; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demand for relief that the property be condemned and taken for the uses and purposes set forth in the petition, and that the interest sought be vested in the petitioner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-369; s. 2, ch. 77-51; s. 358, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 2006-11.</History></Section>