<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Process; service and publication.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of the petition, the clerk of the court shall issue a summons to show cause why the property should not be taken, directed “to all whom it may concern,” containing the names of all the defendants named in the petition, commanding them and any other persons claiming any interest in the property described to serve written defenses to the petition on a day specified in the summons not less than 28 nor more than 60 days from the date of the summons. A copy of the summons and the petition shall be served upon all resident defendants in the manner provided by law and not less than 20 days before the return day.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any defendant is alleged to be a nonresident of the state, or if the name or residence of any defendant is alleged to be unknown, or if personal service cannot be had upon any defendant for any other reason, the clerk shall cause a notice to be published at least once each week for 2 consecutive weeks prior to the return day in some newspaper published in the county; provided, however, that if the petitioner be a municipality and a newspaper is published therein, the notice shall be published in such a newspaper. This notice shall contain the names of the defendants to whom it is directed, a description of the property sought to be appropriated, the nature of the action, and the name of the court in which it is pending. The clerk shall mail a copy of the summons and the petition to each out-of-state defendant at the address as set forth in the petition. The clerk shall file a certificate of mailing which, together with proof of publication, shall constitute effective service as though the defendant had been personally served with process within this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of any party to receive notice by mail shall not invalidate the proceedings of the court or any order made pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-369; s. 2, ch. 90-279; s. 359, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>