<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eminent domain procedure with respect to condominium common elements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other provision of this chapter or any other provision of the Florida Statutes to the contrary notwithstanding, the procedure for the exercise of eminent domain with respect to the taking of a portion of the common elements of a condominium shall comply with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to the exercise of eminent domain or a negotiated sale for the purchase or taking of a portion of the common elements of a condominium, the condemning authority shall have the responsibility of contacting the condominium association and acquiring the most recent rolls indicating the names of the unit owners or contacting the appropriate taxing authority to obtain the names of the owners of record on the tax rolls. Notification shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the unit owners of record of the condominium units by the condemning authority indicating the intent to purchase or take the required property and requesting a response from the unit owner. The condemning authority shall be responsible for the expense of sending notification pursuant to this section. Such notice shall, at a minimum, include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the condemning authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written or visual description of the property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public purpose for which the property is needed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appraisal value of the property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear, concise statement relating to the unit owner’s right to object to the taking or appraisal value and the procedures and effects of exercising that right.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear, concise statement relating to the power of the association to convey the property on behalf of the unit owners if no objection to the taking or appraisal value is raised, and the effects of this alternative on the unit owner.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation may adopt, by rule, a standard form for such notice and may require the notice to include any additional relevant information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of a response by the unit owner within 30 days, the unit owner shall be deemed to have acquiesced to the association acting as the unit owner’s representative in any subsequent proceeding relating to the parcel at issue. Unit owners who object to the purchase or taking or the appraisal of value within 30 days after the date the notice is received shall have all of their legal rights preserved with regard to the taking, the appraisal of value, and all other rights which appertain to unit ownership. Failure to raise an objection within the 30-day period shall only constitute an acquiescence by the unit owner to the association acting as the unit owner’s representative in any subsequent proceeding relating to the parcel at issue and shall not affect any other rights of the unit owner. In the event that no unit owners shall so object, the condemning authority may rely upon a power of sale vested in the condominium association. The condemning authority shall only be required to name as defendants, should eminent domain proceedings be necessitated, the association and those owners of units which shall have objected to the taking or appraisal value within the 30-day period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature, through the adoption of this section, to provide a mechanism to either eliminate or minimize the necessity for naming individual unit owners in eminent domain proceedings for the acquisition of a portion of the common elements of a condominium and the necessity of incidental title searches and legal actions necessitated by naming multiple unit owners as defendants.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-336; s. 9, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>