<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Presuit negotiation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2000, before an eminent domain proceeding is brought under this chapter or chapter 74, the condemning authority must attempt to negotiate in good faith with the fee owner of the parcel to be acquired, must provide the fee owner with a written offer and, if requested, a copy of the appraisal upon which the offer is based, and must attempt to reach an agreement regarding the amount of compensation to be paid for the parcel.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than the time the initial written or oral offer of compensation for acquisition is made to the fee owner, the condemning authority must notify the fee owner of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all or a portion of his or her property is necessary for a project.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the project for which the parcel is considered necessary, and the parcel designation of the property to be acquired.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, within 15 business days after receipt of a request by the fee owner, the condemning authority will provide a copy of the appraisal report upon which the offer to the fee owner is based; copies, to the extent prepared, of the right-of-way maps or other documents that depict the proposed taking; and copies, to the extent prepared, of the construction plans that depict project improvements to be constructed on the property taken and improvements to be constructed adjacent to the remaining property, including, but not limited to, plan, profile, cross-section, drainage, and pavement marking sheets, and driveway connection detail. The condemning authority shall provide any additional plan sheets within 15 days of request.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee owner’s statutory rights under ss. 73.091 and 73.092, or alternatively provide copies of these provisions of law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee owner’s rights and responsibilities under paragraphs (b) and (c) and subsection (4), or alternatively provide copies of these provisions of law.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The condemning authority must provide a written offer of compensation to the fee owner as to the value of the property sought to be appropriated and, where less than the entire property is sought to be appropriated, any damages to the remainder caused by the taking. The owner must be given at least 30 days after either receipt of the notice or the date the notice is returned as undeliverable by the postal authorities to respond to the offer, before the condemning authority files a condemnation proceeding for the parcel identified in the offer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice and written offer must be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the fee owner’s last known address listed on the county ad valorem tax roll. Alternatively, the notice and written offer may be personally delivered to the fee owner of the property. If there is more than one owner of a property, notice to one owner constitutes notice to all owners of the property. The return of the notice as undeliverable by the postal authorities constitutes compliance with this provision. The condemning authority is not required to give notice or a written offer to a person who acquires title to the property after the notice required by this section has been given.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding this subsection, with respect to lands acquired under s. 259.041, the condemning authority is not required to give the fee owner the current appraisal before executing an option contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2000, before an eminent domain proceeding is brought under this chapter or chapter 74 by the Department of Transportation or by a county, municipality, board, district, or other public body for the condemnation of right-of-way, the condemning authority must make a good faith effort to notify the business owners, including lessees, who operate a business located on the property to be acquired.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The condemning authority must notify the business owner of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all or a portion of his or her property is necessary for a project.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the project for which the parcel is considered necessary, and the parcel designation of the property to be acquired.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, within 15 business days after receipt of a request by the business owner, the condemning authority will provide a copy of the appraisal report upon which the offer to the fee owner is based; copies, to the extent prepared, of the right-of-way maps or other documents that depict the proposed taking; and copies, to the extent prepared, of the construction plans that depict project improvements to be constructed on the property taken and improvements to be constructed adjacent to the remaining property, including, but not limited to, plan, profile, cross-section, drainage, pavement marking sheets, and driveway connection detail. The condemning authority shall provide any additional plan sheets within 15 days of request.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business owner’s statutory rights under ss. 73.071, 73.091, and 73.092.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business owner’s rights and responsibilities under paragraphs (b) and (c) and subsection (4).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice must be made subsequent to or concurrent with the condemning authority’s making the written offer of compensation to the fee owner pursuant to subsection (1). The notice must be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the address of the registered agent for the business located on the property to be acquired, or if no agent is registered, by certified mail or personal delivery to the address of the business located on the property to be acquired. Notice to one owner of a multiple ownership business constitutes notice to all business owners of that business. The return of the notice as undeliverable by the postal authorities constitutes compliance with these provisions. The condemning authority is not required to give notice to a person who acquires an interest in the business after the notice required by this section has been given. Once notice has been made to business owners under this subsection, the condemning authority may file a condemnation proceeding pursuant to chapter 73 or chapter 74 for the property identified in the notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the business qualifies for business damages pursuant to s. 73.071(3)(b) and the business intends to claim business damages, the business owner must, within 180 days after either receipt of the notice or the date the notice is returned as undeliverable by the postal authorities, or at a later time mutually agreed to by the condemning authority and the business owner, submit to the condemning authority a good faith written offer to settle any claims of business damage. The written offer must be sent to the condemning authority by certified mail, return receipt requested. Absent a showing of a good faith justification for the failure to submit a business damage offer within 180 days, the court must strike the business owner’s claim for business damages in any condemnation proceeding. If the court finds that the business owner has made a showing of a good faith justification for the failure to timely submit a business damage offer, the court shall grant the business owner up to 180 days within which to submit a business damage offer, which the condemning authority must respond to within 120 days.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business damage offer must include an explanation of the nature, extent, and monetary amount of such damage and must be prepared by the owner, a certified public accountant, or a business damage expert familiar with the nature of the operations of the owner’s business. The business owner shall also provide to the condemning authority copies of the owner’s business records that substantiate the good faith offer to settle the business damage claim. If additional information is needed beyond data that may be obtained from business records existing at the time of the offer, the business owner and condemning authority may agree on a schedule for the submission of such information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “business records” includes, but is not limited to, copies of federal income tax returns, federal income tax withholding statements, federal miscellaneous income tax statements, state sales tax returns, balance sheets, profit and loss statements, and state corporate income tax returns for the 5 years preceding notification which are attributable to the business operation on the property to be acquired, and other records relied upon by the business owner that substantiate the business damage claim.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 120 days after receipt of the good faith business damage offer and accompanying business records, the condemning authority must, by certified mail, accept or reject the business owner’s offer or make a counteroffer. Failure of the condemning authority to respond to the business damage offer, or rejection thereof pursuant to this section, must be deemed to be a counteroffer of zero dollars for purposes of subsequent application of s. 73.092(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time in the presuit negotiation process, the parties may agree to submit the compensation or business damage claims to nonbinding mediation. The parties shall agree upon a mediator certified under s. 44.102. In the event that there is a settlement reached as a result of mediation or other mutually acceptable dispute resolution procedure, the agreement reached shall be in writing. The written agreement provided for in this section shall incorporate by reference the right-of-way maps, construction plans, or other documents related to the taking upon which the settlement is based. In the event of a settlement, both parties shall have the same legal rights that would have been available under law if the matter had been resolved through eminent domain proceedings in circuit court with the maps, plans, or other documents having been made a part of the record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a settlement is reached between the condemning authority and a property or business owner prior to a lawsuit being filed, the property or business owner who settles compensation claims in lieu of condemnation shall be entitled to recover costs in the same manner as provided in s. 73.091 and attorney’s fees in the same manner as provided in s. 73.092, more specifically as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attorney’s fees for presuit negotiations under this section regarding the amount of compensation to be paid for the land, severance damages, and improvements must be calculated in the same manner as provided in s. 73.092(1) unless the parties otherwise agree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If business damages are recovered by the business owner based on the condemning authority accepting the business owner’s initial offer or the business owner accepting the condemning authority’s initial counteroffer, attorney’s fees must be calculated in accordance with s. 73.092(2), (3), (4), and (5) for the attorney’s time incurred in presentation of the business owner’s good faith offer under paragraph (2)(c). Otherwise, attorney’s fees for the award of business damages must be calculated as provided in s. 73.092(1), based on the difference between the final judgment or settlement of business damages and the counteroffer to the business owner’s offer by the condemning authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presuit costs must be presented, calculated, and awarded in the same manner as provided in s. 73.091, after submission by the business or property owner to the condemning authority of all appraisal reports, business damage reports, or other work products for which recovery is sought, and upon transfer of title of the real property by closing, upon payment of any amounts due for business damages, or upon final judgment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the parties cannot agree on the amount of costs and attorney’s fees to be paid by the condemning authority, the business or property owner may file a complaint in the circuit court in the county in which the property is located to recover attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This shall only apply when the action is by the Department of Transportation, county, municipality, board, district, or other public body for the condemnation of a road right-of-way.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of negotiations or of any written or oral statements used in mediation or negotiations between the parties under this section is inadmissible in any condemnation proceeding, except in a proceeding to determine reasonable costs and attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 99-385; s. 8, ch. 2001-256.</History></Section>