<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0073.0155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality; business information provided to a governmental condemning authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following business information provided by the owner of a business to a governmental condemning authority as part of an offer of business damages under s. 73.015 is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution if the owner requests in writing that the business information be held confidential and exempt:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal tax returns or tax information confidential under 26 U.S.C. s. 6103.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State tax returns or tax information confidential under s. 213.053.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Balance sheets, profit-and-loss statements, cash-flow statements, inventory records, or customer lists or number of customers for a business operating on the parcel to be acquired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A franchise, distributorship, or lease agreement of which the business operating on the parcel to be acquired is the subject.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Materials that relate to methods of manufacture or production, potential trade secrets, patentable material, or actual trade secrets as defined in s. 688.002.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other proprietary confidential business information related to the business operating on the parcel to be acquired, if the owner attests in writing to the governmental condemning authority that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information is being relied upon to substantiate a claim for business damages under s. 73.015;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information has not otherwise been publicly disclosed;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information cannot be readily obtained by the public using alternative means;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information is used by the business to protect or further a business advantage over those who do not know or use the information; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclosure of the information would injure the business in the marketplace.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency as defined in s. 119.011 may inspect and copy the confidential and exempt business information exclusively for the transaction of official business by, or on behalf of, an agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prevent an agency from offering the confidential and exempt business information as evidence in a legal proceeding and does not prevent a court from determining whether to close a portion of a court record from subsequent public disclosure after trial in order to maintain the confidentiality of that information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any employee or agent of an agency receiving such confidential and exempt business information who willfully and knowingly violates this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-224; s. 1, ch. 2004-46; s. 1, ch. 2009-234.</History></Section>