<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0365.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obscene or harassing telephone calls.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes a telephone call to a location at which the person receiving the call has a reasonable expectation of privacy; during such call makes any comment, request, suggestion, or proposal which is obscene, lewd, lascivious, filthy, vulgar, or indecent; and by such call or such language intends to offend, annoy, abuse, threaten, or harass any person at the called number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes a telephone call, whether or not conversation ensues, without disclosing his or her identity and with intent to annoy, abuse, threaten, or harass any person at the called number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes or causes the telephone of another repeatedly or continuously to ring, with intent to harass any person at the called number; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes repeated telephone calls, during which conversation ensues, solely to harass any person at the called number,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever knowingly permits any telephone under his or her control to be used for any purpose prohibited by this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each telephone directory hereafter published for distribution to the members of the general public shall contain a notice which explains this law; such notice shall be printed in type which is no smaller than the smallest type on the same page and shall be preceded by the word “warning.” The provisions of this section shall not apply to directories solely for business advertising purposes, commonly known as classified directories.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each telephone company in this state shall cooperate with the law enforcement agencies of this state in using its facilities and personnel to detect and prevent violations of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this section shall apply to telephone calls made in good faith in the ordinary course of business or commerce.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 63-51; s. 1, ch. 69-25; s. 276, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-270; ss. 2, 4, ch. 80-275; s. 550, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>