<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.942" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspections and audits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative of the department may at any reasonable time enter to inspect and audit, in order to ascertain compliance with this part or rules adopted to implement this part, any specified stationary source subject to the requirements of s. 112(r)(7), except a building that is used exclusively for a private residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative may at any reasonable time have access to any specified stationary source subject to s. 112(r)(7) for inspection and copying any supporting documentation required under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not refuse reasonable entry or access to any authorized representative of the department who requests entry for purposes of inspection and who presents appropriate credentials; nor shall any person obstruct, hamper, or interfere with such inspection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inspection or audit under subsection (1) may be conducted only after:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent for the inspection is received from the owner, operator, or person in charge; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate inspection warrant as provided in this section is obtained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inspection warrant as authorized by this chapter may be issued by a judge of any county court or circuit court of this state which has jurisdiction over the place or thing to be searched.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a proper affidavit is made, the judge may issue an inspection warrant if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It appears that the properties to be inspected may be connected with or contain evidence of the violation of any of the provisions of this part or any rule properly promulgated thereunder; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspection sought is an integral part of a larger scheme of systematic routine inspections that are necessary to, and consistent with, the continuing efforts of the department to ensure compliance with the provisions of this part and any rules adopted thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall, before issuing the warrant, have the application for the warrant duly sworn to and subscribed by a representative of the department; and he or she may receive further testimony from witnesses, supporting affidavits, or depositions in writing to support the application. The affidavit and further proof must set forth the facts tending to establish the grounds specified in paragraph (b) or the reasons for believing that such grounds exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon examination of the application and proofs submitted and if satisfied that cause exists for issuing the inspection warrant, the judge shall issue a warrant, signed by him or her with the name of his or her office, to any department representative, which warrant will authorize the representative to inspect the property described in the warrant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall periodically audit Risk Management Plans submitted by owners or operators of stationary sources subject to s. 112(r)(7) and require revisions of such plans when necessary to ensure compliance with this part. The audit and revision requirements must substantially comply with federal regulations implementing s. 112(r)(7). The department shall develop, with the advice and consent of the commission, an annual audit work plan which identifies specified stationary sources or audits based on the program resources available. Stationary sources will be prioritized for audits based on factors which include, but are not limited to, stationary source location and proximity to population centers, chemical characteristics and inventories, stationary source accident history, process accident history, compliance or inspection by allied agency programs, and the results of stationary sources’ self-audits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, owners or operators of specified stationary sources subject to s. 112(r)(7) shall receive an oral exit interview at the conclusion of an inspection or audit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following an audit or inspection, the department shall issue the owner or operator a written preliminary determination of any necessary revisions to the stationary source Risk Management Plan to ensure that the plan meets the requirements of this part and rules adopted to implement this part. The preliminary determination must include an explanation of the basis for the revisions, reflecting industry standards and guidelines to the extent that such standards and guidelines are applicable, and must include a timetable for their implementation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide reasonable notice of its intent to conduct an onsite inspection or audit of a specified stationary source. Inspections or audits may be conducted without notice in response to an accidental release or to protect the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-193.</History></Section>