<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.937" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division has the power and duty to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek delegation from the United States Environmental Protection Agency to implement the Accidental Release Prevention Program under s. 112(r)(7) of the Clean Air Act and the federal implementing regulations for specified sources subject to s. 112(r)(7) of the Clean Air Act. Implementation for all other sources subject to s. 112(r)(7) of the Clean Air Act shall be performed by the United States Environmental Protection Agency; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure the timely submission of Risk Management Plans and any subsequent revisions of Risk Management Plans.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, modify, and repeal rules, with the advice and consent of the commission, necessary to obtain delegation from the United States Environmental Protection Agency and to administer the s. 112(r)(7) Accidental Release Prevention Program in this state for the specified stationary sources with no expansion or addition of the regulatory program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and execute contracts and other agreements necessary or convenient to the administration of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate its activities under this part with its other emergency management responsibilities, including its responsibilities and activities under parts I, II, and III of this chapter and with the related activities of other state and local agencies, keeping separate accounts for all activities conducted under this part which are supported or partially supported from the trust fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish, with the advice and consent of the commission, a technical assistance and outreach program to assist owners and operators of specified stationary sources subject to s. 112(r)(7) in complying with the reporting and fee requirements of this part. This program is designed to facilitate and ensure timely submission of proper certifications or compliance schedules and timely submission and registration of Risk Management Plans and revised registrations and Risk Management Plans if required for these sources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a quarterly report to the State Emergency Response Commission on income and expenses for the state’s Accidental Release Prevention Program under this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure that this program is self-supporting, the division shall provide administrative support, including staff, facilities, materials, and services to implement this part for specified stationary sources subject to s. 252.939 and provide necessary funding to local emergency planning committees and county emergency management agencies for work performed to implement this part. Each state agency with regulatory, inspection, or technical assistance programs for specified stationary sources subject to this part shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the division which specifically outlines how each agency’s staff, facilities, materials, and services will be used to support implementation. It is the Legislature’s intent to implement this part as efficiently and economically as possible, using existing expertise and resources, if available and appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prevent the duplication of investigative efforts and resources, the division, on behalf of the commission, shall coordinate with any federal agencies or agents thereof, including the federal Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board, or its successor, which are performing accidental release investigations for specified stationary sources, and may coordinate with any agencies of the state which are performing accidental release investigations. This accidental release investigation coordination is not intended to limit or take the place of any individual agency accidental release investigation under separate authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote efficient administration of this program and specified stationary sources, only the division may seek delegation from the United States Environmental Protection Agency for this program. Further, the division may not delegate this program to any local environmental agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-193; s. 235, ch. 99-245; s. 2, ch. 99-353; s. 113, ch. 2011-142; s. 8, ch. 2011-213.</History></Section>