<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.358" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency-preparedness prescription medication refills.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health insurers, managed care organizations, and other entities that are licensed by the Office of Insurance Regulation and provide prescription medication coverage as part of a policy or contract shall waive time restrictions on prescription medication refills, which include suspension of electronic “refill too soon” edits to pharmacies, to enable insureds or subscribers to refill prescriptions in advance, if there are authorized refills remaining, and shall authorize payment to pharmacies for at least a 30-day supply of any prescription medication, regardless of the date upon which the prescription had most recently been filled by a pharmacist, when the following conditions occur:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person seeking the prescription medication refill resides in a county that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is under a hurricane warning issued by the National Weather Service;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is declared to be under a state of emergency in an executive order issued by the Governor; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has activated its emergency operations center and its emergency management plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prescription medication refill is requested within 30 days after the origination date of the conditions stated in this section or until such conditions are terminated by the issuing authority or no longer exist. The time period for the waiver of prescription medication refills may be extended in 15- or 30-day increments by emergency orders issued by the Office of Insurance Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This section does not excuse or exempt an insured or subscriber from compliance with all other terms of the policy or contract providing prescription medication coverage. This section takes effect July 1, 2006.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 2006-71.</History></Section>