<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0252.373" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Allocation of funds; rules.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated from the Emergency Management, Preparedness, and Assistance Trust Fund shall be allocated by the division for the following purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To implement and administer state and local emergency management programs, including administration, training, and operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For grants and loans to state or regional agencies, local governments, and private organizations to implement projects that will further state and local emergency management objectives. These projects must include, but need not be limited to, projects that will promote public education on disaster preparedness and recovery issues, enhance coordination of relief efforts of statewide private sector organizations, and improve the training and operations capabilities of agencies assigned lead or support responsibilities in the state comprehensive emergency management plan, including the State Fire Marshal’s Office for coordinating the Florida fire services. The division shall establish criteria and procedures for competitive allocation of these funds by rule. No more than 5 percent of any award made pursuant to this subparagraph may be used for administrative expenses. This competitive criteria must give priority consideration to hurricane evacuation shelter retrofit projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To meet any matching requirements imposed as a condition of receiving federal disaster relief assistance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall allocate funds from the Emergency Management, Preparedness, and Assistance Trust Fund to local emergency management agencies and programs pursuant to criteria specified in rule. Such rules shall include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that, at a minimum, a local emergency management agency either:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a program director who works at least 40 hours a week in that capacity; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the county has fewer than 75,000 population or is party to an interjurisdictional emergency management agreement entered into pursuant to s. 252.38(3)(b), that is recognized by the Governor by executive order or rule, have an emergency management coordinator who works at least 20 hours a week in that capacity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifying a formula that establishes a base grant allocation and weighted factors for funds to be allocated over the base grant amount.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifying match requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preferential funding to provide incentives to counties and municipalities to participate in mutual aid agreements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If adequate funds are available as determined by the division, every county shall receive funds at least sufficient to fund a dedicated, full-time emergency preparedness officer position.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-128; s. 11, ch. 98-258; s. 7, ch. 2000-140; s. 54, ch. 2000-171; ss. 42, 53, ch. 2001-254; ss. 53, 79, ch. 2002-402; s. 72, ch. 2003-399; s. 4, ch. 2004-235; s. 48, ch. 2004-269; s. 11, ch. 2005-3; s. 43, ch. 2006-26; s. 4, ch. 2008-5; s. 102, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>