<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lease or loan of state property; transfer of state personnel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the Governor deems it to be in the public interest, she or he may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize any department or agency of the state to lease or lend, on such terms and conditions as it may deem necessary to promote the public welfare and protect the interests of the state, any real or personal property of the state government to the President, the heads of the Armed Forces, or the various federal emergency management agencies of the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a contract on behalf of the state for the lease or loan to any political subdivision of the state, on such terms and conditions as she or he may deem necessary to promote the public welfare and protect the interests of the state, of any real or personal property of the state government or the temporary transfer or employment of personnel of the state government to or by any political subdivision of the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of each political subdivision of the state may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into such contract or lease with the state, accept any such loan, or employ such personnel, and such political subdivision may equip, maintain, utilize, and operate any such property and employ necessary personnel therefor in accordance with the purposes for which such contract is executed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do all things and perform any and all acts which it may deem necessary to effectuate the purpose for which such contract was entered into.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-285; s. 28, ch. 83-334; s. 136, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>