<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Orders and rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with the provisions of chapter 120, the political subdivisions of the state and other agencies designated or appointed by the Governor or in the state comprehensive emergency management plan are authorized and empowered to make, amend, and rescind such orders and rules as are necessary for emergency management purposes and to supplement the carrying out of the provisions of ss. 252.31-252.90, but which are not inconsistent with any orders or rules adopted by the division or by any state agency exercising a power delegated to it by the Governor or the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All orders and rules adopted by the division or any political subdivision or other agency authorized by ss. 252.31-252.90 to make orders and rules have full force and effect of law after adoption in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120 in the event of issuance by the division or any state agency or, if promulgated by a political subdivision of the state or agency thereof, when filed in the office of the clerk or recorder of the political subdivision or agency promulgating the same. All existing laws, ordinances, and rules inconsistent with the provisions of ss. 252.31-252.90, or any order or rule issued under the authority of ss. 252.31-252.90, shall be suspended during the period of time and to the extent that such conflict exists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to attain uniformity so far as practicable throughout the country in measures taken to aid emergency management, all action taken under ss. 252.31-252.90 and all orders and rules made pursuant to such sections shall be taken or made with due consideration of the orders, rules, actions, recommendations, and requests of federal authorities relevant thereto and, to the extent permitted by law, shall be consistent with such orders, rules, actions, recommendations, and requests.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-285; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 12, ch. 78-95; s. 23, ch. 81-169; s. 29, ch. 83-334; s. 18, ch. 93-211; s. 35, ch. 2001-61.</History></Section>