<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the employees of any political subdivision are rendering outside aid pursuant to the authority contained in s. 252.38, such employees shall have the same powers, duties, rights, privileges, and immunities as if they were performing their duties in the political subdivisions in which they are normally employed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The political subdivision in which any equipment is used pursuant to this section shall be liable for any loss or damage thereto and shall pay any expense incurred in the operation and maintenance thereof. No claim for such loss, damage, or expense shall be allowed unless an itemized notice of such claim under oath is served by mail or otherwise upon the chief fiscal officer of the political subdivision in which the equipment was used within 60 days after the loss, damage, or expense is sustained or incurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The political subdivision which is aided pursuant to this section shall also pay and reimburse the political subdivision furnishing such aid for compensation paid to employees furnished under this section during the time of the rendition of such aid and shall defray the actual travel and maintenance expenses of such employees while they are rendering such aid. Such reimbursement shall include any amounts paid or due for compensation due to personal injury or death while such employees are engaged in rendering such aid. The term “employee” as used in this section means, and the provisions of this section apply with equal effect to, paid, volunteer, and auxiliary employees and emergency management services workers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-285; s. 22, ch. 83-334.</History></Section>