<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0252.515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Postdisaster Relief Assistance Act; immunity from civil liability.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Postdisaster Relief Assistance Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who gratuitously and in good faith provides temporary housing, food, water, or electricity to emergency first responders or the immediate family members of emergency first responders in response to an emergency situation related to and arising out of a public health emergency declared pursuant to s. 381.00315 or a state of emergency declared pursuant to s. 252.36 may not be held liable for any civil damages as a result of providing the temporary housing, food, water, or electricity unless the person acts in a manner that demonstrates a reckless disregard for the consequences of another.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency first responder” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician licensed under chapter 458.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An osteopathic physician licensed under chapter 459.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A podiatric physician licensed under chapter 461.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist licensed under chapter 466.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advanced registered nurse practitioner certified under s. 464.012.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician assistant licensed under s. 458.347 or s. 459.022.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A worker employed by a public or private hospital in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A paramedic as defined in s. 401.23(17).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency medical technician as defined in s. 401.23(11).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A firefighter as defined in s. 633.30.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement officer as defined in s. 943.10.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the Florida National Guard.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other personnel designated as emergency personnel by the Governor pursuant to a declared emergency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Immediate family member” means any parent, spouse, child, or sibling.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The immunity provided by this section does not apply to damages as a result of any act or omission:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That occurs more than 6 months after the declaration of the public health emergency pursuant to s. 381.00315 or state of emergency pursuant to s. 252.36, unless the emergency is extended as provided in those sections, in which case the immunity provided by this section continues to apply for the duration of the extension and 6 months thereafter; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is unrelated to the original declared emergency or any extension thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “reckless disregard” means conduct that a reasonable person knew or should have known at the time such services were provided would likely result in injury so as to affect the life or health of another, taking into account the extent or serious nature of the prevailing circumstances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may register with a county emergency management agency as a temporary provider of housing, food, water, or electricity for emergency first responders if the county provides for such registration. A person who has registered with a county emergency management agency as a provider of temporary housing, food, water, or electricity to emergency first responders or the immediate family members of emergency first responders is presumed to have acted in good faith in providing such housing, food, water, or electricity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-43.</History>
</Section>