<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0252.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency mitigation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to prevention measures included in the state and local comprehensive emergency management plans, the Governor shall consider on a continuing basis steps that could be taken to mitigate the harmful consequences of emergencies. At the Governor’s direction and pursuant to any other authority and competence they have, state agencies, including, but not limited to, those charged with responsibilities in connection with flood plain management, stream encroachment and flow regulation, weather modification, fire prevention and control, air quality, public works, land use and land use planning, and construction standards, shall make studies of emergency-mitigation-related matters. The Governor, from time to time, shall make such recommendations to the Legislature, local governments, and other appropriate public and private entities as may facilitate measures for mitigation of the harmful consequences of emergencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate state agencies, in conjunction with the division, shall keep land uses and construction of structures and other facilities under continuing study and identify areas which are particularly susceptible to severe land shifting, subsidence, flood, or other catastrophic occurrence, manmade or natural. The studies under this subsection shall concentrate on means of reducing or avoiding the dangers caused by these occurrences or the consequences thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the division believes, on the basis of the studies or other competent evidence, that an area is susceptible to an emergency of catastrophic proportions without adequate warning; that existing building standards and land use controls in that area are inadequate and could add substantially to the magnitude of the emergency; and that changes in zoning regulations, other land use regulations, or building requirements are essential in order to further the purposes of this section, it shall specify the essential changes to the Governor. If the Governor upon review of the recommendation finds after public hearing that changes are essential, she or he shall so recommend to the agencies or political subdivisions with jurisdiction over the area and subject matter. If no action, or insufficient action, pursuant to her or his recommendations is taken within the time specified by the Governor, she or he shall so inform the Legislature and request legislative action appropriate to mitigate the impact of such an emergency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-285; s. 27, ch. 83-334; s. 135, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>