<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0492.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this chapter, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Professional Geologists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Geology” means the science which includes the treatment of the earth and its origin and history, in general; the investigation of the earth’s crust and interior and the solids and fluids, including all surface and underground waters, and gases which compose the earth; the study of the natural agents, forces, and processes which cause changes in the earth; and the utilization of this knowledge of the earth and its solids, fluids, and gases, and their collective properties and processes, for the benefit of humankind.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Geologist” means an individual who, by reason of her or his knowledge of geology, soils, mathematics, and the physical and life sciences, acquired by education and practical experience, is capable of practicing the science of geology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified geologist” means an individual who possesses all the qualifications for licensure under the provisions of this chapter, except that such person is not licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Professional geologist” means an individual who is licensed as a geologist under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of professional geology” means the performance of, or offer to perform, geological services, including, but not limited to, consultation, investigation, evaluation, planning, and geologic mapping, but not including mapping as prescribed in chapter 472, relating to geological work, except as specifically exempted by this chapter. Any person who practices any specialty branch of the profession of geology, or who by verbal claim, sign, advertisement, letterhead, card, or any other means represents herself or himself to be a professional geologist, or who through the use of some title implies that she or he is a professional geologist or that she or he is licensed under this chapter, or who holds herself or himself out as able to perform or does perform any geological services or work recognized as professional geology, shall be construed to be engaged in the practice of professional geology.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 19, ch. 87-403; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 195, ch. 94-218; s. 517, ch. 97-103; s. 56, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>