<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0492.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by endorsement; requirements; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who, upon applying to the department and remitting an application fee, has been certified by the board that he or she:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has met the qualifications for licensure in s. 492.105(1)(b)-(e).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is the holder of an active license in good standing in a state, trust, territory, or possession of the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was licensed through written examination in at least one state, trust, territory, or possession of the United States, the examination requirements of which have been approved by the board as substantially equivalent to or more stringent than those of this state, and has received a score on such examination which is equal to or greater than the score required by this state for licensure by examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has taken and successfully passed the laws and rules portion of the examination required for licensure as a professional geologist in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to practice professional geology to any applicant who successfully complies with the requirements of this section. The department shall not issue a license to any applicant who is under investigation in any jurisdiction for an offense which would constitute a violation of this chapter. Upon completion of the investigation, the disciplinary provisions of s. 492.113 shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 19, ch. 87-403; s. 51, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 294, ch. 94-119; s. 520, ch. 97-103; s. 60, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>