<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0492.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practice of professional geology by a firm, corporation, or partnership; certificate of authorization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of, or offer to practice, professional geology by individual professional geologists licensed under the provisions of this chapter through a firm, corporation, or partnership offering geological services to the public through individually licensed professional geologists as agents, employees, officers, or partners thereof is permitted subject to the provisions of this chapter, provided that:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At all times that it offers geological services to the public, the firm, corporation, or partnership has on file with the department the name and license number of one or more individuals who hold a current, active license as a professional geologist in the state and are serving as a geologist of record for the firm, corporation, or partnership. A geologist of record may be any principal officer or employee of such firm or corporation, or any partner or employee of such partnership, who holds a current, active license as a professional geologist in this state, or any other Florida-licensed professional geologist with whom the firm, corporation, or partnership has entered into a long-term, ongoing relationship, as defined by rule of the board, to serve as one of its geologists of record. It shall be the responsibility of the firm, corporation, or partnership and the geologist of record to notify the department of any changes in the relationship or identity of that geologist of record within 30 days after such change.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The firm, corporation, or partnership has been issued a certificate of authorization by the department as provided in this chapter. For purposes of this section, a certificate of authorization shall be required of any firm, corporation, partnership, association, or person practicing under a fictitious name and offering geological services to the public; except that, when an individual is practicing professional geology in her or his own name, she or he shall not be required to obtain a certificate of authorization under this section. Such certificate of authorization shall be renewed every 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All final geological papers or documents involving the practice of the profession of geology which have been prepared or approved for the use of such firm, corporation, or partnership, for delivery to any person for public record with the state, shall be dated and bear the signature and seal of the professional geologist or professional geologists who prepared or approved them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fact that a licensed professional geologist practices through a corporation or partnership shall not relieve the registrant from personal liability for negligence, misconduct, or wrongful acts committed by her or him. Partnership and all partners shall be jointly and severally liable for the negligence, misconduct, or wrongful acts committed by their agents, employees, or partners while acting in a professional capacity. Any officer, agent, or employee of a corporation shall be personally liable and accountable only for negligent acts, wrongful acts, or misconduct committed by her or him or committed by any person under her or his direct supervision and control, while rendering professional services on behalf of the corporation. The personal liability of a shareholder of a corporation, in her or his capacity as shareholder, shall be no greater than that of a shareholder-employee of a corporation incorporated under chapter 607. The corporation shall be liable up to the full value of its property for any negligent acts, wrongful acts, or misconduct committed by any of its officers, agents, or employees while they are engaged on behalf of the corporation in the rendering of professional services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The firm, corporation, or partnership desiring a certificate of authorization shall file with the department an application therefor, upon a form to be prescribed by the department, accompanied by the required application fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse to issue a certificate of authorization if any facts exist which would entitle the department to suspend or revoke an existing certificate of authorization or if the department, after giving persons involved a full and fair hearing, determines that any of the officers or directors of said firm or corporation, or partners of said partnership, have violated the provisions of s. 492.113.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 19, ch. 87-403; s. 52, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 294, ch. 94-119; s. 522, ch. 97-103; s. 61, ch. 2000-356; s. 1, ch. 2004-294.</History></Section>