<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0492.105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination; requirements; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a professional geologist shall apply to the department to take the licensure examination. The written licensure examination shall be designed to test an applicant’s qualifications to practice professional geology, and shall include such subjects as will tend to ascertain the applicant’s knowledge of the theory and the practice of professional geology and may include such subjects as are taught in curricula of accredited colleges and universities. The department shall examine each applicant who the board certifies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee and an examination fee which is refundable if the applicant is found to be ineligible to take the examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed any act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a professional geologist licensed pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fulfills the following educational requirements at a college or university the geological curricula of which meet the criteria established by an accrediting agency recognized by the United States Department of Education:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation from such college or university with a major in geology or other related science acceptable to the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory completion of at least 30 semester hours of geological courses, 24 of which must be at the third or fourth year or graduate level.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has at least 7 years of professional geological work experience, which shall include a minimum of 3 years of professional geological work under the supervision of a licensed or qualified geologist or professional engineer registered under chapter 471 as qualified in the field or discipline of professional engineering involved; or have a minimum of 5 accumulative years’ experience in responsible charge of geological work. The following criteria of education and experience qualify, as specified, toward accumulation of the required 7 years of professional geological work:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year of undergraduate study in the geological sciences shall count as <Fraction>1/2</Fraction> year of the experience requirement, up to a maximum of 2 years, and each year of graduate study shall count as 1 year of the experience requirement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit for undergraduate study, graduate study, and graduate courses, individually or in any combination thereof, shall in no case exceed a total of 2 years toward meeting the requirements for at least 7 years of professional geological work.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time teaching or research in the geological sciences at the college level shall be credited year for year toward meeting the requirement in this category.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the applicant shall have been demonstrated by his or her having performed the work in a responsible position as determined by the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to practice professional geology to any person who has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paid the appropriate license fee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Been certified by the board as qualified to practice professional geology; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passed the written licensure examination; provided that applicants meeting the other requirements of this section may be licensed without written examination if application is made in proper form within 1 calendar year of October 1, 1987.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue a license to any applicant who is under investigation in any jurisdiction for an offense which would constitute a violation of this chapter. Upon completion of the investigation, the disciplinary provisions of s. 492.113 shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 19, ch. 87-403; s. 1, ch. 89-79; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 294, ch. 94-119; s. 519, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 98-116; s. 58, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>