<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0492.113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions in subsection (3) may be taken:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of s. 492.112 or any other provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license to practice professional geology by bribery or fraudulent misrepresentations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice professional geology revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of professional geology or the ability to practice professional geology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the licensee knows to be false, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records include only those that are signed in the capacity of a licensed professional geologist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing an act of fraud or deceit, negligence, incompetence, or misconduct in the practice of professional geology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of chapter 455.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing on a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affixing or permitting to be affixed her or his name to geological papers, reports, or documents that were not prepared by her or him or under her or his responsible supervision, direction, or control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a rule of the department or board or any order of the department or board previously entered in a disciplinary hearing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall specify, by rule, what acts or omissions constitute a violation of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any person guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the licensee on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may specify.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restriction of the authorized scope of practice by the licensee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall reissue the license of a disciplined professional geologist or business upon certification by the board that the disciplined person has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 19, ch. 87-403; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 293, ch. 94-119; s. 524, ch. 97-103; s. 157, ch. 98-166; s. 218, ch. 2000-160; s. 63, ch. 2000-356; s. 3, ch. 2004-294.</History></Section>