<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0165.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards for incorporation, merger, and dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The incorporation of a new municipality, other than through merger of existing municipalities, must meet the following conditions in the area proposed for incorporation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must be compact and contiguous and amenable to separate municipal government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must have a total population, as determined in the latest official state census, special census, or estimate of population, in the area proposed to be incorporated of at least 1,500 persons in counties with a population of 75,000 or less, and of at least 5,000 population in counties with a population of more than 75,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must have an average population density of at least 1.5 persons per acre or have extraordinary conditions requiring the establishment of a municipal corporation with less existing density.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must have a minimum distance of any part of the area proposed for incorporation from the boundaries of an existing municipality within the county of at least 2 miles or have an extraordinary natural boundary which requires separate municipal government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It must have a proposed municipal charter which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribes the form of government and clearly defines the responsibility for legislative and executive functions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not prohibit the legislative body of the municipality from exercising its powers to levy any tax authorized by the Constitution or general law.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 10, Art. I of the State Constitution, the plan for incorporation must honor existing solid-waste contracts in the affected geographic area subject to incorporation. However, the plan for incorporation may provide for existing contracts for solid-waste-collection services to be honored only for 5 years or the remainder of the contract term, whichever is less, and may require that a copy of the pertinent portion of the contract or other written evidence of the duration of the contract, excluding any automatic renewals or evergreen provisions, be provided to the municipality within a reasonable time after a written request to do so.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The incorporation of a new municipality through merger of existing municipalities and associated unincorporated areas must meet the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The area proposed for incorporation must be compact and contiguous and susceptible to urban services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unincorporated area to be included must meet the standards provided in s. 171.042, if available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan for merger and incorporation must provide for an equitable arrangement in relation to bonded indebtedness and the status and pension rights of employees of each governmental unit proposed to be merged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 10, Art. I of the State Constitution, the plan for merger must honor existing solid-waste contracts in the affected geographic area subject to merger. However, the plan for merger may provide for existing contracts for solid-waste-collection services to be honored only for 5 years or the remainder of the contract term, whichever is shorter, and may require that a copy of the pertinent portion of the contract or other written evidence of the duration of the contract, excluding any automatic renewals or so-called “evergreen” provisions, be provided to the municipality within a reasonable time following a written request to do so.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dissolution of a municipality must meet the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The municipality to be dissolved must not be substantially surrounded by other municipalities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county or another municipality must be demonstrably able to provide necessary services to the municipal area proposed for dissolution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An equitable arrangement must be made in relation to bonded indebtedness and vested rights of employees of the municipality to be dissolved.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-192; s. 41, ch. 89-169; s. 6, ch. 98-258; s. 3, ch. 2000-304; s. 1, ch. 2002-23.</History></Section>