<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0099.09651" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Signature requirements for ballot position in year of apportionment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a year of apportionment, any candidate for representative to Congress, state Senate, or state House of Representatives seeking ballot position by the petition process prescribed in s. 99.095 shall obtain at least the number of signatures equal to one-third of 1 percent of the ideal population for the district of the office being sought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “ideal population” means the total population of the state based upon the most recent decennial census divided by the number of districts for representative to Congress, state Senate, or state House of Representatives. For the purposes of this section, ideal population shall be calculated as of July 1 of the year prior to apportionment. The ideal population for a state Senate district and a state representative district shall be calculated by dividing the total population of the state by 40 for a state Senate district and by dividing by 120 for a state representative district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signatures may be obtained from any registered voter in Florida regardless of party affiliation or district boundaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petitions shall state the name of the office the candidate is seeking, but shall not include a district number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, all requirements and procedures relating to the petition process shall conform to the requirements and procedures in nonapportionment years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 91-107; s. 4, ch. 99-318; s. 17, ch. 2005-277.</History></Section>