<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0099.103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of State to remit part of filing fees and party assessments of candidates to state executive committee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If more than three-fourths of the full authorized membership of the state executive committee of any party was elected at the last previous election for such members and if such party is declared by the Department of State to have recorded on the registration books of the counties, as of the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January prior to the primary election in general election years, 5 percent of the total registration of such counties when added together, such committee shall receive, for the purpose of meeting its expenses, all filing fees collected by the Department of State from its candidates less an amount equal to 15 percent of the filing fees, which amount the Department of State shall deposit in the General Revenue Fund of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not later than 20 days after the close of qualifying in even-numbered years, the Department of State shall remit 95 percent of all filing fees, less the amount deposited in general revenue pursuant to subsection (1), or party assessments that may have been collected by the department to the respective state executive committees of the parties complying with subsection (1). Party assessments collected by the Department of State shall be remitted to the appropriate state executive committee, irrespective of other requirements of this section, provided such committee is duly organized under the provisions of chapter 103. The remainder of filing fees or party assessments collected by the Department of State shall be remitted to the appropriate state executive committees not later than the date of the primary election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29935, 1955; s. 24, ch. 57-1; s. 1, ch. 57-62; s. 4, ch. 57-166; s. 1, ch. 69-295; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 11, ch. 77-175; s. 2, ch. 83-251; s. 4, ch. 91-107; s. 14, ch. 97-13; s. 10, ch. 2005-286.</History></Section>