<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0385.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Diabetes Advisory Council; creation; function; membership.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To guide a statewide comprehensive approach to diabetes prevention, diagnosis, education, care, treatment, impact, and costs thereof, there is created a Diabetes Advisory Council that serves as the advisory unit to the Department of Health, other governmental agencies, professional and other organizations, and the general public. The council shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide statewide leadership to continuously improve the lives of Floridians with diabetes and reduce the burden of diabetes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a forum for the discussion and study of issues related to the public health approach for the delivery of health care services to persons with diabetes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By June 30 of each year, meet with the State Surgeon General or designee to make specific recommendations regarding the public health aspects of the prevention and control of diabetes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the council shall be appointed by the Governor with advice from the State Surgeon General. Members shall serve 4-year terms or until their successors are appointed or qualified.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall be composed of 26 citizens of the state who have knowledge of, or work in, the area of diabetes mellitus as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five interested citizens, three of whom are affected by diabetes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-one members, who must include one representative from each of the following areas: nursing with diabetes-educator certification; dietary with diabetes educator certification; podiatry; ophthalmology or optometry; psychology; pharmacy; adult endocrinology; pediatric endocrinology; the American Diabetes Association (ADA); the Juvenile Diabetes Foundation (JDF); the Florida Academy of Family Physicians; a community health center; a county health department; an American Diabetes Association recognized community education program; each medical school in the state; an osteopathic medical school; the insurance industry; a Children’s Medical Services diabetes regional program; and an employer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more representatives from the Department of Health, who shall serve on the council as ex officio members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall annually elect from its members a chair and vice chair. The council shall meet at the chair’s discretion; however, at least three meetings shall be held each year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting its meetings, the council shall use accepted rules of procedure. A majority of the members of the council constitutes a quorum, and action by a majority of a quorum is necessary for the council to take any official action. The Department of Health shall keep a complete record of the proceedings of each meeting. The record shall show the names of the members present and the actions taken. The records shall be kept on file with the department, and these and other documents about matters within the jurisdiction of the council may be inspected by members of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without remuneration but may be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061, to the extent resources are available.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall serve as an intermediary for the council if the council coordinates, applies for, or accepts any grants, funds, gifts, or services made available to it by any agency or department of the Federal Government, or any private agency or individual, for assistance in the operation of the council.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 80-62; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 6, 97, ch. 86-220; ss. 3, 5, 6, ch. 89-93; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 684, ch. 95-148; s. 69, ch. 97-101; s. 32, ch. 97-237; s. 25, ch. 99-397; s. 42, ch. 2008-6; s. 1, ch. 2010-57.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.345.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>