<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0450.191" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Executive Office of the Governor; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Executive Office of the Governor is authorized and directed to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consult with migrant and seasonal workers and their employers as to the ways and means of improving living and working conditions of migrant and seasonal workers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Health in establishing minimum standards of preventive and curative health and of housing and sanitation in migrant labor camps and in making surveys to determine the adequacy of preventive and curative health services available to occupants of migrant labor camps.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide coordination for the enforcement of ss. 381.008-381.0088 and ss. 450.27-450.38.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Business and Professional Regulation in coordinating and enforcing all applicable labor laws, including, but not limited to, those relating to private employment agencies, child labor, wage payments, wage claims, and farm labor contractors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Education to provide educational facilities for the children of migrant laborers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to establish minimum standards for the transporting of migrant laborers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services to conduct an education program for employers of migrant laborers pertaining to the standards, methods, and objectives of the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Children and Family Services in coordinating all public assistance programs as they may apply to migrant laborers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate all federal, state, and local programs pertaining to migrant laborers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with the Department of Economic Opportunity in the recruitment and referral of migrant laborers and other persons for the planting, cultivation, and harvesting of agricultural crops in Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall arrange, through the Department of Health, for the provision of the supplementary services set forth in paragraph (1)(b) to the extent of available appropriations. Such services may be provided through the use of one or more traveling dispensaries, or by contract with physicians, dentists, hospitals, or clinics, or in such manner as may be recommended by the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 69-106; s. 155, ch. 77-104; s. 141, ch. 79-190; s. 40, ch. 81-169; s. 54, ch. 91-297; s. 218, ch. 99-8; s. 142, ch. 2000-165; s. 62, ch. 2002-194; s. 6, ch. 2004-64; s. 401, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>