<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0450.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this chapter, the word, phrase, or term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farm work” includes all agricultural labor performed upon farms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farm” includes stock, dairy, poultry, fruit, fur-bearing animal, and truck farms; ranches; nurseries; and orchards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child” or “minor” means any person 17 years of age or younger, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is or has been married;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s disability of nonage has been removed by a court of competent jurisdiction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is serving or has served in the Armed Forces of the United States;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It has been found by a court having jurisdiction over the person that it is in the best interest of such minor to work and the court specifically approves any employment of such person, including the terms and conditions of such employment; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has graduated from an accredited high school or holds a high school equivalency diploma.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Entertainment industry” means any group, entity, organization, or individual, in which the services of any minor are rendered in any capacity in conjunction with any motion picture, television, video, audio, theatrical, or still photography, using any format whether now existing or hereafter developed, including, but not limited to, theatrical film, commercial, documentary, television, radio, and/or cable, by any medium, whether now existing or hereafter developed, including theater, television, audiocassette, or videocassette; legitimate theaters or photography; recording; modeling; theatrical productions or publicity; rodeos; circuses; musical performances; or any other performances where minors perform.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 75-195; s. 3, ch. 81-192; s. 35, ch. 83-174; s. 8, ch. 91-147; s. 25, ch. 95-345; s. 135, ch. 2000-165; s. 61, ch. 2002-194.</History></Section>