<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0450.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance, revocation, and suspension of, and refusal to issue or renew, certificate of registration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue to any person a certificate of registration as a farm labor contractor, nor shall it renew such certificate, until:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has executed a written application therefor in a form and pursuant to regulations prescribed by the department and has submitted such information as the department may prescribe.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has obtained and holds a valid federal certificate of registration as a farm labor contractor, or a farm labor contractor employee, unless exempt by federal law. However, the department shall renew a certificate of registration after such person’s federal certificate of registration expires if such person files a timely application for renewal with the United States Department of Labor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person pays to the department, by cashier’s check, certified check, or money order, a nonrefundable application fee of $125. Fees collected by the department under this subsection shall be deposited in the State Treasury into the Professional Regulation Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has successfully taken and passed the farm labor contractor examination.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has designated an agent to receive service of process and other official or legal documents. The agent must be available during regular business hours, Monday through Friday, to accept service on behalf of the farm labor contractor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may revoke, suspend, or refuse to issue or renew any certificate of registration when it is shown that the farm labor contractor has:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violated or failed to comply with any provision of this part or the rules adopted pursuant to this part;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made any misrepresentation or false statement in his or her application for a certificate of registration;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Given false or misleading information concerning terms, conditions, or existence of employment to persons who are recruited or hired to work on a farm;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Been assessed a civil fine by the department for which payment is overdue;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to pay reemployment assistance taxes as determined by the Department of Economic Opportunity; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to pay federal employee taxes as determined by the Internal Revenue Service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall suspend, revoke, or refuse to issue or renew a certificate of registration upon receipt of a final order of suspension, revocation, or refusal to issue or renew the federal certificate of registration from the United States Department of Labor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revocation, suspension of, or refusal to renew any permit hereunder will not render any then-current and valid contract invalid nor affect the terms of such contract for the duration of the growing season then in progress.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse to issue or renew, or may suspend or revoke, a certificate of registration if the applicant or holder is not the real party in interest in the application or certificate of registration and the real party in interest is a person who has been refused issuance or renewal of a certificate, has had a certificate suspended or revoked, or does not qualify under this section for a certificate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may permanently revoke or refuse to issue or renew a certificate of registration if such applicant or certificateholder has been convicted within the preceding 5 years of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A crime under state or federal law:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relating to gambling, or to the sale, distribution, or possession of alcoholic beverages.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committed in connection with, or incident to, any farm labor contracting activities; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony under state or federal law involving robbery, bribery, extortion, embezzlement, grand larceny, burglary, or arson.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may permanently revoke or refuse to issue or renew a certificate of registration if such applicant or certificateholder has been convicted of a violation of narcotics laws, murder, rape, assault with intent to kill, assault that inflicts grievous bodily injury, prostitution, peonage, smuggling, or harboring individuals who have entered the country illegally.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receipt and acceptance of a certificate of registration as a farm labor contractor constitutes unconditional permission for and acquiescence by the contractor to the inspection by department personnel of books, ledgers, and all other documents that are related to the performance of the contractor’s farm labor activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 6, ch. 71-234; s. 1, ch. 71-977; s. 1, ch. 77-25; ss. 3, 4, ch. 83-42; s. 5, ch. 85-243; ss. 3, 4, ch. 90-245; s. 18, ch. 91-147; s. 2, ch. 94-179; s. 176, ch. 97-103; s. 145, ch. 2000-165; s. 13, ch. 2004-64; s. 28, ch. 2004-234; s. 4, ch. 2007-86; s. 2, ch. 2010-124; s. 402, ch. 2011-142; s. 74, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 77-25, provides that this section is repealed when an agreement is made as permitted in ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25; ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25, were amended by s. 1, ch. 85-243.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>