<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0450.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hazardous occupations prohibited; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No minor 15 years of age or younger, whether or not such person’s disabilities of nonage have been removed by marriage or otherwise, shall be employed or permitted or suffered to work in any of the following occupations:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with power-driven machinery, except power mowers with cutting blades 40 inches or less.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any manufacturing that makes or processes a product with the use of industrial machines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacture, transportation, or use of explosive or highly flammable substances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sawmills or logging operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On any scaffolding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In heavy work in the building trades.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of a motor vehicle, except a motorscooter which he or she is licensed to operate, except that 14-year-old and 15-year-old workers may drive farm tractors in the course of their farmwork under the close supervision of their parents on a family-operated farm, and except that qualified 14-year-old and 15-year-old workers may drive tractors in the course of their farmwork under the close supervision of the farm operator. “Qualified,” as used herein, means having completed a training course in tractor operation sponsored by a recognized agricultural or vocational agency, as evidenced by duly executed certificate, such certificate to be filed with the farm operator for the duration of the employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In oiling, cleaning, or wiping machinery or shafting or applying belts to pulleys.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In repairing of elevators or other hoisting apparatus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work in freezers or meat coolers and all work in preparation of meats for sale, except wrapping, sealing, labeling, weighing, pricing, and stocking when performed in another area. This shall not prohibit work done in the normal operations of a food service facility licensed by chapter 509.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven laundry or drycleaning machinery or any similar power-driven machinery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At spray painting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alligator wrestling, work in connection with snake pits, or similar hazardous activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Door-to-door selling of magazine subscriptions, candy, cookies, flowers, or other merchandise or commodities, except merchandise of nonprofit organizations, such as the Girl Scouts of America or the Boy Scouts of America.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In working with meat and vegetable slicing machines.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No minor under 18 years of age, whether such person’s disabilities of nonage have been removed, shall be employed or permitted or suffered to work in any of the following places of employment or in any of the following occupations, provided that the provisions of paragraphs (b), (e), (g), (h), (j), (m), (o), and (q) shall not apply to the employment of student learners under the conditions prescribed in s. 450.161:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In or around explosive or radioactive materials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On any scaffolding, roof, superstructure, residential or nonresidential building construction, or ladder above 6 feet.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In or around toxic substances or corrosives, including pesticides or herbicides, unless proper field entry time allowances have been followed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any mining occupation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven woodworking machines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven hoisting apparatus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven metal forming, punching, or shearing machines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Slaughtering, meat packing, processing, or rendering, except as provided in 29 C.F.R. part 570.61(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven bakery machinery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the operation of power-driven paper products and printing machines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturing brick, tile, and like products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wrecking or demolition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Excavation operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Logging or sawmilling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Working on electric apparatus or wiring.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Firefighting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating or assisting to operate, including starting, stopping, connecting or disconnecting, feeding, or any other activity involving physical contact associated with operating, a tractor over 20 PTO horsepower, any trencher or earthmoving equipment, fork lift, or any harvesting, planting, or plowing machinery, or any moving machinery.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No minor under 18 years of age, whether such person’s disabilities of nonage have been removed by marriage or otherwise, shall be employed or permitted or suffered to work in any place of employment or at any occupation hazardous or injurious to the life, health, safety, or welfare of such minor, as such places of employment or occupations may be determined and declared by the department to be hazardous and injurious to the life, health, safety, or welfare of such minor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to minors employed in the entertainment industry.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 28240, 1953; s. 5, ch. 57-224; ss. 4, 5, ch. 61-182; s. 1, ch. 63-82; ss. 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-283; s. 2, ch. 75-195; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 11, ch. 78-95; s. 42, ch. 79-7; s. 36, ch. 83-174; s. 11, ch. 91-147; s. 1, ch. 92-151; s. 26, ch. 95-345; s. 1, ch. 96-356; s. 1076, ch. 97-103; s. 136, ch. 2000-165.</History></Section>