<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0450.28" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farm labor contractor” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who, for a fee or other valuable consideration, recruits, transports into or within the state, supplies, or hires at any one time in any calendar year one or more farm workers to work for, or under the direction, supervision, or control of, a third person; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who recruits, transports into or within the state, supplies, or hires at any one time in any calendar year one or more farm workers and who, for a fee or other valuable consideration, directs, supervises, or controls all or any part of the work of such workers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Carpool” means an arrangement made by the workers using one worker’s own vehicle for transportation to and from work and for which the driver or owner of the vehicle is not paid by any third person other than the members of the carpool.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Immediate family member” means a person having one of the following relationships to another: husband, wife, father, mother, son, or daughter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Minor violation” means a violation of a specific state or federal law or rule that does not result in economic or physical harm to any person recruited, transported, supplied, or hired by a farm labor contractor or create a significant threat of such harm.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Major violation” means a violation of a specific state or federal law or rule that results in economic or physical harm to any person recruited, transported, supplied, or hired by a farm labor contractor or creates a significant threat of such harm.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Timely application for renewal” means the application for a federal certificate of registration as a farm labor contractor, or a farm labor contractor employee, is filed, as defined by federal law, with the United States Department of Labor at least 30 days before its expiration date.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 71-234; s. 1, ch. 77-25; s. 156, ch. 77-104; s. 44, ch. 79-7; s. 1, ch. 83-42; s. 41, ch. 83-174; s. 2, ch. 85-243; s. 30, ch. 95-345; s. 143, ch. 2000-165; s. 63, ch. 2002-194; s. 11, ch. 2004-64; s. 8, ch. 2006-81; s. 1, ch. 2010-124.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 77-25, provides that this section is repealed when an agreement is made as permitted in ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25; ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25, were amended by s. 1, ch. 85-243.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>