<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0450.38" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement of farm labor laws.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, association, or corporation not excluded under s. 450.29 that commits a minor violation of this part and, upon conviction, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, is punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, association, or corporation that commits a major violation of this part and, upon conviction, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, is punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, association, or corporation that commits a violation of this part or of any rule adopted thereunder may be assessed a civil penalty of not more than $2,500 for each such violation. Such assessed penalties shall be paid by cashier’s check, certified check, or money order and shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund. The department shall not institute or maintain any administrative proceeding to assess a civil penalty under this subsection when the violation is the subject of a criminal indictment or information under this section which results in a criminal penalty being imposed, or of a criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding by the United States government or an agency thereof which results in a criminal or civil penalty being imposed. The department may adopt rules prescribing the criteria to be used to determine the amount of the civil penalty and to provide notification to persons assessed a civil penalty under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a complaint of the department being filed in the circuit court of the county in which the farm labor contractor resides or may be doing business, any farm labor contractor who fails to obtain a certificate of registration as required by this part may, in addition to such penalties, be enjoined from engaging in any activity which requires the farm labor contractor to possess a certificate of registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of any investigation or proceeding conducted by the department, the secretary of the department or the secretary’s designee shall have the power to administer oaths, take depositions, make inspections when authorized by statute, issue subpoenas which shall be supported by affidavit, serve subpoenas and other process, and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, documents, and other evidence. The secretary of the department or the secretary’s designee shall exercise this power on the secretary’s own initiative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A farm labor contractor who commits a minor violation of this part shall be issued a warning for the first violation. A civil penalty in increments of $250 may be assessed for each successive violation of a specific statute or rule of this part up to a maximum of $2,500.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A farm labor contractor who commits a major violation of a specific statute or rule of this part shall be assessed a civil penalty of up to $2,500 in accordance with the criteria established by the department pursuant to s. 450.38.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys for the enforcement of the farm labor laws shall be transferred to the Professional Regulation Trust Fund from the Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund of the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12A, ch. 71-234; s. 1, ch. 77-25; s. 6, ch. 85-243; s. 6, ch. 90-245; s. 18, ch. 91-147; s. 4, ch. 94-179; s. 13, ch. 98-149; s. 150, ch. 2000-165; s. 19, ch. 2004-64; s. 1, ch. 2005-58.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 77-25, provides that this section is repealed when an agreement is made as permitted in ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25; ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25, were amended by s. 1, ch. 85-243.</Text></Note></Section>