<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0450.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts of farm labor contractor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee may not:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any misrepresentation or false statement in his or her application for a certificate of registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or cause to be made to any person any false, fraudulent, or misleading representation or publish or circulate or cause to be published or circulated any false, fraudulent, or misleading information concerning the terms, conditions, or existence of employment at any place or places, by any person or persons, or of any individual or individuals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any charge or deduction from wages for any tools, equipment, transportation, or recruiting fees that are for the benefit of the employer unless in compliance with the federal Fair Labor Standards Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retaliate against any person that has filed a complaint or aided an investigation pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with or employ any person acting in the capacity of a farm labor contractor, or performing activities defined in s. 450.28(1), when that person does not have a current certificate of registration issued by the department pursuant to the requirements of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 71-234; s. 1, ch. 77-25; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-551; s. 30, ch. 92-173; s. 177, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 2002-161; s. 16, ch. 2004-64.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 77-25, provides that this section is repealed when an agreement is made as permitted in ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25; ss. 2-4, ch. 77-25, were amended by s. 1, ch. 85-243.</Text></Note></Section>