<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0895.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Term of RICO lien notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of a RICO lien notice shall be for a period of 6 years from the date of filing, unless a renewal RICO lien notice has been filed by the investigative agency; in such case, the term of the renewal RICO lien notice shall be for a period of 6 years from the date of its filing. The investigative agency shall be entitled to only one renewal of the RICO lien notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The investigative agency filing a RICO lien notice may release in whole or in part the RICO lien notice or may release any specific real property or beneficial interest from the RICO lien notice upon such terms and conditions as it may determine. A release of a RICO lien notice executed by the investigative agency may be filed in the official records of any county. No charge or fee shall be imposed for the filing of a release of a RICO lien notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no civil proceeding has been instituted by the investigative agency seeking a forfeiture of any property owned by the person named in the RICO lien notice, the acquittal in the criminal proceeding of the person named in the RICO lien notice or the dismissal of the criminal proceeding shall terminate the RICO lien notice and, in such case, the filing of the RICO lien notice shall have no effect. In the event the criminal proceeding has been dismissed or the person named in the RICO lien notice has been acquitted in the criminal proceeding, the RICO lien notice shall continue for the duration of the civil proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no civil proceeding is then pending against the person named in a RICO lien notice, the person named in the RICO lien notice may institute an action in the county where the notice has been filed against the investigative agency that filed the notice seeking a release or extinguishment of the notice. In such case:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall, upon the motion of such person, immediately enter an order setting a date for hearing, which date shall be not less than 5 or more than 10 days after the suit has been filed, and the order along with a copy of the complaint shall be served on the investigative agency within 3 days after the institution of the suit. At the hearing, the court shall take evidence on the issue of whether any real property or beneficial interest owned by such person is covered by the RICO lien notice or is otherwise subject to forfeiture under the Florida RICO Act; if such person shows by a preponderance of the evidence that the RICO lien notice is not applicable to him or her or that any real property or beneficial interest owned by the person is not subject to forfeiture under the Florida RICO Act, the court shall enter a judgment extinguishing the RICO lien notice or releasing the real property or beneficial interest from the RICO lien notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall immediately enter its order releasing from the RICO lien notice any specific real property or beneficial interest if a sale of such real property or beneficial interest is pending and the filing of the notice prevents the sale of the property or interest; however, the proceeds resulting from the sale of such real property or beneficial interest shall be deposited into the registry of the court, subject to the further order of the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the hearing set forth in paragraph (a), the court may release any real property or beneficial interest from the RICO lien notice, upon the posting by such person of such security as is equal to the value of the real property or beneficial interest owned by such person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event a civil proceeding is pending against a person named in a RICO lien notice, the court upon motion by such person may grant the relief set forth herein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 81-141; s. 1450, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>