<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0201.133" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of tax on documents not to be recorded; certificates of registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 201.132, any person who has averaged or will average at least 5 taxable transactions per month shall register with the department and remit to the department all taxes due for documents not to be recorded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person described in subsection (1) shall apply for a certificate of registration with the department for each business location. The application shall include the name and address of the applicant together with such other information as the department may require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue certificates of registration to qualified applicants who are required to register under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person described in subsection (1) who is required to register and remit tax imposed by this chapter shall file a report with the department not later than the 20th day of each month certifying the amount of tax payable for the preceding month, and a remittance shall be submitted with the report to cover the amount of tax payable for the preceding month. Any person who fails to timely report and pay any tax as required under this section shall be subject to penalties and interest imposed by this chapter. Report forms shall be furnished by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons described in subsection (1) shall be subject to audit and shall make their records available for ready inspection by the department and shall post a bond at their own expense as may be required by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons described in subsection (1) shall keep a journal, or other account book or record of original entry, showing a listing of all documents executed and delivered. The journal shall show a daily listing of such documents unless another time period is required by the department. The journal shall show every transaction and the amount, whether the transaction is taxable or not. In the case of taxable transactions, the journal shall show the amount of tax payable with respect to each transaction. In the case of nontaxable transactions, the journal shall disclose the basis on which the exemption from tax is claimed. Such records shall be kept in permanent form and retained indefinitely in the files subject to verification by the representative of the department. The following notation or similar language along with the certificate of registration number shall be made on each individual document requiring tax: “Florida documentary stamp tax required by law in the amount of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> has been paid or will be paid directly to the Department of Revenue. Certificate of Registration #<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 201.132, any person engaged in an average of less than 5 taxable transactions per month is required to remit tax imposed by this chapter to the department not later than the 20th day of the month for tax due for the preceding month for documents not to be recorded. Any person who fails to timely report and pay any tax as required under this subsection shall be subject to penalties and interest imposed by this chapter. Report forms shall be furnished by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the department may require:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted for the preceding four calendar quarters did not exceed $1,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A semiannual return and payment when the tax remitted for the preceding four calendar quarters did not exceed $500.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual return and payment when the tax remitted for the preceding four calendar quarters did not exceed $100.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 81-14; s. 14, ch. 96-395.</History></Section>