<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0201.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discretionary surtax; administration and collection; Housing Assistance Loan Trust Fund; reporting requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county, as defined by s. 125.011(1), may levy, subject to the provisions of s. 125.0167, a discretionary surtax on documents taxable under the provisions of s. 201.02, except that there shall be no surtax on any document pursuant to which the interest granted, assigned, transferred, or conveyed involves only a single-family residence. The single-family residence may be a condominium unit, a unit held through stock ownership or membership representing a proprietary interest in a corporation owning a fee or a leasehold initially in excess of 98 years, or a detached dwelling.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of chapter 201, except s. 201.15, apply to the surtax. The Department of Revenue shall pay to the governing authority of the county which levies the surtax all taxes, penalties, and interest collected under this section less any costs of administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county that levies the surtax shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include in the financial report required under s. 218.32 information showing the revenues and the expenses of the trust fund for the fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt a housing plan every 3 years which includes provisions substantially similar to the plans required in s. 420.9075(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have adopted an affordable housing element of its comprehensive land use plan which complies with s. 163.3177(6)(f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require by resolution that the staff or entity that has administrative authority for implementing the housing plan prepare and submit to the county’s governing body an annual report substantially similar to the annual report required in s. 420.9075(10).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 83-220; s. 1, ch. 84-270; s. 1, ch. 89-252; ss. 1, 7, ch. 2009-131.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed effective October 1, 2031, by s. 3, ch. 83-220, as amended by s. 1, ch. 84-270; s. 1, ch. 89-252; and s. 1, ch. 2009-131.</Text></Note></Section>