<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0105.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of election or retention to office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELECTION.<EmDash />In circuits and counties holding elections:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of an unopposed candidate for the office of circuit judge, county court judge, or member of a school board shall not appear on any ballot, and such candidate shall be deemed to have voted for himself or herself at the general election.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If two or more candidates, neither of whom is a write-in candidate, qualify for such an office, the names of those candidates shall be placed on the ballot at the primary election. If any candidate for such office receives a majority of the votes cast for such office in the primary election, the name of the candidate who receives such majority shall not appear on any other ballot unless a write-in candidate has qualified for such office. An unopposed candidate shall be deemed to have voted for himself or herself at the general election. If no candidate for such office receives a majority of the votes cast for such office in the primary election, the names of the two candidates receiving the highest number of votes for such office shall be placed on the general election ballot. If more than two candidates receive an equal and highest number of votes, the name of each candidate receiving an equal and highest number of votes shall be placed on the general election ballot. In any contest in which there is a tie for second place and the candidate placing first did not receive a majority of the votes cast for such office, the name of the candidate placing first and the name of each candidate tying for second shall be placed on the general election ballot.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The candidate who receives the highest number of votes cast for the office in the general election shall be elected to such office. If the vote at the general election results in a tie, the outcome shall be determined by lot.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RETENTION.<EmDash />With respect to any justice or judge who qualifies to run for retention in office, the question prescribed in s. 105.041(2) shall be placed on the ballot at the general election. If a majority of the qualified electors voting on such question within the territorial jurisdiction of the court vote for retention, the justice or judge shall be retained for a term of 6 years commencing on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January following the general election. If less than a majority of the qualified electors voting on such question within the territorial jurisdiction of the court vote for retention, a vacancy shall exist in such office upon the expiration of the term being served by the justice or judge.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 71-49; s. 38, ch. 77-175; s. 19, ch. 81-105; s. 632, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 99-326; s. 4, ch. 99-355; s. 23, ch. 2005-286.</History></Section>