<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.0195" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court-issued delayed birth certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the provisions of s. 382.019, any state resident or person born in this state who does not have a birth certificate may, at any time after birth, file a petition in the circuit court in the county of residence or in the alleged county of his or her birth, setting forth the date, place, and parentage of birth and petitioning the court to issue a delayed birth certificate. The petition must be on a form furnished by the department and must be accompanied by a certified statement from the state registrar of the alleged state of birth, stating that, based on the facts submitted by the petitioner, a birth certificate for the petitioner is not on file.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of the petition, the court shall hold a hearing at which time such evidence may be presented as may be required by the court to establish the fact of the petitioner’s birth and the date, place, and parentage of his or her birth. However, a certificate may not be granted based solely on the uncorroborated testimony of the petitioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the evidence is sufficient, the court shall issue a delayed birth certificate on a form furnished by the department. Documentation submitted by the petitioner in support of the petition shall be recorded on the delayed birth certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original and court copies of the delayed birth certificate issued by the court shall be distributed as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One copy shall be filed in the circuit court as a permanent record.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the birth occurred in this state, one copy shall be delivered to the petitioner and the original shall be mailed to the department by the clerk of the court within 10 days after the delayed certificate is issued by the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the birth occurred outside this state, the original certificate plus one copy shall be delivered to the petitioner by the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A delayed birth certificate issued by a court pursuant to this section and registered with the department may not be amended except by court order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, 6, 10, ch. 21931, 1943; s. 1, ch. 22887, 1945; s. 24, ch. 63-559; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 73-299; s. 24, ch. 73-334; s. 118, ch. 77-147; s. 7, ch. 83-230; s. 16, ch. 87-387; s. 667, ch. 95-148; s. 101, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of former ss. 382.40, 382.44, 382.45, 382.48; former s. 382.018.</Text></Note></Section>