<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth” means a certificate issued to record and memorialize the birth of a stillborn child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certification” or “certified” means a document containing all or a part of the exact information contained on the original vital record, and which, when issued by the State Registrar, has the full force and effect of the original vital record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified homeless youth” means a minor who is a homeless child or youth, including an unaccompanied youth, as those terms are defined in 42 U.S.C. s. 11434a, and who has been certified as homeless or unaccompanied by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A school district homeless liaison;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of an emergency shelter program funded by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, or the director’s designee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of a runaway or homeless youth basic center or transitional living program funded by the United States Department of Health and Human Services, or the director’s designee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dead body” means a human body or such parts of a human body from the condition of which it reasonably may be concluded that death recently occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dissolution of marriage” includes an annulment of marriage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fetal death” means death prior to the complete expulsion or extraction of a product of human conception from its mother if the 20th week of gestation has been reached and the death is indicated by the fact that after such expulsion or extraction the fetus does not breathe or show any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Final disposition” means the burial, interment, cremation, removal from the state, or other authorized disposition of a dead body or a fetus as described in subsection (7). In the case of cremation, dispersion of ashes or cremation residue is considered to occur after final disposition; the cremation itself is considered final disposition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Funeral director” means a licensed funeral director or direct disposer licensed pursuant to chapter 497 or other person who first assumes custody of or effects the final disposition of a dead body or a fetus as described in subsection (7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Legal age” means a person who is not a minor, or a minor who has had the disability of nonage removed as provided under chapter 743.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Live birth” means the complete expulsion or extraction of a product of human conception from its mother, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which, after such expulsion, breathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, and definite movement of the voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical examiner” means a person appointed pursuant to chapter 406.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a person authorized to practice medicine, osteopathic medicine, or chiropractic medicine pursuant to chapter 458, chapter 459, or chapter 460.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registrant” means the child entered on a birth certificate, the deceased entered on a death certificate, and the husband or wife entered on a marriage or dissolution of marriage record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stillbirth” means an unintended, intrauterine fetal death after a gestational age of not less than 20 completed weeks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vital records” or “records” means certificates or reports of birth, death, fetal death, marriage, dissolution of marriage, name change filed pursuant to s. 68.07, and data related thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vital statistics” means a system of registration, collection, preservation, amendment, and certification of vital records, the collection of other reports required by this act, and activities related thereto, including the tabulation, analysis, and publication of data obtained from vital records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-387; s. 52, ch. 97-101; s. 87, ch. 97-237; s. 254, ch. 98-166; s. 2, ch. 2004-34; s. 138, ch. 2004-301; s. 2, ch. 2006-118; s. 1, ch. 2012-186.</History></Section>