<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.009" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recognition of brain death under certain circumstances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For legal and medical purposes, where respiratory and circulatory functions are maintained by artificial means of support so as to preclude a determination that these functions have ceased, the occurrence of death may be determined where there is the irreversible cessation of the functioning of the entire brain, including the brain stem, determined in accordance with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determination of death pursuant to this section shall be made in accordance with currently accepted reasonable medical standards by two physicians licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459. One physician shall be the treating physician, and the other physician shall be a board-eligible or board-certified neurologist, neurosurgeon, internist, pediatrician, surgeon, or anesthesiologist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The next of kin of the patient shall be notified as soon as practicable of the procedures to determine death under this section. The medical records shall reflect such notice; if such notice has not been given, the medical records shall reflect the attempts to identify and notify the next of kin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No recovery shall be allowed nor shall criminal proceedings be instituted in any court in this state against a physician or licensed medical facility that makes a determination of death in accordance with this section or which acts in reliance thereon, if such determination is made in accordance with the accepted standard of care for such physician or facility set forth in <Reference Number="1" />s. 766.102. Except for a diagnosis of brain death, the standard set forth in this section is not the exclusive standard for determining death or for the withdrawal of life support systems.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-216; s. 8, ch. 87-387.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substituted by the editors for a reference to s. 768.45, which was transferred to s. 766.102 by the reviser incident to compiling the 1988 Supplement to the Florida Statutes 1987.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 382.085.</Text></Note></Section>