<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of local registrars.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local registrar is charged with the strict and thorough enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and rules adopted hereunder in his or her registration district, and shall make an immediate report to the department of any violation or apparent violation of this law or rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local registrar shall make available blank forms as necessary and shall examine each certificate of live birth, death, or fetal death when presented for registration in order to ascertain whether or not it has been completed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and adopted rules. All birth, death, and fetal death certificates shall be typewritten in permanent black ink, and a certificate is not complete and correct if it does not supply each item of information called for or satisfactorily account for its omission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local registrar or his or her deputy, if authorized by the department, shall sign as registrar in attestation of the date of registration and may also make and preserve a local record of each birth, death, and fetal death certificate registered by him or her, in such manner as directed by the department. The local registrar shall transmit daily to the department all original certificates registered. If no births, deaths, or fetal deaths occurred in any month, the local registrar or deputy shall, on the 7th day of the following month, report that fact to the department on a form provided for such purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local registrar, immediately upon appointment, shall designate one or more deputy registrars to act on behalf of the local registrar.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 19, 23, ch. 6892, 1915; RGS 2072, 2089, 2092; CGL 3272, 3289, 3292; s. 16, ch. 25372, 1949; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 114, ch. 77-147; s. 4, ch. 87-387; s. 663, ch. 95-148; s. 90, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of former ss. 382.05, 382.33, 382.36.</Text></Note></Section>