<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.006" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Burial-transit permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funeral director who first assumes custody of a dead body or fetus must obtain a burial-transit permit prior to final disposition and within 5 days after death. The application for a burial-transit permit must be signed by the funeral director and include the funeral director’s license number. The funeral director must attest on the application that he or she has contacted the physician’s or medical examiner’s office and has received assurance that the physician or medical examiner will provide medical certification of the cause of death within 72 hours after receipt of the death certificate from the funeral director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A burial-transit permit shall be issued by the local registrar or subregistrar of the registration district in which the death occurred or the body was found. A burial-transit permit shall not be issued:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Until a complete and satisfactory certificate of death or fetal death has been filed in accordance with the requirements of this chapter and adopted rules, unless the funeral director provides adequate assurance that a complete and satisfactory certificate will be so registered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except under conditions prescribed by the department, if the death occurred from some disease which is held by the department to be infectious, contagious, or communicable and dangerous to the public health.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funeral director shall deliver the burial-transit permit to the person in charge of the place of final disposition, before interring or otherwise disposing of the dead body or fetus within this state; or when transported to a point outside the state, the permit shall accompany the dead body or fetus to its destination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A burial-transit permit issued under the law of another state or country, or a certification of a death certificate issued under the law of a state or country that does not issue burial-transit permits, which accompanies a dead body or fetus brought into this state shall be authority for final disposition of the dead body or fetus in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules of the department may provide for the issuance of a burial-transit permit prior to the filing of a certificate of death or fetal death upon conditions designed to assure compliance with the purposes of this chapter in cases in which compliance with the requirement that the certificate be filed prior to the issuance of the permit would result in undue hardship.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Burial-transit permits filed with the local registrar under the provisions of this chapter may be destroyed after the expiration of 3 years from the date of filing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-312; s. 5, ch. 87-387; s. 91, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 382.061.</Text></Note></Section>