<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0382.0085" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stillbirth registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any stillborn child in this state, the department shall, within 60 days, issue a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth upon the request of a parent named on a fetal death certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person who is required to file a fetal death certificate under this chapter shall advise the parent of a stillborn child:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the parent may request the preparation of a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth in addition to the fetal death certificate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the parent may obtain a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth by contacting the Office of Vital Statistics;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How the parent may contact the Office of Vital Statistics to request a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a copy of the original certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth is a document that is available as a public record when held by an agency as defined under s. 119.011(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The request for a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth must be on a form prescribed by the department by rule and include the date of the stillbirth and the county in which the stillbirth occurred. The request shall normally include the state file number of the fetal death report pursuant to s. 382.008.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth must contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the stillbirth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county in which the stillbirth occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the stillborn child as provided on the original or amended certificate of the fetal death report pursuant to s. 382.008. If a name does not appear on the original or amended fetal death certificate and the requesting parent does not wish to provide a name, the Office of Vital Statistics shall fill in the certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth with the name “baby boy” or “baby girl” and the last name of the parents as provided in s. 382.013(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state file number of the corresponding certificate of fetal death.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement: “This certificate is not proof of live birth.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth shall be a public record when held by an agency as defined under s. 119.011(2). The Office of Vital Statistics must inform any parent who requests a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth that a copy of the document is available as a public record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent may request that the Office of Vital Statistics issue a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth regardless of the date on which the certificate of fetal death was issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is final agency action, not subject to review under chapter 120, for the Office of Vital Statistics to refuse to issue a certificate to a person who is not a parent named on the fetal death certificate and who is not entitled to a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Vital Statistics may not use a certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth to calculate live birth statistics.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section or s. 382.002(15) may not be used to establish, bring, or support a civil cause of action seeking damages against any person or entity for bodily injury, personal injury, or wrongful death for a stillbirth.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe by rules adopted pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 the form, content, and process for the certificate of birth resulting in stillbirth.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-118; s. 2, ch. 2012-186.</History></Section>