<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0603.152" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maturity standard for limes; applicability; testing of limes; rules and regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall be applicable and effective only in the event that there shall cease to be a federal marketing agreement as referred to in s. 603.151. In such event, the following shall be applicable:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the word “limes” shall mean and include limes of all varieties and clones of acid limes grown in the state classified botanically as <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Citrus aurantifolia</Font> (Christm.) Swingle and includes the group known as large fruited limes (Tahiti, Persian, Bearss, Pond, Idemor).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limes shall be deemed to be mature only when clipped or picked, or otherwise severed from the tree and the limes in each lot have been found by inspection as herein provided to contain an average of 42 percent juice content by volume, and no limes in any such lot shall contain less than 38 percent juice content by volume and measure at least 1<Fraction>7/8</Fraction> inches in diameter when measured on a line perpendicular to a line running from the stem end to the blossom end, except from March 15 to May 1 of each year, during which latter period of time, limes shall measure at least 1<Fraction>3/4</Fraction> inches along the said diameter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tests of the juice content of limes hereunder shall be based upon the average maximum amount of liquid contents which can be extracted from the flesh and pulp of not less than 10 average individual specimens of said limes of any lot of limes. The testing of the juice content of limes on a percentage basis by volume shall be the total maximum amount of liquid contents of the limes being tested when determined by the percentage of such juice contents as compared to the total volume displacement of said limes before the juice is extracted. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall, by proper rules and regulations, be authorized to prescribe the manner, method, cost and expense of drawing of said samples and of conducting said tests. In the making of such tests, the juice of the limes being tested shall not be strained through a cloth or other strainer but shall be considered for testing as said juice comes from the juice extractor. The juice extractor used shall be any suitable mechanical device or fruit press used for extracting juice, such type or kind of extractor or fruit press to be determined and approved by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any limes not conforming to the standards, as set forth herein, shall be deemed and held to be immature and shall be destroyed under the supervision of an inspector; provided however, that limes meeting the juice content requirements but not meeting the size requirements as set forth in subsection (2) above may be diverted directly to a processing plant under the supervision of an inspector; provided further that in event of an emergency such as a freeze or hurricane the department, at its own discretion, may waive size requirements only.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any producer, shipper, forwarding company, private carrier, or common carrier, to sell, ship or transport limes, unless the same has been inspected by the department, or its authorized inspectors or agents, and a certificate of such inspection obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to have at all times a copy of such inspection certificate present with such a lot or cargo of limes being shipped shall be prima facie evidence of violation of the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is hereby authorized to make such rules, regulations, and orders as may be necessary to carry out the provisions and intent of this section, and such rules, regulations, and orders issued by the department shall have the force and effect of law when not inconsistent therewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-437; s. 1, ch. 65-169; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 631, ch. 71-136.</History></Section>