<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0603.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement of Federal Marketing Agreement Act by state as to certain vegetables.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the period of time in each year that tomatoes, cucumbers, avocados, or limes are subject to any regulations issued by the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States pursuant to an order issued by said Secretary of Agriculture under the authority and provisions of the Act of Congress known as the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended, (48 Stat. s. 1, as amended; 7 U.S.C. ss. 601 et seq.), it shall be unlawful for any producer, shipper, forwarding company, private carrier, or common carrier, to ship or transport outside the production area defined in said regulations and order of the Secretary of Agriculture, any lot or cargo of tomatoes, cucumbers, avocados or limes subject to the provisions of any such existing regulations, unless the same has been inspected by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, or its authorized inspectors or agents, and a certificate of such inspection obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to have at all times a copy of such inspection certificate present with such lot or cargo of tomatoes, cucumbers, avocados or limes being shipped or transported outside the production area as defined in said regulations or order of the Secretary of Agriculture, shall be prima facie evidence of violation of the provisions of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services is hereby authorized to make such rules, regulations, and orders as may be necessary to carry out the provisions and intent of this section, and such rules, regulations, and orders issued by the department shall have the force and effect of law when not inconsistent therewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates the provisions of subsection (1) shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, chs. 59-501, 59-502, 59-503; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 630, ch. 71-136.</History></Section>