<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0603.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tropical Fruit Advisory Council.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services the Tropical Fruit Advisory Council to consist of eight members as follows: the chair of the State Agricultural Advisory Council or a designee thereof; a representative from the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences at the University of Florida who is a specialist in tropical fruits; and six additional commercial members representing as fairly as may be possible the diverse tropical fruit industry and tropical fruit growers associations, who shall be appointed for a 4-year term by the Commissioner of Agriculture. Initially, the Commissioner of Agriculture shall appoint two members for a term of 4 years, two members for a term of 3 years, two members for a term of 2 years, and two members for a term of 1 year. Thereafter, members shall be appointed for 4-year terms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately after their appointment, the members of the council shall meet and organize by electing a chair, a vice chair, and a secretary, and shall adopt rules of procedure for governing their deliberations. The terms of such officers shall be for 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet in South Florida at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the Commissioner of Agriculture, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three-fourths of the members of the council shall constitute a quorum for all purposes, and an act by a majority of such quorum at any meeting shall constitute an official act of the council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary responsibilities of the Tropical Fruit Advisory Council shall be to provide necessary assistance, review, and recommendations for drafting a South Florida Tropical Fruit Plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 5, ch. 90-277; s. 45, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 991, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>