<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.333" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Real estate, in general.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer shall not directly or indirectly acquire or hold real estate except as authorized in this section.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may acquire and hold:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land and buildings thereon used or acquired for use as its principal home office and branch offices for the convenient transaction of its own business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property acquired in satisfaction in whole or in part of loans, mortgages, liens, judgments, decrees, or debts previously owing to the insurer, in the course of its business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property acquired in part payment of the consideration on the sale of other real property owned by it, if such transaction effects a net reduction in the insurer’s investment in real estate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property acquired by gift or devise or through merger, consolidation, or bulk reinsurance of another insurer under this code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional real property and equipment incident to real property, if necessary or convenient for the enhancement of the marketability or sale value of real property previously acquired or held by it under paragraphs (b)-(d), but subject to the prior written approval of the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may acquire and hold real property for the purposes of investment subject to the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount shall not exceed 5 percent of the insurer’s admitted assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount in any one property shall not exceed 1 percent of the insurer’s admitted assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount in unimproved land shall not exceed 0.5 percent of the insurer’s admitted assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no time limit for the disposal of investment real estate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount in real property acquired and held by an insurer shall not exceed 15 percent of the insurer’s admitted assets, but the office may grant permission to the insurer to invest in real property in such increased amount as it may deem proper.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 158, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 115, 122, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 890, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>