<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standard Valuation Law; life insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section shall be known as the “Standard Valuation Law.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL VALUATION.<EmDash />The office shall annually value, or cause to be valued, the reserve liabilities, hereinafter called “reserves,” for all outstanding life insurance policies and annuity and pure endowment contracts of every life insurer doing business in this state, and may certify the amount of any such reserves, specifying the mortality table or tables, rate or rates of interest, and methods, net-level premium method or others, used in the calculation of such reserves. In the case of an alien insurer, such valuation shall be limited to its insurance transactions in the United States. In calculating such reserves, the office may use group methods and approximate averages for fractions of a year or otherwise. It may accept in its discretion the insurer’s calculation of such reserves. In lieu of the valuation of the reserves herein required of any foreign or alien insurer, it may accept any valuation made or caused to be made by the insurance supervisory official of any state or other jurisdiction when such valuation complies with the minimum standard herein provided and if the official of such state or jurisdiction accepts as sufficient and valid for all legal purposes the certificate of valuation of the office when such certificate states the valuation to have been made in a specified manner according to which the aggregate reserves would be at least as large as if they had been computed in the manner prescribed by the law of that state or jurisdiction. When any such valuation is made by the office, it may use the actuary of the office or employ an actuary for the purpose; and the reasonable compensation of the actuary, at a rate approved by the office, and reimbursement of travel expenses pursuant to s. 624.320 upon demand by the office, supported by an itemized statement of such compensation and expenses, shall be paid by the insurer. When a domestic insurer furnishes the office with a valuation of its outstanding policies as computed by its own actuary or by an actuary deemed satisfactory for the purpose by the office, the valuation shall be verified by the actuary of the office without cost to the insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACTUARIAL OPINION OF RESERVES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each life insurance company doing business in this state shall annually submit the opinion of a qualified actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts specified by the commission by rule are computed appropriately, are based on assumptions which satisfy contractual provisions, are consistent with prior reported amounts, and comply with applicable laws of this state. The commission by rule shall define the specifics of this opinion and add any other items determined to be necessary to its scope.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opinion shall be submitted with the annual statement reflecting the valuation of such reserve liabilities for each year ending on or after December 31, 1992.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opinion shall apply to all business in force, including individual and group health insurance plans, in the form and substance acceptable to the office as specified by rule of the commission.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules providing the standards of the actuarial opinion consistent with standards adopted by the Actuarial Standards Board on December 31, 2002, and subsequent revisions thereto, provided that the standards remain substantially consistent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an opinion required to be submitted by a foreign or alien company, the office may accept the opinion filed by that company with the insurance supervisory official of another state if the office determines that the opinion reasonably meets the requirements applicable to a company domiciled in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, “qualified actuary” means a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries who also meets the requirements specified by rule of the commission.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary action by the office against the company or the qualified actuary shall be in accordance with the insurance code and related rules adopted by the commission.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A memorandum in the form and substance specified by rule shall be prepared to support each actuarial opinion.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurance company fails to provide a supporting memorandum at the request of the office within a period specified by rule of the commission, or if the office determines that the supporting memorandum provided by the insurance company fails to meet the standards prescribed by rule of the commission, the office may engage a qualified actuary at the expense of the company to review the opinion and the basis for the opinion and prepare such supporting memorandum as is required by the office.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, any memorandum or other material in support of the opinion is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1); however, the memorandum or other material may be released by the office with the written consent of the company, or to the American Academy of Actuaries upon request stating that the memorandum or other material is required for the purpose of professional disciplinary proceedings and setting forth procedures satisfactory to the office for preserving the confidentiality of the memorandum or other material. If any portion of the confidential memorandum is cited by the company in its marketing or is cited before any governmental agency other than a state insurance department or is released by the company to the news media, no portion of the memorandum is confidential.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the opinion required by subparagraph (a)1., the office may, pursuant to commission rule, require an opinion of the same qualified actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts specified by the commission by rule, when considered in light of the assets held by the company with respect to the reserves and related actuarial items, including but not limited to the investment earnings on the assets and considerations anticipated to be received and retained under the policies and contracts, make adequate provision for the company’s obligations under the policies and contracts, including, but not limited to, the benefits under, and expenses associated with, the policies and contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may provide by rule for a transition period for establishing any higher reserves which the qualified actuary may deem necessary in order to render the opinion required by this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM STANDARD FOR VALUATION OF POLICIES AND CONTRACTS ISSUED BEFORE OPERATIVE DATE OF STANDARD NONFORFEITURE LAW.<EmDash />The minimum standard for the valuation of all such policies and contracts issued prior to the operative date of s. 627.476 (Standard Nonforfeiture Law) shall be any basis satisfactory to the office. Any basis satisfactory to the former Department of Insurance on the effective date of this code shall be deemed to meet such minimum standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM STANDARD FOR VALUATION OF POLICIES AND CONTRACTS ISSUED ON OR AFTER OPERATIVE DATE OF STANDARD NONFORFEITURE LAW.<EmDash />Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (h) and subsections (6), (11), and (14), the minimum standard for the valuation of all such policies and contracts issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476 (Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance) shall be the commissioners’ reserve valuation method defined in subsections (7), (11), and (14); 5 percent interest for group annuity and pure endowment contracts and 3.5 percent interest for all other such policies and contracts, or in the case of life insurance policies and contracts, other than annuity and pure endowment contracts, issued on or after July 1, 1973, 4 percent interest for such policies issued prior to October 1, 1979, and 4.5 percent interest for such policies issued on or after October 1, 1979; and the following tables:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all ordinary policies of life insurance issued on the standard basis, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such policies:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued prior to the operative date of s. 627.476(9), the commissioners’ 1958 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table; except that, for any category of such policies issued on female risks, modified net premiums and present values, referred to in subsection (7), may be calculated according to an age not more than 6 years younger than the actual age of the insured.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476(9), the commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table or, at the election of the insurer for any one or more specified plans of life insurance, the commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table with Ten-Year Select Mortality Factors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after July 1, 2004, ordinary mortality tables, adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for such policies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all industrial life insurance policies issued on the standard basis, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such policies:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued prior to the first date to which the commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table is applicable according to s. 627.476, the 1941 Standard Industrial Mortality Table; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For such policies issued on or after that date, the commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual annuity and pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such policies, the 1937 Standard Annuity Mortality Table or, at the option of the insurer, the Annuity Mortality Table for 1949, Ultimate, or any modification of either of these tables approved by the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For group annuity and pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such policies, the Group Annuity Mortality Table for 1951; any modification of such table approved by the office; or, at the option of the insurer, any of the tables or modifications of tables specified for individual annuity and pure endowment contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For total and permanent disability benefits in or supplementary to ordinary policies or contracts:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies or contracts issued on or after January 1, 1966, the tables of period 2 disablement rates and the 1930 to 1950 termination rates of the 1952 disability study of the Society of Actuaries, with due regard to the type of benefit;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies or contracts issued on or after January 1, 1961, and prior to January 1, 1966, either those tables or, at the option of the insurer, the class three disability table (1926);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued prior to January 1, 1961, the class three disability table (1926); and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies or contracts issued on or after July 1, 2004, tables of disablement rates and termination rates adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for those policies or contracts.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any such table for active lives shall be combined with a mortality table permitted for calculating the reserves for life insurance policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For accidental death benefits in or supplementary to policies:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after January 1, 1966, the 1959 Accidental Death Benefits Table;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after January 1, 1961, and prior to January 1, 1966, either that table or, at the option of the insurer, the Intercompany Double Indemnity Mortality Table;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued prior to January 1, 1961, the Intercompany Double Indemnity Mortality Table; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after July 1, 2004, tables of accidental death benefits adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for those policies.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Either table shall be combined with a mortality table permitted for calculating the reserves for life insurance policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For group life insurance, life insurance issued on the substandard basis, and other special benefits, such tables as may be approved by the office as being sufficient with relation to the benefits provided by such policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (6), the minimum standard for the valuation of all individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued on or after the operative date of this paragraph and for all annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after such operative date under group annuity and pure endowment contracts shall be the commissioners’ reserve valuation method defined in subsection (7) and the following tables and interest rates:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued prior to October 1, 1979, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such contracts, the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of this table approved by the office, and 6 percent interest for single-premium immediate annuity contracts and 4 percent interest for all other individual annuity and pure endowment contracts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual single-premium immediate annuity contracts issued on or after October 1, 1979, and prior to October 1, 1986, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such contracts, the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of this table approved by the office, and 7.5 percent interest. For such contracts issued on or after October 1, 1986, the 1983 Individual Annual Mortality Table, or any modification of such table approved by the office, and the applicable calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as described in subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued on or after October 1, 1979, and prior to October 1, 1986, other than single-premium immediate annuity contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such contracts, the 1971 Individual Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of this table approved by the office, and 5.5 percent interest for single-premium deferred annuity and pure endowment contracts and 4.5 percent interest for all other such individual annuity and pure endowment contracts. For such contracts issued on or after October 1, 1986, the 1983 Individual Annual Mortality Table, or any modification of such table approved by the office, and the applicable calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as described in subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all annuities and pure endowments purchased prior to October 1, 1979, under group annuity and pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits purchased under such contracts, the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of this table approved by the office, and 6 percent interest.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after October 1, 1979, and prior to October 1, 1986, under group annuity and pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits purchased under such contracts, the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of this table approved by the office, and 7.5 percent interest. For such contracts purchased on or after October 1, 1986, the 1983 Group Annuity Mortality Table, or any modification of such table approved by the office, and the applicable calendar year statutory valuation interest rate as described in subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">After July 1, 1973, any insurer may have filed with the former Department of Insurance a written notice of its election to comply with the provisions of this paragraph after a specified date before January 1, 1979, which shall be the operative date of this paragraph for such insurer. However, an insurer may elect a different operative date for individual annuity and pure endowment contracts from that elected for group annuity and pure endowment contracts. If an insurer makes no such election, the operative date of this paragraph for such insurer shall be January 1, 1979.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the mortality tables specified in this subsection, and subject to rules previously adopted by the former Department of Insurance, the insurance company may, at its option:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute the applicable 1958 CSO or CET Smoker and Nonsmoker Mortality Tables, in lieu of the 1980 CSO or CET mortality table standard, for policies issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476(9) and before January 1, 1989.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute the applicable 1980 CSO or CET Smoker and Nonsmoker Mortality Tables in lieu of the 1980 CSO or CET mortality table standard;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the Annuity 2000 Mortality Table for determining the minimum standard of valuation for individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued on or after January 1, 1998, and before July 1, 1998.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the 1994 GAR Table for determining the minimum standard of valuation for annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after January 1, 1998, and before July 1, 1998, under group annuity and pure endowment contracts.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt by rule the model regulation for valuation of life insurance policies as approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners in March 1999, including tables of select mortality factors, and may make the regulation effective for policies issued on or after January 1, 2000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued on or after July 1, 2004, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits purchased under those contracts, individual annuity mortality tables adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for those contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all annuities and pure endowments purchased on or after July 1, 2004, under group annuity and pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits purchased under those contracts, group annuity mortality tables adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for those contracts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM STANDARD OF VALUATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest rates used in determining the minimum standard for the valuation of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All life insurance policies issued in a particular calendar year on or after the operative date of s. 627.476(9);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued in a particular calendar year on or after January 1, 1982;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All annuities and pure endowments purchased in a particular calendar year on or after January 1, 1982, under group annuity and pure endowment contracts; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net increase, if any, in a particular calendar year after January 1, 1982, in amounts held under guaranteed interest contracts,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be the calendar year statutory valuation interest rates for the year-of-issue purchase or increase as defined in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The calendar year statutory valuation interest rates I shall be determined as follows, and the results rounded to the nearest 0.25 percent:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For life insurance:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">I = 0.03 + W(R1–0.03) + (W/2)(R2–0.09).</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For purposes of this subparagraph, “R1” is the lesser of R and .09; “R2” is the greater of R and .09; “R” is the reference interest rate defined in this subsection; and “W” is the weighting factor defined in this subsection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For single-premium immediate annuities and for annuity benefits involving life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and from guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">I = 0.03 + W(R–0.03).</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For purposes of this subparagraph, “R” is the reference interest rate defined in this subsection, and “W” is the weighting factor defined in this subsection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on an issue-year basis, except as stated in subparagraph 2., the formula for life insurance stated in subparagraph 1. shall apply to annuities and guaranteed interest contracts with guarantee durations in excess of 10 years, and the formula for single-premium immediate annuities stated in subparagraph 2. shall apply to annuities and guaranteed interest contracts with guarantee durations of 10 years or less.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options, the formula for single-premium immediate annuities stated in subparagraph 2. shall apply.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a change-in-fund basis, the formula for single-premium immediate annuities stated in subparagraph 2. shall apply.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, if the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for any life insurance policies issued in any calendar year determined without reference to this sentence differs from the corresponding actual rate for similar policies issued in the immediately preceding calendar year by less than 0.5 percent, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for such life insurance policies shall be equal to the corresponding actual rate for the immediately preceding calendar year. For purposes of applying the immediately preceding sentence, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for life insurance policies issued in a calendar year shall be determined for 1980, the reference interest rate defined for 1979 being used, and shall be determined for each subsequent calendar year regardless of when s. 627.476(9) becomes operative.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The weighting factors referred to in the formulas stated in paragraph (b) are given in the following tables:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weighting factors for life insurance:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Guarantee Duration<FlushRight />Weighting</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"> (Years)<FlushRight />Factors</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">10 or less:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />0.50</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">More than 10, but not more than 20:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />0.45</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">More than 20:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />0.35</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For life insurance, the “guarantee duration” is the maximum number of years the life insurance can remain in force on a basis guaranteed in the policy or under options to convert to plans of life insurance with premium rates or nonforfeiture values or both which are guaranteed in the original policy.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weighting factor for single-premium immediate annuities and for annuity benefits involving life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options: 0.80.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weighting factors for other annuities and for guaranteed interest contracts, except as stated in subparagraph 2., shall be as specified in sub-subparagraphs a., b., and c., according to the rules and definitions in sub-subparagraphs d., e., and f. and in paragraph (f):</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on an issue-year basis:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Guarantee Duration<FlushRight />Weighting Factor</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"> (Years)<FlushRight />for Plan Type</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">5 or less:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />A—0.80</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">B—0.60</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">C—0.50</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">More than 5, but not more than 10:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />A—0.75</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">B—0.60</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">C—0.50</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">More than 10, but not more than 20:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />A—0.65</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">B—0.50</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">C—0.45</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">More than 20:<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />A—0.45</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">B—0.35</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">C—0.35</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on a change-in-fund basis, the factors shown in sub-subparagraph a. increased by: 0.15 for Plan Type A; 0.25 for Plan Type B; 0.05 for Plan Type C.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on an issue-year basis, other than those with no cash settlement options, which do not guarantee interest on considerations received more than 1 year after issue or purchase and for annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on a change-in-fund basis which do not guarantee interest rates on considerations received more than 12 months beyond the valuation date, the factors shown in sub-subparagraph a. or derived in sub-subparagraph b. increased by: 0.05 for Plan Type A; 0.05 for Plan Type B; 0.05 for Plan Type C.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, the “guarantee duration” is the number of years for which the contract guarantees interest rates in excess of the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for life insurance policies with guarantee duration in excess of 20 years. For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options, the guarantee duration is the number of years from the date of issue or date of purchase to the date annuity benefits are scheduled to commence.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plan type,” as used in the tables above, is defined as follows:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan Type A: At any time, the policyholder may withdraw funds only with an adjustment to reflect changes in interest rates or asset values since receipt of the funds by the insurer; the policyholder may withdraw funds only without such adjustment but in installments over 5 years or more; the policyholder may withdraw funds only as an immediate life annuity; or no withdrawal is permitted.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan Type B: Before expiration of the interest rate guarantee, the policyholder may withdraw funds only with an adjustment to reflect changes in interest rates or asset values since receipt of the funds by the insurer; the policyholder may withdraw funds only without such adjustment but in installments over 5 years or more; or no withdrawal is permitted. At the end of interest rate guarantee, funds may be withdrawn without such adjustment in a single sum or installments over less than 5 years.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan Type C: The policyholder may withdraw funds before expiration of interest rate guarantee in a single sum or installments over less than 5 years either without adjustment to reflect changes in interest rates or asset values since receipt of the funds by the insurer or subject only to a fixed surrender charge stipulated in the contract as a percentage of the fund.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may elect to value guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options and annuities with cash settlement options on either an issue-year basis or on a change-in-fund basis. Guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options and other annuities with no cash settlement options must be valued on an issue-year basis.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “reference interest rate” referred to in paragraph (b) is defined as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all life insurance, the lesser of the average over a period of 36 months and the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year next preceding the year of issue, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For single-premium immediate annuities and for annuity benefits involving life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or year of purchase, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a year-of-issue basis, except as stated in subparagraph 2., with guarantee duration in excess of 10 years, the lesser of the average over a period of 36 months and the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a year-of-issue basis, except as stated in subparagraph 2., with guarantee duration of 10 years or less, the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options, the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a change-in-fund basis, except as stated in subparagraph 2., the average over a period of 12 months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of the change in the fund, of the interest rate index.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest rate index shall be the Moody’s Corporate Bond Yield Average-Monthly Average Corporates as published by Moody’s Investors Service, Inc., as long as this index is calculated by using substantially the same methodology as used by it on January 1, 1981. If Moody’s corporate bond yield average ceases to be calculated in this manner, the interest rate index shall be the index approved by rule promulgated by the commission. The methodology used in determining the index approved by rule shall be substantially the same as the methodology employed on January 1, 1981, for determining Moody’s Corporate Bond Yield Average-Monthly Average Corporates as published by Moody’s Investors Service, Inc.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, an “issue-year basis” of valuation refers to a valuation basis under which the interest rate used to determine the minimum valuation standard for the entire duration of the annuity or guaranteed interest contract is the calendar year valuation interest rate for the year of purchase of the annuity or guaranteed interest contract; and the “change-in-fund” basis of valuation refers to a valuation basis under which the interest rate used to determine the minimum valuation standard applicable to each change in the fund held under the annuity or guaranteed interest contract is the calendar year valuation interest rate for the year of the change in the fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMMISSIONERS’ RESERVE VALUATION METHOD.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection and subsections (11) and (14), reserves according to the commissioners’ reserve valuation method, for the life insurance and endowment benefits of policies providing for a uniform amount of insurance and requiring the payment of uniform premiums, shall be the excess, if any, of the present value, at the date of valuation, of such future guaranteed benefits provided for by such policies, over the then-present value of any future modified net premiums therefor. The modified net premiums for any such policy shall be such uniform percentage of the respective contract premiums for such benefits that the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of all such modified net premiums shall be equal to the sum of the then-present value of such benefits provided for by the policy and the excess of sub-subparagraph a. over sub-subparagraph b. as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A net-level annual premium equal to the present value, at the date of issue, of such benefits provided for after the first policy year, divided by the present value, at the date of issue, of an annuity of one per annum payable on the first and each subsequent anniversary of such policy on which a premium falls due; provided, however, that such net-level annual premium shall not exceed the net-level annual premium on the 19-year premium whole life plan for insurance of the same amount at an age 1 year higher than the age at issue of such policy.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A net-1-year-term premium for such benefits provided for in the first policy year.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any life insurance policy which is issued on or after January 1, 1985, for which the contract premium in the first policy year exceeds that of the second year and for which no comparable additional benefit is provided in the first year for such excess, and which provides an endowment benefit, a cash surrender value, or a combination thereof in an amount greater than such excess premium, the reserve according to the commissioners’ reserve valuation method as of any policy anniversary occurring on or before the assumed ending date, defined herein as the first policy anniversary on which the sum of any endowment benefit and any cash surrender value then available is greater than such excess premium, shall, except as otherwise provided in subsection (11), be the greater of the reserve as of such policy anniversary calculated as described in subparagraph 1. and the reserve as of such policy anniversary calculated as described in subparagraph 1. but with:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value defined in subparagraph 1. being reduced by 15 percent of the amount of such excess first year premium;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All present values of benefits and premiums being determined without reference to premiums or benefits provided for by the policy after the assumed ending date;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy being assumed to mature on such date as an endowment; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cash surrender value provided on such date being considered as an endowment benefit.</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In making the above comparison, the mortality and interest bases stated in subsections (5) and (6) shall be used.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves according to the commissioners’ reserve valuation method for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life insurance policies providing for a varying amount of insurance or requiring the payment of varying premiums;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Group annuity and pure endowment contracts, purchased under a retirement plan or plan of deferred compensation, established or maintained by an employer, including a partnership or sole proprietorship, or by an employee organization, or by both, other than a plan providing individual retirement accounts or individual retirement annuities under s. 408 of the Internal Revenue Code, as now or hereafter amended;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disability and accidental death benefits in all policies and contracts; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other benefits, except life insurance and endowment benefits in life insurance policies, and benefits provided by all other annuity and pure endowment contracts,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be calculated by a method which is consistent with and yields results consistent with the principles of paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall apply to all annuity and pure endowment contracts other than group annuity and pure endowment contracts purchased under a retirement plan or plan of deferred compensation, established or maintained by an employer, including a partnership or sole proprietorship, or by an employee organization, or by both, other than a plan providing individual retirement accounts or individual retirement annuities under s. 408 of the Internal Revenue Code, as now or hereafter amended. Reserves according to the commissioners’ annuity reserve method for benefits under annuity or pure endowment contracts, excluding any disability and accidental death benefits in such contracts, shall be the greatest of the respective excesses of the present values, at the date of valuation, of the future guaranteed benefits, including guaranteed nonforfeiture benefits, provided for by such contracts at the end of each respective contract year, over the present value, at the date of valuation, of any future valuation considerations derived from future gross considerations, required by the terms of such contract, that become payable prior to the end of such respective contract year. The future guaranteed benefits shall be determined by using the mortality table, if any, and the interest rate or rates specified in such contracts for determining guaranteed benefits. The valuation considerations are the portions of the respective gross considerations applied under the terms of such contracts to determine nonforfeiture values.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM AGGREGATE RESERVES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event shall an insurer’s aggregate reserves for all life insurance policies, excluding disability and accidental death benefits, issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476, be less than the aggregate reserves calculated in accordance with the methods set forth in subsections (7), (11), and (12) and the mortality table or tables and rate or rates of interest used in calculating nonforfeiture benefits for such policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event may the aggregate reserves for all policies, contracts, and benefits be less than the aggregate reserves determined by the qualified actuary to be necessary to render the opinion required by subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPTIONAL RESERVE BASIS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for all policies and contracts issued prior to the operative date of s. 627.476 may be calculated, at the option of the insurer, according to any standards which produce greater aggregate reserves for all such policies and contracts than the minimum reserves required by the laws in effect immediately prior to such date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any category of policies, contracts, or benefits specified in subsections (5) and (6), issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476 (the Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance), reserves may be calculated, at the option of the insurer, according to any standard or standards which produce greater aggregate reserves for such category than those calculated according to the minimum standard herein provided; but the rate or rates of interest used for policies and contracts, other than annuity and pure endowment contracts, shall not be higher than the corresponding rate or rates of interest used in calculating any nonforfeiture benefits provided for therein.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOWER VALUATIONS.<EmDash />An insurer which at any time had adopted any standard of valuation producing greater aggregate reserves than those calculated according to the minimum standard herein provided may, with the approval of the office, adopt any lower standard of valuation, but not lower than the minimum herein provided; however, for the purposes of this subsection, the holding of additional reserves previously determined by a qualified actuary to be necessary to render the opinion required by subsection (3) shall not be deemed to be the adoption of a higher standard of valuation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFICIENCY RESERVE.<EmDash />If in any contract year the gross premium charged by any life insurer on any policy or contract is less than the valuation net premium for the policy or contract calculated by the method used in calculating the reserve thereon but using the minimum valuation standards of mortality and rate of interest, there shall be maintained on such policy or contract a deficiency reserve in addition to the reserve defined by subsections (7) and (12). For each such policy or contract, the deficiency reserve shall be the present value, according to the minimum valuation standards of mortality and rate of interest, of the differences between all such valuation net premiums and the corresponding premiums charged for such policy or contract during the remainder of the premium-paying period. For any category of policies, contracts, or benefits specified in subsections (5) and (6), issued on or after the operative date of s. 627.476 (the Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance), the aggregate deficiency reserves may be reduced by the amount, if any, by which the aggregate reserves actually calculated in accordance with subsection (9) exceed the minimum aggregate reserves prescribed by subsection (8). The minimum valuation standards of mortality and rate of interest referred to in this subsection are those standards stated in subsections (5) and (6). However, for any life insurance policy which is issued on or after January 1, 1985, for which the gross premium in the first policy year exceeds that of the second year and for which no comparable additional benefit is provided in the first year for such excess, and which provides an endowment benefit, a cash surrender value, or a combination thereof in an amount greater than such excess premium, the foregoing provisions of this subsection shall be applied as if the method actually used in calculating the reserve for such policy were the method described in subsection (7), the provisions of subparagraph (7)(a)2. being ignored. The amount of the deficiency reserve, if any, at each policy anniversary of such a policy shall be the excess, if any, of the amount determined by the foregoing provisions of this subsection plus the reserve calculated by the method described in subsection (7), the provisions of subparagraph (7)(a)2. being ignored, over the reserve actually calculated by the method described in subsection (7), the provisions of subparagraph (7)(a)2. being taken into account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ALTERNATE METHOD FOR DETERMINING RESERVES IN CERTAIN CASES.<EmDash />In the case of any plan of life insurance which provides for future premium determination, the amounts of which are to be determined by the insurer based on then estimates of future experience, or in the case of any plan of life insurance or annuity which is of such a nature that the minimum reserves cannot be determined by the methods described in subsection (7), the reserves which are held under any such plan shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be appropriate in relation to the benefits and the pattern of premiums for that plan; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be computed by a method which is consistent with the principles of this section, as determined by rules promulgated by the commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREDIT LIFE AND DISABILITY POLICIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued prior to January 1, 2004:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum reserve for single-premium credit disability insurance, monthly premium credit life insurance, and monthly premium credit disability insurance shall be the unearned gross premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to single-premium credit life insurance policies, the insurer shall establish and maintain reserves that are not less than the value, at the valuation date, of the risk for the unexpired portion of the period for which the premium has been paid as computed on the basis of the commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table and 3.5 percent interest. At the discretion of the office, the insurer may make a reasonable assumption as to the ages at which net premiums are to be determined. In lieu of the foregoing basis, reserves based upon unearned gross premiums may be used at the option of the insurer.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on or after January 1, 2004:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum reserve for single-premium credit disability insurance shall be either:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unearned gross premium, or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based upon a morbidity table that is adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and is specified in a rule the commission adopts pursuant to subsection (14).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum reserve for monthly premium credit disability insurance shall be the unearned gross premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum reserve for monthly premium credit life insurance shall be the unearned gross premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to single-premium credit life insurance policies, the insurer shall establish and maintain reserves that are not less than the value, at the valuation date, of the risk for the unexpired portion of the period for which the premium has been paid as computed on the basis of the commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table or any ordinary mortality table, adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, that is approved by rule adopted by the commission for use in determining the minimum standard of valuation for such policies; and an interest rate determined in accordance with subsection (6). At the discretion of the office, the insurer may make a reasonable assumption as to the ages at which net premiums are to be determined. In lieu of the foregoing basis, reserves based upon unearned gross premiums may be used at the option of the insurer.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM STANDARDS FOR HEALTH PLANS.<EmDash />The commission shall adopt a rule containing the minimum standards applicable to the valuation of health plans in accordance with sound actuarial principles.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 120, ch. 59-205; ss. 1, 2, ch. 61-106; s. 17, ch. 63-400; s. 1, ch. 65-11; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 73-324; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-356; ss. 1, 6, ch. 81-289; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 98, 809(1st), 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 48, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-118; s. 21, ch. 95-211; s. 369, ch. 96-406; s. 8, ch. 97-292; s. 2, ch. 2000-365; s. 873, ch. 2003-261; s. 7, ch. 2004-370; s. 152, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>