<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.329" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chattel mortgages.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with a mortgage loan on the security of real estate designed and used primarily for residential purposes only, which mortgage loan was acquired pursuant to s. 625.327, an insurer may lend or invest an amount not exceeding 20 percent of the amount loaned on or invested in such real estate mortgage on the security of a chattel mortgage to be amortized by regular periodic payments within a term of not more than 5 years, and representing a first and prior lien, except for taxes not then delinquent, on personal property constituting durable equipment owned by the mortgagor and kept and used in the mortgaged premises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “durable equipment” includes only mechanical refrigerators, air-conditioning equipment, mechanical laundering machines, heating and cooking stoves and ranges, and, in addition, in the case of apartment houses and hotels, room furniture and furnishings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the acquisition of a chattel mortgage hereunder, items of property to be included therein shall be separately appraised by a qualified appraiser and the fair market value thereof determined. No such chattel mortgage loan shall exceed in amount the same ratio of loan to the value of the property as is applicable to the companion loan on the real property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not prohibit an insurer from taking liens on personal property as additional security for any investment otherwise eligible under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 154, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 122, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>