<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.62" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duration and release of deposit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every certificate of deposit filed and every deposit made in this state by an insurer, prior to or pursuant to this code, made voluntarily or pursuant to specific requirements shall be subject to the applicable provisions of this code as amended from time to time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the deposit is required under the retaliatory provision, s. 624.5091, the deposit shall be held for so long as the basis for such retaliation exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the deposit is required under the requirements of another state, province, or country and is held pursuant to s. 625.51(2), the deposit shall be held for so long as another state, province, or country has filed notification of reliance on the deposit and has denied release authorization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such deposit, whether in the form of a certificate of deposit or otherwise, shall be released and returned:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the insurer during solvency to the extent such deposit is in excess of the amount required;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the insurer, during solvency, upon its written request, to the extent such deposit is in excess of the amount then required under this code; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the insurer, during solvency, upon its written request, when such insurer has met all requirements and the office is satisfied, or, for deposits made under s. 625.51(2) or (3), the department is satisfied, that the deposit is no longer necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proper order of a court of competent jurisdiction, to the receiver, conservator, rehabilitator, liquidator of the insurer, or to any other properly designated official or officials who succeed to the management and control of the insurer’s assets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 178, ch. 59-205; s. 2, ch. 61-166; s. 2, ch. 63-19; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 132, 134, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 44, ch. 90-132; ss. 56, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 898, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>