<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investments in subsidiaries and related corporations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZATION.<EmDash />Any insurer, either by itself or in cooperation with one or more persons, may organize or acquire one or more subsidiaries, subject to the limitation of subsection (2). Such subsidiaries may conduct any kind of business, and their authority to do so shall not be limited by reason of the fact that they are subsidiaries of an insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADDITIONAL INVESTMENT AUTHORITY.<EmDash />In addition to investments in common stock, preferred stock, debt obligations, and other securities permitted under all other sections of this chapter, an insurer may also invest and maintain investments in common stock, preferred stock, debt obligations, and other securities of one or more subsidiaries or related corporations. At the time any such new or additional investment is made, the sum of the insurer’s cost of such investment and the aggregate values as permitted by s. 625.151(3) of all existing investments in such corporations shall not exceed the lesser of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent of the insurer’s admitted assets; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of the insurer’s surplus as to policyholders in excess of the minimum surplus as to policyholders required to be maintained by the insurer under this code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Subsidiary” means a corporation in which the insurer holds, directly or indirectly through an intermediary, sufficient stock to give the insurer a controlling interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Related corporation” means a corporation in which the insurer’s parent corporation holds, directly or indirectly through an intermediary, sufficient stock to give the insurer’s parent corporation a controlling interest.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to a limited reciprocal, “related corporation” means any corporation that is a member of the limited reciprocal.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEBT OBLIGATIONS.<EmDash />Debt obligations, other than mortgage loans, made under the authority of this section must meet amortization requirements in accordance with the latest edition of the publication “Valuation of Securities” by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its successor organization; provided that such amortization methodology is substantially similar to the methodology used by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners in its July 1, 2002, edition of such publication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT INCLUDES LOANS.<EmDash />For purposes of this section, an insurer’s investment in a subsidiary or related corporation shall be deemed to include all sums loaned to such subsidiary or related corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTRUCTION.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall be construed to expand, extend, or otherwise enlarge the provisions of chapter 687.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 150, ch. 59-205; s. 1, ch. 65-17; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 70-188; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 110, 122, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 46, ch. 89-360; s. 8, ch. 90-119; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 885, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>