<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0625.327" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mortgage loans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may invest any of its funds in bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness which are secured by first mortgages or deeds of trust upon improved real property located in the United States or Canada or which are secured by first mortgages or deeds of trust upon leasehold estates having an unexpired term of not less than 40 years (inclusive of the term or terms which may be provided by enforceable options of renewal) in improved real property located in the United States or Canada. In all cases the security for the loan must be a first lien upon such real property, and there must not be any condition or right of reentry or forfeiture not insured against under which, in the case of real property other than leaseholds, such lien can be cut off or subordinated or otherwise disturbed or under which, in the case of leaseholds, the insurer is unable to continue the lease in force for the duration of the loan. Nothing herein shall prohibit any investment by reason of the existence of any prior lien for ground rents, taxes, assessments, or other similar charges not yet delinquent. This section shall not be deemed to prohibit investment in mortgages or similar obligations when made under s. 625.326.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Improved real estate” means all farmlands used for tillage, crops, or pasture; timberlands; and all real estate on which permanent improvements, and improvements under construction or in process of construction, suitable for residential, institutional, commercial, or industrial use are situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such mortgage loan or loans made or acquired by an insurer on any one property shall, at the time of investment by the insurer, exceed the larger of the following amounts, as applicable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ninety-five percent of the value of the real property or leasehold securing the same in the case of a mortgage on a dwelling primarily intended for occupancy by not more than four families if they insure down to 75 percent with a licensed mortgage insurance company, or 75 percent of such value in the case of other real estate mortgages;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of any insurance or guaranty of such loan by the United States or by any agency or instrumentality thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage-of-value limit on the amount of the loan applicable under paragraph (a), plus the amount by which the excess of such loan over such percentage-of-value limit is insured or guaranteed by the United States or by any agency or instrumentality thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a purchase money mortgage given to secure the purchase price of real estate sold by the insurer, the amount so loaned or invested shall not exceed the unpaid portion of the purchase price.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall be deemed to prohibit an insurer from renewing or extending a loan for the original or a lesser amount where a shrinkage in value of the real estate securing the loan would cause its value to be less than the amount otherwise required in relation to the amount of the loan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section supersede any inconsistent provision of s. 106 of the Secondary Mortgage Market Enhancement Act of 1984 (15 U.S.C. s. 77r).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 152, 153, ch. 59-205; s. 2, ch. 65-17; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 112, 122, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 52, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of s. 625.327 and former s. 625.328.</Text></Note></Section>