<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.385" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Educational planning and information systems.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EDUCATIONAL PLANNING.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education is responsible for all planning functions for the department, including collection, analysis, and interpretation of all data, information, test results, evaluations, and other indicators that are used to formulate policy, identify areas of concern and need, and serve as the basis for short-range and long-range planning. Such planning shall include assembling data, conducting appropriate studies and surveys, and sponsoring research and development activities designed to provide information about educational needs and the effect of alternative educational practices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall maintain a continuing system of planning and budgeting designed to aid in identifying and meeting the educational needs of students and the public. Provision shall be made for coordination between district school boards and Florida College System institution boards of trustees concerning the planning for career education and adult educational programs. The major emphasis of the system shall be upon locally determined goals and objectives, the state plan for education, and the Sunshine State Standards developed by the Department of Education and adopted by the State Board of Education. The district planning and budgeting system must include consideration of student achievement data obtained pursuant to ss. 1008.22 and 1008.34. The system shall be structured to meet the specific management needs of the district and to align the budget adopted by the district school board with the plan the board has also adopted. Each district school board shall utilize its system of planning and budgeting to emphasize a system of school-based management in which individual school centers become the principal planning units and to integrate planning and budgeting at the school level.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPREHENSIVE MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS.<EmDash />The Commissioner of Education shall develop and implement an integrated information system for educational management. The system must be designed to collect, via electronic transfer, all student and school performance data required to ascertain the degree to which schools and school districts are meeting state performance standards, and must be capable of producing data for a comprehensive annual report on school and district performance. In addition, the system shall support, as feasible, the management decisions to be made in each division of the department and at the individual school and district levels. Similar data elements among divisions and levels shall be compatible. The system shall be based on an overall conceptual design; the information needed for such decisions, including fiscal, student, program, personnel, facility, community, evaluation, and other relevant data; and the relationship between cost and effectiveness. The system shall be managed and administered by the commissioner and shall include a district subsystem component to be administered at the district level, with input from the reports-and-forms control management committees. Each district school system with a unique management information system shall assure that compatibility exists between its unique system and the district component of the state system so that all data required as input to the state system is made available via electronic transfer and in the appropriate input format.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific responsibilities of the commissioner shall include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consulting with school district representatives in the development of the system design model and implementation plans for the management information system for public school education management;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing operational definitions for the proposed system;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining the information and specific data elements required for the management decisions made at each educational level, recognizing that the primary unit for information input is the individual school and recognizing that time and effort of instructional personnel expended in collection and compilation of data should be minimized;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing standardized terminology and procedures to be followed at all levels of the system;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing a standard transmittal format to be used for collection of data from the various levels of the system;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing appropriate computer programs to assure integration of the various information components dealing with students, personnel, facilities, fiscal, program, community, and evaluation data;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing the necessary programs to provide statistical analysis of the integrated data provided in subparagraph 6. in such a way that required reports may be disseminated, comparisons may be made, and relationships may be determined in order to provide the necessary information for making management decisions at all levels;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing output report formats which will provide district school systems with information for making management decisions at the various educational levels;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing a phased plan for distributing computer services equitably among all public schools and school districts in the state as rapidly as possible. The plan shall describe alternatives available to the state in providing such computing services and shall contain estimates of the cost of each alternative, together with a recommendation for action. In developing the plan, the feasibility of shared use of computing hardware and software by school districts, Florida College System institutions, and universities shall be examined. Laws or administrative rules regulating procurement of data processing equipment, communication services, or data processing services by state agencies shall not be construed to apply to local agencies which share computing facilities with state agencies;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting the district school systems in establishing their subsystem components and assuring compatibility with current district systems;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing procedures for continuous evaluation of system efficiency and effectiveness;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiating a reports-management and forms-management system to ascertain that duplication in collection of data does not exist and that forms and reports for reporting under state and federal requirements and other forms and reports are prepared in a logical and uncomplicated format, resulting in a reduction in the number and complexity of required reports, particularly at the school level; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiating such other actions as are necessary to carry out the intent of the Legislature that a management information system for public school management needs be implemented. Such other actions shall be based on criteria including, but not limited to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the reporting requirement;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The origination of the reporting requirement;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of origin of the reporting requirement; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of repeal of the reporting requirement.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific responsibilities of each district school system shall include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing, at the district level, a reports-control and forms-control management system committee composed of school administrators and classroom teachers. The district school board shall appoint school administrator members and classroom teacher members or, in school districts where appropriate, the classroom teacher members shall be appointed by the bargaining agent. Teachers shall constitute a majority of the committee membership. The committee shall periodically recommend procedures to the district school board for eliminating, reducing, revising, and consolidating paperwork and data collection requirements and shall submit to the district school board an annual report of its findings.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With assistance from the commissioner, developing systems compatibility between the state management information system and unique local systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing, with the assistance of the department, inservice training dealing with management information system purposes and scope, a method of transmitting input data, and the use of output report information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a plan for continuous review and evaluation of local management information system needs and procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advising the commissioner of all district management information needs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transmitting required data input elements to the appropriate processing locations in accordance with guidelines established by the commissioner.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining required reports, comparisons, and relationships to be provided to district school systems by the system output reports, continuously reviewing these reports for usefulness and meaningfulness, and submitting recommended additions, deletions, and change requirements in accordance with the guidelines established by the commissioner.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being responsible for the accuracy of all data elements transmitted to the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the expertise in the state system of public education, as well as contracted services, be utilized to hasten the plan for full implementation of a comprehensive management information system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The State Board of Education shall adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 384, ch. 2002-387; s. 111, ch. 2004-357; s. 110, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>