<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.43" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Career program reporting requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall develop a system of performance measures in order to evaluate the career education programs as required in s. 1008.42. This system must measure program enrollment, completion rates, placement rates, and amount of earnings at the time of placement. Placement and employment information, where applicable, shall contain data relevant to job retention, including retention rates. The State Board of Education shall adopt by rule the specific measures and any definitions needed to establish the system of performance measures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To measure and report program enrollment and completion rates, the Department of Education shall use data in the automated student databases generated by the public schools and Florida College System institutions. To measure and report placement rates and amount of earnings at the time of placement, the department shall use data in the reports produced by the Florida Education and Training Placement Information Program as required in s. 1008.39. If any placement information is not available from the Florida Education and Training Placement Information Program, the school district or the Florida College System institution may provide placement information collected by the school district or the Florida College System institution. However, this supplemental information must be verifiable by the department and must not be commingled with the database maintained by the Florida Education and Training Placement Information Program. The State Board of Education shall specify by rule the statistically valid, verifiable, uniform procedures by which school districts and Florida College System institutions may collect and report placement information to supplement the reports from the Florida Education and Training Placement Information Program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt standards for the department, district school boards, and Florida College System institution district boards of trustees to use in program planning, program review, and program evaluation. The standards must include, at a minimum, the completion rates, placement rates, and earnings from employment of former students of career education programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt procedures for reviewing the career education programs administered by the district school boards and the Florida College System institution district boards of trustees when program performance falls below the standards required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually, the department shall compile the reports submitted in compliance with the rules adopted under this section and shall produce a statewide report that addresses the extent to which school districts and Florida College System institutions are meeting the standards established under paragraph (1)(c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education may adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 391, ch. 2002-387; s. 115, ch. 2004-357; s. 114, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>