<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Common placement testing for public postsecondary education.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education, in conjunction with the Board of Governors, shall develop and implement a common placement test for the purpose of assessing the basic computation and communication skills of students who intend to enter a degree program at any public postsecondary educational institution. Public postsecondary educational institutions shall provide appropriate modifications of the test instruments or test procedures for students with disabilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common placement testing program shall include at a minimum the following: the capacity to diagnose basic competencies in the areas of English, reading, and mathematics which are essential to perform college-level work; prerequisite skills that relate to progressively advanced instruction in mathematics, such as algebra and geometry; prerequisite skills that relate to progressively advanced instruction in language arts, such as English composition and literature; and provision of test information to students on the specific deficiencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules that require high schools to evaluate before the beginning of grade 12 the college readiness of each student who scores at Level 2 or Level 3 on the reading portion of the grade 10 FCAT or Level 2, Level 3, or Level 4 on the mathematics assessments under s. 1008.22(3)(c). High schools shall perform this evaluation using results from the corresponding component of the common placement test prescribed in this section, or an equivalent test identified by the State Board of Education. The State Board of Education shall identify in rule the assessments necessary to perform the evaluations required by this subsection and shall work with the school districts to administer the assessments. The State Board of Education shall establish by rule the minimum test scores a student must achieve to demonstrate readiness. Students who demonstrate readiness by achieving the minimum test scores established by the state board and enroll in a Florida College System institution within 2 years of achieving such scores shall not be required to retest or enroll in remediation when admitted to any Florida College System institution. The high school shall use the results of the test to advise the students of any identified deficiencies and to provide 12th grade students, and require them to complete, appropriate postsecondary preparatory instruction prior to high school graduation. The curriculum provided under this subsection shall be identified in rule by the State Board of Education and encompass Florida’s Postsecondary Readiness Competencies. Other elective courses may not be substituted for the selected postsecondary reading, mathematics, or writing preparatory course unless the elective course covers the same competencies included in the postsecondary reading, mathematics, or writing preparatory course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Students who have been identified as requiring additional preparation pursuant to subsection (1) shall enroll in college-preparatory or other adult education pursuant to s. 1004.93 in Florida College System institutions to develop needed college-entry skills. The State Board of Education shall specify by rule provisions for alternative remediation opportunities and retesting policies. These students shall be permitted to take courses within their degree program concurrently in other curriculum areas for which they are qualified while enrolled in college-preparatory instruction courses. A student enrolled in a college-preparatory course may concurrently enroll only in college credit courses that do not require the skills addressed in the college-preparatory course. A degree-seeking student who is required to complete a college-preparatory course must successfully complete the required college-preparatory studies by the time the student has accumulated 12 hours of lower-division college credit degree coursework; however, a student may continue enrollment in degree-earning coursework provided the student maintains enrollment in college-preparatory coursework for each subsequent semester until college-preparatory coursework requirements are completed, and provided the student demonstrates satisfactory performance in degree-earning coursework. A student who has accumulated 12 college credit hours and has not yet demonstrated proficiency in the basic competency areas of reading, writing, and mathematics must be advised in writing of the requirements for associate degree completion and state university admission, including information about future financial aid eligibility and the potential costs of accumulating excessive college credit as described in s. 1009.286. Before a student is considered to have met basic computation and communication skills requirements, the student must demonstrate successful mastery of the required developmental education competencies as defined in State Board of Education rule. Credit awarded for college-preparatory instruction may not be counted toward fulfilling the number of credits required for a degree.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A university board of trustees may contract with a Florida College System institution board of trustees for the Florida College System institution to provide such instruction on the state university campus. Any state university in which the percentage of incoming students requiring college-preparatory instruction equals or exceeds the average percentage of such students for the Florida College System may offer college-preparatory instruction without contracting with a Florida College System institution; however, any state university offering college-preparatory instruction as of January 1, 1996, may continue to provide such services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student may not be enrolled in a college credit mathematics or English course on a dual enrollment basis unless the student has demonstrated adequate precollegiate preparation on the section of the basic computation and communication skills assessment required pursuant to subsection (1) that is appropriate for successful student participation in the course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 373, ch. 2002-387; s. 124, ch. 2007-217; s. 19, ch. 2008-235; s. 10, ch. 2010-22; s. 106, ch. 2011-5; s. 26, ch. 2011-175; s. 14, ch. 2011-177.</History>
</Section>