<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Board of Education oversight enforcement authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall oversee the performance of district school boards and Florida College System institution boards of trustees in enforcement of all laws and rules. District school boards and Florida College System institution boards of trustees shall be primarily responsible for compliance with law and state board rule.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to ensure compliance with law or state board rule, the State Board of Education shall have the authority to request and receive information, data, and reports from school districts and Florida College System institutions. District school superintendents and Florida College System institution presidents are responsible for the accuracy of the information and data reported to the state board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education may investigate allegations of noncompliance with law or state board rule and determine probable cause. The commissioner shall report determinations of probable cause to the State Board of Education which shall require the district school board or Florida College System institution board of trustees to document compliance with law or state board rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the district school board or Florida College System institution board of trustees cannot satisfactorily document compliance, the State Board of Education may order compliance within a specified timeframe.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the State Board of Education determines that a district school board or Florida College System institution board of trustees is unwilling or unable to comply with law or state board rule within the specified time, the state board shall have the authority to initiate any of the following actions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the Legislature that the school district or Florida College System institution has been unwilling or unable to comply with law or state board rule and recommend action to be taken by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the discretionary lottery appropriation until the school district or Florida College System institution complies with the law or state board rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withhold the transfer of state funds, discretionary grant funds, or any other funds specified as eligible for this purpose by the Legislature until the school district or Florida College System institution complies with the law or state board rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Declare the school district or Florida College System institution ineligible for competitive grants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require monthly or periodic reporting on the situation related to noncompliance until it is remedied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to create a private cause of action or create any rights for individuals or entities in addition to those provided elsewhere in law or rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 376, ch. 2002-387; s. 51, ch. 2004-41; s. 125, ch. 2007-217; s. 108, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>