<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State university accountability process.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that an accountability process be implemented that provides for the systematic, ongoing evaluation of quality and effectiveness of state universities. It is further the intent of the Legislature that this accountability process monitor performance at the system level in each of the major areas of instruction, research, and public service, while recognizing the differing missions of each of the state universities. The accountability process shall provide for the adoption of systemwide performance standards and performance goals for each standard identified through a collaborative effort involving state universities, the Board of Governors, the Legislature, and the Governor’s Office, consistent with requirements specified in s. 1001.706. These standards and goals shall be consistent with s. 216.011(1) to maintain congruity with the performance-based budgeting process. This process requires that university accountability reports reflect measures defined through performance-based budgeting. The performance-based budgeting measures must also reflect the elements of teaching, research, and service inherent in the missions of the state universities.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By December 31 of each year, the Board of Governors shall submit an annual accountability report providing information on the implementation of performance standards, actions taken to improve university achievement of performance goals, the achievement of performance goals during the prior year, and initiatives to be undertaken during the next year. The accountability reports shall be designed in consultation with the Governor’s Office, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, and the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors shall recommend in the annual accountability report any appropriate modifications to this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 393, ch. 2002-387; s. 130, ch. 2007-217; s. 13, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>