<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida’s K-20 education performance accountability system; legislative intent; mission, goals, and systemwide measures; data quality improvements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance accountability system implemented to assess the effectiveness of Florida’s seamless K-20 education delivery system provide answers to the following questions in relation to its mission and goals:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What is the public receiving in return for funds it invests in education?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How effectively is Florida’s K-20 education system educating its students?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How effectively are the major delivery sectors promoting student achievement?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How are individual schools and postsecondary education institutions performing their responsibility to educate their students as measured by how students are performing and how much they are learning?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The K-20 education performance accountability system be established as a single, unified accountability system with multiple components, including, but not limited to, measures of adequate yearly progress, individual student learning gains in public schools, school grades, and return on investment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The K-20 education performance accountability system comply with the requirements of the “No Child Left Behind Act of 2001,” Pub. L. No. 107-110, and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education and the Board of Governors of the State University System recommend to the Legislature systemwide performance standards; the Legislature establish systemwide performance measures and standards; and the systemwide measures and standards provide Floridians with information on what the public is receiving in return for the funds it invests in education and how well the K-20 system educates its students.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education establish performance measures and set performance standards for individual public schools and Florida College System institutions, with measures and standards based primarily on student achievement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors of the State University System establish performance measures and set performance standards for individual state universities, including actual completion rates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISSION, GOALS, AND SYSTEMWIDE MEASURES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mission of Florida’s K-20 education system shall be to increase the proficiency of all students within one seamless, efficient system, by allowing them the opportunity to expand their knowledge and skills through learning opportunities and research valued by students, parents, and communities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The process for establishing state and sector-specific standards and measures must be:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Focused on student success.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Addressable through policy and program changes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Efficient and of high quality.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Measurable over time.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Simple to explain and display to the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aligned with other measures and other sectors to support a coordinated K-20 education system.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall maintain an accountability system that measures student progress toward the following goals:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Highest student achievement, as indicated by evidence of student learning gains at all levels.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seamless articulation and maximum access, as measured by evidence of progression, readiness, and access by targeted groups of students identified by the Commissioner of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Skilled workforce and economic development, as measured by evidence of employment and earnings.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Quality efficient services, as measured by evidence of return on investment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other goals as identified by law or rule.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">K-20 EDUCATION DATA QUALITY IMPROVEMENTS.<EmDash />To provide data required to implement education performance accountability measures in state and federal law, the Commissioner of Education shall initiate and maintain strategies to improve data quality and timeliness. All data collected from state universities shall, as determined by the commissioner, be integrated into the K-20 data warehouse. The commissioner shall have unlimited access to such data solely for the purposes of conducting studies, reporting annual and longitudinal student outcomes, and improving college readiness and articulation. All public educational institutions shall provide data to the K-20 data warehouse in a format specified by the commissioner.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School districts and public postsecondary educational institutions shall maintain information systems that will provide the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, and the Legislature with information and reports necessary to address the specifications of the accountability system. The level of comprehensiveness and quality shall be no less than that which was available as of June 30, 2001.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Colleges and universities eligible to participate in the William L. Boyd, IV, Florida Resident Access Grant Program shall report student-level data for each student who receives state funds in a format prescribed by the Department of Education. At a minimum, data shall be reported annually to the department and include retention rates, transfer rates, completion rates, graduation rates, employment and placement rates, and earnings of graduates.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall determine the standards for the required data, monitor data quality, and measure improvements. The commissioner shall report annually to the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives data quality indicators and ratings for all school districts and public postsecondary educational institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner shall continuously monitor and review the collection of paperwork, data, and reports by school districts and complete an annual review of such collection no later than June 1 of each year. The annual review must include recommendations for consolidating paperwork, data, and reports, wherever feasible, in order to reduce the burdens on school districts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By July 1 of each year, the commissioner shall prepare a report assisting the school districts in eliminating or consolidating paperwork, data, and reports by providing suggestions, technical assistance, and guidance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before establishing any new reporting or data collection requirements, the Commissioner of Education shall utilize existing data being collected to reduce duplication and minimize paperwork.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The State Board of Education shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section relating to the K-20 data warehouse.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 375, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-80; s. 13, ch. 2005-56; s. 44, ch. 2006-74; s. 20, ch. 2008-235; s. 199, ch. 2010-102; s. 107, ch. 2011-5; s. 12, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>