<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1008.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida College System institution accountability process.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that a management and accountability process be implemented which provides for the systematic, ongoing improvement and assessment of the improvement of the quality and efficiency of the Florida College System institutions. Accordingly, the State Board of Education and the Florida College System institution boards of trustees shall develop and implement an accountability plan to improve and evaluate the instructional and administrative efficiency and effectiveness of the Florida College System. This plan shall be designed in consultation with staff of the Governor and the Legislature and must address the following issues:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation rates of A.A. and A.S. degree-seeking students compared to first-time-enrolled students seeking the associate degree.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minority student enrollment and retention rates.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student performance, including student performance in college-level academic skills, mean grade point averages for Florida College System institution A.A. transfer students, and Florida College System institution student performance on state licensure examinations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Job placement rates of Florida College System institution career students.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student progression by admission status and program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Career accountability standards identified in s. 1008.42.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Institutional assessment efforts related to the requirements of s. III in the Criteria for Accreditation of the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other measures approved by the State Board of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall submit an annual report, to coincide with the submission of the agency strategic plan required by law, providing the results of initiatives taken during the prior year and the initiatives and related objective performance measures proposed for the next year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall address within the annual evaluation of the performance of the executive director, and the Florida College System institution boards of trustees shall address within the annual evaluation of the presidents, the achievement of the performance goals established by the accountability process.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 392, ch. 2002-387; s. 116, ch. 2004-357; s. 129, ch. 2007-217; s. 115, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>