<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0521.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retail lessor must:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose to the retail lessee in the lease agreement in a separate blocked section, in capital letters of at least 12-point bold type, with the appropriate amounts specified, as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">THIS IS A LEASE AGREEMENT.<NewLine />THIS IS NOT A PURCHASE AGREEMENT.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">PLEASE REVIEW THESE MATTERS CAREFULLY AND SEEK INDEPENDENT PROFESSIONAL ADVICE IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS CONCERNING THIS TRANSACTION. YOU ARE ENTITLED TO AN EXACT COPY OF THE AGREEMENT YOU SIGN.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">CAPITALIZED COST $<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush"> (Your total cost of goods, services, &amp; fees.)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">CAPITALIZED COST REDUCTION $<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush"> (Your total credits.)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">ADJUSTED OR NET CAPITALIZED COST $<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush"> (Your net cost of goods, services, &amp; fees.)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For purposes of this subsection, that portion of the disclosure stating the terms “capitalized cost,” “capitalized cost reduction,” and “adjusted or net capitalized cost,” and the explanations contained in the parentheticals, as well as their respective amounts, are not required to be disclosed if the terms “gross capitalized cost,” “capitalized cost reduction,” and “adjusted capitalized cost” and the descriptions and disclosures set forth and required by the federal Consumer Leasing Act, 15 U.S.C. s. 1667 et seq., and Federal Reserve Board Regulation M. 12 C.F.R. part 213, are set forth elsewhere in the lease agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the retail lessee with a copy of the lease agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 95-350; s. 1, ch. 98-128; s. 1, ch. 2005-125.</History></Section>