<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0399.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Design, installation, and alteration of conveyances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conveyance covered by this chapter may not be erected, constructed, installed, or altered within buildings or structures until a permit has been obtained from the department. Permits must be applied for by a registered elevator company and may only be granted upon receipt and approval of an application to be made on a form prescribed by the department, accompanied by proper fees and a sworn statement from an agent of the registered elevator company that the plans meet all applicable elevator safety and building codes. Permits may be granted only to registered elevator companies in good standing. When any material alteration is made, the alteration must conform to applicable requirements of the Florida Building Code and the provisions of this chapter. A copy of the permit and plans must be kept at the construction site at all times while the work is in progress and until a certificate of operation is issued. A permit shall not be required for construction or repair of elevators in seeking to attain compliance with emergency elevator access requirements. Elevator owners shall forward to the department, in an electronic format approved by the department, an emergency access notification that compliance measures are either not required or are being implemented. The emergency access notification must also contain specific compliance information, including the current compliance status, specific measures required to attain compliance, and certification by a state-certified inspector. Fees may not be assessed for the filing of the emergency access notification. The department shall maintain an emergency elevator access registry that is available to the State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services for enforcement purposes. The Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide by rule for permit application requirements and permit fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits may be revoked for the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are any false statements or misrepresentations as to the material facts in the application, plans, or specifications on which the permit was based.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permit was issued in error and not in accordance with the code or rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The work detailed under the permit is not being performed in accordance with the provisions of the application, plans, or specifications or with the code or conditions of the permit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction permitholder to whom the permit was issued fails or refuses to comply with a stop-work order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit expires if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The work authorized by the permit is not commenced within 6 months after the date of issuance, or within a shorter period of time as the department may specify at the time the permit is issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The work is suspended or abandoned for a period of 60 days, or such shorter period of time as the department may specify at the time the permit is issued, after the work has been started. For good cause, the department may allow a discretionary extension for the foregoing period.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All new conveyance installations must be performed by a registered elevator company. Before any vertical conveyance is used, except those in a private residence, it must be inspected by a certified elevator inspector not employed, associated, or having a conflict of interest with the elevator construction permitholder or elevator owner and certified as meeting the safety provisions of the Florida Building Code, including the performance of all required safety tests. The certified elevator inspector shall provide the original copy of the inspection report to the department within 5 days after the inspection. A certificate of operation may not be issued until the permitholder provides an affidavit signed by the construction supervisor attesting that the supervisor directly supervised the construction or installation of the elevator. Vertical conveyances, including stairway chairlifts, and inclined or vertical wheelchair lifts located in private residences are not required to obtain a certificate of operation under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the department’s request, and to facilitate oversight and monitoring, the permitholder shall notify the department of the scheduled final inspection date and time for purposes of acquiring a certificate of inspection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each elevator shall comply with the edition of the Florida Building Code or Elevator Safety Code that was in effect at the time of receipt of application for the construction permit for the elevator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each alteration to, or relocation of, an elevator shall comply with the edition of the Florida Building Code or Elevator Safety Code that was in effect at the time of receipt of the application for the construction permit for the alteration or relocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any change is made in the classification of an elevator, the elevator shall comply with all of the requirements of the version of the Florida Building Code or Elevator Safety Code that were in effect at the time of receipt of the application for the construction permit for the change in classification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The temporary use of an elevator during installation or alteration is authorized for a period of 30 days after the completion of a satisfactory temporary operation inspection. An additional 30-day period of temporary use is authorized from the date of completion of each additional satisfactory temporary operation inspection. A satisfactory temporary operation inspection must satisfy the following criteria: the elevator is tested under contract load; the hoistway is fully enclosed; the hoistway doors and interlocks are installed; the car is completely enclosed, including door or gate and top; all electrical safety devices are installed and properly functioning; and terminal stopping equipment is in place for a safe runby and proper clearance. When a car is provided with a temporary enclosure, the operating means must be by constant pressure push-button or lever-type switch. The car may not exceed the minimum safe operating speed of the elevator, and the governor tripping speed must be set in accordance with the operating speed of the elevator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporary use is authorized only when a satisfactory temporary operation inspection report, completed within the last 30 days, by a certified elevator inspector, and a notice prescribed by the department, bearing a statement that the elevator has not been finally approved by a certified elevator inspector, are conspicuously posted in the elevator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 24096, 1947; s. 3, ch. 57-227; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 5, 6, ch. 71-228; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 16, 17, ch. 83-145; s. 8, ch. 93-16; s. 25, ch. 2000-141; ss. 8, 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 5, ch. 2002-293; s. 8, ch. 2002-299; s. 2, ch. 2004-12.</History></Section>