<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0828.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 828.22-828.26.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 828.22-828.26, the following words shall have the meanings indicated:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association doing business in this state, in whole or in part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Slaughter” means the act of killing one or more livestock animals for any purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Slaughterer” means any person other than a licensed veterinarian, or an employee of a humane society or animal control agency, who kills livestock.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Livestock” means cattle, calves, sheep, swine, horses, mules, goats, ostriches, rheas, emus, and any other domestic animal that can or may be used in the preparation of animal products. For the purposes of ss. 828.22-828.26, “livestock” does not include poultry and aquatic species.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Humane method” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method whereby the animal is rapidly and effectively rendered insensitive to pain by electrical or chemical means or by a penetrating captive bolt or gunshot with appropriate caliber and placement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method in accordance with ritual requirements of any religious faith whereby the animal suffers loss of consciousness by anemia of the brain caused by the simultaneous and instantaneous severance of the carotid arteries with a sharp instrument.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-254; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 282, ch. 71-377; s. 4, ch. 92-206; s. 38, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>