<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0828.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Euthanasia of animals offered for sale by pet shops.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warm-blooded animal, except one held as food for another animal, offered for sale, or obtained for sale by a pet shop may be euthanized only by administering sodium pentobarbital, a sodium pentobarbital derivative, or a substance or procedure which acts on the central nervous system and is clinically proven to be humane.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lethal solution must be administered in the following order of preference:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By intravenous injection by hypodermic needle;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By intraperitoneal injection by hypodermic needle;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By intracardial injection by hypodermic needle; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By solution or powder added to food.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An animal may be tranquilized with an approved, humane substance before euthanasia is performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Succinylcholine chloride, curare, a curariform mixture, a substance which acts as a neuromuscular blocking agent, or a chamber which causes a change in body oxygen, except a chamber which uses commercially bottled carbon monoxide gas, may not be used on a warm-blooded animal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Euthanasia must be performed by a licensed veterinarian or layperson who is humane and proficient in the method used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An animal may not be left unattended between the time euthanasia procedures are commenced and the time death occurs, nor may its body be disposed of until death is confirmed by a qualified person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney may bring an action to enjoin a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 91-29.</History></Section>