<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0828.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Controlled substances and legend drugs; permits for use.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Pharmacy shall adopt rules providing for the issuance of permits authorizing the purchase, possession, and use of sodium pentobarbital, sodium pentobarbital with lidocaine, tiletamine hydrochloride, alone or combined with zolazepam (including Telazol), xylazine (including Rompun), ketamine, acepromazine maleate (also acetylpromazine, and including Atravet or Acezine), alone or combined with etorphine (including Immobilon), and yohimbine hydrochloride, alone or combined with atipamezole (including Antisedan) by county or municipal animal control agencies or humane societies registered with the Secretary of State for the purpose of euthanizing injured, sick, or abandoned domestic animals which are in their lawful possession or for the chemical immobilization of animals. The rules shall set forth guidelines for the proper storage and handling of these prescription drugs and such other provisions as may be necessary to ensure that the drugs are used solely for the purpose set forth in this section. The rules shall also provide for an application fee not to exceed $50 and a biennial renewal fee not to exceed $50. Upon formal, written request and recommendation adopted in a public meeting by the Board of Veterinary Medicine, the Board of Pharmacy may, by rule, add controlled substances and legend drugs to the list of prescription drugs in this subsection upon a finding that such additions are necessary for the humane and lawful euthanasia of injured, sick, or abandoned domestic animals or chemical immobilization of animals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or municipal animal control agency or any humane society registered with the Secretary of State may apply to the Department of Health for a permit to purchase, possess, and use the prescription drugs authorized under subsection (1). Upon certification by the Board of Pharmacy that the applicant meets the qualifications set forth in the rules, the Department of Health shall issue the permit. The possession and use of the prescription drugs authorized under subsection (1) is limited to those employees or agents of the permittee certified in accordance with s. 828.058 or s. 828.27 while operating in the scope of their respective official or employment duties with the permittee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the board may deny a permit, and revoke, suspend, or refuse to renew the permit of any permittee, and may fine, place on probation, or otherwise discipline any permittee, upon a determination that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or permittee or any of its employees or agents is using or has used a prescription drug authorized under subsection (1) for any purpose other than that set forth in this section; </Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or permittee has failed to take reasonable precautions against misuse, theft, loss, or diversion of such prescription drugs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or permittee has failed to detect or to report to the Department of Health a significant loss, theft, or inventory shortage of such prescription drugs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or permittee has failed to follow the rules of the Board of Pharmacy regarding proper storage and handling of such prescription drugs; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permittee has violated any provision of this section, chapter 465, chapter 499, or any rule adopted under those chapters.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules implementing subsection (3), provided that disciplinary action may be taken only for a substantial violation of the provisions of this section or the rules adopted under this section. In determining the severity of an administrative penalty to be assessed under this section, the department or the Board of Pharmacy shall consider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the violation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any actions taken by the person to correct the violation or to remedy complaints, and the timing of those actions; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health may issue an emergency order immediately suspending a permit issued under this section upon a determination that a permittee, as a result of any violation of any provision of this section or any rule adopted under this section, presents a danger to the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to licensed pharmacies, veterinarians, or health care practitioners operating within the scope of the applicable professional act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-346; s. 35, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 87-398; s. 249, ch. 94-218; s. 2, ch. 2012-173.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 500.1518.</Text></Note></Section>