<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0828.058" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Euthanasia of dogs and cats.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sodium pentobarbital, a sodium pentobarbital derivative, or other agent the Board of Veterinary Medicine may approve by rule shall be the only methods used for euthanasia of dogs and cats by public or private agencies, animal shelters, or other facilities which are operated for the collection and care of stray, neglected, abandoned, or unwanted animals. A lethal solution shall be used in the following order of preference:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intravenous injection by hypodermic needle;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intraperitoneal injection by hypodermic needle; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the dog or cat is unconscious with no corneal reflex, intracardial injection by hypodermic needle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dog or cat may be tranquilized with an approved and humane substance before euthanasia is performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Succinylcholine chloride, curare, curariform mixtures, any substance which acts as a neuromuscular blocking agent, or a chamber which causes a change in body oxygen may not be used on a dog or cat for any purpose. However, whenever an emergency situation exists which requires the immediate euthanasia of an injured, diseased, or dangerous animal, a law enforcement officer, a veterinarian, or an agent of a local animal control unit or the designee of such an agent may humanely destroy the animal, as provided in s. 828.05.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Euthanasia shall be performed only by a licensed veterinarian or an employee or agent of a public or private agency, animal shelter, or other facility that is operated for the collection and care of stray, neglected, abandoned, or unwanted animals, provided the employee or agent has successfully completed a 16-hour euthanasia technician certification course. The curriculum for such course must be approved by the Board of Veterinary Medicine and must include, at a minimum, the pharmacology, proper administration, and storage of euthanasia solutions; federal and state laws regulating the storage and accountability of euthanasia solutions; euthanasia technician stress management; and proper disposal of euthanized animals. An employee or agent performing euthanasia before October 1, 1993, must obtain certification by October 1, 1994. An employee or agent who begins performing euthanasia on or after October 1, 1993, must obtain certification before performing any euthanasia. However, a certified veterinarian technician who is an employee or agent as defined in the subsection, may perform euthanasia without completing the certification course required by this subsection. Euthanasia must be performed in a humane and proficient manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No dog or cat may be left unattended between the time euthanasia procedures are first begun and the time death occurs, nor may its body be disposed of until death is confirmed by a qualified person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney may bring an action to enjoin any violation of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of this act is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, ch. 84-105; s. 201, ch. 91-224; s. 6, ch. 93-13; s. 3, ch. 2012-173.</History></Section>