<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.047" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident license; reciprocal agreement; authorized purchase.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may waive all or part of the examination requirements provided for in this part on a reciprocal basis with any other state or agency, or an Indian tribe, that has substantially the same or better standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonresident applying for a license under this part to operate in the state shall file a Designation of Registered Agent naming the Secretary of State as the agent of the nonresident, upon whom process may be served in the event of any suit against the nonresident. The designation shall be prepared on a form provided by the department and shall render effective the jurisdiction of the courts of this state over the nonresident applicant. However, any nonresident who has a duly appointed registered agent upon whom process may be served as provided by law shall not be required to designate the Secretary of State as registered agent. The Secretary of State shall be allowed the registered-agent fees as provided by law for designating registered agents. The department shall be furnished with a copy of the designation of the Secretary of State or of a registered agent which is certified by the Secretary of State. The Secretary of State shall notify the department of any service of process it receives as registered agent for persons licensed under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restricted-use pesticides may be purchased by any person who holds a valid applicator’s license or who holds a valid purchase authorization card issued by the department or by a licensee under chapter 388 or chapter 482. A nonlicensed person may apply restricted-use pesticides under the direct supervision of a licensed applicator. An applicator’s license shall be issued by the department on a form supplied by it in accordance with the requirements of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 11, ch. 94-233; s. 17, ch. 2000-154; s. 30, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>