<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.2031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural employer” means any person who hires or contracts for the services of workers to perform activities related to the production of agricultural plants or any person who is an owner of, or responsible for, the management or condition of an agricultural establishment that uses such workers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural establishment” means any farm, forest, nursery, or greenhouse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural plant” means any plant grown or maintained for commercial or research purposes and includes, but is not limited to, food, feed, fiber plants, trees, turfgrass, flowers, shrubs, ornamentals, and seedlings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Designated representative” means any organization or person to whom a worker gives written authorization to exercise the right to request the agricultural pesticide information pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fact sheet” means an agricultural pesticide fact sheet approved by the state or Federal Government that provides information about the impacts of the use of an agricultural pesticide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Material safety data sheet” means written, electronic, or printed material concerning an agricultural pesticide that sets forth the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chemical name and the common name of the agricultural pesticide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The hazards or other risks in the use of the agricultural pesticide, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The potential for fire, explosions, corrosivity, and reactivity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The known acute health effects and chronic health effects of exposure to the agricultural pesticide, including those medical conditions that are generally recognized as being aggravated by exposure to the agricultural pesticide.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary routes of entry and symptoms of overexposure.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proper handling practices, necessary personal protective equipment, and other proper or necessary safety precautions in circumstances that involve the use of or exposure to the agricultural pesticide, including appropriate emergency treatment in case of overexposure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The emergency procedures for spills, fire, disposal, and first aid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the known specific potential health risks posed by the agricultural pesticide, which is written in lay terms and is intended to alert any person who reads the information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The year and month, if available, that the information was compiled and the name, address, and emergency telephone number of the manufacturer responsible for preparing the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retaliatory action” means an action, such as dismissal, demotion, harassment, blacklisting with other employers, reducing pay or work hours, or taking away company housing, that is taken by any agricultural employer against a worker who exercises any right under the provisions of the United States Environmental Protection Agency Worker Protection Standard, 40 C.F.R. s. 1707(b), or this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trainer” means any person who is qualified to train workers under the pesticide safety training requirements of the United States Environmental Protection Agency Worker Protection Standard, 40 C.F.R. s. 170.130.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Worker” means any person, including a farmworker or a self-employed person, who receives any type of compensation for employment that involves tasks relating to the production of agricultural plants on an agricultural establishment. The term “worker” does not include any person employed by a commercial pesticide-handling establishment to perform tasks as a crop advisor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 2004-64; s. 6, ch. 2005-210.</History></Section>