<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stop-sale, stop-use, removal, or hold orders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a pesticide or device is being offered or exposed for sale, used, or held in violation of any of the provisions of this part, the department may issue and enforce a stop-sale, stop-use, removal, or hold order, in writing, to the owner or custodian of the pesticide or device, ordering that the pesticide or device be held at a designated place until the part has been complied with and the pesticide or device is released, in writing, by the department or the violation has been disposed of by court order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written notice is warning to all persons, including, but not limited to, the owner or custodian of the pesticide or the owner’s or custodian’s agents or employees, to scrupulously refrain from moving, bothering, altering, or interfering with the pesticide or device or from altering, defacing, or in any way interfering with the written notice or permitting the same to be done. The willful violation of these provisions is a misdemeanor, subjecting the violator to the penalty provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall release the pesticide or device under a stop-sale, stop-use, removal, or hold order when the owner or custodian complies with the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or custodian, with authorization and supervision of the department, may relabel the pesticide or device so that the label will conform to the product, or transfer and return the product to the manufacturer or supplier for the purpose of bringing the product in compliance with the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; s. 1, ch. 67-527; s. 1, ch. 69-12; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 440, ch. 71-136; s. 7, ch. 73-63; s. 7, ch. 79-210; s. 1, ch. 90-65; ss. 22, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 18, ch. 94-233; s. 25, ch. 2000-154; s. 37, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>