<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration; rules; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may by rule:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Declare as a pest any form of plant or animal life or virus which is injurious to plants, humans, domestic animals, articles, or substances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for the taking and handling of samples and establish tolerances and deficiencies where not specifically provided for in this part; assess penalties; and prohibit the sale or use of pesticides or devices shown to be detrimental to human beings, the environment, or agriculture or to be otherwise of questionable value.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine whether pesticides, and quantities of substances contained in pesticides, are injurious to the environment. The department shall be guided by the United States Environmental Protection Agency regulations in this determination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish requirements governing aircraft used for the aerial application of pesticides, including requirements for recordkeeping, annual aircraft registration, secure storage when not in use, area-of-application information, and reporting any sale, lease, purchase, rental, or transfer of such aircraft to another person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish requirements governing the secure storage of pesticides used by aerial pesticide applicators.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to adopt by rule the primary standards established by the United States Environmental Protection Agency with respect to pesticides. If the provisions of this part are preempted in part by federal law, those provisions not preempted shall apply. This part is intended as comprehensive and exclusive regulation of pesticides in this state. Except as provided in chapters 373, 376, 388, 403, and 482, or as otherwise provided by law, no agency, commission, department, county, municipality, or other political subdivision of the state may adopt laws, regulations, rules, or policies pertaining to pesticides, including their registration, packaging, labeling, distribution, sale, or use, except that local jurisdictions may adopt or enforce an ordinance pertaining to pesticides if that ordinance is in the area of occupational license taxes, building and zoning regulations, disposal or spillage of pesticides within a water well zone, or pesticide safety regulations relating to containment at the storage site.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 179, ch. 71-377; ss. 5, 6, ch. 73-63; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 2, ch. 82-106; ss. 16, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 13, ch. 94-233; s. 477, ch. 97-103; s. 20, ch. 2000-154; s. 1, ch. 2001-360; s. 32, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>