<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Misbranding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pesticide or device is misbranded if its labeling bears any statement, design, or graphic representation which is false or misleading in any particular.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pesticide is misbranded if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is an imitation of, or is offered for sale under the name of, another pesticide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its labeling bears any reference to registration under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The labeling accompanying it does not contain instructions for use which are necessary and, if complied with, adequate for the protection of the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The label does not contain a warning or caution statement which may be necessary and, if complied with, adequate to prevent injury to living humans and other vertebrate animals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The label does not bear an ingredient statement on that part of the immediate container, and on the outside container or wrapper, if there is one, through which the ingredient statement on the immediate container cannot be clearly read, of the retail package which is presented or displayed under customary conditions of purchase.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any word, statement, or other information required by or under authority of this part to appear on the labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness, as compared with other words, statements, designs, or graphic matter in the labeling, and in such terms as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is injurious to living humans or other vertebrate animals or vegetation, except weeds, to which it is applied, or to the person applying such pesticide as directed or in accordance with commonly recognized practice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a plant regulator, defoliant, or desiccant, when used as directed, it is injurious to living humans or other vertebrate animals, or vegetation, to which it is applied, or to the person applying such pesticide. However, physical or physiological effects on plants or parts thereof shall not be deemed to be injury when this is the purpose for which the plant regulator, defoliant, or desiccant was applied in accordance with the label claims and recommendations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any ingredient which is present in amounts which are not likely to be effective when used according to directions is given undue prominence or conspicuousness, as compared with ingredients which are present in effective amounts, in its labeling. Such ingredient shall appear only in the ingredient statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is found to be ineffective when tested in the laboratory.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is found by the department to be of short measure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-63; s. 1, ch. 79-210; s. 1, ch. 82-106; s. 1, ch. 82-167; s. 15, ch. 84-338; ss. 3, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 5, ch. 94-233; s. 475, ch. 97-103; s. 11, ch. 2000-154; s. 24, ch. 2004-64.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 487.021(37).</Text></Note></Section>