<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tolerances, deficiencies, and penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No deficiency will exist in connection with the analysis or report on the analysis of any sample of a pesticide unless the deficiency is greater than 3 percent of the amount guaranteed of one or more of the active ingredients or added ingredients claimed, except as provided by the department by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a pesticide is found by analysis to be deficient in an active ingredient beyond the tolerance as provided in this part, the registrant is subject to a penalty for the deficiency, not to exceed $10,000 per violation. However, no penalty shall be assessed when the official sample was taken from a pesticide that was in the possession of a consumer for more than 45 days from the date of purchase by that consumer, or when the product label specifies that the product should be used by an expiration date that has passed. Procedures for assessing penalties shall be established by rule, based on the degree of the deficiency. Penalties assessed shall be paid to the consumer or, in the absence of a known consumer, the department. If the penalty is not paid within the prescribed period of time as established by rule, the department may deny, suspend, or revoke the registration of any pesticide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a pesticide is found to be ineffective, it shall be deemed to be misbranded and subject to a penalty as established by rule, not to exceed $10,000 per violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a pesticide is found by the department to be of short measure while in the possession of the consumer, the registrant shall make payment in full to the consumer in an amount consistent with procedures to be established by rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 439, ch. 71-136; s. 4, ch. 82-106; s. 100, ch. 83-218; s. 20, ch. 84-338; s. 5, ch. 90-65; ss. 21, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 17, ch. 94-233; s. 24, ch. 2000-154; s. 36, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>