<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; administrative fine; injunction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided in this part, when the department finds any person, applicant, or licensee has violated any provision of this part or rule adopted under this part, it may enter an order imposing any one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a warning letter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the licensee on probation for a specified period of time and subject to conditions the department may specify by rule, including requiring the licensee to attend continuing education courses, to demonstrate competency through a written or practical examination, or to work under the direct supervision of another licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $10,000 for each violation. When imposing any fine under this paragraph, the department shall consider the degree and extent of harm caused by the violation, the cost of rectifying the damage, the amount of money the violator benefited from by noncompliance, whether the violation was committed willfully, and the compliance record of the violator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this part or rules adopted pursuant thereto commits a misdemeanor of the second degree and upon conviction is punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. For a subsequent violation, such person commits a misdemeanor of the first degree and upon conviction is punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the remedies provided in this part and notwithstanding the existence of any adequate remedy at law, the department may bring an action to enjoin the violation or threatened violation of any provision of this part, or rule adopted under this part, in the circuit court of the county in which the violation occurred or is about to occur. Upon the department’s presentation of competent and substantial evidence to the court of the violation or threatened violation, the court shall immediately issue the temporary or permanent injunction sought by the department. The injunction shall be issued without bond. A single act in violation of any provision of this part shall be sufficient to authorize the issuance of an injunction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 9, 18, ch. 74-247; s. 64, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 13, ch. 79-210; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 14, 15, ch. 82-167; ss. 2, 4, ch. 90-65; ss. 34, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 26, ch. 94-233; s. 33, ch. 2000-154; s. 45, ch. 2004-64.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 487.14, 487.158(2), 487.165.</Text></Note></Section>