<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalties provided for violations of s. 487.031(2) shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any carrier while lawfully engaged in transporting a pesticide within this state, if such carrier, upon request, permits the department or its designated agent to copy all records showing the transactions in and movement of the articles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public officials of this state and the Federal Government engaged in the performance of their official duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer or shipper of a pesticide intended for experimental use, if the use is conducted by or under the supervision of a state or federal agency authorized to conduct pesticide research or by a person who has obtained a permit in accordance with department rules prior to shipment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No article shall be deemed in violation of this part when intended solely for export to a foreign country and when prepared or packed according to the specifications or directions of the purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, registration required under this part is not required in the case of a pesticide stored or shipped from one manufacturing plant within this state to another manufacturing plant within this state operated by the same person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall be construed to apply to persons duly licensed or certified under chapter 388 or chapter 482 performing any pest control or other operation for which they are licensed or certified under those chapters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agricultural employer may provide coveralls, chemical-resistant gloves, and chemical-resistant footwear, instead of the personal protective equipment specified on the label, for any worker doing irrigation work for which the only contact with treated surfaces is to the feet, lower legs, hands, and arms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection is not authorized to institute proceedings against any property owner or leaseholder of property under the provisions of s. 376.307(5) to recover any costs or damages associated with pesticide contamination of soil or water, or the evaluation, assessment, or remediation of pesticide contamination of soil or water, including sampling, analysis, and restoration of soil or potable water supplies, subject to the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pesticide contamination of soil or water is determined to be the result of the use of pesticides by the property owner or leaseholder, in accordance with state and federal law, applicable registered labels, and rules on property classified as agricultural land pursuant to s. 193.461;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property owner or leaseholder maintains records of such pesticide applications and such records are provided to the department upon request;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of pesticide contamination of soil or water, the department, upon request, shall make such records available to the Department of Environmental Protection;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not limit regulatory authority under a federally delegated or approved program; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is remedial in nature and shall apply retroactively.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department, in consultation with the secretary of the Department of Environmental Protection, may adopt rules prescribing the format, content, and retention time for records to be maintained under this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-457; s. 4, ch. 65-295; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 79-210; s. 2, ch. 86-116; ss. 20, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 16, ch. 94-233; s. 23, ch. 2000-154; s. 14, ch. 2000-308; s. 35, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>