<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classification of antifouling paint containing organotin compounds as restricted-use pesticides; prohibition of distribution and sale.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall classify antifouling paints containing organotin compounds having an acceptable release rate as restricted-use pesticides subject to the requirements of this part. Antifouling paints containing organotin having acceptable release rates and sold in spray cans of 16 ounces avoirdupois weight or less for outboard motor or lower unit use are exempt from the restricted-use pesticide classification requirement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall initiate action under chapter 120, to deny or cancel the registration of antifouling paints containing organotin compounds which do not have an acceptable release rate or do not meet other criteria established by the department in accordance with this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribution, sale, and use of antifouling paints containing organotin compounds with acceptable release rates shall be limited to dealers and applicators licensed by the department in accordance with this part, to distribute, sell, or use restricted-use pesticides. Such paint may be applied only by licensed applicators and may be applied only to vessels which exceed 25 meters in length or which have aluminum hulls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person other than a paint manufacturer may not sell or deliver to, or purchase or receive from, another person at retail or wholesale any substance containing tin compounds for the purpose of adding such substance to paint to create an antifouling paint.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-194; s. 1, ch. 89-296; ss. 32, 37, ch. 92-115; s. 25, ch. 94-233; s. 32, ch. 2000-154; s. 44, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>