<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.2051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Availability of agricultural pesticide information to workers and medical personnel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agricultural employer shall make available agricultural pesticide information concerning any agricultural pesticide to any worker:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who enters an agricultural-pesticide-treated area on an agricultural establishment where:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agricultural pesticide has been applied within 30 days of that entry; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A restricted-entry interval has been in effect; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who may be exposed to the agricultural pesticide during normal conditions of use or in a foreseeable emergency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agricultural pesticide information provided pursuant to subsection (1) must be in the form of a fact sheet or a material safety data sheet. The agricultural employer shall provide a written copy of the information provided pursuant to subsection (1) within 2 working days after a request for the information by a worker or a designated representative. In the case of a pesticide-related medical emergency, the agricultural employer shall provide a written copy of the information promptly upon the request of the worker, the designated representative, or medical personnel treating the worker.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the initial purchase of a product and with the first purchase after the material safety data sheet is updated, the distributor, manufacturer, or importer of agricultural pesticides shall obtain or develop and provide each direct purchaser of an agricultural pesticide with a material safety data sheet. If the material safety data sheet or fact sheet for the agricultural pesticide is not available when the agricultural pesticide is purchased, the agricultural employer shall take appropriate and timely steps to obtain the material safety data sheet or fact sheet from the distributor, the manufacturer, the department, a federal agency, or another distribution source.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall produce and make available to a trainer a one-page general agricultural pesticide safety sheet. The safety sheet must be in a language understandable to the worker and must include, but need not be limited to, illustrated instructions on preventing agricultural pesticide exposure and toll-free telephone numbers to the Florida Poison Control Centers. The trainer shall provide the safety sheet to the worker pursuant to the United States Environmental Protection Agency Worker Protection Standard, 40 C.F.R. s. 170.130.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 51, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>