<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0487.044" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification; examination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may independently, or through the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, develop a certification program, including an optional training session of at least 4 hours, designed to ensure the competency of those persons to whom the department issues licenses. A standard core examination shall be developed which shall be administered to all applicants for licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require each applicant for a certified applicator’s license to demonstrate competence by a written or oral examination in which the applicant must demonstrate adequate knowledge concerning the proper use and application of restricted-use pesticides in each classification for which application for license is made. The examination may be prepared, administered, and evaluated by the department. Each applicant for a certified applicator’s license shall demonstrate minimum competence as to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proper use of the equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The environmental hazards that may be involved in applying restricted-use pesticides.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calculating the concentration of restricted-use pesticides to be used in particular circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of common pests to be controlled and the damages caused by such pests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protective clothing and respiratory equipment required during the handling and application of restricted-use pesticides.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General precautions to be followed in the disposal of containers, as well as the cleaning and decontamination of the equipment which the applicant proposes to use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable state and federal pesticide laws, rules, and regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General safety precautions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 37, ch. 92-115.</History></Section>