<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0514.0115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions from supervision or regulation; variances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private pools and water therapy facilities connected with facilities connected with hospitals, medical doctors’ offices, and licensed physical therapy establishments shall be exempt from supervision under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pools serving no more than 32 condominium or cooperative units which are not operated as a public lodging establishment shall be exempt from supervision under this chapter, except for water quality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pools serving condominium or cooperative associations of more than 32 units and whose recorded documents prohibit the rental or sublease of the units for periods of less than 60 days are exempt from supervision under this chapter, except that the condominium or cooperative owner or association must file applications with the department and obtain construction plans approval and receive an initial operating permit. The department shall inspect the swimming pools at such places annually, at the fee set forth in s. 514.033(3), or upon request by a unit owner, to determine compliance with department rules relating to water quality and lifesaving equipment. The department may not require compliance with rules relating to swimming pool lifeguard standards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private pool used for instructional purposes in swimming shall not be regulated as a public pool.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any pool serving a residential child care agency registered and exempt from licensure pursuant to s. 409.176 shall be exempt from supervision or regulation under this chapter related to construction standards if the pool is used exclusively by the facility’s residents and if admission may not be gained by the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may grant variances from any rule adopted under this chapter pursuant to procedures adopted by department rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 14, ch. 85-173; s. 2, ch. 87-117; s. 46, ch. 98-151; s. 1, ch. 99-182.</History></Section>