<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0514.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of fee schedules authorized.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to establish a schedule of fees to be charged by the department or by any authorized county health department as detailed in s. 514.025. Fees assessed under this chapter shall be in an amount sufficient to meet the cost of carrying out the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee schedule shall be: for original construction or development plan approval, not less than $275 and not more than $500; for modification of original construction, not less than $100 and not more than $150; for an initial operating permit, not less than $125 and not more than $250; and for review of variance applications, not less than $240 and not more than $400. The department shall assess the minimum fees provided in this subsection until a fee schedule is promulgated by rule of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees shall be based on pool aggregate gallonage, which shall be: up to and including 25,000 gallons, not less than $75 and not more than $125; and in excess of 25,000 gallons, not less than $160 and not more than $265, except for a pool inspected pursuant to s. 514.0115(2)(b) for which the annual fee shall be $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees collected by the department in accordance with this chapter shall be deposited into the Grants and Donations Trust Fund or the County Health Department Trust Fund. Any fee collected under this chapter is nonrefundable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not charge any fees for services provided under this chapter other than those fees authorized in this section. However, the department shall prorate the initial annual fee for an operating permit on a half-year basis.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 78-356; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 9, ch. 83-230; ss. 6, 13, 14, ch. 85-173; s. 1, ch. 87-117; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 9, ch. 96-407; s. 225, ch. 97-101; s. 49, ch. 98-151; s. 109, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>