<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0514.0315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required safety features for public swimming pools and spas.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public swimming pool or spa must be equipped with an anti-entrapment system or device that complies with American Society of Mechanical Engineers/American National Standards Institute standard A112.19.8, or any successor standard.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public swimming pool or spa built before January 1, 1993, with a single main drain other than an unblockable drain must be equipped with at least one of the following features that complies with any American Society of Mechanical Engineers, American National Standards Institute, American Society for Testing and Materials, or other applicable consumer product safety standard for such system or device and protects against evisceration and body-and-limb suction entrapment:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A safety vacuum release system that ceases operation of the pump, reverses the circulation flow, or otherwise provides a vacuum release at a suction outlet when a blockage is detected and that has been tested by an independent third party and found to conform to American Society of Mechanical Engineers/American National Standards Institute standard A112.19.17, American Society for Testing and Materials standard F2387, or any successor standard.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A suction-limiting vent system with a tamper-resistant atmospheric opening.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A gravity drainage system that uses a collector tank.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An automatic pump shut-off system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A device or system that disables the drain.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination and selection of a feature under subsection (2) for a public swimming pool or spa constructed before January 1, 1993, is at the sole discretion of the owner or operator of the public swimming pool or spa. A licensed contractor described in s. 489.105(3)(j), (k), or (l) must install the feature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2011-222; s. 68, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>