<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0514.023" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sampling of beach waters; and public bathing places; health advisories.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “beach waters” means the waters along the coastal and intracoastal beaches and shores of the state, and includes salt water and brackish water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt and enforce rules to protect the health, safety, and welfare of persons using the beach waters and public bathing places of the state. The rules must establish health standards and prescribe procedures and timeframes for bacteriological sampling of beach waters and public bathing places.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue health advisories if the quality of beach waters or a public bathing place fails to meet standards established by the department. The issuance of health advisories related to the results of bacteriological sampling of beach waters is preempted to the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department issues a health advisory against swimming in beach waters or a public bathing place on the basis of finding elevated levels of fecal coliform, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Escherichia coli</Font>, or enterococci bacteria in a water sample, the department shall concurrently notify the municipality or county in which the affected beach waters are located, whichever has jurisdiction, and the local office of the Department of Environmental Protection, of the advisory. The local office of the Department of Environmental Protection shall promptly investigate wastewater treatment facilities within 1 mile of the affected beach waters or public bathing place to determine if a facility experienced an incident that may have contributed to the contamination and provide the results of the investigation in writing or by electronic means to the municipality or county, as applicable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-309; s. 1, ch. 2009-231; s. 105, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>