<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0514.028" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advisory review board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall appoint an advisory review board which shall meet as necessary or at least quarterly, to recommend agency action on variance request, rule and policy development, and other technical review problems. The board shall be comprised of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative from the office of licensure and certification of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative from the county health departments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three representatives from the swimming pool construction industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative from the public lodging industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative from a county or local building department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the advisory review board is to promote better relations, understanding, and cooperation between such industries and the department; to review and make recommendations regarding department product approval standards; to suggest means of better protecting the health, welfare, or safety of persons using the services offered by such industries; and to give the department the benefit of the knowledge and experience of the board concerning the industries and individual businesses affected by the laws and rules administered by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall be reimbursed for travel expenses incurred in connection with service on the advisory review board pursuant to s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 14, 15, ch. 85-173; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-429; s. 152, ch. 97-101; s. 78, ch. 97-237; s. 17, ch. 2011-222.</History></Section>