<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0390.0112" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Termination of pregnancies; reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of any medical facility in which any pregnancy is terminated shall submit a monthly report which contains the number of procedures performed, the reason for same, and the period of gestation at the time such procedures were performed to the agency. The agency shall be responsible for keeping such reports in a central place from which statistical data and analysis can be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the termination of pregnancy is not performed in a medical facility, the physician performing the procedure shall be responsible for reporting such information as required in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports submitted pursuant to this section shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and shall not be revealed except upon the order of a court of competent jurisdiction in a civil or criminal proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person required under this section to file a report or keep any records who willfully fails to file such report or keep such records may be subject to a $200 fine for each violation. The agency shall be required to impose such fines when reports or records required under this section have not been timely received. For purposes of this section, timely received is defined as 30 days following the preceding month.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 79-302; s. 1, ch. 90-336; s. 191, ch. 97-101; s. 3, ch. 97-151; s. 2, ch. 98-1; s. 78, ch. 99-8; s. 202, ch. 99-13.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 390.002.</Text></Note></Section>