<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0390.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of agency; rules; disposal of fetal remains.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may develop and enforce rules pursuant to ss. 390.011-390.018 and part II of chapter 408 for the health, care, and treatment of persons in abortion clinics and for the safe operation of such clinics.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules shall be reasonably related to the preservation of maternal health of the clients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules shall be in accordance with s. 797.03 and may not impose an unconstitutional burden on a woman’s freedom to decide whether to terminate her pregnancy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules shall provide for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance of pregnancy termination procedures only by a licensed physician.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making, protection, and preservation of patient records, which shall be treated as medical records under chapter 458.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For clinics that perform abortions in the first trimester of pregnancy only, these rules shall be comparable to rules that apply to all surgical procedures requiring approximately the same degree of skill and care as the performance of first trimester abortions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For clinics that perform or claim to perform abortions after the first trimester of pregnancy, the agency shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter, including the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules for an abortion clinic’s physical facilities. At a minimum, these rules shall prescribe standards for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate private space that is specifically designated for interviewing, counseling, and medical evaluations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dressing rooms for staff and patients.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate lavatory areas.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Areas for preprocedure hand washing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private procedure rooms.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate lighting and ventilation for abortion procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surgical or gynecological examination tables and other fixed equipment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postprocedure recovery rooms that are equipped to meet the patients’ needs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency exits to accommodate a stretcher or gurney.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Areas for cleaning and sterilizing instruments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate areas for the secure storage of medical records and necessary equipment and supplies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The display in the abortion clinic, in a place that is conspicuous to all patients, of the clinic’s current license issued by the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules to prescribe abortion clinic supplies and equipment standards, including supplies and equipment that are required to be immediately available for use or in an emergency. At a minimum, these rules shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe required clean and sterilized equipment and supplies, including medications, required for the conduct, in an appropriate fashion, of any abortion procedure that the medical staff of the clinic anticipates performing and for monitoring the progress of each patient throughout the procedure and recovery period.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe required equipment, supplies, and medications that shall be available and ready for immediate use in an emergency and requirements for written protocols and procedures to be followed by staff in an emergency, such as the loss of electrical power.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe equipment and supplies for required laboratory tests and requirements for protocols to calibrate and maintain laboratory equipment or equipment operated by clinic staff at the abortion clinic.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require ultrasound equipment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that all equipment is safe for the patient and the staff, meets applicable federal standards, and is checked annually to ensure safety and appropriate calibration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules relating to abortion clinic personnel. At a minimum, these rules shall require that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The abortion clinic designate a medical director who is licensed to practice medicine in this state and who has admitting privileges at a licensed hospital in this state or has a transfer agreement with a licensed hospital within reasonable proximity of the clinic.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a physician is not present after an abortion is performed, a registered nurse, licensed practical nurse, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant shall be present and remain at the clinic to provide postoperative monitoring and care until the patient is discharged.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surgical assistants receive training in counseling, patient advocacy, and the specific responsibilities associated with the services the surgical assistants provide.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Volunteers receive training in the specific responsibilities associated with the services the volunteers provide, including counseling and patient advocacy as provided in the rules adopted by the director for different types of volunteers based on their responsibilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules relating to the medical screening and evaluation of each abortion clinic patient. At a minimum, these rules shall require:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A medical history including reported allergies to medications, antiseptic solutions, or latex; past surgeries; and an obstetric and gynecological history.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physical examination, including a bimanual examination estimating uterine size and palpation of the adnexa.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate laboratory tests, including:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urine or blood tests for pregnancy performed before the abortion procedure.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A test for anemia.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rh typing, unless reliable written documentation of blood type is available.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other tests as indicated from the physical examination.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An ultrasound evaluation for all patients. The rules shall require that if a person who is not a physician performs an ultrasound examination, that person shall have documented evidence that he or she has completed a course in the operation of ultrasound equipment as prescribed in rule. The rules shall require clinics to be in compliance with s. 390.0111.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the physician is responsible for estimating the gestational age of the fetus based on the ultrasound examination and obstetric standards in keeping with established standards of care regarding the estimation of fetal age as defined in rule and shall write the estimate in the patient’s medical history. The physician shall keep original prints of each ultrasound examination of a patient in the patient’s medical history file.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules relating to the abortion procedure. At a minimum, these rules shall require:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a physician, registered nurse, licensed practical nurse, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant is available to all patients throughout the abortion procedure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standards for the safe conduct of abortion procedures that conform to obstetric standards in keeping with established standards of care regarding the estimation of fetal age as defined in rule.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate use of general and local anesthesia, analgesia, and sedation if ordered by the physician.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate precautions, such as the establishment of intravenous access at least for patients undergoing post-first trimester abortions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate monitoring of the vital signs and other defined signs and markers of the patient’s status throughout the abortion procedure and during the recovery period until the patient’s condition is deemed to be stable in the recovery room.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules that prescribe minimum recovery room standards. At a minimum, these rules shall require that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postprocedure recovery rooms are supervised and staffed to meet the patients’ needs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediate postprocedure care consists of observation in a supervised recovery room for as long as the patient’s condition warrants.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinic arranges hospitalization if any complication beyond the medical capability of the staff occurs or is suspected.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered nurse, licensed practical nurse, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant who is trained in the management of the recovery area and is capable of providing basic cardiopulmonary resuscitation and related emergency procedures remains on the premises of the abortion clinic until all patients are discharged.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician shall sign the discharge order and be readily accessible and available until the last patient is discharged to facilitate the transfer of emergency cases if hospitalization of the patient or viable fetus is necessary.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician discusses Rho(D) immune globulin with each patient for whom it is indicated and ensures that it is offered to the patient in the immediate postoperative period or that it will be available to her within 72 hours after completion of the abortion procedure. If the patient refuses the Rho(D) immune globulin, a refusal form approved by the agency shall be signed by the patient and a witness and included in the medical record.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written instructions with regard to postabortion coitus, signs of possible problems, and general aftercare are given to each patient. Each patient shall have specific written instructions regarding access to medical care for complications, including a telephone number to call for medical emergencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a specified minimum length of time that a patient remains in the recovery room by type of abortion procedure and duration of gestation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician ensures that a registered nurse, licensed practical nurse, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant from the abortion clinic makes a good faith effort to contact the patient by telephone, with the patient’s consent, within 24 hours after surgery to assess the patient’s recovery.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipment and services are readily accessible to provide appropriate emergency resuscitative and life support procedures pending the transfer of the patient or viable fetus to the hospital.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules that prescribe standards for followup care. At a minimum, these rules shall require that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A postabortion medical visit that includes a medical examination and a review of the results of all laboratory tests is offered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A urine pregnancy test is obtained at the time of the followup visit to rule out continuing pregnancy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a continuing pregnancy is suspected, the patient shall be evaluated and a physician who performs abortions shall be consulted.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules to prescribe minimum abortion clinic incident reporting. At a minimum, these rules shall require that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The abortion clinic records each incident that results in serious injury to a patient or a viable fetus at an abortion clinic and shall report an incident in writing to the agency within 10 days after the incident occurs. For the purposes of this paragraph, “serious injury” means an injury that occurs at an abortion clinic and that creates a serious risk of substantial impairment of a major bodily organ.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a patient’s death occurs, other than a fetal death properly reported pursuant to law, the abortion clinic reports it to the department not later than the next department workday.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules adopted pursuant to this section shall not limit the ability of a physician to advise a patient on any health issue.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section and the rules adopted pursuant hereto shall be in addition to any other laws, rules, and regulations which are applicable to facilities defined as abortion clinics under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt and enforce rules, in the interest of protecting the public health, to ensure the prompt and proper disposal of fetal remains and tissue resulting from pregnancy termination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any owner, operator, or employee of an abortion clinic fails to dispose of fetal remains and tissue in a manner consistent with the disposal of other human tissue in a competent professional manner, the license of such clinic may be suspended or revoked, and such person is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 78-382; s. 1, ch. 80-413; s. 1, ch. 86-286; ss. 1, 4, 5, ch. 88-97; s. 65, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 97-151; s. 2, ch. 2005-95; s. 15, ch. 2007-230; s. 96, ch. 2008-4; s. 2, ch. 2011-224.</History>
</Section>