<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0472.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Education; substituting demonstration of competency for clock-hour requirements; accreditation; consultation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board requires a student to complete a specific number of clock hours of classroom instruction for initial licensure purposes, the board shall establish the minimal competencies that such student must demonstrate in order to be licensed. The demonstration of such competencies may be substituted for specific classroom clock-hour requirements established in statute or rule which are related to instructional programs for licensure purposes. Student demonstration of the established minimum competencies shall be certified by the educational institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law, educational programs and institutions which are required by statute to be accredited, but which were accredited by an agency that has since ceased to perform an accrediting function, shall be recognized until such programs and institutions are accredited by a qualified successor to the original accrediting agency, an accrediting agency recognized by the United States Department of Education, or an accrediting agency recognized by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall consult with the Commission for Independent Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, and the State Board of Education prior to adopting any changes to training requirements relating to entry into the profession. This consultation must allow the educational board to provide advice regarding the impact of the proposed changes in terms of the length of time necessary to complete the training program and the fiscal impact of the changes. The educational board must be consulted only when an institution offering the training program falls under its jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2009-66.</History></Section>