<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0472.029" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorization to enter lands of third parties; conditions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN GENERAL.<EmDash />Surveyors and mappers or their subordinates may go on, over, and upon the lands of others when necessary to make surveys and maps or locate or set monuments, and, in so doing, may carry with them their agents and employees necessary for that purpose. Entry under the right granted by this subsection does not constitute trespass, and surveyors and mappers and their duly authorized agents or employees so entering are not liable to arrest or to a civil action by reason of such entry; however, this subsection does not give authority to registrants, subordinates, agents, or employees to destroy, injure, damage, or move any physical improvements on lands of another without the written permission of the landowner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIABILITY AND DUTY OF CARE ON AGRICULTURAL LAND.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person regulated by this chapter who enters agricultural land shall do so in compliance with all federal, state, and local laws, rules, and regulations pertaining to premises security, agricultural protections, and other health and safety requirements in place on such land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A landowner is not liable to any third party for civil or criminal acts or damages that result from the negligent or intentional conduct of any person regulated by this chapter on agricultural land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If written notice is not delivered to the landowner or landowner’s registered agent at least 3 business days prior to entry on an agricultural parcel containing more than 160 acres, the duty of care owed by the landowner to those regulated by this chapter is that due an undiscovered trespasser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection applies only to land classified as agricultural pursuant to s. 193.461.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 37, 42, ch. 79-243; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 7, ch. 89-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 94, ch. 94-119; s. 6, ch. 2002-41.</History></Section>