<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0472.0351" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for discipline; penalties; enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions specified in subsection (2) may be taken:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of s. 472.031;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license to practice surveying and mapping by bribery or fraudulent misrepresentations;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice surveying and mapping revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country, for a violation that constitutes a violation under the laws of this state. The acceptance of a relinquishment of licensure, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of charges against the license by a licensing authority is an action against the license;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of guilty, no contest, or nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of surveying and mapping or the ability to practice surveying and mapping;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the licensee knows to be false, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records include only those that are signed in the capacity of a registered surveyor and mapper;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that the licensee is guilty of fraud or deceit, or of negligence, incompetency, or misconduct, in the practice of surveying and mapping;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform a statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensed surveyor and mapper; violating a provision of this chapter, a rule of the board or department, or a lawful order of the board or department; or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing on a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been found liable in a civil proceeding for knowingly filing a false report or complaint with the department against another licensee;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this chapter or the rules of the department or the board;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, employing, or advising any unlicensed person or entity to practice surveying and mapping contrary to this chapter or the rules of the department or the board;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in or related to the practice of professional surveying or mapping or employing a trick or scheme in or related to the practice of professional surveying or mapping;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on the client for the purpose of financial gain of the licensee or a third party;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or accepting and performing professional responsibilities the licensee knows, or has reason to know, the licensee is not competent to perform;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating or contracting for the performance of professional responsibilities by a person when the licensee delegating or contracting for performance of such responsibilities knows, or has reason to know, such person is not qualified by training, experience, and authorization when required to perform them; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly interfering with an investigation or inspection authorized by statute, or with any disciplinary proceeding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board finds a surveyor or mapper guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1) or a violation of this chapter which occurred before obtaining a license, the board may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for licensure, or approval of an application for licensure with restrictions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the surveyor or mapper on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may specify. Those conditions may include, but are not limited to, requiring the licensee to undergo treatment, attend continuing education courses, submit to be reexamined, work under the supervision of another licensee, or satisfy any terms which are reasonably tailored to the violations found.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restriction of the authorized scope of practice by the surveyor or mapper.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corrective action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall reissue the license of a disciplined surveyor or mapper upon certification by the board that he or she has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other discipline imposed pursuant to this section, the board may assess costs and attorney fees related to the investigation and prosecution of the case.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where the board or the department imposes a fine or assessment and the fine or assessment is not paid within a reasonable time, which may be prescribed in the rules of the board or in the order assessing such fines or costs, the department or the Department of Legal Affairs may contract for the collection of, or bring a civil action to recover, the fine or assessment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue to or renew the license of any person or business entity against which the board has assessed a fine, interest, costs, or attorney fees associated with an investigation and prosecution until the person or business entity has paid the full amount due or complies with or satisfies all terms and conditions of the final order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board determines that revocation of a license is the appropriate penalty, the revocation shall be permanent. However, the board may establish, by rule, requirements for reapplication by applicants whose licenses have been permanently revoked. Such requirements may include, but are not limited to, satisfying current requirements for an initial license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 2009-66; s. 13, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>