<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0472.0201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public inspection of information required from applicants; exceptions; examination hearing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All information required by the department of any applicant shall be a public record and shall be open to public inspection pursuant to s. 119.07, except financial information, medical information, school transcripts, examination questions, answers, papers, grades, and grading keys, which are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and shall not be discussed with or made accessible to anyone except members of the board, the department, and staff thereof, who have a bona fide need to know such information. Any information supplied to the department by any other agency which is exempt from the provisions of chapter 119 or is confidential shall remain exempt or confidential pursuant to applicable law while in the custody of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule the procedure by which an applicant, and the applicant’s attorney, may review examination questions and answers. Examination questions and answers are not subject to discovery but may be introduced into evidence and considered only in camera in any administrative proceeding under chapter 120. If an administrative hearing is held, the department shall provide challenged examination questions and answers to the administrative law judge. The examination questions and answers provided at the hearing are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1), unless invalidated by the administrative law judge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless an applicant notifies the department at least 5 days before an examination hearing of the applicant’s inability to attend, or unless an applicant can demonstrate an extreme emergency for failing to attend, the department may require an applicant who fails to attend to pay reasonable attorney’s fees, costs, and court costs of the department for the examination hearing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2009-66.</History></Section>