<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0472.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules of the board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board has authority to adopt rules to implement this chapter conferring duties upon it. This specific grant of rulemaking authority to the board shall be exercised only through proceedings pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 and with the prior approval of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules authorizing the use of professional titles by retired surveyors and mappers. Such rules shall establish guidelines designed to avoid abuse by retirees and confusion on the part of the general public. The rules shall not require continuing education requirements in order to use a professional title by a retiree.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has standing to challenge any rule or proposed rule of the board pursuant to s. 120.56. In addition to challenges for any invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority, the administrative law judge, upon such a challenge by the department, may declare all or part of a rule or proposed rule invalid if it:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not protect the public from any significant and discernible harm or damages;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restricts competition or the availability of professional services in the state or in a significant part of the state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unnecessarily increases the cost of professional services without a corresponding or equivalent public benefit.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A presumption is not created for the existence of any of the conditions cited in this subsection if the department challenges the rule or proposed rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the board is a substantially interested party for purposes of s. 120.54(7). The board may, as an adversely affected party, initiate and maintain an action pursuant to s. 120.68 challenging final agency action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed board rule that has not been modified to remove proposed committee objections of the Administrative Procedures Committee must receive approval from the department before filing the rule with the Department of State for final adoption. The department may repeal any rule enacted by the board which has taken effect without having met proposed committee objections of the Administrative Procedures Committee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 87-349; s. 23, ch. 88-392; ss. 5, 7, ch. 89-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 87, ch. 94-119; s. 143, ch. 98-200; s. 3, ch. 2002-41; s. 7, ch. 2009-66.</History></Section>