<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0472.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, may establish fees to be paid for applications, examination, reexamination, licensing and renewal, inactive status application and reactivation of inactive licenses, recordmaking and recordkeeping, and applications for providers of continuing education. The board may also establish by rule a delinquency fee. The board shall establish fees that are adequate to ensure the continued operation of the board. Fees shall be based on department estimates of the revenue required to implement ss. 472.001-472.037 and the provisions of law with respect to the regulation of surveyors and mappers. If the department determines, based on estimates of available revenue collected pursuant to this section, that the General Inspection Trust Fund contains funds that exceed the amount required to cover the necessary functions of the board, the department shall, by rule, waive the license renewal fees for licensees under this chapter for a period not to exceed 2 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application and examination fee shall not exceed $125 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department to purchase the examination from the National Council of Engineering Examiners or a similar national organization. The examination fee shall be in an amount which covers the cost of obtaining and administering the examination and shall be refunded if the applicant is found ineligible to sit for the examination. The application fee shall be nonrefundable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial license fee shall not exceed $200.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for a certificate of authorization shall not exceed $125.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The biennial renewal fee shall not exceed $500.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for a temporary registration or certificate to practice surveying and mapping may not exceed $100 for an individual or $200 for a business firm.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for licensure by endorsement shall not exceed $200.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for application for inactive status or for reactivation of an inactive license shall not exceed $150.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for applications from providers of continuing education may not exceed $500.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds collected under this section, and the amount paid for licenses, fines, and fees, shall be deposited into the General Inspection Trust Fund of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If sufficient action is not taken by the board within 1 year after notification by the department that license fees are projected to be inadequate, the department shall set license fees on behalf of the board to cover anticipated costs and to maintain the required cash balance. Further, it is the legislative intent that this regulated profession not operate with a negative cash balance. The department may provide by rule for the advancement of sufficient funds if this profession is operating with a negative cash balance. Such advancement may be for a period not to exceed 2 consecutive years and shall require interest to be paid by the regulated profession. Interest shall be calculated at the current rate earned on General Inspection Trust Fund investments. Interest earned shall be allocated to the various funds in accordance with the allocation of investment earnings during the period of the advance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, by rule, assess and collect a special assessment from each active, inactive, and delinquent licensee in an amount necessary to eliminate a cash deficit or, if there is not a cash deficit, in an amount sufficient to maintain the financial integrity of this profession as required in this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract with public and private entities to receive and deposit revenue pursuant to this section. The Legislature shall appropriate funds from the General Inspection Trust Fund sufficient to carry out the provisions of this chapter. To the maximum extent possible, the department shall directly charge all expenses under this chapter to the account of the regulated profession. For the purpose of this subsection, direct charge expenses shall include, but not be limited to, costs for investigations, examinations, and legal services. The department shall maintain adequate records to support its allocation of department expenses. The department shall provide the board with reasonable access to these records upon request. The board shall be provided an annual report of revenue and direct and allocated expenses related to the operation of the profession. These reports shall be used by the board to determine the amount of license fees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A condensed management report of budgets, finances, performance statistics, and recommendations shall be provided to the board at least once a quarter. The department shall identify and include in such presentations any changes, or projected changes, made to the board’s budget since the last presentation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a duplicate license is required or requested by a licensee, the board may charge a fee as determined by rule not to exceed $25 before issuing a duplicate license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the board shall charge a fee not to exceed $25 for the certification of a public record. The fee shall be determined by rule of the department. The department or the appropriate board shall assess a fee for duplication of a public record as provided in s. 119.07(4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 23, 42, ch. 79-243; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 16, 44, ch. 82-179; s. 21, ch. 88-205; ss. 2, 5, 7, ch. 89-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 88, ch. 94-119; s. 6, ch. 2001-63; s. 9, ch. 2009-66; s. 5, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>