<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0440.491" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reemployment of injured workers; rehabilitation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Carrier” means group self-insurance funds or individual self-insureds authorized under this chapter and commercial funds or insurance entities authorized to write workers’ compensation insurance under chapter 624.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical care coordination” includes, but is not limited to, coordinating physical rehabilitation services such as medical, psychiatric, or therapeutic treatment for the injured employee, providing health training to the employee and family, and monitoring the employee’s recovery. The purposes of medical care coordination are to minimize the disability and recovery period without jeopardizing medical stability, to assure that proper medical treatment and other restorative services are timely provided in a logical sequence, and to contain medical costs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rehabilitation provider” means a rehabilitation nurse, rehabilitation counselor, or vocational evaluator providing reemployment assessments, medical care coordination, reemployment services, or vocational evaluations under this section, possessing one or more of the following nationally recognized rehabilitation provider credentials:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Rehabilitation Registered Nurse, C.R.R.N., certified by the Association of Rehab Professionals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Rehabilitation Counselor, C.R.C., certified by the Commission of Rehabilitation Counselor Certifications.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Case Manager, C.C.M., certified by the Commission for Case Management Certification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Disability Management Specialist, C.D.M.S., certified by the Certified Disability Management Specialist Commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Vocational Evaluator, C.V.E., certified by the Commission of Rehabilitation Counselor Certification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified Occupational Health Nurse, C.O.H.N., certified by the American Board of Occupational Health Nurses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reemployment assessment” means a written assessment performed by a rehabilitation provider which provides a comprehensive review of the medical diagnosis, treatment, and prognosis; includes conferences with the employer, physician, and claimant; and recommends a cost-effective physical and vocational rehabilitation plan to assist the employee in returning to suitable gainful employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reemployment services” means services that include, but are not limited to, vocational counseling, job-seeking skills training, ergonomic job analysis, transferable skills analysis, selective job placement, labor market surveys, and arranging other services such as education or training, vocational and on-the-job, which may be needed by the employee to secure suitable gainful employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reemployment status review” means a review to determine whether an injured employee is at risk of not returning to work.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Suitable gainful employment” means employment or self-employment that is reasonably attainable in light of the employee’s age, education, work history, transferable skills, previous occupation, and injury, and which offers an opportunity to restore the individual as soon as practicable and as nearly as possible to his or her average weekly earnings at the time of injury.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vocational evaluation” means a review of the employee’s physical and intellectual capabilities, his or her aptitudes and achievements, and his or her work-related behaviors to identify the most cost-effective means toward the employee’s return to suitable gainful employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of this section to encourage the provision of medical care coordination and reemployment services that are necessary to assist the employee in returning to work as soon as is medically feasible.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REEMPLOYMENT STATUS REVIEWS AND REPORTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an employee who has suffered an injury compensable under this chapter is unemployed 60 days after the date of injury and is receiving benefits for temporary total disability, temporary partial disability, or wage loss, and has not yet been provided medical care coordination and reemployment services voluntarily by the carrier, the carrier must determine whether the employee is likely to return to work and must report its determination to the department and the employee. The report shall include the identification of both the carrier and the employee, and the carrier claim number and any case number assigned by the Office of the Judges of Compensation Claims. The carrier must thereafter determine the reemployment status of the employee at 90-day intervals as long as the employee remains unemployed, is not receiving medical care coordination or reemployment services, and is receiving the benefits specified in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If medical care coordination or reemployment services are voluntarily undertaken within 60 days of the date of injury, such services may continue to be provided as agreed by the employee and the carrier.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REEMPLOYMENT ASSESSMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The carrier may require the employee to receive a reemployment assessment as it considers appropriate. However, the carrier is encouraged to obtain a reemployment assessment if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The carrier determines that the employee is at risk of remaining unemployed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case involves catastrophic or serious injury.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The carrier shall authorize a rehabilitation provider to provide the reemployment assessment. The rehabilitation provider shall conduct its assessment and issue a report to the carrier and the employee within 30 days after the time such assessment is complete.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rehabilitation provider recommends that the employee receive medical care coordination or reemployment services, the carrier shall advise the employee of the recommendation and determine whether the employee wishes to receive such services. The employee shall have 15 days after the date of receipt of the recommendation in which to agree to accept such services. If the employee elects to receive services, the carrier may refer the employee to a rehabilitation provider for such coordination or services within 15 days of receipt of the assessment report or notice of the employee’s election, whichever is later.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEDICAL CARE COORDINATION AND REEMPLOYMENT SERVICES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once the carrier has assigned a case to a rehabilitation provider for medical care coordination or reemployment services, the provider shall develop a reemployment plan and submit the plan to the carrier and the employee for approval.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rehabilitation provider concludes that training and education are necessary to return the employee to suitable gainful employment, or if the employee has not returned to suitable gainful employment within 180 days after referral for reemployment services or receives $2,500 in reemployment services, whichever comes first, the carrier must discontinue reemployment services and refer the employee to the department for a vocational evaluation. Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 627, the cost of a reemployment assessment and the first $2,500 in reemployment services to an injured employee must not be treated as loss adjustment expense for workers’ compensation ratemaking purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A carrier may voluntarily provide medical care coordination or reemployment services to the employee at intervals more frequent than those required in this section. Voluntary services offered by the carrier for any of the following injuries must be considered benefits for purposes of ratemaking: traumatic brain injury; spinal cord injury; amputation, including loss of an eye or eyes; burns of 5 percent or greater of the total body surface.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If medical care coordination or reemployment services have not been undertaken as prescribed in paragraph (3)(b), a rehabilitation service provider, facility, or agency that performs a reemployment assessment shall not provide medical care coordination or reemployment services for the employees it assesses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRAINING AND EDUCATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon referral of an injured employee by the carrier, or upon the request of an injured employee, the department shall conduct a training and education screening to determine whether it should refer the employee for a vocational evaluation and, if appropriate, approve training and education or other vocational services for the employee. At the time of such referral, the carrier shall provide the department a copy of any reemployment assessment or reemployment plan provided to the carrier by a rehabilitation provider. The department may not approve formal training and education programs unless it determines, after consideration of the reemployment assessment, that the reemployment plan is likely to result in return to suitable gainful employment. The department is authorized to expend moneys from the Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund, established by s. 440.50, to secure appropriate training and education at a Florida public college or at a career center established under s. 1001.44, or to secure other vocational services when necessary to satisfy the recommendation of a vocational evaluator. As used in this paragraph, “appropriate training and education” includes securing a general education diploma (GED), if necessary. The department shall by rule establish training and education standards pertaining to employee eligibility, course curricula and duration, and associated costs. For purposes of this subsection, training and education services may be secured from additional providers if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The injured employee currently holds an associate degree and requests to earn a bachelor’s degree not offered by a Florida public college located within 50 miles from his or her customary residence;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The injured employee’s enrollment in an education or training program in a Florida public college or career center would be significantly delayed; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The most appropriate training and education program is available only through a provider other than a Florida public college or career center or at a Florida public college or career center located more than 50 miles from the injured employee’s customary residence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an employee who has attained maximum medical improvement is unable to earn at least 80 percent of the compensation rate and requires training and education to obtain suitable gainful employment, the employer or carrier shall pay the employee additional training and education temporary total compensation benefits while the employee receives such training and education for a period not to exceed 26 weeks, which period may be extended for an additional 26 weeks or less, if such extended period is determined to be necessary and proper by a judge of compensation claims. The benefits provided under this paragraph shall not be in addition to the 104 weeks as specified in s. 440.15(2). However, a carrier or employer is not precluded from voluntarily paying additional temporary total disability compensation beyond that period. If an employee requires temporary residence at or near a facility or an institution providing training and education which is located more than 50 miles away from the employee’s customary residence, the reasonable cost of board, lodging, or travel must be borne by the department from the Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund established by s. 440.50. An employee who refuses to accept training and education that is recommended by the vocational evaluator and considered necessary by the department will forfeit any additional training and education benefits and any additional payment for lost wages under this chapter. The carrier shall notify the injured employee of the availability of training and education benefits as specified in this chapter. The Department of Financial Services shall include information regarding the eligibility for training and education benefits in informational materials specified in ss. 440.207 and 440.40. </Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERMANENT DISABILITY.<EmDash />The judge of compensation claims may not adjudicate an injured employee as permanently and totally disabled until or unless the carrier is given the opportunity to provide a reemployment assessment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT CONTRACTS.<EmDash />The department may contract with one or more third parties including, but not limited to, rehabilitation providers, to administer training and education screenings, reemployment assessments, vocational evaluations, and reemployment services authorized under this section. Any person or firm selected by the department may not have a conflict of interest that might affect its ability to independently perform its responsibilities with respect to administering the provisions of this subsection. A rehabilitation provider who contracts with the department to provide screenings or evaluations may not provide training or education to the injured employee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 93-415; s. 75, ch. 96-418; s. 1055, ch. 97-103; s. 48, ch. 2002-194; s. 31, ch. 2003-412; s. 67, ch. 2004-5; s. 75, ch. 2005-2; s. 3, ch. 2010-155; s. 3, ch. 2011-63; s. 5, ch. 2011-97; s. 6, ch. 2012-135.</History>
</Section>