<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0440.094" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Extraterritorial reciprocity.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employee in this state subject to this chapter temporarily leaves the state incidental to his or her employment and receives an accidental injury arising out of and in the course of employment, the employee is, or the beneficiaries of the employee if the injury results in death are, entitled to the benefits of this chapter as if the employee were injured within this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee from another state and the employer of the employee in the other state are exempt from this chapter while the employee is temporarily in this state doing work for the employer if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer has furnished workers’ compensation insurance coverage under the workers’ compensation insurance or similar laws of the other state to cover the employee’s employment while in this state;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extraterritorial provisions of this chapter are recognized in the other state; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees and employers who are covered in this state are likewise exempted from the application of the workers’ compensation insurance or similar laws of the other state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits under the workers’ compensation insurance or similar laws of the other state, or other remedies under similar law, are the exclusive remedy against the employer for any injury, whether resulting in death or not, received by the employee while temporarily working for that employer in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate from the duly authorized officer of the appropriate department of another state certifying that the employer of the other state is insured in that state and has provided extraterritorial coverage insuring employees while working in this state is prima facie evidence that the employer carries that workers’ compensation insurance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever in any appeal or other litigation the construction of the laws of another jurisdiction is required, the courts shall take judicial notice of such construction of the laws of the other jurisdiction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an employee has a claim under the workers’ compensation law of another state, territory, province, or foreign nation for the same injury or occupational disease as the claim filed in this state, the total amount of compensation paid or awarded under such other workers’ compensation law shall be credited against the compensation due under the Florida Workers’ Compensation Law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, an employee is considered to be temporarily in a state doing work for an employer if the employee is working for his employer in a state other than the state where he or she is primarily employed, for no more than 10 consecutive days, or no more than 25 total days, during a calendar year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to any claim made on or after July 1, 2011, regardless of the date of the accident.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-171.</History>
</Section>