<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0440.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigatory records relating to workers’ compensation employer compliance; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All investigatory records made or received pursuant to s. 440.107 and any records necessary to complete an investigation held by the department are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until the investigation is completed or ceases to be active. For purposes of this section, an investigation is considered “active” while such investigation is being conducted by the department with a reasonable, good faith belief that it may lead to the filing of administrative, civil, or criminal proceedings. An investigation does not cease to be active if the agency is proceeding with reasonable dispatch and there is a good faith belief that action may be initiated by the agency or other administrative or law enforcement agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After an investigation is completed or ceases to be active, information in records relating to the investigation remains confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution if disclosure of that information would:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jeopardize the integrity of another active investigation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal a trade secret, as defined in s. 688.002;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal business or personal financial information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal personal identifying information regarding the identity of a confidential source;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defame or cause unwarranted damage to the good name or reputation of an individual or jeopardize the safety of an individual; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal investigative techniques or procedures.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide information made confidential and exempt by this section to any law enforcement agency or administrative agency for use in the performance of its official duties and responsibilities. The receiving agency must maintain the confidential and exempt status of such information.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-407; s. 22, ch. 2002-194; s. 1, ch. 2003-106.</History></Section>