<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0440.092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special requirements for compensability; deviation from employment; subsequent intervening accidents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECREATIONAL AND SOCIAL ACTIVITIES.<EmDash />Recreational or social activities are not compensable unless such recreational or social activities are an expressly required incident of employment and produce a substantial direct benefit to the employer beyond improvement in employee health and morale that is common to all kinds of recreation and social life.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GOING OR COMING.<EmDash />An injury suffered while going to or coming from work is not an injury arising out of and in the course of employment whether or not the employer provided transportation if such means of transportation was available for the exclusive personal use by the employee, unless the employee was engaged in a special errand or mission for the employer. For the purposes of this subsection and not withstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, an injury to a law enforcement officer as defined in s. 943.10(1), during the officer’s work period or while going to or coming from work in an official law enforcement vehicle, shall be presumed to be an injury arising out of and in the course of employment unless the injury occurred during a distinct deviation for a nonessential personal errand. If, however, the employer’s policy or the collective bargaining agreement that applies to the officer permits such deviations for nonessential errands, the injury shall be presumed to arise out of and in the course of employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEVIATION FROM EMPLOYMENT.<EmDash />An employee who is injured while deviating from the course of employment, including leaving the employer’s premises, is not eligible for benefits unless such deviation is expressly approved by the employer, or unless such deviation or act is in response to an emergency and designed to save life or property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRAVELING EMPLOYEES.<EmDash />An employee who is required to travel in connection with his or her employment who suffers an injury while in travel status shall be eligible for benefits under this chapter only if the injury arises out of and in the course of employment while he or she is actively engaged in the duties of employment. This subsection applies to travel necessarily incident to performance of the employee’s job responsibility but does not include travel to and from work as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUBSEQUENT INTERVENING ACCIDENTS.<EmDash />Injuries caused by a subsequent intervening accident arising from an outside agency which are the direct and natural consequence of the original injury are not compensable unless suffered while traveling to or from a health care provider for the purpose of receiving remedial treatment for the compensable injury.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 90-201; s. 10, ch. 91-1; s. 6, ch. 93-415; s. 103, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 2001-168.</History></Section>