<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0440.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement of compensation orders; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of default by the employer or carrier in the payment of compensation due under any compensation order of a judge of compensation claims or other failure by the employer or carrier to comply with such order within 10 days after the order becomes final, any circuit court of this state within the jurisdiction of which the employer or carrier resides or transacts business shall, upon application by the department or any beneficiary under such order, have jurisdiction to issue a rule nisi directing such employer or carrier to show cause why a writ of execution, or such other process as may be necessary to enforce the terms of such order, shall not be issued, and, unless such cause is shown, the court shall have jurisdiction to issue a writ of execution or such other process or final order as may be necessary to enforce the terms of such order of the judge of compensation claims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where the employer is insured and the carrier fails to comply with any compensation order of a judge of compensation claims or court within 10 days after such order becomes final, the department shall notify the office of such failure and the office shall suspend the license of such carrier to do an insurance business in this state, until such carrier has complied with such order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where the employer is a self-insurer and fails to comply with any compensation order of a judge of compensation claims or court within 10 days after such order becomes final, the department may suspend or revoke any authorization previously given to the employer to be a self-insurer, and the Florida Self-Insurers Guaranty Association, Incorporated, may call or sue upon the surety bond or exercise its rights under the letter of credit deposited by the self-insurer with the association as a qualifying security deposit as may be necessary to satisfy the order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case wherein the employee fails to comply with any order of a judge of compensation claims within 10 days after such order becomes final, the judge of compensation claims may dismiss the claim or suspend payments due under said claim until the employee complies with such order. The judge of compensation claims may strike the defenses of the employer, if said employer is self-insured, or of the insurance carrier, if said employer is not self-insured, if said employer or carrier fails to comply with any order of a judge of compensation claims within 10 days after such order becomes final.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 17481, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 5966(24); s. 10, ch. 18413, 1937; s. 7, ch. 28241, 1953; s. 2, ch. 67-554; ss. 13, 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 120, ch. 71-355; s. 14, ch. 74-197; s. 23, ch. 78-300; ss. 18, 124, ch. 79-40; ss. 13, 21, ch. 79-312; s. 6, ch. 81-119; s. 43, ch. 89-289; s. 56, ch. 90-201; s. 52, ch. 91-1; s. 4, ch. 91-46; s. 36, ch. 2002-194; s. 1, ch. 2002-262; s. 482, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>