<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0440.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorization of collective bargaining agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the limitation stated in subsection (2), a provision that is mutually agreed upon in any collective bargaining agreement filed with the department between an individually self-insured employer or other employer upon consent of the employer’s carrier and a recognized or certified exclusive bargaining representative establishing any of the following shall be valid and binding:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An alternative dispute resolution system to supplement, modify, or replace the provisions of this chapter which may include, but is not limited to, conciliation, mediation, and arbitration. Arbitration held pursuant to this section shall be binding on the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of an agreed-upon list of certified health care providers of medical treatment which may be the exclusive source of all medical treatment under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of a limited list of physicians to conduct independent medical examinations which the parties may agree shall be the exclusive source of independent medical examiners pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A light-duty, modified-job, or return-to-work program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vocational rehabilitation or retraining program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall allow any agreement that diminishes an employee’s entitlement to benefits as otherwise set forth in this chapter. Any such agreement in violation of this provision shall be null and void.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 93-415; s. 35, ch. 2002-194.</History></Section>