<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0440.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Election of exemption; revocation of election; notice; certification.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporate officer who elects not to accept the provisions of this chapter or who, after electing such exemption, revokes that exemption shall mail to the department in Tallahassee notice to such effect in accordance with a form to be prescribed by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each sole proprietor or partner who elects to be included in the definition of “employee” or who, after such election, revokes that election must mail to the department in Tallahassee notice to such effect, in accordance with a form to be prescribed by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each officer of a corporation who is engaged in the construction industry and who elects an exemption from this chapter or who, after electing such exemption, revokes that exemption, must submit a notice to such effect to the department on a form prescribed by the department. The notice of election to be exempt which is electronically submitted to the department by the officer of a corporation who is allowed to claim an exemption as provided by this chapter must list the name, federal tax identification number, date of birth, Florida driver license number or Florida identification card number, all certified or registered licenses issued pursuant to chapter 489 held by the person seeking the exemption, the registration number of the corporation filed with the Division of Corporations of the Department of State, and the percentage of ownership evidencing the required ownership under this chapter. The notice of election to be exempt must identify each corporation that employs the person electing the exemption and must list the social security number or federal tax identification number of each such employer and the additional documentation required by this section. In addition, the notice of election to be exempt must provide that the officer electing an exemption is not entitled to benefits under this chapter, must provide that the election does not exceed exemption limits for officers provided in s. 440.02, and must certify that any employees of the corporation whose officer elects an exemption are covered by workers’ compensation insurance. Upon receipt of the notice of the election to be exempt, receipt of all application fees, and a determination by the department that the notice meets the requirements of this subsection, the department shall issue a certification of the election to the officer, unless the department determines that the information contained in the notice is invalid. The department shall revoke a certificate of election to be exempt from coverage upon a determination by the department that the person does not meet the requirements for exemption or that the information contained in the notice of election to be exempt is invalid. The certificate of election must list the name of the corporation listed in the request for exemption. A new certificate of election must be obtained each time the person is employed by a new or different corporation that is not listed on the certificate of election. A copy of the certificate of election must be sent to each workers’ compensation carrier identified in the request for exemption. Upon filing a notice of revocation of election, an officer who is a subcontractor or an officer of a corporate subcontractor must notify her or his contractor. Upon revocation of a certificate of election of exemption by the department, the department shall notify the workers’ compensation carriers identified in the request for exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of election to be exempt from the provisions of this chapter must contain a notice that clearly states in substance the following: “Any person who, knowingly and with intent to injure, defraud, or deceive the department or any employer or employee, insurance company, or any other person, files a notice of election to be exempt containing any false or misleading information is guilty of a felony of the third degree.” Each person filing a notice of election to be exempt shall personally sign the notice and attest that he or she has reviewed, understands, and acknowledges the foregoing notice.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notice given under subsection (1), subsection (2), or subsection (3) shall become effective when issued by the department or 30 days after an application for an exemption is received by the department, whichever occurs first. However, if an accident or occupational disease occurs less than 30 days after the effective date of the insurance policy under which the payment of compensation is secured or the date the employer qualified as a self-insurer, such notice is effective as of 12:01 a.m. of the day following the date it is mailed to the department in Tallahassee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of election to be exempt which is issued on or after January 1, 2013, in accordance with this section is valid for 2 years after the effective date stated thereon. Both the effective date and the expiration date must be listed on the face of the certificate by the department. The certificate must expire at midnight, 2 years from its issue date, as noted on the face of the exemption certificate. A certificate of election to be exempt may be revoked before its expiration by the officer for whom it was issued or by the department for the reasons stated in this section. At least 60 days before the expiration date of a certificate of exemption, the department shall send notice of the expiration date to the certificateholder at the address on the certificate or to the e-mail address on file with the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contractor responsible for compensation under s. 440.10 may register in writing with the workers’ compensation carrier for any subcontractor and shall thereafter be entitled to receive written notice from the carrier of any cancellation or nonrenewal of the policy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must assess a fee of $50 with each request for a construction industry certificate of election to be exempt or renewal of election to be exempt under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds collected by the department shall be used to administer this section, to audit the businesses that pay the fee for compliance with any requirements of this chapter, and to enforce compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may by rule prescribe forms and procedures for filing an election of exemption, revocation of election to be exempt, and notice of election of coverage for all employers and require specified forms to be submitted by all employers in filing for the election of exemption. The department may by rule prescribe forms and procedures for issuing a certificate of the election of exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each officer of a corporation who is actively engaged in the construction industry and who elects an exemption from this chapter shall maintain business records as specified by the department by rule, which rules must include the provision that any corporation with exempt officers engaged in the construction industry must maintain written statements of those exempted persons affirmatively acknowledging each such individual’s exempt status.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporate officer permitted by this chapter to claim an exemption must be listed on the records of this state’s Secretary of State, Division of Corporations, as a corporate officer. The department shall issue a stop-work order under s. 440.107(7) to any corporation who employs a person who claims to be exempt as a corporate officer but who fails or refuses to produce the documents required under this subsection to the department within 3 business days after the request is made.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certificates of election to be exempt issued under subsection (3) shall apply only to the corporate officer named on the notice of election to be exempt and apply only within the scope of the business or trade listed on the notice of election to be exempt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notices of election to be exempt and certificates of election to be exempt shall be subject to revocation if, at any time after the filing of the notice or the issuance of the certificate, the person named on the notice or certificate no longer meets the requirements of this section for issuance of a certificate. The department shall revoke a certificate at any time for failure of the person named on the certificate to meet the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer of a corporation who elects exemption from this chapter by filing a certificate of election under this section may not recover benefits or compensation under this chapter. For purposes of determining the appropriate premium for workers’ compensation coverage, carriers may not consider any officer of a corporation who validly meets the requirements of this section to be an employee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporate officer who is an affiliated person of a person who is delinquent in paying a stop-work order and penalty assessment order issued pursuant to s. 440.107, or owed pursuant to a court order, is ineligible for an election of exemption. The stop-work order and penalty assessment shall be in effect against any such affiliated person. As used in this subsection, the term “affiliated person” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The spouse of such other person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who directly or indirectly owns or controls, or holds with the power to vote, 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of such other person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who directly or indirectly owns 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities that are directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with the power to vote by such other person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or group of persons who directly or indirectly control, are controlled by, or are under common control with such other person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who directly or indirectly acquires all or substantially all of the other assets of such other person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer, director, trustee, partner, owner, manager, joint venturer, or employee of such other person or a person performing duties similar to persons in such positions; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has an officer, director, trustee, partner, or joint venturer in common with such person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 17481, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 5966(5); ss. 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 70-148; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 3, ch. 74-197; s. 2, ch. 75-209; s. 23, ch. 78-300; s. 124, ch. 79-40; s. 21, ch. 79-312; s. 43, ch. 89-289; s. 56, ch. 90-201; s. 52, ch. 91-1; s. 2, ch. 91-2; s. 3, ch. 93-415; s. 99, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 98-125; s. 2, ch. 98-174; s. 40, ch. 99-240; s. 13, ch. 2002-194; s. 6, ch. 2002-236; s. 468, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2003-412; s. 74, ch. 2005-2; s. 52, ch. 2006-1; ss. 3, 4, ch. 2012-213.</History>
</Section>