<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0213.67" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Garnishment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person is delinquent in the payment of any taxes, penalties, and interest owed to the department, the executive director or his or her designee may give notice of the amount of such delinquency by registered mail, by personal service, or by electronic means, including, but not limited to, facsimile transmissions, electronic data interchange, or use of the Internet, to all persons having in their possession or under their control any credits or personal property, exclusive of wages, belonging to the delinquent taxpayer, or owing any debts to such delinquent taxpayer at the time of receipt by them of such notice. Thereafter, any person who has been notified may not transfer or make any other disposition of such credits, other personal property, or debts until the executive director or his or her designee consents to a transfer or disposition or until 60 days after the receipt of such notice. However, the credits, other personal property, or debts that exceed the delinquent amount stipulated in the notice are not subject to this section, wherever held, if the taxpayer does not have a prior history of tax delinquencies. If during the effective period of the notice to withhold, any person so notified makes any transfer or disposition of the property or debts required to be withheld under this section, he or she is liable to the state for any indebtedness owed to the department by the person with respect to whose obligation the notice was given to the extent of the value of the property or the amount of the debts thus transferred or paid if, solely by reason of such transfer or disposition, the state is unable to recover the indebtedness of the person with respect to whose obligation the notice was given. If the delinquent taxpayer contests the intended levy in circuit court or under chapter 120, the notice under this section remains effective until that final resolution of the contest. Any financial institution receiving such notice will maintain a right of setoff for any transaction involving a debit card occurring on or before the date of receipt of such notice.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons who have been notified must, within 5 days after receipt of the notice, advise the executive director or his or her designee of the credits, other personal property, or debts in their possession, under their control, or owing them, and must advise the executive director or designee within 5 days after coming into possession or control of any subsequent credits, personal property, or debts owed during the time prescribed by the notice. Any such person coming into possession or control of such subsequent credits, personal property, or debts may not transfer or dispose of them during the time prescribed by the notice or before the department consents to a transfer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the last 30 days of the 60-day period set forth in subsection (1), the executive director or his or her designee may levy upon such credits, other personal property, or debts. The levy must be accomplished by delivery of a notice of levy by registered mail, upon receipt of which the person possessing the credits, other personal property, or debts shall transfer them to the department or pay to the department the amount owed to the delinquent taxpayer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notice that is delivered under this section is effective at the time of delivery against all credits, other personal property, or debts of the delinquent taxpayer which are not at the time of such notice subject to an attachment, garnishment, or execution issued through a judicial process.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person acting in accordance with the terms of the notice or levy issued by the executive director or his or her designee is expressly discharged from any obligation or liability to the delinquent taxpayer with respect to such credits, other personal property, or debts of the delinquent taxpayer affected by compliance with the notice of freeze or levy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Levy may be made under subsection (3) upon credits, other personal property, or debt of any person with respect to any unpaid tax, penalties, and interest only after the executive director or his or her designee has notified such person in writing of the intention to make such levy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No less than 30 days before the day of the levy, the notice of intent to levy required under paragraph (a) shall be given in person or sent by certified or registered mail to the person’s last known address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice required in paragraph (a) must include a brief statement that sets forth in simple and nontechnical terms:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section relating to levy and sale of property;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedures applicable to the levy under this section;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative and judicial appeals available to the taxpayer with respect to such levy and sale, and the procedures relating to such appeals; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The alternatives, if any, available to taxpayers which could prevent levy on the property.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A taxpayer may contest the notice of intent to levy provided for under subsection (6) by filing an action in circuit court. Alternatively, the taxpayer may file a petition under the applicable provisions of chapter 120. After an action has been initiated under chapter 120 to contest the notice of intent to levy, an action relating to the same levy may not be filed by the taxpayer in circuit court, and judicial review is exclusively limited to appellate review pursuant to s. 120.68. Also, after an action has been initiated in circuit court, an action may not be brought under chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action may not be brought to contest a notice of intent to levy under chapter 120 or in circuit court, later than 21 days after the date of receipt of the notice of intent to levy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide notice to the Chief Financial Officer, in electronic or other form specified by the Chief Financial Officer, listing the taxpayers for which tax warrants are outstanding. Pursuant to subsection (1), the Chief Financial Officer shall, upon notice from the department, withhold all payments to any person or business, as defined in s. 212.02, which provides commodities or services to the state, leases real property to the state, or constructs a public building or public work for the state. The department may levy upon the withheld payments in accordance with subsection (3). The provisions of s. 215.422 do not apply from the date the notice is filed with the Chief Financial Officer until the date the department notifies the Chief Financial Officer of its consent to make payment to the person or 60 days after receipt of the department’s notice in accordance with subsection (1), whichever occurs earlier.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may bring an action in circuit court for an order compelling compliance with any notice issued under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 92-320; s. 1, ch. 94-82; s. 1505, ch. 95-147; s. 19, ch. 98-342; s. 27, ch. 99-208; s. 192, ch. 2003-261; s. 14, ch. 2010-138; s. 8, ch. 2011-4.</History>
</Section>