<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0213.732" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jeopardy findings and assessments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall generally exhaust reasonable collection efforts prior to making a jeopardy finding or assessment; however, if the exhaustion of collection efforts would create or prolong the jeopardy, the department need not exhaust collection efforts or may exhaust only those efforts consistent with the jeopardy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue to the taxpayer, with any jeopardy assessment, a notice or finding of the facts which constitute a jeopardy to the revenue. A warrant, lien, or other detainer of property may be issued and recorded as provided by law simultaneously with the issuance of a jeopardy assessment. Such warrant, lien, or detainer may proceed to execution, levy, and seizure as provided by law. However, the department shall not hold an execution sale or other sale of the property without order of a court of competent jurisdiction until the expiration of the time provided in s. 72.011 for filing an action in circuit court or petition for administrative proceeding or, if such an action or petition is filed, until the decision rendered in such action or proceeding is final.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall also notify the taxpayer that the taxpayer shall have the opportunity to appear at a conference within 10 days and make an oral or written statement of why he or she believes no jeopardy to the revenue exists or why a jeopardy lien or warrant should be released, if one was recorded. Upon request of the taxpayer, the department shall meet with the taxpayer at a time set by the department within 10 days after the issuance of the assessment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conference shall be conducted informally and shall not be in the nature of a formal evidentiary proceeding. The taxpayer may present relevant information, orally or in writing; however, discovery and cross-examination shall not be allowed. The department shall not be required to transcribe the proceedings, but the taxpayer may transcribe the proceedings at the taxpayer’s cost.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the taxpayer makes a statement under subsection (3), the department shall determine within 20 days after its receipt of such statement whether such jeopardy lien, warrant, or other detainer should be released. The department shall send written notice of such finding to the taxpayer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that the jeopardy lien, warrant, or other detainer should be released, the department shall release the subject property within a reasonable time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department proceeds to seize or freeze the assets of a taxpayer upon a determination of jeopardy, the taxpayer shall have a right to a meeting with the department, as provided by subsection (3), immediately or within 24 hours after requesting such meeting. The department shall, within 24 hours after such meeting, determine whether to release the seizure or freeze. If the department does not release such seizure or freeze of property, the taxpayer shall have a right to request a hearing within 5 days before the circuit court, at which hearing the taxpayer and the department may present evidence with respect to the issue of jeopardy. Venue in such an action shall lie in the county in which the seizure was effected or, if there are multiple seizures based upon the same assessment, venue shall also lie in Leon County. Whenever an action is filed to seek review of a jeopardy finding under this subsection, the court shall set an immediate hearing and shall give the case priority over other pending cases other than those filed pursuant to s. 119.11.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 92-315; s. 1133, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>