<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0213.0535" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration Information Sharing and Exchange Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Registration Information Sharing and Exchange Program, or “RISE,” is established and shall be coordinated by the Department of Revenue. Periodically, each participant in the program shall share the tax administration information specified in this section in the format prescribed by the department. To the fullest extent practicable, the information <Reference Number="1" />shall be shared in a computer-processable medium.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information that is subject to sharing includes the registrant’s, licensee’s, or taxpayer’s name, mailing address, business location, and federal employer identification number or social security number; any applicable business type code; any applicable county code; and such other tax registration information as the department prescribes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local government that participates in the program is responsible for transmitting its shared data to participating state agencies. Each state agency participating in the program is responsible for transmitting its shared data to the other participating state agencies and to the appropriate participating local governments. Data shall be transmitted within 20 days after the close of the reporting period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are two levels of participation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each unit of state or local government responsible for administering one or more of the provisions specified in subparagraphs 1.-8. is a level-one participant. Level-one participants shall exchange, monthly or quarterly, as determined jointly by each participant and the department, the data enumerated in subsection (2) for each new registrant, new filer, or initial reporter, permittee, or licensee, with respect to the following taxes, licenses, or permits:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sales and use tax imposed under chapter 212.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist development tax imposed under s. 125.0104.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist impact tax imposed under s. 125.0108.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local business taxes imposed under chapter 205.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convention development taxes imposed under s. 212.0305.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lodging and food service establishment licenses issued pursuant to chapter 509.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beverage law licenses issued pursuant to chapter 561.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipal resort tax as authorized under chapter 67-930, Laws of Florida.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Level-two participants include the Department of Revenue and local officials responsible for collecting the tourist development tax pursuant to s. 125.0104, the tourist impact tax pursuant to s. 125.0108, or a convention development tax pursuant to s. 212.0305, or a municipal resort tax as authorized under chapter 67-930, Laws of Florida. Level-two participants shall, in addition to the data shared by level-one participants, exchange data relating to tax payment history, audit assessments, and registration cancellations of dealers engaging in transient rentals, and such data may relate only to sales and use taxes, tourist development taxes, convention development taxes, and municipal resort tax. The department shall prescribe, by rule, the data elements to be shared and the frequency of sharing; however, audit assessments must be shared at least quarterly.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A level-two participant may disclose information as provided in paragraph (b) in response to a request for such information from any other level-two participant. Information relative to specific taxpayers shall be requested or disclosed under this paragraph only to the extent necessary in the administration of a tax or licensing provision as enumerated in paragraph (a). When a disclosure made under this paragraph involves confidential information provided to the participant by the Department of Revenue, the participant who provides the information shall maintain records of the disclosures, which records shall be subject to review by the Department of Revenue for a period of 5 years after the date of the disclosure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision of law imposing confidentiality upon data shared under this section, including, but not limited to, any provision imposing penalties for disclosure, applies to recipients of this data and their employees. Data exchanged under this section may not be provided to any person or entity other than a person or entity administering the tax or licensing provisions of those provisions of law enumerated in paragraph (4)(a), and such data may not be used for any purpose other than for enforcing those tax or licensing provisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to data on new registrants, the information shared by level-one participants in the first month of the program shall include data for all active registrants, taxpayers, licensees, or permittees under the provisions of law enumerated in paragraph (4)(a).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 92-319; s. 31, ch. 92-320; s. 1, ch. 95-362; s. 64, ch. 96-406; s. 16, ch. 98-342; s. 32, ch. 2002-218; s. 35, ch. 2003-254; s. 20, ch. 2007-5.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amendment to this section by s. 32, ch. 92-319, uses the word “must.”</Text></Note></Section>