<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0213.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracts with county tax collectors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may enter into contracts with county tax collectors for the purpose of collecting delinquent taxes, penalties, and interest, including taxes for which the department has generated a bill or notice. The department shall execute a contract with the tax collector in the manner provided in chapter 287. Before commencing litigation to recover a delinquent tax, penalty, or interest, the tax collector must provide the taxpayer, or the taxpayer’s authorized representative, with at least 30 days’ notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Revenue shall determine, and the contract must provide, the manner in which the tax collector shall be compensated for collection services. The department may add the tax collector’s compensation to the amount of the delinquent tax, penalty, or interest, and the tax collector shall collect that amount as a part of the delinquent tax, or the department may deduct the tax collector’s compensation from the amount of the delinquent tax, penalty, or interest which is collected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax collector shall remit to the department all funds collected, less the amount of compensation provided for in the contract, within 7 business days after the end of the week in which the delinquent tax, penalty, or interest is collected. The tax collector shall remit funds to the department by electronic transfer and use the forms prescribed by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As provided in s. 195.084, the department may share confidential information with the tax collector for the purpose of collecting delinquent taxes, penalties, and interest, including taxes for which the department has generated a bill or notice. The tax collector is bound by the same requirements of confidentiality as the Department of Revenue with respect to confidential information. A breach of confidentiality is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 96-299.</History></Section>