<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0513.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not establish or maintain a mobile home park, lodging park, recreational vehicle park, or recreational camp in this state without first obtaining a permit from the department. Such permit is not transferable from one place or person to another. Each permit must be renewed annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse a permit to, or refuse to renew the permit of, any park or camp that is not constructed or maintained in accordance with law and with the rules of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may suspend or revoke a permit issued to any person that operates or maintains such a park or camp if such person fails to comply with this chapter or the rules adopted by the department under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit for the operation of a park or camp may not be renewed or transferred if the permittee has an outstanding fine assessed pursuant to this chapter which is in final-order status and judicial reviews are exhausted, unless the transferee agrees to assume the outstanding fine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a park or camp regulated under this chapter is sold or its ownership transferred, the transferee must apply for a permit to the department before the date of transfer. The applicant must provide the department with a copy of the recorded deed or lease agreement before the department may issue a permit to the applicant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 12419, 1927; CGL 4141; s. 1, ch. 19365, 1939; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 439, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 14, 15, ch. 83-321; s. 7, ch. 84-182; ss. 4, 26, ch. 93-150.</History></Section>