<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0513.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recreational vehicle parks; eviction; grounds; proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator of any recreational vehicle park may remove or cause to be removed from such park, in the manner provided in this section, any transient guest of the park who, while on the premises of the park, illegally possesses or deals in a controlled substance as defined in chapter 893 or disturbs the peace and comfort of other persons; who causes harm to the physical park; or who fails to make payment of rent at the rental rate agreed upon and by the time agreed upon. The admission of a person to, or the removal of a person from, any recreational vehicle park shall not be based upon race, color, national origin, sex, physical disability, or creed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator of any recreational vehicle park shall notify such guest that the park no longer desires to entertain the guest and shall request that such guest immediately depart from the park. Such notice shall be given in writing. If such guest has paid in advance, the park shall, at the time such notice is given, tender to the guest the unused portion of the advance payment. Any guest who remains or attempts to remain in such park after being requested to leave is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a guest has accumulated an outstanding account in excess of an amount equivalent to three nights’ rent at a recreational vehicle park, the operator may disconnect all utilities of the recreational vehicle and notify the guest that the action is for the purpose of requiring the guest to confront the operator or permittee and arrange for the payment of the guest’s account. Such arrangement must be in writing, and a copy shall be furnished to the guest. Upon entering into such agreement, the operator shall reconnect the utilities of the recreational vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person is illegally on the premises of any recreational vehicle park, the operator of such park may call upon any law enforcement officer of this state for assistance. It is the duty of such law enforcement officer, upon the request of such operator, to place under arrest and take into custody for violation of this section any guest who violates subsection (1) or subsection (2) in the presence of the officer. If a warrant has been issued by the proper judicial officer for the arrest of any violator of subsection (1) or subsection (2), the officer shall serve the warrant, arrest the person, and take the person into custody. Upon arrest, with or without warrant, the guest is deemed to have given up any right to occupancy or to have abandoned the guest’s right to occupancy of the premises of the recreational vehicle park; and the operator of the park shall employ all reasonable and proper means to care for any personal property left on the premises by such guest and shall refund any unused portion of moneys paid by such guest for the occupancy of such premises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the grounds for eviction established by law, grounds for eviction may be established in a written lease agreement between a recreational vehicle park operator or permittee and a recreational vehicle park occupant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 15, ch. 83-321; s. 12, ch. 84-182; s. 93, ch. 85-81; s. 132, ch. 91-224; ss. 24, 26, ch. 93-150.</History></Section>