<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0600.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Declaration of state policy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act is passed:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the exercise of the police power of this state to promote and protect the public health, peace, safety, and general welfare, and to stabilize and protect the citrus fruit industry of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the citrus fruit crop grown in Florida comprises the major agricultural crop of Florida and the marketing thereof is affected with a public interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because it is hereby found and declared that, because of the increased and ever-increasing production of citrus fruit in Florida and elsewhere, except in years of freezes or other emergencies that substantially reduce the total crop, the marketing of citrus fruit grown in Florida in excess of reasonable and normal market demands therefor, disorderly marketing of such citrus fruit, unfair methods of competition in the marketing of such citrus fruit, and the inherent inability of individual producers to develop new and larger markets for Florida grown citrus fruit result in an unreasonable and unnecessary economic waste of the agricultural wealth of this state. Such conditions and the accompanying waste jeopardize the future continued production of quality citrus fruit for the people of this and other states and areas, prevent citrus fruit producers from obtaining a fair return from their labor and the citrus fruit which they produce, and impair the economic value of their citrus fruit groves. As a consequence, the purchasing power of such producers has been in the past, and in all likelihood will continue to be in the future, unless such conditions are remedied, low in relation to that of persons engaged in other gainful occupations within this state. Citrus fruit producers are thereby prevented from maintaining a proper and reasonable standard of living and from contributing their fair share to the support of the necessary governmental and educational functions, thus tending to unfairly increase the tax burdens of other citizens of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the conditions hereinbefore described and set forth vitally concern the health, peace, safety, and general welfare of the people of this state, it is hereby declared to be the policy of this state to aid citrus fruit producers and handlers in preventing economic waste in the production and marketing of their citrus fruit, to develop more efficient and equitable methods in the marketing of citrus fruit, and to aid citrus fruit producers and handlers in restoring and maintaining their purchasing power at a more adequate, equitable, and reasonable level.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-88; s. 44, ch. 83-334.</History></Section>