<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0537.016" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subpoenas; enforcement actions; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may issue and serve subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents, papers, books, records, and other evidence before the office in any matter pertaining to this act. The office may administer oaths and affirmations to any person whose testimony is required. If any person refuses to testify; produce books, records, and documents; or otherwise refuses to obey a subpoena issued under this section, the office may enforce the subpoena in the same manner as subpoenas issued under the Administrative Procedure Act are enforced. Witnesses are entitled to the same fees and mileage as they are entitled to by law for attending as witnesses in the circuit court, unless such examination or investigation is held at the place of business or residence of the witness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other powers conferred upon the office to enforce or administer this act, the office may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce or administer this act, any rule or order adopted under this act, or any written agreement entered into with the office. In such action, the office may seek any relief at law or equity, including a temporary or permanent injunction, appointment of a receiver or administrator, or an order of restitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and serve upon a person an order requiring such person to cease and desist and take corrective action whenever the office finds that such person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this act, any rule or order adopted under this act, or any written agreement entered into with the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the office finds that conduct described in paragraph (b) presents an immediate danger to the public health, safety, or welfare requiring an immediate final order, the office may issue an emergency cease and desist order reciting with particularity the facts underlying such findings. The emergency cease and desist order is effective immediately upon service of a copy of the order on the respondent named in the order and shall remain effective for 90 days. If the office begins nonemergency proceedings under paragraph (b), the emergency cease and desist order remains effective until the conclusion of the proceedings under ss. 120.569 and 120.57.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to administer this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2000-138; s. 648, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>