<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0537.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right to reclaim; lost title loan agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person presenting identification of such person as the borrower and presenting the borrower’s copy of the title loan agreement to the title loan lender is presumed to be entitled to reclaim the loan property described in the title loan agreement. However, if the title loan lender determines that the person is not the borrower, the title loan lender is not required to allow the redemption of the loan property by such person. The person reclaiming the loan property must sign the borrower’s copy of the title loan agreement which the title loan lender may retain to evidence such person’s receipt of the loan property. A person reclaiming the loan property who is not the borrower must show identification to the title loan lender, together with notarized written authorization from the borrower, and the title loan lender shall record that person’s name and address on the title loan agreement retained by the title loan lender. In such case, the person reclaiming the borrower’s copy of the title loan agreement shall be provided a copy of such signed form as evidence of such agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the borrower’s copy of the title loan agreement is lost, destroyed, or stolen, the borrower must notify the title loan lender, in writing by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, or in person evidenced by a signed receipt, and receipt of such notice shall invalidate such title loan agreement if the loan property has not previously been reclaimed. Before delivering the loan property or issuing a new title loan agreement, the title loan lender shall require the borrower to make a written statement of the loss, destruction, or theft of the borrower’s copy of the title loan agreement. The title loan lender shall record on the written statement the type of identification and the identification number accepted from the borrower, the date the statement is given, and the number or date of the title loan agreement lost, destroyed, or stolen. The statement shall be signed by the title loan lender or the title loan office employee who accepts the statement from the borrower. The title loan lender shall not impose any type of fee for providing the borrower with a copy of the title loan agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2000-138.</History></Section>