<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0537.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required; license fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not act as a title loan lender or own or operate a title loan office unless such person has an active title loan lender license issued by the office under this act. A title loan lender may not own or operate more than one title loan office unless the lender obtains a separate title loan lender license for each title loan office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person applying for licensure as a title loan lender shall file with the office an application, the bond required by s. 537.005(3), a nonrefundable application fee of $1,200, a nonrefundable investigation fee of $200, and a complete set of fingerprints taken by an authorized law enforcement officer. The office shall submit such fingerprints to the Department of Law Enforcement for state processing, and the Department of Law Enforcement shall forward the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for national processing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office determines that an application should be approved, the office shall issue a license for a period not to exceed 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license shall be renewed biennially by filing a renewal form and a nonrefundable renewal fee of $1,200. A license that is not renewed by the end of the biennial period shall automatically revert to inactive status. An inactive license may be reactivated within 6 months after becoming inactive by filing a reactivation form, payment of the nonrefundable $1,200 renewal fee, and payment of a nonrefundable reactivation fee of $600. A license that is not reactivated within 6 months after becoming inactive may not be reactivated and shall automatically expire. The commission shall establish by rule the procedures for renewal and reactivation of a license and shall adopt a renewal form and a reactivation form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license must be conspicuously displayed at the title loan office. When a licensee wishes to move a title loan office to another location, the licensee shall provide prior written notice to the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued pursuant to this act is not transferable or assignable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee shall designate and maintain a registered agent in this state for service of process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person or a group of persons, directly or indirectly or acting by or through one or more persons, proposes to purchase or acquire a 50 percent or more interest in a licensee, such person or group shall submit an initial application for licensure under this act prior to such purchase or acquisition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to allow for electronic filing of applications, fees, and forms required by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by the office under this act shall be deposited into the Regulatory Trust Fund of the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2000-138; s. 641, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>