<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0537.009" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recordkeeping; reporting; safekeeping of property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every title loan lender shall maintain, at the lender’s title loan office, such books, accounts, and records of the business conducted under the license issued for such place of business as will enable the office to determine the licensee’s compliance with this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may authorize the maintenance of books, accounts, and records at a location other than the lender’s title loan office. The office may require books, accounts, and records to be produced and available at a reasonable and convenient location in this state within a reasonable period of time after such a request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title loan lender shall maintain the original copy of each completed title loan agreement on the title loan office premises, and shall not obliterate, discard, or destroy any such original copy, for a period of at least 2 years after making the final entry on any loan recorded in such office or after an examination by the Office of Financial Regulation, whichever is later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loan property which is delivered to a title loan lender shall be securely stored and maintained at the title loan office unless the loan property has been forwarded to the appropriate state agency for the purpose of having a lien recorded or deleted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may prescribe by rule the books, accounts, documents, and records, and the minimum information to be shown in the books, accounts, documents, and records, of licensees so that such records will enable the office to determine compliance with the provisions of this act. In addition, the commission may prescribe by rule requirements for the destruction of books, accounts, records, and documents retained by the licensee after completion of the time period specified in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2000-138; s. 645, ch. 2003-261; s. 51, ch. 2006-213.</History></Section>