<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0166.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Charter amendments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a municipality may, by ordinance, or the electors of a municipality may, by petition signed by 10 percent of the registered electors as of the last preceding municipal general election, submit to the electors of said municipality a proposed amendment to its charter, which amendment may be to any part or to all of said charter except that part describing the boundaries of such municipality. The governing body of the municipality shall place the proposed amendment contained in the ordinance or petition to a vote of the electors at the next general election held within the municipality or at a special election called for such purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon adoption of an amendment to the charter of a municipality by a majority of the electors voting in a referendum upon such amendment, the governing body of said municipality shall have the amendment incorporated into the charter and shall file the revised charter with the Department of State. All such amendments are effective on the date specified therein or as otherwise provided in the charter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality may amend its charter pursuant to this section notwithstanding any charter provisions to the contrary. This section shall be supplemental to the provisions of all other laws relating to the amendment of municipal charters and is not intended to diminish any substantive or procedural power vested in any municipality by present law. A municipality may, by ordinance and without referendum, redefine its boundaries to include only those lands previously annexed and shall file said redefinition with the Department of State pursuant to the provisions of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no restrictions by the municipality on any employee’s or employee group’s political activity, while not working, in any referendum changing employee rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality may, by unanimous vote of the governing body, abolish municipal departments provided for in the municipal charter and amend provisions or language out of the charter which has been judicially construed, either by judgment or by binding legal precedent from a decision of a court of last resort, to be contrary to either the State Constitution or Federal Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each municipality shall, by ordinance or charter provision, provide procedures for filling a vacancy in office caused by death, resignation, or removal from office. Such ordinance or charter provision shall also provide procedures for filling a vacancy in candidacy caused by death, withdrawal, or removal from the ballot of a qualified candidate following the end of the qualifying period which leaves fewer than two candidates for an office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-129; s. 1, ch. 86-95; s. 1, ch. 90-106; s. 43, ch. 90-315; s. 45, ch. 94-136.</History></Section>