<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0166.043" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ordinances and rules imposing price controls; findings required; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as hereinafter provided, no county, municipality, or other entity of local government shall adopt or maintain in effect an ordinance or a rule which has the effect of imposing price controls upon a lawful business activity which is not franchised by, owned by, or under contract with, the governmental agency, unless specifically provided by general law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not prevent the enactment by local governments of public service rates otherwise authorized by law, including water, sewer, solid waste, public transportation, taxicab, or port rates, rates for towing of vehicles from or immobilization of vehicles on private property, or rates for removal and storage of wrecked or disabled vehicles from an accident scene or the removal and storage of vehicles in the event the owner or operator is incapacitated, unavailable, leaves the procurement of wrecker service to the law enforcement officer at the scene, or otherwise does not consent to the removal of the vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties must establish maximum rates which may be charged on the towing of vehicles from or immobilization of vehicles on private property, removal and storage of wrecked or disabled vehicles from an accident scene or for the removal and storage of vehicles, in the event the owner or operator is incapacitated, unavailable, leaves the procurement of wrecker service to the law enforcement officer at the scene, or otherwise does not consent to the removal of the vehicle. However, if a municipality chooses to enact an ordinance establishing the maximum fees for the towing or immobilization of vehicles as described in paragraph (b), the county’s ordinance established under s. 125.0103 shall not apply within such municipality.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No law, ordinance, rule, or other measure which would have the effect of imposing controls on rents shall be adopted or maintained in effect except as provided herein and unless it is found and determined, as hereinafter provided, that such controls are necessary and proper to eliminate an existing housing emergency which is so grave as to constitute a serious menace to the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law, ordinance, rule, or other measure which has the effect of imposing controls on rents shall terminate and expire within 1 year and shall not be extended or renewed except by the adoption of a new measure meeting all the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, no controls shall be imposed on rents for any accommodation used or offered for residential purposes as a seasonal or tourist unit, as a second housing unit, or on rents for dwelling units located in luxury apartment buildings. For the purposes of this section, a luxury apartment building is one wherein on January 1, 1977, the aggregate rent due on a monthly basis from all dwelling units as stated in leases or rent lists existing on that date divided by the number of dwelling units exceeds $250.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No municipality, county, or other entity of local government shall adopt or maintain in effect any law, ordinance, rule, or other measure which would have the effect of imposing controls on rents unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such measure is duly adopted by the governing body of such entity of local government, after notice and public hearing, in accordance with all applicable provisions of the Florida and United States Constitutions, the charter or charters governing such entity of local government, this section, and any other applicable laws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such governing body makes and recites in such measure its findings establishing the existence in fact of a housing emergency so grave as to constitute a serious menace to the general public and that such controls are necessary and proper to eliminate such grave housing emergency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such measure is approved by the voters in such municipality, county, or other entity of local government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any court action brought to challenge the validity of rent control imposed pursuant to the provisions of this section, the evidentiary effect of any findings or recitations required by subsection (5) shall be limited to imposing upon any party challenging the validity of such measure the burden of going forward with the evidence, and the burden of proof (that is, the risk of nonpersuasion) shall rest upon any party seeking to have the measure upheld.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, municipalities, counties, or other entity of local government may adopt and maintain in effect any law, ordinance, rule, or other measure which is adopted for the purposes of increasing the supply of affordable housing using land use mechanisms such as inclusionary housing ordinances.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 77-50; s. 82, ch. 79-400; s. 2, ch. 88-240; s. 3, ch. 90-283; s. 53, ch. 97-300; s. 5, ch. 98-324; s. 9, ch. 99-360; s. 34, ch. 2001-201.</History></Section>