<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0166.0497" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alteration, amendment, or expansion of established downtown development district; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the governing body of a municipality that has created a downtown development district pursuant to chapter 65-1090, Laws of Florida, determines that it is necessary to alter, amend, or expand the boundaries of the established district by the inclusion of additional territory or the exclusion of lands from the limits of the established district, in order to revitalize and preserve property values or to prevent deterioration in the original district or its surrounding areas, it shall, by resolution, declare its intention to do so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the resolution of intent, the governing body shall set a date for a public hearing on adoption of an ordinance altering, amending, or expanding the district and describing the new proposed district. Upon the adoption of the resolution, the governing body shall cause a notice of the public hearing to be published in a newspaper of general circulation published in the municipality, which notice shall be published one time not less than 30 nor more than 60 days prior to the date of the hearing. The notice shall set forth the date, time, and place of the hearing and shall describe the new proposed boundaries of the district. Any citizen, taxpayer, or property owner shall have the right to be heard in opposition to the proposed amendment or expansion of the district. After the public hearing, if the governing body intends to proceed with the amendment or expansion of the district, it shall, in the manner authorized by law, adopt an ordinance defining the new district. The governing body shall not incorporate land into the district not included in the description contained in the resolution and the notice of public hearing, but it may eliminate any lands from that description when it adopts the ordinance containing the final determination of the boundaries.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 99-208.</History></Section>