<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0374.986" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Taxing authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax assessor, tax collector, and board of county commissioners of each and every county in said district, shall, when requested by the board, prepare from their official records and deliver any and all information that may be from time to time requested from him or her or them or either of them by the board regarding the tax valuation, assessments, collection, and any other information regarding the levy, assessment, and collection of taxes in each of said counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may annually assess and levy against the taxable property in the district a tax not to exceed one-tenth mill on the dollar for each year, and the proceeds from such tax shall be used by the district for all expenses of the district including the purchase price of right-of-way and other property. The board shall, on or before the 31st day of July of each year, prepare a tentative annual written budget of the district’s expected income and expenditures. In addition, the board shall compute a proposed millage rate to be levied as taxes for that year upon the taxable property in the district for the purposes of said district. The proposed budget shall be submitted to the Department of Environmental Protection for its approval. Prior to adopting a final budget, the district shall comply with the provisions of s. 200.065, relating to the method of fixing millage, and shall fix the final millage rate by resolution of the district and shall also, by resolution, adopt a final budget pursuant to chapter 200. Copies of such resolutions executed in the name of the board by its chair, and attested by its secretary, shall be made and delivered to the county officials specified in s. 200.065 of each and every county in the district, to the Department of Revenue, and to the Chief Financial Officer. Thereupon, it shall be the duty of the property assessor of each of said counties to assess, and the tax collector of each of said counties to collect, a tax at the rate fixed by said resolution of the board upon all of the real and personal taxable property in said counties for said year (and such officers shall perform such duty) and said levy shall be included in the warrant of the tax assessors of each of said counties and attached to the assessment roll of taxes for each of said counties. The tax collectors of each of said counties shall collect such taxes so levied by the board in the same manner as other taxes are collected, and shall pay the same within the time and in the manner prescribed by law, to the treasurer of the board. It shall be the duty of the Chief Financial Officer to assess and levy on all railroad lines and railroad property and telegraph lines and telegraph property in the district a tax at the rate prescribed by resolution of the board, and to collect the tax thereon in the same manner as he or she is required by law to assess and collect taxes for state and county purposes and to remit the same to the treasurer of the board. All such taxes shall be held by the treasurer of the district for the credit of the district and paid out by him or her as provided herein. The tax assessor and property appraiser of each of said counties shall be entitled to payment as provided for by general laws.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 96-425; s. 47, ch. 97-96; s. 388, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>