<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0104.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remuneration by candidate for services, support, etc.; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person supporting a candidate, or for any candidate, in order to aid or promote the nomination or election of such candidate in any election, directly or indirectly to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promise to appoint another person, promise to secure or aid in securing appointment, nomination or election of another person to any public or private position, or to any position of honor, trust, or emolument, except one who has publicly announced or defined what his or her choice or purpose in relation to any election in which he or she may be called to take part, if elected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give, or promise to give, pay, or loan, any money or other thing of value to the owner, editor, publisher, or agent, of any communication media, as well as newspapers, to advocate or oppose, through such media, any candidate for nomination in any election or any candidate for election, and no such owner, editor, or agent shall give, solicit, or accept such payment or reward. It shall likewise be unlawful for any owner, editor, publisher, or agent of any poll-taking or poll-publishing concern to advocate or oppose through such poll any candidate for nomination in any election or any candidate for election in return for the giving or promising to give, pay, or loan any money or other thing of value to said owner, editor, publisher, or agent of any poll-taking or poll-publishing concern.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give, pay, expend, or contribute any money or thing of value for the furtherance of the candidacy of any other candidate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish, give, or deliver to another person any money or other thing of value for any purpose prohibited by the election laws.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This subsection shall not prohibit a candidate from furnishing complimentary tickets to the candidate’s campaign fund raiser to other candidates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A candidate may give his or her own personal or business funds to another candidate, so long as the contribution is not given in exchange for a promise or expectation that the recipient will directly or indirectly do anything to aid or promote the candidacy of the contributor which the recipient would not have otherwise done.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and from and after conviction shall be disqualified to hold office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 2, ch. 65-379; s. 26, ch. 71-136; s. 35, ch. 77-175; s. 52, ch. 79-400; s. 33, ch. 89-338; s. 617, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>