<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0922.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proceedings when person under sentence of death appears to be insane.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the Governor is informed that a person under sentence of death may be insane, the Governor shall stay execution of the sentence and appoint a commission of three psychiatrists to examine the convicted person. The Governor shall notify the psychiatrists in writing that they are to examine the convicted person to determine whether he or she understands the nature and effect of the death penalty and why it is to be imposed upon him or her. The examination of the convicted person shall take place with all three psychiatrists present at the same time. Counsel for the convicted person and the state attorney may be present at the examination. If the convicted person does not have counsel, the court that imposed the sentence shall appoint counsel to represent him or her.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receiving the report of the commission, if the Governor decides that the convicted person has the mental capacity to understand the nature of the death penalty and the reasons why it was imposed upon him or her, the Governor shall immediately lift the stay and notify the Attorney General of such action. Within 10 days after such notification, the Governor must set the new date for execution of the death sentence. When the new date for execution of the death sentence is set by the Governor under this subsection, the Attorney General shall notify the inmate’s counsel of record of the date and time of execution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Governor decides that the convicted person does not have the mental capacity to understand the nature of the death penalty and why it was imposed on him or her, the Governor shall have the convicted person committed to a Department of Corrections mental health treatment facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person under sentence of death has been committed to a Department of Corrections mental health treatment facility, he or she shall be kept there until the facility administrator determines that he or she has been restored to sanity. The facility administrator shall notify the Governor of his or her determination, and the Governor shall appoint another commission to proceed as provided in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall allow reasonable fees to psychiatrists appointed under the provisions of this section which shall be paid by the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 268, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(278); s. 134, ch. 70-339; s. 1, ch. 85-193; s. 3, ch. 96-213; s. 1839, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>