<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1001.65" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida College System institution presidents; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president is the chief executive officer of the Florida College System institution, shall be corporate secretary of the Florida College System institution board of trustees, and is responsible for the operation and administration of the Florida College System institution. Each Florida College System institution president shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend the adoption of rules, as appropriate, to the Florida College System institution board of trustees to implement provisions of law governing the operation and administration of the Florida College System institution, which shall include the specific powers and duties enumerated in this section. Such rules shall be consistent with law, the mission of the Florida College System institution, and the rules and policies of the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare a budget request and an operating budget pursuant to s. 1011.30 for approval by the Florida College System institution board of trustees at such time and in such format as the State Board of Education may prescribe.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and implement policies and procedures to recruit, appoint, transfer, promote, compensate, evaluate, reward, demote, discipline, and remove personnel, within law and rules of the State Board of Education and in accordance with rules or policies approved by the Florida College System institution board of trustees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Govern admissions, subject to law and rules or policies of the Florida College System institution board of trustees and the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve, execute, and administer contracts for and on behalf of the Florida College System institution board of trustees for licenses; the acquisition or provision of commodities, goods, equipment, and services; leases of real and personal property; and planning and construction to be rendered to or by the Florida College System institution, provided such contracts are within law and guidelines of the State Board of Education and in conformance with policies of the Florida College System institution board of trustees, and are for the implementation of approved programs of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act for the Florida College System institution board of trustees as custodian of all Florida College System institution property and financial resources. The authority vested in the Florida College System institution president under this subsection includes the authority to prioritize the use of Florida College System institution space, property, equipment, and resources and the authority to impose charges for the use of those items.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the internal academic calendar of the Florida College System institution within general guidelines of the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the Florida College System institution’s program of intercollegiate athletics.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the board of trustees the establishment and termination of programs within the approved role and scope of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Award degrees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the board of trustees a schedule of tuition and fees to be charged by the Florida College System institution, within law and rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organize the Florida College System institution to efficiently and effectively achieve the goals of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review periodically the operations of the Florida College System institution in order to determine how effectively and efficiently the Florida College System institution is being administered and whether it is meeting the goals of its strategic plan adopted by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements for student exchange programs that involve students at the Florida College System institution and students in other institutions of higher learning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve the internal procedures of student government organizations and provide purchasing, contracting, and budgetary review processes for these organizations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure compliance with federal and state laws, rules, regulations, and other requirements that are applicable to the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain all data and information pertaining to the operation of the Florida College System institution, and report on the attainment by the Florida College System institution of institutional and statewide performance accountability goals.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certify to the department a project’s compliance with the requirements for expenditure of PECO funds prior to release of funds pursuant to the provisions of chapter 1013.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to the law enforcement agency and fire department that has jurisdiction over the Florida College System institution a copy of the floor plans and other relevant documents for each educational facility as defined in s. 1013.01(6). After the initial submission of the floor plans and other relevant documents, the Florida College System institution president shall submit, by October 1 of each year, revised floor plans and other relevant documents for each educational facility that was modified during the preceding year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a committee to consider requests for waivers from the provisions of <Reference Number="1"/>s. 1008.29 and approve or disapprove the committee’s recommendations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement jointly with school superintendents a comprehensive dual enrollment articulation agreement for the students enrolled in their respective school districts and service areas pursuant to s. 1007.271(21).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have authority, after notice to the student of the charges and after a hearing thereon, to expel, suspend, or otherwise discipline any student who is found to have violated any law, ordinance, or rule or regulation of the State Board of Education or of the board of trustees of the Florida College System institution pursuant to the provisions of s. 1006.62.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit an annual employment accountability plan to the Department of Education pursuant to the provisions of s. 1012.86.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually evaluate, or have a designee annually evaluate, each department chairperson, dean, provost, and vice president in achieving the annual and long-term goals and objectives of the Florida College System institution’s employment accountability plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have vested with the president or the president’s designee the authority that is vested with the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 81, ch. 2002-387; s. 22, ch. 2011-5; s. 3, ch. 2012-191.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 21, ch. 2009-59.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>