<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1001.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specific powers and duties of the Department of Education.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to all other duties assigned to it by law or by rule of the State Board of Education, the department shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt the statewide kindergarten screening in accordance with s. 1002.69.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implement a training program to develop among state and district educators a cadre of facilitators of school improvement in accordance with the provisions of chapter 1008.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the needs of the state system of public education as they relate to the development and production of materials used in instruction, in accordance with the requirements of chapter 1006.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After complying with the provisions of s. 257.37, the Department of Education may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photograph, microphotograph, or reproduce on film or prints, documents, records, data, and information of a permanent character and destroy any of the documents after they have been photographed and after audit of the department has been completed for the period embracing the dates of the instruments. Photographs or microphotographs in the form of film or prints made in compliance with the provisions of this subsection shall have the same force and effect as the originals would have, and shall be treated as originals for the purpose of their admissibility in evidence. Duly certified or authenticated reproductions of such photographs or microphotographs shall be admitted in evidence equally with the original photographs or microphotographs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Destroy general correspondence that is over 3 years old; records of bills, accounts, vouchers, and requisitions that are over 5 years old and copies of which have been filed with the Chief Financial Officer; and other records, papers, and documents over 3 years old that do not serve as part of an agreement or understanding and do not have value as permanent records.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 2002-387; s. 1943, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2004-484.</History></Section>