<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1001.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida College System institution boards of trustees; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boards of trustees shall be responsible for cost-effective policy decisions appropriate to the Florida College System institution’s mission, the implementation and maintenance of high-quality education programs within law and rules of the State Board of Education, the measurement of performance, the reporting of information, and the provision of input regarding state policy, budgeting, and education standards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is vested with the responsibility to govern its respective Florida College System institution and with such necessary authority as is needed for the proper operation and improvement thereof in accordance with rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of trustees shall have the power to take action without a recommendation from the president and shall have the power to require the president to deliver to the board of trustees all data and information required by the board of trustees in the performance of its duties. A board of trustees shall ask the Commissioner of Education to authorize an investigation of the president’s actions by the department’s inspector general if the board considers such investigation necessary. The inspector general shall provide a report detailing each issue under investigation and shall recommend corrective action. If the inspector general identifies potential legal violations, he or she shall refer the potential legal violations to the Commission on Ethics, the Department of Law Enforcement, the Attorney General, or another appropriate authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees, after considering recommendations submitted by the Florida College System institution president, may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of law conferring duties upon it. These rules may supplement those prescribed by the State Board of Education if they will contribute to the more orderly and efficient operation of Florida College System institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is specifically authorized to adopt rules, procedures, and policies, consistent with law and rules of the State Board of Education, related to its mission and responsibilities as set forth in s. 1004.65, its governance, personnel, budget and finance, administration, programs, curriculum and instruction, buildings and grounds, travel and purchasing, technology, students, contracts and grants, or college property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall have responsibility for the use, maintenance, protection, and control of Florida College System institution owned or Florida College System institution controlled buildings and grounds, property and equipment, name, trademarks and other proprietary marks, and the financial and other resources of the Florida College System institution. Such authority may include placing restrictions on activities and on access to facilities, firearms, food, tobacco, alcoholic beverages, distribution of printed materials, commercial solicitation, animals, and sound.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees has responsibility for the establishment and discontinuance of program and course offerings in accordance with law and rule; provision for instructional and noninstructional community services, location of classes, and services provided; and dissemination of information concerning such programs and services. New programs must be approved pursuant to s. 1004.03.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees has responsibility for: ensuring that students have access to general education courses as identified in rule; requiring no more than 60 semester hours of degree program coursework, including 36 semester hours of general education coursework, for an associate in arts degree; notifying students that earned hours in excess of 60 semester hours may not be accepted by state universities; notifying students of unique program prerequisites; and ensuring that degree program coursework beyond general education coursework is consistent with degree program prerequisite requirements adopted pursuant to s. 1007.25(5).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees has authority for policies related to students, enrollment of students, student records, student activities, financial assistance, and other student services.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall govern admission of students pursuant to s. 1007.263 and rules of the State Board of Education. A board of trustees may establish additional admissions criteria, which shall be included in the dual enrollment articulation agreement developed according to s. 1007.271(21), to ensure student readiness for postsecondary instruction. Each board of trustees may consider the past actions of any person applying for admission or enrollment and may deny admission or enrollment to an applicant because of misconduct if determined to be in the best interest of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall adopt rules establishing student performance standards for the award of degrees and certificates pursuant to s. 1004.68.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boards of trustees are authorized to establish intrainstitutional and interinstitutional programs to maximize articulation pursuant to s. 1007.22.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boards of trustees shall identify their general education curricula pursuant to s. 1007.25(6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees must adopt a written antihazing policy, provide a program for the enforcement of such rules, and adopt appropriate penalties for violations of such rules pursuant to the provisions of s. 1006.63.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may establish a uniform code of conduct and appropriate penalties for violation of its rules by students and student organizations, including rules governing student academic honesty. Such penalties, unless otherwise provided by law, may include fines, the withholding of diplomas or transcripts pending compliance with rules or payment of fines, and the imposition of probation, suspension, or dismissal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees pursuant to s. 1006.53 shall adopt a policy in accordance with rules of the State Board of Education that reasonably accommodates the religious observance, practice, and belief of individual students in regard to admissions, class attendance, and the scheduling of examinations and work assignments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of trustees may contract with the board of trustees of a state university for the Florida College System institution to provide college-preparatory instruction on the state university campus.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall establish fees pursuant to ss. 1009.22, 1009.23, 1009.25, 1009.26, and 1009.27.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall submit an institutional budget request, including a request for fixed capital outlay, and an operating budget to the State Board of Education for review in accordance with guidelines established by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall account for expenditures of all state, local, federal and other funds in the manner described by the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is responsible for the uses for the proceeds of academic improvement trust funds pursuant to s. 1011.85.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall develop a strategic plan specifying institutional goals and objectives for the Florida College System institution for recommendation to the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall develop an accountability plan pursuant to s. 1008.45.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees must expend performance funds provided for workforce education pursuant to the provisions of s. 1011.80.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is accountable for performance in certificate career education and diploma programs pursuant to s. 1008.43.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall establish the personnel program for all employees of the Florida College System institution, including the president, pursuant to the provisions of chapter 1012 and rules and guidelines of the State Board of Education, including: compensation and other conditions of employment; recruitment and selection; nonreappointment; standards for performance and conduct; evaluation; benefits and hours of work; leave policies; recognition; inventions and work products; travel; learning opportunities; exchange programs; academic freedom and responsibility; promotion; assignment; demotion; transfer; ethical obligations and conflict of interest; restrictive covenants; disciplinary actions; complaints; appeals and grievance procedures; and separation and termination from employment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall appoint, suspend, or remove the president of the Florida College System institution. The board of trustees may appoint a search committee. The board of trustees shall conduct annual evaluations of the president in accordance with rules of the State Board of Education and submit such evaluations to the State Board of Education for review. The evaluation must address the achievement of the performance goals established by the accountability process implemented pursuant to s. 1008.45 and the performance of the president in achieving the annual and long-term goals and objectives established in the Florida College System institution’s employment accountability program implemented pursuant to s. 1012.86.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to enter into contracts to provide a State Community College System Optional Retirement Program pursuant to s. 1012.875 and to enter into consortia with other boards of trustees for this purpose.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to purchase annuities for its Florida College System institution personnel who have 25 or more years of creditable service and who have reached age 55 and have applied for retirement under the Florida Retirement System pursuant to the provisions of s. 1012.87.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of trustees may defray all costs of defending civil actions against officers, employees, or agents of the board of trustees pursuant to s. 1012.85.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees has authority for risk management, safety, security, and law enforcement operations. Each board of trustees is authorized to employ personnel, including police officers pursuant to s. 1012.88, to carry out the duties imposed by this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall provide rules governing parking and the direction and flow of traffic within campus boundaries. Except for sworn law enforcement personnel, persons employed to enforce campus parking rules have no authority to arrest or issue citations for moving traffic violations. The board of trustees may adopt a uniform code of appropriate penalties for violations. Such penalties, unless otherwise provided by law, may include the levying of fines, the withholding of diplomas or transcripts pending compliance with rules or payment of fines, and the imposition of probation, suspension, or dismissal. Moneys collected from parking rule infractions shall be deposited in appropriate funds at each Florida College System institution for student financial aid purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees constitutes the contracting agent of the Florida College System institution. It may when acting as a body make contracts, sue, and be sued in the name of the board of trustees. In any suit, a change in personnel of the board of trustees shall not abate the suit, which shall proceed as if such change had not taken place.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to contract for the purchase, sale, lease, license, or acquisition in any manner, including purchase by installment or lease-purchase contract which may provide for the payment of interest on the unpaid portion of the purchase price and for the granting of a security interest in the items purchased, subject to the provisions of subsection (38) and ss. 1009.22 and 1009.23, of goods, materials, equipment, and services required by the Florida College System institution. The board of trustees may choose to consolidate equipment contracts under master equipment financing agreements made pursuant to s. 287.064.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall be responsible for managing and protecting real and personal property acquired or held in trust for use by and for the benefit of such Florida College System institution. To that end, any board of trustees is authorized to be self-insured, to enter into risk management programs, or to purchase insurance for whatever coverage it may choose, or to have any combination thereof, in anticipation of any loss, damage, or destruction. A board of trustees may contract for self-insurance services pursuant to s. 1004.725.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to enter into agreements for, and accept, credit card, charge card, and debit card payments as compensation for goods, services, tuition, and fees. Each Florida College System institution is further authorized to establish accounts in credit card, charge card, and debit card banks for the deposit of sales invoices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="29">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may provide incubator facilities to eligible small business concerns pursuant to s. 1004.79.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="30">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may establish a technology transfer center for the purpose of providing institutional support to local business and industry and governmental agencies in the application of new research in technology pursuant to the provisions of s. 1004.78.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="31">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may establish economic development centers for the purpose of serving as liaisons between Florida College System institutions and the business sector pursuant to the provisions of s. 1004.80.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="32">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may establish a child development training center pursuant to s. 1004.81.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="33">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to develop and produce work products relating to educational endeavors that are subject to trademark, copyright, or patent statutes pursuant to chapter 1004.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="34">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall administer the facilities program pursuant to chapter 1013, including but not limited to: the construction of public educational and ancillary plants; the acquisition and disposal of property; compliance with building and life safety codes; submission of data and information relating to facilities and construction; use of buildings and grounds; establishment of safety and sanitation programs for the protection of building occupants; and site planning and selection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="35">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may exercise the right of eminent domain pursuant to the provisions of chapter 1013.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="36">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may enter into lease-purchase arrangements with private individuals or corporations for necessary grounds and buildings for Florida College System institution purposes, other than dormitories, or for buildings other than dormitories to be erected for Florida College System institution purposes. Such arrangements shall be paid from capital outlay and debt service funds as provided by s. 1011.84(2), with terms not to exceed 30 years at a stipulated rate. The provisions of such contracts, including building plans, are subject to approval by the Department of Education, and no such contract may be entered into without such approval.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="37">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may purchase, acquire, receive, hold, own, manage, lease, sell, dispose of, and convey title to real property, in the best interests of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="38">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees is authorized to enter into short-term loans and installment, lease-purchase, and other financing contracts for a term of not more than 5 years, including renewals, extensions, and refundings. Payments on short-term loans and installment, lease-purchase, and other financing contracts pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to annual appropriation by the board of trustees. Each board of trustees is authorized to borrow funds and incur long-term debt, including promissory notes, installment sales agreements, lease-purchase agreements, certificates of participation, and other similar long-term financing arrangements, only as specifically provided in ss. 1009.22(6) and (9) and 1009.23(11) and (12). At the option of the board of trustees, bonds issued pursuant to ss. 1009.22(6) and (9) and 1009.23(11) and (12) may be secured by a combination of revenues authorized to be pledged to bonds pursuant to such subsections. Revenue bonds may not be secured by or paid from, directly or indirectly, tuition, financial aid fees, the Florida College System Program Fund, or any other operating revenues of a Florida College System institution. Lease-purchase agreements may be secured by a combination of revenues as specifically authorized pursuant to ss. 1009.22(7) and 1009.23(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="39">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall prescribe conditions for direct-support organizations to be certified and to use Florida College System institution property and services. Conditions relating to certification must provide for audit review and oversight by the board of trustees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="40">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may adopt policies pursuant to s. 1010.02 that provide procedures for transferring to the direct-support organization of that Florida College System institution for administration by such organization contributions made to the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="41">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees shall exert every effort to collect all delinquent accounts pursuant to s. 1010.03.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="42">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall implement a plan, in accordance with guidelines of the State Board of Education, for working on a regular basis with the other Florida College System institution boards of trustees, representatives of the university boards of trustees, and representatives of the district school boards to achieve the goals of the seamless education system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="43">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees has responsibility for compliance with state and federal laws, rules, regulations, and requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="44">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may adopt rules, procedures, and policies related to institutional governance, administration, and management in order to promote orderly and efficient operation, including, but not limited to, financial management, budget management, physical plant management, and property management.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="45">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may adopt rules and procedures related to data or technology, including, but not limited to, information systems, communications systems, computer hardware and software, and networks.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="46">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees may consider the past actions of any person applying for employment and may deny employment to a person because of misconduct if determined to be in the best interest of the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="47">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract or employment agreement, or renewal or renegotiation of an existing contract or employment agreement, containing a provision for severance pay with an officer, agent, employee, or contractor must include the provisions required in s. 215.425.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="48">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees shall use purchasing agreements and state term contracts pursuant to s. 287.056 or enter into consortia and cooperative agreements to maximize the purchasing power for goods and services. A consortium or cooperative agreement may be statewide, regional, or a combination of institutions, as appropriate to achieve the lowest cost, with the goal of achieving a 5-percent savings on existing contract prices through the use of new cooperative arrangements or new consortium contracts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 80, ch. 2002-387; s. 75, ch. 2004-357; s. 4, ch. 2005-146; s. 74, ch. 2007-217; s. 1, ch. 2008-163; s. 2, ch. 2009-60; s. 21, ch. 2011-5; ss. 4, 12, ch. 2011-177; s. 4, ch. 2012-134; s. 2, ch. 2012-191; s. 4, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>