<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1001.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers of State Board of Education.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education is the chief implementing and coordinating body of public education in Florida except for the State University System, and it shall focus on high-level policy decisions. It has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of law conferring duties upon it for the improvement of the state system of K-20 public education except for the State University System. Except as otherwise provided herein, it may, as it finds appropriate, delegate its general powers to the Commissioner of Education or the directors of the divisions of the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education has the following duties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt comprehensive educational objectives for public education except for the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt comprehensive long-range plans and short-range programs for the development of the state system of public education except for the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exercise general supervision over the divisions of the Department of Education as necessary to ensure coordination of educational plans and programs and resolve controversies and to minimize problems of articulation and student transfers, to ensure that students moving from one level of education to the next have acquired competencies necessary for satisfactory performance at that level, and to ensure maximum utilization of facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt, in consultation with the Board of Governors, and from time to time modify, minimum and uniform standards of college-level communication and computation skills generally associated with successful performance and progression through the baccalaureate level and to identify college-preparatory high school coursework and postsecondary-level coursework that prepares students with the academic skills necessary to succeed in postsecondary education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt and submit to the Governor and Legislature, as provided in s. 216.023, a coordinated K-20 education budget that estimates the expenditure requirements for the Board of Governors, as provided in s. 1001.706, the State Board of Education, including the Department of Education and the Commissioner of Education, and all of the boards, institutions, agencies, and services under the general supervision of the Board of Governors, as provided in s. 1001.706, or the State Board of Education for the ensuing fiscal year. The State Board of Education may not amend the budget request submitted by the Board of Governors. Any program recommended by the Board of Governors or the State Board of Education which will require increases in state funding for more than 1 year must be presented in a multiyear budget plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To hold meetings, transact business, keep records, adopt a seal, and, except as otherwise provided by law, perform such other duties as may be necessary for the enforcement of laws and rules relating to the state system of public education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To approve plans for cooperating with the Federal Government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To approve plans for cooperating with other public agencies in the development of rules and in the enforcement of laws for which the state board and such agencies are jointly responsible.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To review plans for cooperating with appropriate nonpublic agencies for the improvement of conditions relating to the welfare of schools.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To create such subordinate advisory bodies as are required by law or as it finds necessary for the improvement of education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To constitute any education bodies or other structures as required by federal law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist in the economic development of the state by developing a state-level planning process to identify future training needs for industry, especially high-technology industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist in the planning and economic development of the state by establishing a clearinghouse for information on educational programs of value to economic development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt cohesive rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54, within statutory authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To authorize the allocation of resources in accordance with law and rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract with independent institutions accredited by an agency whose standards are comparable to the minimum standards required to operate a postsecondary educational institution at that level in the state. The purpose of the contract is to provide those educational programs and facilities which will meet needs unfulfilled by the state system of public postsecondary education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To recommend that a district school board take action consistent with the state board’s decision relating to an appeal of a charter school application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enforce systemwide education goals and policies except as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish a detailed procedure for the implementation and operation of a systemwide K-20 technology plan that is based on a common set of data definitions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish accountability standards for existing legislative performance goals, standards, and measures, and order the development of mechanisms to implement new legislative goals, standards, and measures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt criteria and implementation plans for future growth issues, such as new Florida College System institutions and Florida College System institution campus mergers, and to provide for cooperative agreements between and within public and private education sectors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop, in conjunction with the Board of Governors, and periodically review for adjustment, a coordinated 5-year plan for postsecondary enrollment, identifying enrollment and graduation expectations by baccalaureate degree program, and annually submit the plan to the Legislature as part of its legislative budget request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2014-2015 academic year and annually thereafter, to require each Florida College System institution prior to registration to provide each enrolled student electronic access to the economic security report of employment and earning outcomes prepared by the Department of Economic Opportunity pursuant to s. 445.07.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt a strategic plan that specifies goals and objectives for the state’s public schools and Florida College System institutions. The plan shall be formulated in conjunction with plans of the Board of Governors in order to provide for the roles of the universities and Florida College System institutions to be coordinated to best meet state needs and reflect cost-effective use of state resources. The strategic plan must clarify the mission statements of each Florida College System institution and the system as a whole and identify degree programs, including baccalaureate degree programs, to be offered at each Florida College System institution in accordance with the objectives provided in this subsection and the coordinated 5-year plan pursuant to paragraph (2)(v). The strategic plan must cover a period of 5 years, with modification of the program lists after 2 years. Development of each 5-year plan must be coordinated with and initiated after completion of the master plan. The strategic plans must specifically include programs and procedures for responding to the educational needs of teachers and students in the public schools of this state and consider reports and recommendations of the Higher Education Coordinating Council pursuant to s. 1004.015 and the Articulation Coordinating Committee pursuant to s. 1007.01. The state board shall submit a report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives upon modification of the plan and as part of its legislative budget request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education and the Board of Governors shall jointly develop long-range plans and annual reports for financial aid in this state. The long-range plans shall establish goals and objectives for a comprehensive program of financial aid for Florida students and shall be updated every 5 years. The annual report shall include programs administered by the department as well as awards made from financial aid fee revenues, any other funds appropriated by the Legislature for financial assistance, and the value of tuition and fees waived for students enrolled in a dual enrollment course at a public postsecondary educational institution. The annual report shall include an assessment of progress made in achieving goals and objectives established in the long-range plans and recommendations for repealing or modifying existing financial aid programs or establishing new programs. A long-range plan shall be submitted by January 1, 2004, and every 5 years thereafter. An annual report shall be submitted on January 1, 2004, and in each successive year that a long-range plan is not submitted, to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for each Florida College System institution to offer educational training and service programs designed to meet the needs of both students and the communities served.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify, by rule, procedures to be used by the Florida College System institution boards of trustees in the annual evaluations of presidents and review the evaluations of presidents by the boards of trustees, including the extent to which presidents serve both institutional and system goals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish, in conjunction with the Board of Governors, an effective information system that will provide composite data concerning the Florida College System institutions and state universities and ensure that special analyses and studies concerning the institutions are conducted, as necessary, for provision of accurate and cost-effective information concerning the institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish criteria for making recommendations for modifying district boundary lines for Florida College System institutions, including criteria for service delivery areas of Florida College System institutions authorized to grant baccalaureate degrees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish criteria for making recommendations concerning all proposals for the establishment of additional centers or campuses for Florida College System institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examine the annual administrative review of each Florida College System institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify, by rule, the college credit courses that may be taken by Florida College System institution students concurrently enrolled in college-preparatory instruction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and submit to the Legislature a 3-year list of priorities for fixed-capital-outlay projects. The State Board of Education may not amend the 3-year list of priorities of the Board of Governors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education is responsible for reviewing and administering the state program of support for the Florida College System institutions and, subject to existing law, shall establish the tuition and out-of-state fees for college-preparatory instruction and for credit instruction that may be counted toward an associate in arts degree, an associate in applied science degree, or an associate in science degree.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall prescribe minimum standards, definitions, and guidelines for Florida College System institutions that will ensure the quality of education, coordination among the Florida College System institutions and state universities, and efficient progress toward accomplishing the Florida College System institution mission. At a minimum, these rules must address:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program offerings and classification, including college-level communication and computation skills associated with successful performance in college and with tests and other assessment procedures that measure student achievement of those skills. The performance measures must provide that students moving from one level of education to the next acquire the necessary competencies for that level.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for curriculum development, graduation requirements, college calendars, and program service areas. These provisions must include rules that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the award of an associate in arts degree to a student who successfully completes 60 semester credit hours at the Florida College System institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require all of the credits accepted for the associate in arts degree to be in the statewide course numbering system as credits toward a baccalaureate degree offered by a state university or a Florida College System institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with students initially entering a Florida College System institution in 2014-2015 and thereafter, require no more than 30 semester credit hours in general education courses in the subject areas of communication, mathematics, social sciences, humanities, and natural sciences.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The rules should encourage Florida College System institutions to enter into agreements with state universities that allow Florida College System institution students to complete upper-division-level courses at a Florida College System institution. An agreement may provide for concurrent enrollment at the Florida College System institution and the state university and may authorize the Florida College System institution to offer an upper-division-level course or distance learning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student admissions, conduct and discipline, nonclassroom activities, and fees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Budgeting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business and financial matters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports, surveys, and information systems, including forms and dates of submission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 2002-387; s. 68, ch. 2007-217; s. 8, ch. 2011-5; s. 1, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>