<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1001.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers of district school board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board, after considering recommendations submitted by the district school superintendent, shall exercise the following general powers:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine policies and programs consistent with state law and rule deemed necessary by it for the efficient operation and general improvement of the district school system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of law conferring duties upon it to supplement those prescribed by the State Board of Education and the Commissioner of Education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe and adopt standards and policies to provide each student the opportunity to receive a complete education program, including language arts, mathematics, science, social studies, health, physical education, foreign languages, and the arts, as defined by the Sunshine State Standards. The standards and policies must emphasize integration and reinforcement of reading, writing, and mathematics skills across all subjects, including career awareness, career exploration, and career and technical education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract, sue, and be sued. The district school board shall constitute the contracting agent for the district school system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform duties and exercise those responsibilities that are assigned to it by law or by rules of the State Board of Education or the Commissioner of Education and, in addition thereto, those that it may find to be necessary for the improvement of the district school system in carrying out the purposes and objectives of the education code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assign students to schools.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements for accepting credit card, charge card, and debit card payments as compensation for goods, services, tuition, and fees, as authorized by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 54, ch. 2002-387; s. 10, ch. 2006-74.</History></Section>