<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1001.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Responsibility for the State University System under s. 7, Art. IX of the State Constitution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For purposes of this act, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board of Governors” as it relates to the State University System and as used in s. 7, Art. IX of the State Constitution and Title XLVIII and other sections of the Florida Statutes is the Board of Governors of the State University System which belongs to and is part of the executive branch of state government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Institutions of higher learning” as used in the State Constitution and the Florida Statutes includes publicly funded state universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public officer” as used in the Florida Statutes includes members of the Board of Governors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State university” or “state universities” as used in the State Constitution and the Florida Statutes are agencies of the state which belong to and are part of the executive branch of state government. This definition of state universities as state agencies is only for the purposes of the delineation of constitutional lines of authority. Statutory exemptions for state universities from statutory provisions relating to state agencies that are in effect on the effective date of this act remain in effect and are not repealed by virtue of this definition of state universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTITUTIONAL DUTIES OF THE BOARD OF GOVERNORS OF THE STATE UNIVERSITY SYSTEM.<EmDash />In accordance with s. 7, Art. IX of the State Constitution, the Board of Governors of the State University System has the duty to operate, regulate, control, and be fully responsible for the management of the whole publicly funded State University System and the board, or the board’s designee, has responsibility for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defining the distinctive mission of each constituent university.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defining the articulation of each constituent university in conjunction with the Legislature’s authority over the public schools and Florida College System institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring the well-planned coordination and operation of the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Avoiding wasteful duplication of facilities or programs within the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounting for expenditure of funds appropriated by the Legislature for the State University System as provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting a budget request for legislative appropriations for the institutions under the supervision of the board as provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopting strategic plans for the State University System and each constituent university.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approving, reviewing, and terminating degree programs of the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governing admissions to the state universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serving as the public employer to all public employees of state universities for collective bargaining purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a personnel system for all state university employees; however, the Department of Management Services shall retain authority over state university employees for programs established in ss. 110.123, 110.1232, 110.1234, 110.1238, and 110.161, and in chapters 121, 122, and 238.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complying with, and enforcing for institutions under the board’s jurisdiction, all applicable local, state, and federal laws.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTITUTIONAL DUTIES OF THE LEGISLATURE.<EmDash />In accordance with s. 3, Art. II of the State Constitution, which establishes the separation of powers of three branches of government; s. 1, Art. III of the State Constitution, which vests the legislative power of the state in the Legislature; s. 8, Art. III of the State Constitution, which provides the exclusive executive veto power of the Governor and the exclusive veto override power of the Legislature; s. 19, Art. III of the State Constitution, which requires the Legislature to enact state planning and budget processes and requirements for budget requests by general law; s. 1, Art. VII of the State Constitution, which requires that the authority to expend state funds be by general law enacted by the Legislature; and s. 1, Art. IX of the State Constitution, which requires the Legislature to make adequate provision by law for the “establishment, maintenance, and operation of institutions of higher learning,” the Legislature has the following responsibilities:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making provision by law for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of institutions of higher learning and other public education programs that the needs of the people may require.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriating all state funds through the General Appropriations Act or other law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing tuition and fees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing policies relating to merit and need-based student financial aid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing policies relating to expenditure of, accountability for, and management of funds appropriated by the Legislature or revenues authorized by the Legislature. This includes, but is not limited to, policies relating to: budgeting; deposit of funds; investments; accounting; purchasing, procurement, and contracting; insurance; audits; maintenance and construction of facilities; property; bond financing; leasing; and information reporting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining the actuarial and fiscal soundness of centrally administered state systems by requiring state universities to continue to participate in programs such as the Florida Retirement System, the state group health insurance programs, and the state casualty insurance program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing and regulating the use of state powers and protections, including, but not limited to, eminent domain, certified law enforcement, and sovereign immunity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing policies relating to the health, safety, and welfare of students, employees, and the public while present on the campuses of institutions of higher learning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-285; s. 10, ch. 2010-78; s. 23, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>