<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0791.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Distributor” means any person engaged in the business of selling sparklers to a wholesaler.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of the State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Explosive compound” means any chemical compound, mixture, or device the primary or common purpose of which is to function by the substantially instantaneous release of gas and heat.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fireworks” means and includes any combustible or explosive composition or substance or combination of substances or, except as hereinafter provided, any article prepared for the purpose of producing a visible or audible effect by combustion, explosion, deflagration, or detonation. The term includes blank cartridges and toy cannons in which explosives are used, the type of balloons which require fire underneath to propel them, firecrackers, torpedoes, skyrockets, roman candles, dago bombs, and any fireworks containing any explosives or flammable compound or any tablets or other device containing any explosive substance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fireworks” does not include sparklers approved by the division pursuant to s. 791.013; toy pistols, toy canes, toy guns, or other devices in which paper caps containing twenty-five hundredths grains or less of explosive compound are used, providing they are so constructed that the hand cannot come in contact with the cap when in place for the explosion; and toy pistol paper caps which contain less than twenty hundredths grains of explosive mixture, the sale and use of which shall be permitted at all times.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fireworks” also does not include the following novelties and trick noisemakers:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A snake or glow worm, which is a pressed pellet of not more than 10 grams of pyrotechnic composition that produces a large, snakelike ash which expands in length as the pellet burns and that does not contain mercuric thiocyanate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A smoke device, which is a tube or sphere containing not more than 10 grams of pyrotechnic composition that, upon burning, produces white or colored smoke as the primary effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trick noisemaker, which is a device that produces a small report intended to surprise the user and which includes:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party popper, which is a small plastic or paper device containing not more than 16 milligrams of explosive composition that is friction sensitive, which is ignited by pulling a string protruding from the device, and which expels a paper streamer and produces a small report.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A booby trap, which is a small tube with a string protruding from both ends containing not more than 16 milligrams of explosive compound, which is ignited by pulling the ends of the string, and which produces a small report.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A snapper, which is a small, paper-wrapped device containing not more than four milligrams of explosive composition coated on small bits of sand, and which, when dropped, explodes, producing a small report. A snapper may not contain more than 250 milligrams of total sand and explosive composition.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trick match, which is a kitchen or book match which is coated with not more than 16 milligrams of explosive or pyrotechnic composition and which, upon ignition, produces a small report or shower of sparks.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cigarette load, which is a small wooden peg that has been coated with not more than 16 milligrams of explosive composition and which produces, upon ignition of a cigarette containing one of the pegs, a small report.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An auto burglar alarm, which is a tube which contains not more than 10 grams of pyrotechnic composition that produces a loud whistle or smoke when ignited and which is ignited by use of a squib. A small quantity of explosive, not exceeding 50 milligrams, may also be used to produce a small report.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The sale and use of items listed in this paragraph are permitted at all times.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer” means any person engaged in the manufacture or construction of sparklers in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retailer” means any person who, at a fixed place of business, is engaged in selling sparklers to consumers at retail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Seasonal retailer” means any person engaged in the business of selling sparklers at retail in this state from June 20 through July 5 and from December 10 through January 2 of each year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sparkler” means a device which emits showers of sparks upon burning, does not contain any explosive compounds, does not detonate or explode, is handheld or ground based, cannot propel itself through the air, and contains not more than 100 grams of the chemical compound which produces sparks upon burning. Any sparkler that is not approved by the division is classified as fireworks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wholesaler” means any person engaged in the business of selling sparklers to a retailer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 20445, 1941; s. 1, ch. 57-338; s. 1, ch. 84-201; s. 1, ch. 87-118; s. 36, ch. 89-233; s. 1906, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>