<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Opticianry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Opticianry” means the preparation and dispensing of lenses, spectacles, eyeglasses, contact lenses, and other optical devices to the intended user or agent thereof, upon the written prescription of a licensed allopathic or osteopathic physician or optometrist who is duly licensed to practice or upon presentation of a duplicate prescription. The selection of frame designs, the actual sales transaction, and the transfer of physical possession of lenses, spectacles, eyeglasses, contact lenses, and other optical devices subsequent to performance of all services of the optician shall not be considered the practice of opticianry; however, such physical possession shall not be transferred until the optician has completed the fitting of the optical device upon the customer. The practice of opticianry also includes the duplication of lenses accurately as to power, without prescription. A board-certified optician qualified and operating under rules established by the board may fill, fit, adapt, or dispense any soft contact lens prescription. Such optician may fill, fit, adapt, or dispense any extended wear or hard contact lens prescription to the extent authorized to do so by the prescribing allopathic or osteopathic physician or optometrist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Optician” means any person licensed to practice opticianry pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means supervision where the licensee remains on the premises while all work is being done and gives final approval to any work performed by an employee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board-certified optician” means an optician licensed in this state who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed the National Contact Lens Registry Examination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed a board-approved course of at least 20 contact hours covering the competencies required in fitting, adapting, and dispensing of contact lenses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has met any other requirements established by the board to assure competence in the fitting, adapting, and dispensing of contact lenses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee set by the board not to exceed $100; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been issued a certificate by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Optical establishment” means any establishment in the state which offers, advertises, and performs opticianry services for the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contact lenses” means a prescribed medical device intended to be worn directly against the cornea of the eye to correct vision conditions, act as a therapeutic device, or provide a cosmetic effect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Optical dispensing” means interpreting but not altering a prescription of a licensed physician or optometrist and designing, adapting, fitting, or replacing the prescribed optical aids, pursuant to such prescription, to or for the intended wearer, duplicating lenses, accurately as to power without a prescription, and duplicating nonprescription eyewear and parts of eyewear. “Optical dispensing” does not include selecting frames, transferring an optical aid to the wearer after an optician has completed fitting it, or providing instruction in the general care and use of an optical aid, including placement, removal, hygiene, or cleaning.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 79-275; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 83, ch. 83-329; ss. 2, 11, 12, ch. 86-254; s. 27, ch. 88-205; s. 57, ch. 89-162; s. 29, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 94-192; s. 177, ch. 94-218; s. 138, ch. 98-166; s. 117, ch. 2001-277.</History></Section>