<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring or attempting to procure a license by misrepresentation, bribery, or fraud or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring or attempting to procure a license for any other person by making or causing to be made any false representation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by federal or state law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to do so. Such reports or records shall include only those which the person is required to make or file as an optician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to make fee or price information readily available by providing such information upon request or upon the presentation of a prescription.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner which is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraud or deceit, or negligence, incompetency, or misconduct, in the authorized practice of opticianry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing with a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of s. 484.012.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspiring with another licensee or with any person to commit an act, or committing an act, which would coerce, intimidate, or preclude another licensee from lawfully advertising her or his services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully submitting to any third-party payor a claim for services which were not provided to a patient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep written prescription files.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully failing to report any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this part or of rules of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on a client in such a manner as to exploit the client for financial gain of the licensee or of a third party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permitting any person not licensed as an optician in this state to fit or dispense any lenses, spectacles, eyeglasses, or other optical devices which are part of the practice of opticianry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, in a court of this state or other jurisdiction, a crime which relates to the ability to practice opticianry or to the practice of opticianry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been disciplined by a regulatory agency in another state for any offense that would constitute a violation of Florida law or rules regulating opticianry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice opticianry with reasonable skill and safety by reason of illness or use of drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition. An optician affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that she or he can resume the competent practice of opticianry with reasonable skill and safety to her or his customers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall not reinstate the license of an optician it has deemed unqualified until such time as it is satisfied that the optician has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and that such person is capable of safely engaging in the practice of opticianry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permitholder under this part shall be subject to the provisions of this section which shall be enforced by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 79-275; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 7, 11, 12, ch. 86-254; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 248, ch. 94-119; s. 5, ch. 94-192; s. 449, ch. 97-103; s. 140, ch. 98-166; s. 198, ch. 2000-160; s. 46, ch. 2000-318; s. 49, ch. 2001-277; s. 24, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>