<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Hearing Aid Specialists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dispensing hearing aids” means and includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting and interpreting hearing tests for purposes of selecting suitable hearing aids, making earmolds or ear impressions, and providing appropriate counseling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All acts pertaining to the selling, renting, leasing, pricing, delivery, and warranty of hearing aids.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hearing aid specialist” means a person duly licensed in this state to practice the dispensing of hearing aids.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hearing aid” means an amplifying device to be worn by a hearing-impaired person to improve hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trainee” means a person studying hearing aid dispensing under the direct supervision of an active licensed hearing aid specialist for the purpose of qualifying for certification to sit for the licensure examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hearing aid establishment” means any establishment in the state which offers, advertises, and performs hearing aid services for the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sponsor” means an active, licensed hearing aid specialist under whose direct supervision one or more trainees are studying hearing aid dispensing for the purpose of qualifying for certification to sit for the licensure examination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 18, ch. 83-153; ss. 1, 7, ch. 84-94; ss. 2, 19, 20, ch. 86-283; s. 1, ch. 87-47; s. 22, ch. 90-341; s. 11, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 179, ch. 94-218; s. 172, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>