<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.053" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice dispensing hearing aids unless the person is a licensed hearing aid specialist;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the name or title “hearing aid specialist” when the person has not been licensed under this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as her or his own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give false, incomplete, or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof for the purposes of obtaining a license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a hearing aid specialist license that is delinquent or has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly employ unlicensed persons in the practice of dispensing hearing aids; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly conceal information relative to violations of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any of the provisions of this section is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person licensed under this part allows the sale of a hearing aid by an unlicensed person not registered as a trainee or fails to comply with the requirements of s. 484.0445(2) relating to supervision of trainees, the board shall, upon determination of that violation, order the full refund of moneys paid by the purchaser upon return of the hearing aid to the seller’s place of business.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 18, ch. 83-153; ss. 1, 7, ch. 84-94; ss. 14, 19, 20, ch. 86-283; s. 22, ch. 90-341; s. 11, ch. 90-345; s. 116, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 251, ch. 94-119; s. 455, ch. 97-103; s. 156, ch. 99-397; s. 7, ch. 2000-154; s. 61, ch. 2000-318.</History></Section>