<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of s. 456.072(1), s. 484.0512, or s. 484.053.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license to dispense hearing aids by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentations, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to dispense hearing aids revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of dispensing hearing aids or the ability to practice dispensing hearing aids, including violations of any federal laws or regulations regarding hearing aids.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records shall include only those reports or records which are signed in one’s capacity as a licensed hearing aid specialist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner which is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that the licensee is guilty of fraud or deceit or of negligence, incompetency, or misconduct in the practice of dispensing hearing aids.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failure to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the board or department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing with a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using, or causing or promoting the use of, any advertising matter, promotional literature, testimonial, guarantee, warranty, label, brand, insignia, or other representation, however disseminated or published, which is misleading, deceiving, or untruthful.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Showing or demonstrating, or, in the event of sale, delivery of, a product unusable or impractical for the purpose represented or implied by such action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresentation of professional services available in the fitting, sale, adjustment, service, or repair of a hearing aid, or use of the terms “doctor,” “clinic,” “clinical,” “medical audiologist,” “clinical audiologist,” “research audiologist,” or “audiologic” or any other term or title which might connote the availability of professional services when such use is not accurate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representation, advertisement, or implication that a hearing aid or its repair is guaranteed without providing full disclosure of the identity of the guarantor; the nature, extent, and duration of the guarantee; and the existence of conditions or limitations imposed upon the guarantee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representing, directly or by implication, that a hearing aid utilizing bone conduction has certain specified features, such as the absence of anything in the ear or leading to the ear, or the like, without disclosing clearly and conspicuously that the instrument operates on the bone conduction principle and that in many cases of hearing loss this type of instrument may not be suitable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any predictions or prognostications as to the future course of a hearing impairment, either in general terms or with reference to an individual person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stating or implying that the use of any hearing aid will improve or preserve hearing or prevent or retard the progression of a hearing impairment or that it will have any similar or opposite effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any statement regarding the cure of the cause of a hearing impairment by the use of a hearing aid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representing or implying that a hearing aid is or will be “custom-made,” “made to order,” or “prescription-made” or in any other sense specially fabricated for an individual person when such is not the case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Canvassing from house to house or by telephone either in person or by an agent for the purpose of selling a hearing aid, except that contacting persons who have evidenced an interest in hearing aids, or have been referred as in need of hearing aids, shall not be considered canvassing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to submit to the board on an annual basis, or such other basis as may be provided by rule, certification of testing and calibration of audiometric testing equipment on the form approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to provide all information as described in s. 484.051(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on a client in such a manner as to exploit the client for financial gain of the licensee or of a third party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall revoke the license of any hearing aid specialist found guilty of canvassing as described in this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall reissue the license of a hearing aid specialist who has been disciplined upon certification by the board that the hearing aid specialist has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 18, ch. 83-153; ss. 1, 7, ch. 84-94; s. 84, ch. 85-81; ss. 16, 19, 20, ch. 86-283; s. 22, ch. 90-341; s. 11, ch. 90-345; s. 33, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 252, ch. 94-119; s. 142, ch. 98-166; s. 157, ch. 99-397; s. 200, ch. 2000-160; ss. 27, 46, ch. 2000-318; ss. 50, 85, ch. 2001-277; s. 25, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>