<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0484.0501" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimal procedures and equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following minimal procedures shall be used in the fitting and selling of hearing aids:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pure tone audiometric testing by air and bone to determine the type and degree of hearing deficiency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective masking when indicated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate testing to determine speech reception thresholds, speech discrimination scores, the most comfortable listening levels, uncomfortable loudness levels, and the selection of the best fitting arrangement for maximum hearing aid benefit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following equipment shall be used:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A wide range audiometer which meets the specifications of the American National Standards Institute for diagnostic audiometers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A speech audiometer or a master hearing aid in order to determine the most comfortable listening level and speech discrimination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final fitting ensuring physical and operational comfort of the hearing aid shall be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following medical clearance shall be obtained: If, upon inspection of the ear canal with an otoscope in the common procedure of a hearing aid fitter and upon interrogation of the client, there is any recent history of infection or any observable anomaly, the client shall be instructed to see a physician, and a hearing aid shall not be fitted until medical clearance is obtained for the condition noted. If, upon return, the condition noted is no longer observable and the client signs a medical waiver, a hearing aid may be fitted. Any person with a significant difference between bone conduction hearing and air conduction hearing must be informed of the possibility of medical correction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hearing aid office must have available, or have access to, a selection of hearing aid models, hearing aid supplies, and services complete enough to accommodate the various needs of the hearing aid wearers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of the initial examination for fitting and sale of a hearing aid, the attending hearing aid specialist must notify the prospective purchaser or client of the benefits of telecoil, “t” coil, or “t” switch technology, including increased access to telephones and noninvasive access to assistive listening systems required under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each audiometric test conducted by a licensee or authorized trainee in the fitting and selling of hearing aids shall be made in a testing room that has been certified by the department, or by an agent approved by the department, not to exceed the following sound pressure levels at the specified frequencies: 250Hz-40dB, 500Hz-40dB, 750Hz-40dB, 1000Hz-40dB, 1500Hz-42dB, 2000Hz-47dB, 3000Hz-52dB, 4000Hz-57dB, 6000Hz-62dB, and 8000Hz-67dB. An exception to this requirement shall be made in the case of a client who, after being provided written notice of the benefits and advantages of having the test conducted in a certified testing room, requests that the test be conducted in a place other than the licensee’s certified testing room. Such request shall be documented by a waiver which includes the written notice and is signed by the licensee and the client prior to the testing. The waiver shall be executed on a form provided by the department. The executed waiver shall be attached to the client’s copy of the contract, and a copy of the executed waiver shall be retained in the licensee’s file.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the power to prescribe the minimum procedures and equipment which shall be used in the conducting of hearing assessments, and for the fitting and selling of hearing aids, including equipment that will measure the hearing aid’s response curves to ensure that they meet the manufacturer’s specifications. These procedures and equipment may differ from those provided in this section in order to take full advantage of devices and equipment which may hereafter become available and which are demonstrated to be of greater efficiency and accuracy. The board shall adopt and enforce rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection and subsection (6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized officer or employee of the department shall have the right to make such inspections and investigations as are necessary in order to determine the state of compliance with the provisions of this section and the applicable rules and may enter the premises of a licensee and inspect the records of same upon reasonable belief that a violation of this law is being or has been committed or that the licensee has failed or is failing to comply with the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 18, ch. 83-153; ss. 1, 7, ch. 84-94; s. 1, ch. 85-262; ss. 11, 19, 20, ch. 86-283; s. 22, ch. 90-341; s. 11, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 250, 335, ch. 94-119; s. 8, ch. 94-160.</History></Section>