<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0260.0125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation on liability of private landowners whose property is designated as part of the statewide system of greenways and trails.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private landowner whose land is designated as part of the statewide system of greenways and trails pursuant to s. 260.016(2)(d), including a person holding a subservient interest, owes no duty of care to keep that land safe for entry or use by others or to give warning to persons entering that land of any hazardous conditions, structures, or activities thereon. Such landowner shall not:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be presumed to extend any assurance that such land is safe for any purpose;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incur any duty of care toward a person who goes on the land; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Become liable or responsible for any injury to persons or property caused by the act or omission of a person who goes on the land.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraph (a) apply whether the person going on the designated greenway or trail is an invitee, licensee, trespasser, or otherwise.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any private landowner who consents to designation of his or her land as part of the statewide system of greenways and trails pursuant to s. 260.016(2)(d) without compensation shall be considered a volunteer, as defined in s. 110.501, and shall be covered by state liability protection pursuant to s. 768.28, including s. 768.28(9).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) shall not apply if there is any charge made or usually made by the landowner for entering or using the land designated as a greenway or trail, or any part thereof, or if any commercial or other activity whereby profit is derived by the landowner from the patronage of the general public is conducted on the land so designated or any part thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incentives granted by any unit of government to the private landowner, including tax incentives, grants, or other financial consideration specific to the development or management of designated greenways and trails, shall not be construed as a charge for use or profit derived from patronage for purposes of this subsection and shall not be construed as monetary or material compensation for purposes of subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) shall also apply to adjacent land owned by the private landowner who consents to designation of a greenway or trail where such adjacent land is accessed through the land so designated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a private landowner agrees to make his or her land available for public use as a designated greenway or trail, the department or its designee shall post notices along the boundary of the designated greenway or trail which inform the public that the land adjacent to the greenway or trail is private property upon which unauthorized entry for any purpose is prohibited and constitutes trespassing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such notices must comply with s. 810.011(5) and shall constitute a warning to unauthorized persons to remain off the private property and not to depart from the designated greenway or trail. Any person who commits such an unauthorized entry commits a trespass as provided in s. 810.09.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If agreed to by the department and the landowner in the designation agreement, a landowner whose land is designated as part of the statewide system of greenways and trails pursuant to s. 260.016(2)(d) shall be indemnified for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any injury or damage incurred by a third party arising out of the use of the designated greenway or trail;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any injury or damage incurred by a third party on lands adjacent to and accessed through the designated greenway or trail; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any damage to the landowner’s property, including land adjacent to and accessed through the designated greenway or trail, caused by the act or omission of a third person resulting from any use of the land so designated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not relieve any person of liability that would otherwise exist for deliberate, willful, or malicious injury to persons or property. The provisions of this section shall not be deemed to create or increase the liability of any person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-336; s. 3, ch. 2001-182; s. 48, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>