<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0260.0144" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sponsorship of state greenways and trails.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into a concession agreement with a not-for-profit entity or private sector business or entity for commercial sponsorship to be displayed on state greenway and trail facilities or property specified in this section. The department may establish the cost for entering into a concession agreement.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A concession agreement shall be administered by the department and must include the requirements found in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space for a commercial sponsorship display may be provided through a concession agreement on certain state-owned greenway or trail facilities or property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signage or displays erected under this section shall comply with the provisions of s. 337.407 and chapter 479, and shall be limited as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One large sign or display, not to exceed 16 square feet in area, may be located at each trailhead or parking area.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One small sign or display, not to exceed 4 square feet in area, may be located at each designated trail public access point.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before installation, each name or sponsorship display must be approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure that the size, color, materials, construction, and location of all signs are consistent with the management plan for the property and the standards of the department, do not intrude on natural and historic settings, and contain only a logo selected by the sponsor and the following sponsorship wording:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of the sponsor)</Directions> proudly sponsors the costs of maintaining the <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of the greenway or trail)</Directions>.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sponsored state greenways and trails are authorized at the following facilities or property:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Keys Overseas Heritage Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blackwater Heritage Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tallahassee-St. Marks Historic Railroad State Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nature Coast State Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withlacoochee State Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General James A. Van Fleet State Trail.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Palatka-Lake Butler State Trail.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into commercial sponsorship agreements for other state greenways or trails as authorized in this section. A qualified entity that desires to enter into a commercial sponsorship agreement shall apply to the department on forms adopted by department rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All costs of a display, including development, construction, installation, operation, maintenance, and removal costs, shall be paid by the concessionaire.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A concession agreement shall be for a minimum of 1 year, but may be for a longer period under a multiyear agreement, and may be terminated for just cause by the department upon 60 days’ advance notice. Just cause for termination of a concession agreement includes, but is not limited to, violation of the terms of the concession agreement or any provision of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commercial sponsorship pursuant to a concession agreement is for public relations or advertising purposes of the not-for-profit entity or private sector business or entity, and may not be construed by that not-for-profit entity or private sector business or entity as having a relationship to any other actions of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not create a proprietary or compensable interest in any sign, display site, or location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceeds from concession agreements shall be distributed as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eighty-five percent shall be deposited into the appropriate department trust fund that is the source of funding for management and operation of state greenway and trail facilities and properties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifteen percent shall be deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund for use in the Traffic and Bicycle Safety Education Program and the Safe Paths to School Program administered by the Department of Transportation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2012-198.</History></Section>