<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0430.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise, assist, and protect the state’s elderly citizens to the fullest extent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that programs and services are developed and implemented to be accessible to all elderly citizens to assist them in the achievement or maintenance of maximum independence and quality of life and minimum levels of social dependence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Support and promote the efforts of families and other caregivers in assisting elderly persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote intergenerational activities that will provide citizens of all ages opportunities to enjoy the enriching benefits of interaction and that will promote unity and support for one another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that state government functions effectively and efficiently in serving the elderly through coordination of policy development, planning, and service delivery by all state agencies relating to the elderly population of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that elderly citizens are able to secure prompt, adequate, and accurate information and assistance regarding, but not limited to, health, social welfare, long-term care, protective services, consumer protection, education and training, housing, employment, recreation, transportation, insurance, and retirement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organize the Department of Elderly Affairs as the state agency that has lead responsibility for administering human service programs for the elderly and for developing policy recommendations for long-term care.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 91-115; s. 78, ch. 95-418.</History></Section>