<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0430.707" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, shall select and contract with managed care organizations and, on a prepaid basis, with other qualified providers as defined in s. 430.703(7) to provide long-term care within community diversion pilot project areas. All providers shall report quarterly to the department regarding the entity’s compliance with all the financial and quality assurance requirements of the contract.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, may contract with entities that have submitted an application as a community nursing home diversion project as of July 1, 1998, to provide benefits pursuant to the “Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly” as established in Pub. L. No. 105-33. For the purposes of this community nursing home diversion project, such entities are exempt from the requirements of chapter 641 if the entity is a private, nonprofit, superior-rated nursing home and if at least 50 percent of its residents are eligible for Medicaid. The agency, in consultation with the department, shall accept and forward to the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services an application for expansion of the pilot project from an entity that provides benefits pursuant to the Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly and that is in good standing with the agency, the department, and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 97-87; s. 2, ch. 98-327; s. 24, ch. 2000-163; s. 4, ch. 2005-208; s. 19, ch. 2009-55; s. 24, ch. 2011-135.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Repealed October 1, 2013, by s. 24, ch. 2011-135.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 18, ch. 2012-33, provides that “[n]otwithstanding s. 430.707, Florida Statutes, and subject to federal approval of an additional site for the Program of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE), the Agency for Health Care Administration shall contract with a current PACE organization authorized to provide PACE services in Southeast Florida to develop and operate a PACE program in Broward County to serve frail elders who reside in Broward County. The organization shall be exempt from chapter 641, Florida Statutes. The agency, in consultation with the Department of Elderly Affairs and subject to an appropriation, shall approve up to 150 initial enrollee slots in the Broward program established by the organization.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 19, ch. 2012-33, provides that “[n]otwithstanding s. 430.707, Florida Statutes, and subject to federal approval of the application to be a site for the Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE), the Agency for Health Care Administration shall contract with one private health care organization, the sole member of which is a private, not-for-profit corporation that owns and manages health care organizations licensed in Manatee, Sarasota, and DeSoto Counties which provide comprehensive services, including hospice and palliative care, to frail elders who reside in these counties. The organization shall be exempt from the requirements of chapter 641, Florida Statutes. The agency, in consultation with the Department of Elderly Affairs and subject to an appropriation, shall approve up to 150 initial enrollees in the Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly established by this organization to serve frail elders who reside in Manatee, Sarasota, and DeSoto Counties.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>