<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0430.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Office of Volunteer Community Service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Elderly Affairs the Office of Volunteer Community Service. The office shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compile an inventory of services needed by elderly persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compile an inventory of services being provided to elderly persons to meet those needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine which services needed by elderly persons are not being provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine which services currently not being provided can be provided by older persons acting as volunteers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify those state rules and policies which restrict volunteer service by or for older persons and propose corrective actions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify methods of promoting volunteer service by and for older persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a comprehensive volunteer program that includes an intergenerational component and draws on the strengths and skills of the state’s older population and, to the extent possible, implements the volunteer service credit program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage contributions and grants through private, state, and federal sources for the purpose of promoting, implementing, or evaluating volunteer programs by or for older persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage volunteerism by elders regardless of socioeconomic status. In order to accomplish this, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the office is authorized to provide to those volunteers whose presence is determined to be necessary to the department direct payment of lodging and transportation expenses to a vendor on behalf of such volunteer, or prepayment, or reimbursement of lodging and transportation expenses directly to such volunteer. The office shall not expend or authorize an expenditure in excess of the amount appropriated in any fiscal year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 91-115; s. 2, ch. 2003-67.</History></Section>