<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0430.81" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Implementation of a teaching agency for home and community-based care.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “teaching agency for home and community-based care” means a home health agency licensed under part III of chapter 400 that has access to a resident population of sufficient size to support education, training, and research relating to geriatric care.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs may designate a home health agency as a teaching agency for home and community-based care if the home health agency:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been a not-for-profit, designated community care for the elderly lead agency for home and community-based services for more than 10 consecutive years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participates in a nationally recognized accreditation program and holds a valid accreditation, such as the accreditation awarded by the Community Health Accreditation Program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been in business in this state for a minimum of 20 consecutive years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrates an active program in multidisciplinary education and research that relates to gerontology.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a formalized affiliation agreement with at least one established academic research university with a nationally accredited health professions program in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has salaried academic faculty from a nationally accredited health professions program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a Medicare and Medicaid certified home health agency that has participated in the nursing home diversion program for a minimum of 5 consecutive years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintains insurance coverage pursuant to s. 400.141(1)(s) or proof of financial responsibility in a minimum amount of $750,000. Such proof of financial responsibility may include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining an escrow account consisting of cash or assets eligible for deposit in accordance with s. 625.52; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining and maintaining, pursuant to chapter 675, an unexpired, irrevocable, nontransferable, and nonassignable letter of credit issued by any bank or savings association authorized to do business in this state. This letter of credit shall be used to satisfy the obligation of the agency to the claimant upon presentation of a final judgment indicating liability and awarding damages to be paid by the facility or upon presentment of a settlement agreement signed by all parties to the agreement when such final judgment or settlement is a result of a liability claim against the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A teaching agency for home and community-based care may be affiliated with an academic health center in this state. The purpose of such affiliation is to foster the development of methods for improving and expanding the capability of home health agencies to respond to the medical, health care, psychological, and social needs of frail and elderly persons by providing the most effective and appropriate services. A teaching agency for home and community-based care shall serve as a resource for research and for training health care professionals in providing health care services in home and community-based settings to frail and elderly persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-172.</History>
</Section>