<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0430.902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multiservice senior center.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If practicable, multiservice senior center services shall be available to functionally impaired elderly persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If feasible, a multiservice senior center should be centrally located and easily accessible to public transportation. Provision may be made for transporting persons to the center. A center shall be designed to provide ease of access and use by seniors with varying levels of physical abilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each multiservice senior center is encouraged to have on the premises at all times a functioning automated external defibrillator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Multiservice senior centers that provide automated external defibrillators shall ensure that personnel are properly trained in accordance with s. 401.2915.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of each automated external defibrillator shall be registered with a local emergency medical services medical director.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of automated external defibrillators by employees and volunteers shall be covered under the provisions of ss. 768.13 and 768.1325.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Multiservice senior centers are encouraged to seek national accreditation by the National Institute of Senior Centers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 76-51; s. 18, ch. 78-433; s. 7, ch. 80-181; s. 34, ch. 95-418; s. 2, ch. 2004-367; s. 2, ch. 2005-223.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 409.3629; s. 410.026; s. 430.206.</Text></Note></Section>