<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0430.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community care service system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, through the area agency on aging, shall fund in each planning and service area at least one community care service system that provides case management and other in-home and community services as needed to help the older person maintain independence and prevent or delay more costly institutional care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall fund, through the area agency on aging in each county as defined in s. 125.011(1), more than one community care service system that provides case management and other in-home and community services as needed to help elderly persons maintain independence and prevent or delay more costly institutional care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Core services and other support services may be furnished by public or private agencies or organizations. Each community care service system must be under the direction of a lead agency that coordinates the activities of individual contracting agencies providing community-care-for-the-elderly services. When practicable, the activities of a community care service area may be directed from a multiservice senior center, as defined in s. 430.901, and coordinated with other services offered therein. This subsection does not require programs in existence prior to the effective date of this act to be relocated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall define each core service that is to be provided or coordinated within a community care service area and establish rules and minimum standards for the delivery of core services. The department may conduct or contract for demonstration projects to determine the desirability of new concepts of organization, administration, or service delivery designed to prevent the institutionalization of functionally impaired elderly persons. Evaluations shall be made of the cost-avoidance of such demonstration projects, the ability of the projects to reduce the rate of placement of functionally impaired elderly persons in institutions, and the impact of projects on the use of institutional services and facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A preservice and inservice training program for community-care-for-the-elderly service providers and staff may be designed and implemented to help assure the delivery of quality services. The department shall specify in rules the training standards and requirements for the community-care-for-the-elderly service providers and staff. Training must be sufficient to ensure that quality services are provided to clients and that appropriate skills are developed to conduct the program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has been classified as a functionally impaired elderly person is eligible to receive community-care-for-the-elderly core services.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those elderly persons who are determined by protective investigations to be vulnerable adults in need of services, pursuant to s. 415.104(3)(b), or to be victims of abuse, neglect, or exploitation who are in need of immediate services to prevent further harm and are referred by the adult protective services program, shall be given primary consideration for receiving community-care-for-the-elderly services. As used in this paragraph, “primary consideration” means that an assessment and services must commence within 72 hours after referral to the department or as established in accordance with department contracts by local protocols developed between department service providers and the adult protective services program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall determine an order of prioritization for all other functionally impaired elderly persons seeking community-care-for-the-elderly services which is based upon the potential recipient’s frailty level and likelihood of institutional placement without such services. After determining such frailty level and likelihood of institutional placement, should the list of potential recipients require further prioritization, another factor that must be considered is the potential recipient’s ability to pay for such services. Those who are less able to pay for such services must receive higher priority than those who are better able to pay for such services. A potential recipient’s ability to pay may be determined by the department based on the potential recipient’s self-declared statement of income and expenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding other requirements of this chapter, the Department of Elderly Affairs and the Agency for Health Care Administration shall develop an integrated long-term-care delivery system.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the integrated system shall include organizing and administering service delivery for the elderly, obtaining contracts for services with providers in each service area, monitoring the quality of services provided, determining levels of need and disability for payment purposes, and other activities determined by the department and the agency in order to operate an integrated system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the 2004-2005 state fiscal year:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency and the department shall reimburse providers for case management services on a capitated basis and develop uniform standards for case management within the Aged and Disabled Adult Medicaid waiver program. The coordination of acute and chronic medical services for individuals may be included in the capitated rate for case management services. The agency, in consultation with the department, shall adopt any rules necessary to comply with or administer these requirements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that preservation of the historic aging network of lead agencies is essential to the well-being of Florida’s elderly population. The Legislature finds that the Florida aging network constitutes a system of essential community providers which should be nurtured and assisted to develop systems of operations which allow the gradual assumption of responsibility and financial risk for managing a client through the entire continuum of long-term care services within the area the lead agency is currently serving, and which allow lead agency providers to develop managed systems of service delivery. The department, in consultation with the agency, shall therefore:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a demonstration project in which existing community care for the elderly lead agencies are assisted in transferring their business model and the service delivery system within their current community care service area to enable assumption, over a period of time, of full risk as a community diversion pilot project contractor providing long-term care services in the areas of operation. The department, in consultation with the agency and the Department of Children and Family Services, shall develop an implementation plan for no more than three lead agencies by October 31, 2004.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the demonstration area, a community care for the elderly lead agency shall be initially reimbursed on a prepaid or fixed-sum basis for all home and community-based services provided under the long-term care community diversion pilot project. By the end of the third year of operation, the lead agency shall be reimbursed on a prepaid or fixed-sum basis for all services under the long-term care community diversion pilot project.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the first year of operation, the department, in consultation with the agency, may place providers at risk to provide nursing home services for the enrolled individuals who are participating in the demonstration project. During the 3-year development period, the agency and the department may limit the level of custodial nursing home risk that the administering entities assume. Under risk-sharing arrangements, during the first 3 years of operation, the department, in consultation with the agency, may reimburse the administering entity for the cost of providing nursing home care for Medicaid-eligible participants who have been permanently placed and remain in a nursing home for more than 1 year, or may disenroll such participants from the demonstration project.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, shall develop reimbursement rates based on the federally approved, actuarially certified rate methodology for the long-term care community diversion pilot project.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, shall ensure that the entity or entities receiving prepaid or fixed-sum reimbursement are assisted in developing internal management and financial control systems necessary to manage the risk associated with providing services under a prepaid or fixed-sum rate system.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department and the agency share risk of custodial nursing home placement, payment rates during the first 3 years of operation shall be set at not more than 100 percent of the costs to the agency and the department of providing equivalent services to the population within the area of the pilot project for the year prior to the year in which the pilot project is implemented, adjusted forward to account for inflation and policy changes in the Medicaid program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community care for the elderly lead agencies that have operated for a period of at least 20 years, which provide Medicare-certified services to elders, and which have developed a system of service provision by health care volunteers shall be given priority in the selection of the pilot project if they meet the minimum requirements specified in the competitive procurement.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency and the department shall adopt rules necessary to comply with or administer these requirements, effect and implement interagency agreements between the agency and the department, and comply with federal requirements.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the agency shall seek federal waivers necessary to implement the requirements of this section.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs shall conduct or contract for an evaluation of the demonstration project. The department shall submit the evaluation to the Governor and the Legislature by January 1, 2007. The evaluation must address the effectiveness of the pilot project in providing a comprehensive system of appropriate and high-quality, long-term care services to elders in the least restrictive setting and make recommendations on expanding the project to other parts of the state. This subparagraph is subject to an appropriation by the Legislature.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, shall work with the fiscal agent for the Medicaid program to develop a service utilization reporting system that operates through the fiscal agent for the capitated plans.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the 2005-2006 state fiscal year:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, shall monitor the newly integrated programs and report on the progress of those programs to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by June 30, 2006. The report must include an initial evaluation of the programs in their early stages following the evaluation plan developed by the department, in consultation with the agency and the selected contractor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall monitor the pilot projects for resource centers on aging and report on the progress of those projects to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by June 30, 2006. The report must include an evaluation of the implementation process in its early stages.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, shall integrate the database systems for the Comprehensive Assessment and Review for Long-Term Care Services (CARES) program and the Client Information and Referral Tracking System (CIRTS) into a single operating assessment information system by June 30, 2006.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the 2006-2007 state fiscal year:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, shall evaluate the Alzheimer’s Disease waiver program and the Adult Day Health Care waiver program to assess whether providing limited intensive services through these waiver programs produces better outcomes for individuals than providing those services through the fee-for-service or capitated programs that provide a larger array of services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, shall begin discussions with the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services regarding the inclusion of Medicare into the integrated long-term care system. By December 31, 2006, the agency shall provide to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a plan for including Medicare in the integrated long-term care system.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 80-181; s. 272, ch. 81-259; s. 9, ch. 90-319; s. 33, ch. 95-418; s. 7, ch. 98-182; s. 99, ch. 2000-349; s. 18, ch. 2001-254; s. 9, ch. 2002-223; ss. 11, 79, ch. 2002-402; s. 3, ch. 2003-67; s. 21, ch. 2003-399; s. 3, ch. 2004-246; s. 7, ch. 2004-386; s. 73, ch. 2005-2; s. 1, ch. 2005-208; s. 4, ch. 2005-223.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 410.0241.</Text></Note></Section>