<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0430.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties and responsibilities of the Department of Elderly Affairs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer human services and long-term care programs, including programs funded under the federal Older Americans Act of 1965, as amended, and other programs that are assigned to it by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be responsible for ensuring that each area agency on aging operates in a manner to ensure that the elderly of this state receive the best services possible. The department shall rescind designation of an area agency on aging or take intermediate measures against the agency, including corrective action, unannounced special monitoring, temporary assumption of operation of one or more programs by the department, placement on probationary status, imposing a moratorium on agency action, imposing financial penalties for nonperformance, or other administrative action pursuant to chapter 120, if the department finds that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intentional or negligent act of the agency has materially affected the health, welfare, or safety of clients, or substantially and negatively affected the operation of an aging services program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency lacks financial stability sufficient to meet contractual obligations or that contractual funds have been misappropriated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency has committed multiple or repeated violations of legal and regulatory requirements or department standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency has failed to continue the provision or expansion of services after the declaration of a state of emergency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency has exceeded its authority or otherwise failed to adhere to the terms of its contract with the department or has exceeded its authority or otherwise failed to adhere to the provisions specifically provided by statute or rule adopted by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency has failed to properly determine client eligibility as defined by the department or efficiently manage program budgets.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency has failed to implement and maintain a department-approved client grievance resolution procedure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as an information clearinghouse at the state level, and assist local-level information and referral resources as a repository and means for the dissemination of information regarding all federal, state, and local resources for assistance to the elderly in the areas of, but not limited to, health, social welfare, long-term care, protective services, consumer protection, education and training, housing, employment, recreation, transportation, insurance, and retirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend guidelines for the development of roles for state agencies that provide services for the aging, review plans of agencies that provide such services, and relay the plans to the Governor and the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Governor and the Legislature an organizational framework for the planning, coordination, implementation, and evaluation of programs related to aging, with the purpose of expanding and improving programs and opportunities available to the state’s elderly population and enhancing a continuum of long-term care. This framework must ensure that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performance objectives are established.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program reviews are conducted statewide.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each major program related to aging is reviewed every 3 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program decisions reinforce the distinctive roles established for state agencies that provide aging services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the Governor and the Legislature regarding the need for and location of programs related to aging.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and coordinate aging research plans of all state agencies to ensure that research objectives address issues and needs of the state’s elderly population. The research activities that must be reviewed and coordinated by the department include, but are not limited to, contracts with academic institutions, development of educational and training curriculums, Alzheimer’s disease and other medical research, studies of long-term care and other personal assistance needs, and design of adaptive or modified living environments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review budget requests for programs related to aging to ensure the most cost-effective use of state funding for the state’s elderly population before submission to the Governor and the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request other departments that administer programs affecting the state’s elderly population to amend their plans, rules, policies, and research objectives as necessary to ensure that programs and other initiatives are coordinated and maximize the state’s efforts to address the needs of the elderly.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold public meetings regularly throughout the state to receive information and maximize the visibility of important issues relating to aging and the elderly.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct policy analysis and program evaluation studies assigned by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist the Governor, each Cabinet member, and members of the Legislature in conducting their responsibilities as they consider appropriate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Call upon appropriate agencies of state government for such assistance as is needed in the discharge of its duties. All agencies shall cooperate in assisting the department in carrying out its responsibilities as prescribed by this section. However, the law regarding confidentiality of information may not be violated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be designated as a state agency that is eligible to receive federal funds for adults who are eligible for assistance through the portion of the federal Child and Adult Care Food Program for adults, which is referred to as the Adult Care Food Program, and that is responsible for establishing and administering the program. The purpose of the Adult Care Food Program is to provide nutritious and wholesome meals and snacks for adults in nonresidential day care centers or residential treatment facilities. To ensure the quality and integrity of the program, the department shall develop standards and procedures that govern sponsoring organizations and adult day care centers. The department shall follow federal requirements and may adopt rules necessary to administer the program and implement relevant federal regulations, including 7 C.F.R. part 226. The rules may address, at a minimum, the program requirements and procedures identified in this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer all Medicaid waivers and programs relating to elders and their appropriations. The waivers include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Assisted Living for the Frail Elderly Waiver.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Aged and Disabled Adult Waiver.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Consumer-Directed Care Plus Program as defined in s. 409.221.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Long-Term Care Community-Based Diversion Pilot Project as described in s. 430.705.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Channeling Services Waiver for Frail Elders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall develop a transition plan for recipients receiving services in long-term care Medicaid waivers for elders or disabled adults on the date eligible plans become available in each recipient’s region defined in s. 409.981(2) to enroll those recipients in eligible plans. This subsection expires October 1, 2014.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 4, 41, ch. 89-294; ss. 5, 7, ch. 91-115; s. 80, ch. 95-418; s. 61, ch. 98-171; s. 206, ch. 99-8; s. 26, ch. 2000-263; s. 4, ch. 2004-386; s. 72, ch. 2005-2; s. 21, ch. 2006-28; s. 18, ch. 2009-55; s. 98, ch. 2010-5; s. 143, ch. 2010-102; s. 22, ch. 2011-135; s. 15, ch. 2012-33.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 410.505.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>