<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0430.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Implementation of a teaching nursing home pilot project.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “teaching nursing home” means a nursing home facility licensed under chapter 400 which contains a minimum of 170 licensed nursing home beds; has access to a resident senior population of sufficient size to support education, training, and research relating to geriatric care; and has a contractual relationship with a federally funded accredited geriatric research center in this state or operates in its own right a geriatric research center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall implement a comprehensive multidisciplinary program of geriatric education and research as a pilot project in a nursing home facility designated by the agency as a teaching nursing home. The program shall be established as a pilot project and shall be administered at the nursing home facility and other appropriate settings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall develop criteria for designating teaching nursing homes in consultation with advocates of the elderly, advocates of persons with disabilities, representatives of the nursing home industry, and representatives of the State University System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be designated as a teaching nursing home, a nursing home licensee must, at a minimum:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a comprehensive program of integrated senior services that include institutional services and community-based services;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in a nationally recognized accreditation program and hold a valid accreditation, such as the accreditation awarded by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations, or, at the time of initial designation, possess a Gold Seal Award as conferred by the state on its licensed nursing home;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been in business in this state for a minimum of 10 consecutive years;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate an active program in multidisciplinary education and research that relates to gerontology;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a formalized contractual relationship with at least one accredited health profession education program located in this state;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have senior staff members who hold formal faculty appointments at universities, which must include at least one accredited health profession education program; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain insurance coverage pursuant to s. 400.141(1)(s) or proof of financial responsibility in a minimum amount of $750,000. Such proof of financial responsibility may include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining an escrow account consisting of cash or assets eligible for deposit in accordance with s. 625.52; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining and maintaining pursuant to chapter 675 an unexpired, irrevocable, nontransferable and nonassignable letter of credit issued by any bank or savings association organized and existing under the laws of this state or any bank or savings association organized under the laws of the United States that has its principal place of business in this state or has a branch office which is authorized to receive deposits in this state. The letter of credit shall be used to satisfy the obligation of the facility to the claimant upon presentment of a final judgment indicating liability and awarding damages to be paid by the facility or upon presentment of a settlement agreement signed by all parties to the agreement when such final judgment or settlement is a result of a liability claim against the facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A teaching nursing home may be affiliated with a medical school within the state and a federally funded center of excellence in geriatric research and education. The purpose of such affiliations is to foster the development of methods for improving and expanding the capability of health care facilities to respond to the medical, psychological, and social needs of frail and elderly persons by providing the most effective and appropriate services. A teaching nursing home shall serve as a resource for research and for training health care professionals in providing health care services in institutional settings to frail and older persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature may provide an annual appropriation to the nursing home facility designated as a teaching nursing home.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order for a nursing home to qualify as a teaching nursing home under this section and to be entitled to the benefits provided under this section, the nursing home must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be primarily operated and established to offer, afford, and render a comprehensive multidisciplinary program of geriatric education and research to residents of the state; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certify to the Agency for Health Care Administration each school year the name, address, and educational history of each trainee approved and accepted for enrollment in the institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A teaching nursing home may not expend any of the funds received under this section for any purpose other than operating and maintaining a teaching nursing home and conducting geriatric research. In addition, a teaching nursing home may not expend any funds received under this section for constructing any building of any kind, nature, or description or for maintaining or operating, in any form or manner, a nursing home or health care facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 99-394; s. 30, ch. 2002-223; s. 65, ch. 2009-223; s. 1, ch. 2010-197.</History>
</Section>