<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0430.204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community-care-for-the-elderly core services; departmental powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall fund, through each area agency on aging, at least one community care service system the primary purpose of which is the prevention of unnecessary institutionalization of functionally impaired elderly persons through the provision of community-based core services. Whenever feasible, an area agency on aging shall be the contracting agency of preference to engage only in the planning and funding of community-care-for-the-elderly core services for functionally impaired elderly persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall fund, through each area agency on aging in each county as defined in s. 125.011(1), more than one community care service system the primary purpose of which is the prevention of unnecessary institutionalization of functionally impaired elderly persons through the provision of community-based core services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All existing community resources available to functionally impaired elderly persons shall be coordinated into a community care service system to provide a continuum of care to such persons as their needs change. Additional services may be provided, but may not be funded from the community-care-for-the-elderly core service funds. Agencies contracting with the department shall ensure that all other funding sources available have been used prior to utilizing community-care-for-the-elderly funds. The department and agencies contracting with the department may accept gifts and grants in order to provide services within a community care service area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of volunteers shall be maximized to provide a range of services for the functionally impaired elderly person. The department shall provide or arrange for the provision of training and supervision of volunteers to ensure the delivery of quality services. The department or contracting agency may provide appropriate insurance coverage to protect volunteers from personal liability while acting within the scope of their volunteer assignments under a community care service area. The coverage may also include excess automobile liability protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or contracting agency shall contract for the provision of the core services required by a community care service area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities contracting to provide core services under ss. 430.201-430.207 must provide a minimum of 10 percent of the funding necessary for the support of project operations. In-kind contributions, whether materials, commodities, transportation, office space, other types of facilities, or personal services, and contributions of money or services from functionally impaired elderly persons may be evaluated and counted as part or all of the required local funding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When possible, services shall be obtained under:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Plan for Medical Assistance under Title XIX of the Social Security Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Plan on Aging under the Older Americans Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated for community care for the elderly must be used only for the provision of community-care-for-the-elderly core services, case management, and directly related expenditures. The department may provide advance funding for the community-care-for-the-elderly program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provider agencies are responsible for the collection of fees for services in accordance with rules adopted by the department. Provider agencies shall assess fees for services rendered in accordance with those rules. To help pay for services received from community care for the elderly, a functionally impaired elderly person shall be assessed a fee based on an overall ability to pay. The fee to be assessed shall be fixed according to a schedule established by the department in cooperation with area agencies, lead agencies, and service providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall evaluate the delivery of services within community care service areas. Accurate analysis of the costs and benefits associated with the establishment and operation of the programs as determined through a uniform cost accounting and reporting system shall be maintained to provide an assessment of the ability of these programs to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the rate of inappropriate entry and placement of functionally impaired elderly persons in institutions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the use of institutional services and facilities; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend legislative and administrative action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 73-343; s. 1, ch. 76-51; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 18, ch. 78-433; s. 4, ch. 80-181; s. 10, ch. 81-271; s. 21, ch. 84-254; s. 18, ch. 86-220; s. 17, ch. 93-200; s. 32, ch. 95-418; s. 8, ch. 2000-337; s. 17, ch. 2001-254; ss. 10, 79, ch. 2002-402; s. 20, ch. 2003-399; s. 2, ch. 2004-246.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 409.3624; s. 410.024.</Text></Note></Section>