<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0023.1231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Mutual Aid Plan; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Mutual Aid Plan must prepare for the distribution and allocation of state resources, including the Florida National Guard, in support of the overall law enforcement mission. The plan shall be administered by the Department of Law Enforcement to implement the policy and purposes set forth in s. 23.121.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement acting under the Governor as the state’s chief law enforcement officer is the director of the Florida Mutual Aid Plan. The director of the Florida Mutual Aid Plan shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate, integrate, and implement law enforcement planning and activities for the use of mutual aid and state resources;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate the organization and direction of the law enforcement services of the Florida Mutual Aid Plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate and implement the gathering and collection of information and intelligence relating to law enforcement mutual aid or assistance from state agencies to support local law enforcement agencies in any local disaster or emergency, and provide information to state and local law enforcement agencies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During a state of emergency declared by the Governor under chapter 252, command, control, and coordinate all state law enforcement personnel and equipment to support local law enforcement agencies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as the liaison with the Division of the Florida Highway Patrol of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles in order to coordinate and integrate plans for traffic control and the participation of the department in the law enforcement operation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as liaison and guide the flow of requests from local law enforcement for requesting law enforcement services from the Florida National Guard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as liaison to the Governor, federal and state departments and agencies, and local law enforcement officials in order to achieve close coordination and cooperation in planning and operations in trouble areas;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guide the flow of law enforcement information from federal and state organizations to local law enforcement officials;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as liaison to the Attorney General in order to keep him or her informed of changes in law enforcement plans and regulations, mutual aid agreements, and current developments in all situations from a legal standpoint; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do other things necessary for the implementation of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain an inventory of all state and local law enforcement resources and the resources of the Florida National Guard, as directed by the director of the Florida Mutual Aid Plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance to state and local agencies in making inventories of their resources, planning, and preparing mutual aid agreements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Draft rules for mutual aid agreements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct surveys as necessary to carry out the purposes of this part; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do other things necessary for the implementation of this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 81-142; s. 2, ch. 87-380; s. 5, ch. 92-165; s. 3, ch. 93-211; s. 87, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>