<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0023.1225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mutual aid agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “mutual aid agreement,” as used in this part, refers to one of the following types of agreement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voluntary cooperation written agreement between two or more law enforcement agencies, which agreement permits voluntary cooperation and assistance of a routine law enforcement nature across jurisdictional lines. The agreement must specify the nature of the law enforcement assistance to be rendered, the agency or entity that shall bear any liability arising from acts undertaken under the agreement, the procedures for requesting and for authorizing assistance, the agency or entity that has command and supervisory responsibility, a time limit for the agreement, the amount of any compensation or reimbursement to the assisting agency or entity, and any other terms and conditions necessary to give it effect. Examples of law enforcement activities that may be addressed in a voluntary cooperation written agreement include, but are not limited to, establishing a joint city-county task force on narcotics smuggling, authorizing school safety officers to enforce laws in an area within 1,000 feet of a school or school board property, authorizing state university police officers to enforce laws within a specified jurisdictional area as agreed upon in the voluntary cooperation written agreement, or establishing a joint city-county traffic enforcement task force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A requested operational assistance written agreement between two or more law enforcement agencies, which agreement is for the rendering of assistance in a law enforcement emergency. The agreement must specify the nature of the law enforcement assistance to be rendered, the agency or entity that shall bear any liability arising from acts undertaken under the agreement, the procedures for requesting and for authorizing assistance, the agency or entity that has command and supervisory responsibility, a time limit for the agreement, the amount of any compensation or reimbursement to the assisting agency or entity, and any other terms and conditions necessary to give it effect. An example of the use of a requested operational assistance written agreement is to meet a request for assistance due to a civil disturbance or other emergency as defined in s. 252.34.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A combination of the agreements described in paragraphs (a) and (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “law enforcement agency” means any agency or unit of government that has authority to employ or appoint law enforcement officers, as defined in s. 943.10(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mutual aid agreement may allow for discretion by the parties as to when, whether, and to what extent assistance will be available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mutual aid agreement may be entered into by a law enforcement agency through a written agreement executed by the chief executive officer of the agency, who is authorized to contractually bind the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of a mutual aid agreement must be filed with the Department of Law Enforcement within 14 days after it is signed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a disaster or emergency such that a state of emergency is declared by the Governor pursuant to chapter 252, the requirement that a requested operational assistance agreement be a written agreement for rendering of assistance in a law enforcement emergency may be waived by the participating agencies for a period of up to 90 days from the declaration of the disaster.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a law enforcement agency lends assistance pursuant to this subsection, all powers, privileges, and immunities listed in s. 23.127, except with regard to interstate mutual aid agreements, apply to the agency or entity, if the law enforcement employees rendering services are being requested and coordinated by the affected local law enforcement executive in charge of law enforcement operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A listing of such agencies or entities and the officers and employees of such agencies or entities rendering assistance pursuant to this subsection must be maintained by the agency or entity requesting such assistance and filed at the end of the 90-day period with the Florida Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 81-142; s. 7, ch. 83-217; s. 1, ch. 83-334; s. 1, ch. 87-380; s. 3, ch. 92-165; s. 2, ch. 93-211; s. 1, ch. 96-276; s. 1, ch. 98-183; s. 3, ch. 2000-369; s. 882, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-153; s. 1, ch. 2009-216.</History></Section>