<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0663.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liquidation; continuation, stay, and injunction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, the office’s taking of possession of any international banking corporation and the liquidation of the corporation shall operate as a stay of and as an injunction against, as of the date the office takes possession of the corporation and applicable to all persons or entities:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement or continuation, including the issuance or employment of process, of a judicial, administrative, or other action or proceeding against the corporation that was or could have been commenced before the taking of possession, or to cover a claim against the corporation that arose before the taking of possession.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enforcement against the corporation, or the business and property of the corporation in this state, of a judgment obtained before the taking of possession.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act to obtain possession of property of the corporation or of property from the corporation or to exercise control over property of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act to create, perfect, or enforce any lien against property of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act to create, perfect, or enforce against property of the corporation any lien to the extent that such lien secures a claim that arose before the taking of possession.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act to collect, assess, or recover a claim against the corporation and the liquidation of the corporation does not operate as a stay of or as an injunction against the claim.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office’s taking of possession of an international banking corporation and the liquidation of the corporation does not operate as a stay of or as an injunction against:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a claim in the liquidation of the corporation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making of a demand upon the office to assume or repudiate a contract of the corporation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exercise of any setoff otherwise permissible under applicable law except limited by s. 663.17;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of any secured creditor with a perfected security interest or other valid lien or security interest enforceable against third parties to retain collateral, including any right of such secured creditor under any security agreement related to a qualified financial contract as defined in s. 663.17 to retain collateral and to apply such collateral in accordance with s. 663.173;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any automatic termination in accordance with the terms of any qualified financial contract or any right to cause the termination or liquidation of any qualified financial contract, as defined in this part in accordance with the terms of such contract;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any right to offset or net out any termination value, payment amount, or other transfer obligation arising under or in connection with one or more such qualified financial contracts; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement of an action under s. 663.181 or any other action relating to the liquidation of the corporation before the court of competent jurisdiction overseeing the liquidation of the corporation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement or continuation of a criminal action or proceeding against the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement or continuation of an action or proceeding pursuant to a governmental unit’s police or regulatory power.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enforcement of a judgment, other than money judgment, obtained in an action or proceeding by a governmental unit to enforce such governmental unit’s police or regulatory power.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance to the corporation by a governmental unit of a notice of tax deficiency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement or continuation of a judicial action or proceeding by a secured creditor with a perfected security interest, or other valid lien or security interest enforceable against third parties, including any right of such secured creditor under any security arrangement related to a qualified financial contract to enforce such interest or lien.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The staying or enjoining of an act against property of an international banking corporation under this section shall continue until such property is no longer the property of the office in possession of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The staying or enjoining of any other act under this section shall continue until the office has concluded liquidating the corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For good cause shown, on request of a party in interest and after notice and hearing, a court of competent jurisdiction overseeing the liquidation of an international banking corporation may grant relief from a stay or injunction provided under this section, including, but not limited to, terminating, annulling, modifying, or conditioning such stay or injunction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any willful violation of a stay or injunction provided in this section by any person who has knowledge of the office’s taking of possession of an international banking corporation that is the subject of the stay or injunction, the office shall recover actual damages, including costs and fees and, in appropriate circumstances, may recover punitive damages.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 97-109; s. 1838, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>