<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0663.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for authority to organize an international development bank.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written application for authority to organize an international development bank shall be filed with the office by the proposed incorporator and shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, residence, and occupation of each incorporator and proposed director.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total initial capital and the number of shares of capital stock to be authorized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location, by street and post office address and county, of the principal office of the proposed international development bank.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If known, the name and residence of the proposed president and the proposed chief executive officer, if other than the proposed president.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such detailed financial, business, and biographical information as the commission or office may reasonably require for each proposed director and for the proposed president and the proposed chief executive officer, if other than the president.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be in such form as adopted by the commission and shall contain such additional information as the commission or office may require and shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable filing fee of $2,500.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 86-82; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 1, ch. 92-303; s. 1847, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2004-340; s. 105, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>