<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0663.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicability of state banking laws.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">International banking corporations having offices in this state shall be subject to all the provisions of the financial institutions codes and chapter 655 as though such international banking corporations were state banks or trust companies, except where it may appear, from the context or otherwise, that such provisions are clearly applicable only to banks or trust companies organized under the laws of this state or the United States. Without limiting the foregoing general provisions, it is the intent of the Legislature that the following provisions are applicable to such banks or trust companies: s. 655.031, relating to administrative enforcement guidelines; s. 655.032, relating to investigations, subpoenas, hearings, and witnesses; s. 655.0321, relating to hearings, proceedings, and related documents and restricted access thereto; s. 655.033, relating to cease and desist orders; s. 655.037, relating to removal by the office of an officer, director, committee member, employee, or other person; s. 655.041, relating to administrative fines and enforcement; s. 655.50, relating to control of money laundering; s. 658.49, relating to loans by banks not exceeding $50,000; and any provision of law for which the penalty is increased under s. 775.31 for facilitating or furthering terrorism. International banking corporations shall not have the powers conferred on domestic banks by the provisions of s. 658.60, relating to deposits of public funds. The provisions of chapter 687, relating to interest and usury, shall apply to all loans not subject to s. 658.49.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither an international bank agency nor an international branch shall have any greater right under, or by virtue of, this section than is granted to banks organized under the laws of this state. Legal and financial terms used herein shall be deemed to refer to equivalent terms used by the country in which the international banking corporation is organized. This chapter and the financial institutions codes may not be construed to authorize any international banking corporation or trust company to conduct trust business, as defined in s. 658.12, from an office in this state except for those activities specifically authorized by ss. 663.061(5) and 663.0625.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-157; ss. 83, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 83-129; s. 21, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 3, 151, ch. 92-303; s. 414, ch. 96-406; s. 5, ch. 97-109; s. 15, ch. 2001-64; s. 1815, ch. 2003-261; s. 130, ch. 2005-2; s. 3, ch. 2010-9.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 659.67(2).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>