<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0663.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permissible activities; prohibited activities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An international development bank shall have the authority:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make loans or otherwise extend credit to foreign business enterprises and foreign governments and to issue and confirm letters of credit, create bankers acceptances, and provide guarantees for the purpose of providing financing to foreign business enterprises and foreign governments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide financing in connection with import-export transactions to the extent permissible for an Edge Act corporation organized under s. 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act, as amended, 12 U.S.C. ss. 611-632;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To invest funds as provided in s. 663.315;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To borrow funds as provided in s. 663.316;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To take deposits from financial institutions, foreign not-for-profit foundations, foreign business enterprises, and organizations which qualify under s. 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code and which had at the end of their last fiscal year no less than $10 million in assets;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To maintain for the account of others credit balances necessarily incidental to, or arising out of, the exercise of its lawful powers. Such credit balances may be disbursed by check or draft; however, the commission shall by rule provide appropriate limitations upon such disbursements to ensure that credit balances are not functionally equivalent to demand deposits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exercise such other incidental powers as shall be reasonably necessary to carry out the authority granted in this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An international development bank shall not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take deposits except as provided in this section;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer deposit accounts other than those permitted to be offered by an international bank agency;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise trust or fiduciary powers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer credit cards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish or use remote financial service units; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a depository of public moneys or be employed as a financial agent of the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 86-82; s. 4, ch. 89-110; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 173, ch. 92-303; s. 1851, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>