<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0766.1015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil immunity for members of or consultants to certain boards, committees, or other entities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of, or health care professional consultant to, any committee, board, group, commission, or other entity shall be immune from civil liability for any act, decision, omission, or utterance done or made in performance of his or her duties while serving as a member of or consultant to such committee, board, group, commission, or other entity established and operated for purposes of quality improvement review, evaluation, and planning in a state-licensed health care facility. Such entities must function primarily to review, evaluate, or make recommendations relating to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of patient stays in health care facilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The professional services furnished with respect to the medical, dental, psychological, podiatric, chiropractic, or optometric necessity for such services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of promoting the most efficient use of available health care facilities and services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adequacy or quality of professional services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The competency and qualifications for professional staff privileges;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonableness or appropriateness of charges made by or on behalf of health care facilities; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patient safety, including entering into contracts with patient safety organizations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such committee, board, group, commission, or other entity must be established in accordance with state law or in accordance with requirements of the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations, established and duly constituted by one or more public or licensed private hospitals or behavioral health agencies, or established by a governmental agency. To be protected by this section, the act, decision, omission, or utterance may not be made or done in bad faith or with malicious intent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2003-416; s. 2, ch. 2004-7.</History></Section>