<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0766.1116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health care practitioner; waiver of license renewal fees and continuing education requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “health care practitioner” means a physician or physician assistant licensed under chapter 458; an osteopathic physician or physician assistant licensed under chapter 459; a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460; a podiatric physician licensed under chapter 461; an advanced registered nurse practitioner, registered nurse, or licensed practical nurse licensed under part I of chapter 464; a dentist or dental hygienist licensed under chapter 466; or a midwife licensed under chapter 467, who participates as a health care provider under s. 766.1115.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, part I of chapter 464, chapter 466, or chapter 467 to the contrary, any health care practitioner who participates as a health care provider under s. 766.1115 and thereby agrees with a governmental contractor to provide his or her services without compensation and as an agent of the governmental contractor to low-income recipients in accordance with s. 766.1115 for at least 160 hours for each biennial licensure period, or, if the health care practitioner is retired, for at least 800 hours during the licensure period, upon providing sufficient proof from the applicable governmental contractor that the health care practitioner has completed the hours at the time of license renewal under procedures specified by the Department of Health, shall be eligible for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waiver of the biennial license renewal fee for an active license; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fulfillment of a maximum of 25 percent of the continuing education hours required for license renewal under s. 456.013(9).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2004-54; s. 4, ch. 2009-41.</History></Section>