<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0766.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings and intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature makes the following findings:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physicians practicing obstetrics are high-risk medical specialists for whom malpractice insurance premiums are very costly, and recent increases in such premiums have been greater for such physicians than for other physicians.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any birth other than a normal birth frequently leads to a claim against the attending physician; consequently, such physicians are among the physicians most severely affected by current medical malpractice problems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because obstetric services are essential, it is incumbent upon the Legislature to provide a plan designed to result in the stabilization and reduction of malpractice insurance premiums for providers of such services in Florida.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of birth-related neurological injury claims are particularly high and warrant the establishment of a limited system of compensation irrespective of fault. The issue of whether such claims are covered by this act must be determined exclusively in an administrative proceeding.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to provide compensation, on a no-fault basis, for a limited class of catastrophic injuries that result in unusually high costs for custodial care and rehabilitation. This plan shall apply only to birth-related neurological injuries.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 60, ch. 88-1; s. 1, ch. 98-113.</History></Section>