<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Land acquisitions financed by Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund moneys.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After July 1, 1986, moneys paid into the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund may be used by the department:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For acquisition of those lands identified pursuant to subsection (5) for hunting, fishing, wildlife habitat restoration, or other outdoor recreational purposes, including the construction of trails, provided such land acquisition is consistent with this section; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For acquisition and reclamation of those lands which will serve the public interest because of the exceptional need to accomplish the particular reclamation and restoration if the owner is unable or unwilling to restore or reclaim the land in accordance with the master reclamation plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may purchase an interest in land which is less than a fee interest, so long as the fee will vest in the state upon the occurrence of an event or date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount not to exceed 1 percent of the uncommitted trust fund balance, exclusive of funds available pursuant to s. 378.034(7), at the beginning of the fiscal year may be used by the designated manager of lands acquired by the state pursuant to this section for management purposes and for reclamation of such lands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands acquired under paragraph (1)(b) may be reclaimed by the department pursuant to this act. If the lands are not needed for a public purpose, the lands shall be sold at public sale for a price which is not less than the amounts expended for purchase and reclamation. The moneys received from the sale shall be deposited into the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By July 1, 1986, the department, in cooperation with the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, shall develop a list identifying those nonmandatory lands which have been or may be naturally reclaimed or which the state may seek to acquire through purchase or donation for hunting, fishing, wildlife habitat restoration, or other outdoor recreational purposes, including the construction of trails. The list shall separately indicate which of the nonmandatory lands are eligible lands.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 84-330; s. 318, ch. 94-356; s. 198, ch. 99-245; s. 3, ch. 2000-176; s. 5, ch. 2003-423; s. 13, ch. 2005-87.</History></Section>