<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.037" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chief Financial Officer; responsibilities and duties with respect to reimbursement of reclamation costs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall reimburse approved reclamation costs, less any amount reasonably retained to ensure completion of the approved reclamation program, subject to the following limitations:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A landowner shall not be entitled to payments in excess of the funds available in the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cost reimbursement shall not exceed the least of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount actually expended and reasonably necessary to effect the reclamation consistent with the standards of the approved master reclamation plan;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reclamation contract amount; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount allowed based on prereclamation land form, to include mined-out areas at $4,000 per reclaimed acre and clay settling areas and other land forms at $2,500 per reclaimed acre adjusted annually by the appropriate inflationary index for construction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall adopt rules to implement the payment provisions of the master reclamation plan and this section, including, but not limited to, periodic reimbursements and competitive procurement of services and commodities to the extent practicable, unless a landowner elects to utilize his or her own personnel and equipment. The landowner may select a method of reimbursement from the alternatives adopted by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 84-330; s. 637, ch. 95-148; s. 402, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>