<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.407" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative of the department may at any reasonable time enter and inspect, for the purpose of ascertaining the state of compliance with the law or rules of the department, any property, premises, or place, except a building which is used exclusively for a private residence, on which a reclamation operation is or will be conducted or where records required by this part or rule are kept.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative of the department may, during normal business hours, have access to and copy any records required under this part and may obtain any other information and samples necessary to determine compliance with the requirements of this part or rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duly authorized representative of the department shall comply with all federal, state, and local safety standards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or operator of the premises shall receive a report setting forth all facts found which relate to compliance status.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon completion of reclamation of an area, the operator shall notify the secretary. The secretary may make an inspection of the area, and if he or she finds that reclamation has been properly completed, the secretary shall notify the operator in writing and release him or her from further obligations regarding that land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If upon the receipt of the notification the secretary determines that an inspection will not be conducted within an operating year, the operator shall be released from the reclamation requirements upon the completion of the second operating year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 328, ch. 94-356; s. 1025, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>