<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Timing of reclamation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation should be completed within 2 years after the completion of mining operations, exclusive of a growing season required to ensure establishment of vegetation. For purposes of this section, completion of reclamation occurs when initial revegetation is completed and not at the time of final release of the reclamation area. For the purpose of s. 378.208, the schedule for complete reclamation is as prescribed in paragraphs (a)-(e).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the period July 1, 1975, to December 31, 1980, for existing mines or the first 5-year period of mining for new mines, reclamation may not be required, and any reclamation that is completed must be credited forward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the period January 1, 1981, to December 31, 1985, for existing mines or the second 5-year period of mining for new mines, reclamation of acres mined must be completed at the rate of an acreage equivalent of 15 percent of the acres mined during the period July 1, 1975, to December 31, 1980, or the immediately preceding 5-year period, as appropriate. Reclamation in excess of the required percentage must be credited forward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the period January 1, 1986, to December 31, 1990, for existing mines or the third 5-year period of mining for new mines, reclamation of acres mined must be completed at the rate of an acreage equivalent of 60 percent of the acres mined during the period January 1, 1981, to December 31, 1985, or the immediately preceding 5-year period, as appropriate. Reclamation in excess of the required percentage must be credited forward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the period January 1, 1991, to December 31, 1995, for existing mines or the fourth 5-year period of mining for new mines, reclamation of acres mined must be completed at the rate of an acreage equivalent of 75 percent of the acres mined during the period January 1, 1986, to December 31, 1990, or the immediately preceding 5-year period, as appropriate. Reclamation in excess of the required percentage must be credited forward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the period January 1, 1996, to December 31, 2000, for existing mines or the fifth 5-year period of mining for new mines, and each 5-year period thereafter, reclamation of acres mined must be completed at the rate of an acreage equivalent of 100 percent of acres mined during the immediately preceding 5-year period. Reclamation in excess of the required percentage must be credited forward.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate of mining during any 5-year period is to be determined solely by the operator and not the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time periods and reclamation rates specified in this section may be modified or waived for experimental reclamation programs, to take into account the effect of temporary shutdown of mining operations or other physical restraints, for unreasonable delays in the processing of reclamation applications by the department, or to relieve or prevent extreme economic hardship on the operator.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 507, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>