<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.703" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fuller’s earth clay reclamation performance standards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All reclamation activities shall, to the extent feasible, be coordinated with resource extraction and in any event shall be initiated at the earliest practicable time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation activities shall be consistent with all applicable local government ordinances at least as stringent as the criteria and standards contained in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation activities shall be conducted in a manner which has no long-term adverse impact on surface and groundwater resources, wildlife, and adjacent lands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drainage systems, wetlands, and other surface waters shall function in manners which are not significantly different from those which existed prior to resource extraction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation shall achieve the stormwater requirements of the appropriate water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule the reclamation sloping requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator shall use best management practices to minimize erosion, including revegetation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plans for revegetation shall incorporate measures to offset wildlife habitat lost as a result of resource extraction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation shall provide for the establishment of flora and fauna which are consistent with intended land use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation and restoration shall result in landforms which are capable of supporting diverse and beneficial land uses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exceptions to the criteria and standards contained in this section may be granted by the secretary for experimental or innovative techniques.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reclamation of the land, including a complete growing season for revegetation, shall be completed within 3 years of the completion of the mining operations associated with the resource extraction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 337, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>