<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Committee; creation; composition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Committee is created within the department to serve as an advisory body on matters relating to nonmandatory land reclamation. The committee shall be composed of five members appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the Cabinet. In making the appointments, the Governor shall consider the needs of the program for engineering, fiscal, reclamation, and environmental expertises. Three of the committee members shall be selected respectively from Hamilton County, Polk County, and Hillsborough County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to achieve staggered terms, of those members first appointed, two members shall be appointed for terms of 2 years each, and three members shall be appointed for terms of 4 years each. Thereafter, a member of the committee shall serve a 4-year term or until his or her successor is appointed. A member of the committee is eligible for reappointment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy on the committee shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. A single vacancy on the committee will not impair the right of the remaining members to exercise the powers of the committee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the committee shall select a chair, whose office shall rotate among the members of the committee annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The committee shall meet at least annually at the call of the chair. The presence of four members is required to constitute a quorum; a vote of three members is necessary for committee action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committee members shall serve without pay. However, members shall be reimbursed from the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund for per diem and travel expenses pursuant to ss. 20.05 and 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 11, ch. 84-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 85-65; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 316, ch. 94-356; s. 1023, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>