<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means an official, committee, department, commission, officer, division, authority, bureau, council, board, section, or unit of government within the state, including a county, municipal, or other local or regional entity or special district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Annual report” means a detailed report, including maps and aerial photographs, submitted for each mine, which describes and delineates mining operations and reclamation or restoration activities undertaken in the previous calendar year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Existing mine” means any area upon which an operation is being conducted, or has been conducted, on October 1, 1986.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Extraction” or “resource extraction” means the removal of resources from their location so as to make them suitable for commercial, industrial, or construction use; but does not include excavation solely in aid of onsite farming or onsite construction, nor the process of searching, prospecting, exploring, or investigating for resources by drilling.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fuller’s earth clay” means clay possessing a high absorptive capacity consisting largely of montmorillonite or palygorskite. Fuller’s earth clay includes attapulgite.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Heavy minerals” means those resources found in conjunction with sand deposits which have a specific gravity of not less than 2.8, and includes an admixture of such resources as zircon, staurolite, and titanium minerals as generally mined in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limestone” means any extracted material composed principally of calcium or magnesium carbonate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means any county or municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mine” means an area of land upon which mining operations have been conducted, are being conducted, or are planned to be conducted, as the term is commonly used in the trade.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New mine” means any mine that is not an existing mine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operation” means any activity, other than prospecting, necessary for site preparation, extraction, waste disposal, storage, or reclamation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operator” means any person engaged in an operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Overburden” means soil and rock removed to gain access to the resource in the process of extraction and means such soil or rock before or after its removal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Peat” means a naturally occurring substance derived primarily from plant materials in a range of decomposing conditions and formed in a water-saturated environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reclamation” means the reasonable rehabilitation of land where resource extraction has occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resource” means soil, clay, peat, stone, gravel, sand, limerock, metallic ore, or any other solid substance of commercial value found in natural deposits on or in the earth, except phosphate, which is regulated by part III.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the Secretary of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wetlands” means any area as defined in s. 373.019, as delineated using the methodology adopted by rule and ratified pursuant to s. 373.421(1). For areas included in an approved conceptual reclamation plan or modification application submitted prior to July 1, 1994, wetlands means any area having dominant vegetation as defined and listed in rule 62-301.200, Florida Administrative Code, regardless of whether the area is within the department’s jurisdiction or whether the water bodies are connected.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 324, ch. 94-356; s. 4, ch. 95-215; s. 5, ch. 2007-191; s. 39, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>