<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Acres mined” means all acres on which mining operations have resulted in extraction of phosphate rock.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Annual report” means a detailed report, including maps and aerial photographs, submitted for each mine, which describes and delineates mining operations and reclamation or restoration activities undertaken in the previous calendar year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conceptual reclamation plan” means a graphic and written description of general activities to be undertaken across the whole mine to comply with the reclamation standards and criteria contained in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mine” means an area of land upon which mining operations have been conducted, are being conducted, or are planned to be conducted, as the term is commonly used in the trade.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mining operations” means those physical activities, other than prospecting and site preparation, which are necessary for extraction, waste disposal, storage, or dam maintenance prior to abandonment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New mine,” as used in s. 378.209, means a mine for which the operator first became obligated to pay a severance tax for the extraction of minerals therefrom after July 1, 1975.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operator” means the person engaged, or seeking to be engaged, in the severance of solid minerals, or any other person who is obligated to reclaim mined lands pursuant to s. 211.32(1). For purposes of s. 378.208 relating to financial responsibility, the term “operator” includes a parent, its subsidiary, or division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reclamation” means the reshaping of lands in a manner that meets the reclamation criteria and standards contained in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Restoration” means the recontouring and revegetation of lands in a manner, consistent with the criteria and standards established under this part, which will maintain or improve the water quality and function of the biological systems present at the site prior to mining. In requiring restoration of an area, the department must recognize technological limitations and economic considerations. For example, restoration must be considered accomplished when immature trees are used; mature trees are not required to be replanted in areas where mature trees were removed to allow mining.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Revegetation” means, in reclaimed areas, a cover of vegetation consistent with the criteria and standards established pursuant to this part and consistent with the land form created and the future land uses. In restored areas, it means a cover of vegetation that is designed to return the restored area to the condition in existence prior to mining.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the Secretary of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; ss. 319, 505, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>