<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0378.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Master reclamation plan.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall amend the master reclamation plan that provides guidelines for the reclamation of lands mined or disturbed by the severance of phosphate rock prior to July 1, 1975, which lands are not subject to mandatory reclamation under part II of chapter 211. In amending the master reclamation plan, the Department of Environmental Protection shall continue to conduct an onsite evaluation of all lands mined or disturbed by the severance of phosphate rock prior to July 1, 1975, which lands are not subject to mandatory reclamation under part II of chapter 211. The master reclamation plan when amended by the Department of Environmental Protection shall be consistent with local government plans prepared pursuant to the Community Planning Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amended master reclamation plan shall identify which of the lands mined or disturbed by the severance of phosphate rock prior to July 1, 1975, meet the following criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quality of surface waters leaving the land does not meet applicable water quality standards, if any; or, health and safety hazards exist on the land; or, the soil has not stabilized and revegetated; or, the remaining natural resources associated with the land are not being conserved;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The environmental or economic utility or aesthetic value of the land would not naturally return within a reasonable time, and reclamation would substantially promote the environmental or economic utility or the aesthetic value of the land;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reclamation of the land is in the public interest because the reclamation, when combined with other reclamation under the master plan, would provide a substantial regional benefit; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reclamation of the land is in the public interest because the reclamation, when combined with other reclamation under the master plan, will provide significant benefits to surface water bodies supplying water for environmental and public purposes in those areas of the state where phosphate mining has been permitted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands evaluated by the department under subsection (1) which meet the criteria set forth in subsection (2) shall be identified with specificity in the master reclamation plan. Lands evaluated by the department under subsection (1) which do not meet the criteria set forth in subsection (2) shall also be identified with specificity in the master reclamation plan as lands which are acceptable in their present form.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon adoption of the amendments to the master reclamation plan as a rule, such plan shall provide the guidelines for approval of reclamation programs for lands covered in the plan, recognizing that reclamation of such lands is not mandatory, but that any payment of costs expended for reclamation paid under s. 378.031 shall be contingent upon conformity with the guidelines set forth in the master reclamation plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 78-136; s. 32, ch. 85-55; s. 2, ch. 2003-423; s. 38, ch. 2009-21; s. 52, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>