<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality of records; availability of information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information relating to prospecting, rock grades, or secret processes or methods of operation which may be required, ascertained, or discovered by inspection or investigation shall be exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1), shall not be disclosed in public hearings, and shall be kept confidential by any member, officer, or employee of the department, if the applicant requests the department to keep such information confidential and informs the department of the basis for such confidentiality. Should the secretary determine that such information requested to be kept confidential shall not be kept confidential, the secretary shall provide the operator with not less than 30 days’ notice of his or her intent to release the information. When making his or her determination, the secretary shall consider the public purposes specified in <Reference Number="1" />s. 119.14(4)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the use of such records in judicial proceedings when ordered to be produced by appropriate subpoena or by order of the court. No such subpoena or order of the court shall abridge or alter the rights or remedies of persons affected in the protection of trade secrets or secret processes in the manner provided by law, and such person affected may take any and all steps available by law to protect such trade secrets or processes. This section shall not prevent the department from providing such information to other agencies if the information is necessary to prepare the reports and studies required by this part. Agencies receiving such information shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (1), the department shall make available for public inspection and copying, during regular office hours, any information filed or submitted pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary may charge a fee to cover the actual cost of duplicating the information filed or submitted pursuant to this part. “Actual cost of duplicating” means the cost of material and supplies used to duplicate the record, but it does not include the labor cost or overhead cost associated with such duplication.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees charged for duplication of public records shall be deposited and accounted for in the manner prescribed for other operating funds of the agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 14, ch. 89-117; s. 3, ch. 91-114; s. 327, ch. 94-356; s. 1024, ch. 95-148; s. 183, ch. 96-406.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 1, ch. 95-217.</Text></Note></Section>