<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0378.411" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification to receive notices of intent to mine, to review, and to inspect for compliance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By petition to the secretary, a local government may request certification to receive notices of intent to mine, to review, and to conduct compliance inspections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In deciding whether to grant certification to a local government, the secretary shall determine whether the following criteria are being met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petitioning local government has adopted and effectively implemented a local government comprehensive plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government has adequate review procedures and the financial and staffing resources necessary to assume responsibility for adequate review and inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government has a record of effectively reviewing, inspecting, and enforcing compliance with local ordinances and state laws.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making his or her determination, the secretary shall consult with the Department of Economic Opportunity, the appropriate regional planning council, and the appropriate water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary shall evaluate the performance of a local government on a regular basis to ensure compliance with this section. All or part of the certification may be rescinded if the secretary determines that the certification is not being carried out pursuant to the requirements of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish the certification procedure by rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-294; s. 331, ch. 94-356; s. 1026, ch. 95-148; s. 117, ch. 99-385; s. 255, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>