<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0562.165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Production of beer or wine for personal or family use; exemption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary, a person who is not prohibited by s. 562.111 from possessing alcoholic beverages may produce beer for personal or family use, and not for sale, in the amounts provided in this section without payment of taxes or fees or without a license. The aggregate amount of such beer permitted to be produced with respect to any household shall be as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not in excess of 200 gallons per calendar year if there are two or more such persons in such household.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not in excess of 100 gallons per calendar year if there is only one such person in such household.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary, a person who is not prohibited by s. 562.111 from possessing alcoholic beverages may produce wine for personal or family use, and not for sale, in the amounts provided in this section without payment of taxes or fees or without a license. The aggregate amount of such wine permitted to be produced with respect to any household shall be as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not in excess of 200 gallons per calendar year if there are two or more such persons in such household.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not in excess of 100 gallons per calendar year if there is only one such person in such household.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any personal or family production of beer or wine in excess of the amount permitted in this section or any sale of such alcoholic beverages constitutes a violation of the Beverage Law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wine and beer made under the provisions of this section may be removed from the premises where made for personal or family use, including use at organized affairs, exhibitions, or competitions, such as homemakers’ contests, tastings, or judgings. Wine or beer used under this subsection shall not be sold or offered for sale.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-365; s. 48, ch. 83-216.</History></Section>