<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0562.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Donation of forfeited beverages or raw materials to state institutions; sale of forfeited beverages.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any alcoholic beverage or raw materials used for the manufacture of alcoholic beverages that may be seized and forfeited under any of the provisions of the Beverage Law may, with the approval and consent of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, be donated to any state-operated or charitable institution that may have a legitimate use therefor in the operation of such institution, or the division may sell such beverage so seized and forfeited to any licensed wholesaler in the state, upon the condition that all federal and state taxes that may be due thereon shall be paid, that such sale shall be made only upon submission by said division of a request for bids to at least five wholesale dealers in the state, and that such sale shall be made to the highest and best bidder therefor. However, if no satisfactory bid from a wholesaler is received, the division may then reject all bids and sell such beverage so seized and forfeited to any retailer, licensed in this state to sell such beverage, upon the condition that all federal and state taxes that may be due thereon shall have been paid, that such sale shall be made only upon submission by said division of a request for bids to at least five retail dealers in the state and that such sale shall be to the highest and best bidder therefor. All moneys received from such sales shall be paid by the division to the Chief Financial Officer for the account of the beverage fund and shall be subject to disbursement in accordance with the law relating thereto.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 19301, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(271aa); s. 8, ch. 22669, 1945; s. 1, ch. 57-327; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 72-230; s. 31, ch. 79-4; s. 220, ch. 94-218; s. 732, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>