<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0562.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Searches; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any authorized employee of the division, any sheriff, any deputy sheriff, or any police officer may make searches of persons, places, and conveyances of any kind whatsoever in accordance with the laws of this state for the purpose of determining whether or not the provisions of the Beverage Law are being violated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any authorized employee of the division, any sheriff, any deputy sheriff, or any police officer may enter in the daytime any building or place where any beverages subject to tax under the Beverage Law or which would be subject to tax thereunder if such beverages were manufactured in or brought into this state in accordance with the regulatory provisions thereof, or any alcoholic beverages, are manufactured, produced, or kept, so far as may be necessary, for the purpose of examining said beverages. When such premises are open at night, such officers may enter them while so open, in the performance of their official duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any owner of such premises or person having the agency, superintendency, or possession of same, who refuses to admit such officer or to suffer her or him to examine such beverages, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who shall forcibly obstruct or hinder the director, any division employee, any sheriff, any deputy sheriff, or any police officer in the execution of any power or authority vested in her or him by law, or who shall forcibly rescue or cause to be rescued any property if the same shall have been seized by such officer, or shall attempt or endeavor to do so, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensees, by the acceptance of their license, agree that their places of business shall always be subject to be inspected and searched without search warrants by the authorized employees of the division and also by sheriffs, deputy sheriffs, and police officers during business hours or at any other time such premises are occupied by the licensee or other persons.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 19301, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(271x), 7648(28), (29); ss. 1, 2, ch. 57-327; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 572, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 72-230; s. 28, ch. 79-11; s. 6, ch. 86-269; s. 868, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>