<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0562.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment of minors or certain other persons by certain vendors prohibited; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in this section, it is unlawful for any vendor licensed under the Beverage Law to employ any person under 18 years of age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional entertainers 17 years of age who are not in school.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minors employed in the entertainment industry, as defined by s. 450.012(5), who have either been granted a waiver under s. 450.095 or employed under the terms of s. 450.132 or under rules adopted pursuant to either of these sections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons under the age of 18 years who are employed in drugstores, grocery stores, department stores, florists, specialty gift shops, or automobile service stations which have obtained licenses to sell beer or beer and wine, when such sales are made for consumption off the premises.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons 17 years of age or over or any person furnishing evidence that he or she is a senior high school student with written permission of the principal of said senior high school or that he or she is a senior high school graduate, or any high school graduate, employed by a bona fide food service establishment where alcoholic beverages are sold, provided such persons do not participate in the sale, preparation, or service of the beverages and that their duties are of such nature as to provide them with training and knowledge as might lead to further advancement in food service establishments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons under the age of 18 years employed as bellhops, elevator operators, and others in hotels when such employees are engaged in work apart from the portion of the hotel property where alcoholic beverages are offered for sale for consumption on the premises.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons under the age of 18 years employed in bowling alleys in which alcoholic beverages are sold or consumed, so long as such minors do not participate in the sale, preparation, or service of such beverages.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons under the age of 18 years employed by a bona fide dinner theater as defined in this paragraph, as long as their employment is limited to the services of an actor, actress, or musician. For the purposes of this paragraph, a dinner theater means a theater presenting consecutive productions playing no less than 3 weeks each in conjunction with dinner service on a regular basis. In addition, both events must occur in the same room, and the only advertised price of admission must include both the cost of the meal and the attendance at the performance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons under the age of 18 years who are employed in places of business licensed under s. 565.02(6), provided such persons do not participate in the sale, preparation, or service of alcoholic beverages.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, a minor to whom this subsection otherwise applies may not be employed if the employment, whether as a professional entertainer or otherwise, involves nudity, as defined in s. 847.001, on the part of the minor and such nudity is intended as a form of adult entertainment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any vendor licensed under the beverage law to employ as a manager or person in charge or as a bartender any person:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been convicted within the last past 5 years of any offense against the beverage laws of this state, the United States, or any other state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been convicted within the last past 5 years in this state or any other state or the United States of soliciting for prostitution, pandering, letting premises for prostitution, keeping a disorderly place, or any felony violation of chapter 893 or the controlled substances act of any other state or the Federal Government.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has, in the last past 5 years, been convicted of any felony in this state, any other state, or the United States.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term “conviction” shall include an adjudication of guilt on a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or forfeiture of a bond when such person is charged with a crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall not apply to any vendor licensed under the provisions of s. 563.02(1)(a) or s. 564.02(1)(a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(237); s. 1, ch. 20830, 1941; s. 1, ch. 22669, 1945; s. 21, ch. 25359, 1949; s. 2, ch. 29964, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-327; s. 1, ch. 61-429; s. 1, ch. 65-534; s. 1, ch. 67-2208; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-183; s. 2, ch. 72-230; s. 1, ch. 73-358; s. 1, ch. 73-365; s. 2, ch. 76-288; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 91-60; s. 6, ch. 92-176; s. 52, ch. 95-144; s. 1, ch. 97-44; s. 861, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>