<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0212.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sales, rental, use, consumption, distribution, and storage tax; specified exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale at retail, the rental, the use, the consumption, the distribution, and the storage to be used or consumed in this state of the following are hereby specifically exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; GENERAL GROCERIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products for human consumption are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this chapter, as used in this subsection, the term “food products” means edible commodities, whether processed, cooked, raw, canned, or in any other form, which are generally regarded as food. This includes, but is not limited to, all of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cereals and cereal products, baked goods, oleomargarine, meat and meat products, fish and seafood products, frozen foods and dinners, poultry, eggs and egg products, vegetables and vegetable products, fruit and fruit products, spices, salt, sugar and sugar products, milk and dairy products, and products intended to be mixed with milk.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Natural fruit or vegetable juices or their concentrates or reconstituted natural concentrated fruit or vegetable juices, whether frozen or unfrozen, dehydrated, powdered, granulated, sweetened or unsweetened, seasoned with salt or spice, or unseasoned; coffee, coffee substitutes, or cocoa; and tea, unless it is sold in a liquid form.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bakery products sold by bakeries, pastry shops, or like establishments that do not have eating facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided by this subsection does not apply to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Food products sold as meals for consumption on or off the premises of the dealer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products furnished, prepared, or served for consumption at tables, chairs, or counters or from trays, glasses, dishes, or other tableware, whether provided by the dealer or by a person with whom the dealer contracts to furnish, prepare, or serve food products to others.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products ordinarily sold for immediate consumption on the seller’s premises or near a location at which parking facilities are provided primarily for the use of patrons in consuming the products purchased at the location, even though such products are sold on a “take out” or “to go” order and are actually packaged or wrapped and taken from the premises of the dealer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sandwiches sold ready for immediate consumption on or off the seller’s premises.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products sold ready for immediate consumption within a place, the entrance to which is subject to an admission charge.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products sold as hot prepared food products.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soft drinks, including, but not limited to, any nonalcoholic beverage, any preparation or beverage commonly referred to as a “soft drink,” or any noncarbonated drink made from milk derivatives or tea, if sold in cans or similar containers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ice cream, frozen yogurt, and similar frozen dairy or nondairy products in cones, small cups, or pints, popsicles, frozen fruit bars, or other novelty items, whether or not sold separately.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food that is prepared, whether on or off the premises, and sold for immediate consumption. This does not apply to food prepared off the premises and sold in the original sealed container, or the slicing of products into smaller portions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products sold through a vending machine, pushcart, motor vehicle, or any other form of vehicle.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Candy and any similar product regarded as candy or confection, based on its normal use, as indicated on the label or advertising thereof.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bakery products sold by bakeries, pastry shops, or like establishments having eating facilities, except when sold for consumption off the seller’s premises.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food products served, prepared, or sold in or by restaurants, lunch counters, cafeterias, hotels, taverns, or other like places of business.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“For consumption off the seller’s premises” means that the food or drink is intended by the customer to be consumed at a place away from the dealer’s premises.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“For consumption on the seller’s premises” means that the food or drink sold may be immediately consumed on the premises where the dealer conducts his or her business. In determining whether an item of food is sold for immediate consumption, the customary consumption practices prevailing at the selling facility shall be considered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Premises” shall be construed broadly, and means, but is not limited to, the lobby, aisle, or auditorium of a theater; the seating, aisle, or parking area of an arena, rink, or stadium; or the parking area of a drive-in or outdoor theater. The premises of a caterer with respect to catered meals or beverages shall be the place where such meals or beverages are served.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hot prepared food products” means those products, items, or components which have been prepared for sale in a heated condition and which are sold at any temperature that is higher than the air temperature of the room or place where they are sold. “Hot prepared food products,” for the purposes of this subsection, includes a combination of hot and cold food items or components where a single price has been established for the combination and the food products are sold in such combination, such as a hot meal, a hot specialty dish or serving, or a hot sandwich or hot pizza, including cold components or side items.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food or drinks not exempt under paragraphs (a), (b), (c), and (d) are exempt, notwithstanding those paragraphs, when purchased with food coupons or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children vouchers issued under authority of federal law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph is effective only while federal law prohibits a state’s participation in the federal food coupon program or Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children if there is an official determination that state or local sales taxes are collected within that state on purchases of food or drinks with such coupons.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph shall not apply to any food or drinks on which federal law shall permit sales taxes without penalty, such as termination of the state’s participation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of the tax on a package that contains exempt food products and taxable nonfood products depends upon the essential character of the complete package.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the taxable items represent more than 25 percent of the cost of the complete package and a single charge is made, the entire sales price of the package is taxable. If the taxable items are separately stated, the separate charge for the taxable items is subject to tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the taxable items represent 25 percent or less of the cost of the complete package and a single charge is made, the entire sales price of the package is exempt from tax. The person preparing the package is liable for the tax on the cost of the taxable items going into the complete package. If the taxable items are separately stated, the separate charge is subject to tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; MEDICAL.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter any medical products and supplies or medicine dispensed according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a prescriber authorized by law to prescribe medicinal drugs; hypodermic needles; hypodermic syringes; chemical compounds and test kits used for the diagnosis or treatment of human disease, illness, or injury; and common household remedies recommended and generally sold for internal or external use in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of illness or disease in human beings, but not including cosmetics or toilet articles, notwithstanding the presence of medicinal ingredients therein, according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue. There shall also be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter artificial eyes and limbs; orthopedic shoes; prescription eyeglasses and items incidental thereto or which become a part thereof; dentures; hearing aids; crutches; prosthetic and orthopedic appliances; and funerals. In addition, any items intended for one-time use which transfer essential optical characteristics to contact lenses shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter; however, this exemption shall apply only after $100,000 of the tax imposed by this chapter on such items has been paid in any calendar year by a taxpayer who claims the exemption in such year. Funeral directors shall pay tax on all tangible personal property used by them in their business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prosthetic and orthopedic appliances” means any apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment used to replace or substitute for any missing part of the body, to alleviate the malfunction of any part of the body, or to assist any disabled person in leading a normal life by facilitating such person’s mobility. Such apparatus, instrument, device, or equipment shall be exempted according to an individual prescription or prescriptions written by a physician licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, or chapter 466, or according to a list prescribed and approved by the Department of Health, which list shall be certified to the Department of Revenue from time to time and included in the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cosmetics” means articles intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body for cleansing, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering the appearance and also means articles intended for use as a compound of any such articles, including, but not limited to, cold creams, suntan lotions, makeup, and body lotions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Toilet articles” means any article advertised or held out for sale for grooming purposes and those articles that are customarily used for grooming purposes, regardless of the name by which they may be known, including, but not limited to, soap, toothpaste, hair spray, shaving products, colognes, perfumes, shampoo, deodorant, and mouthwash.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescription” includes any order for drugs or medicinal supplies written or transmitted by any means of communication by a duly licensed practitioner authorized by the laws of the state to prescribe such drugs or medicinal supplies and intended to be dispensed by a pharmacist. The term also includes an orally transmitted order by the lawfully designated agent of such practitioner. The term also includes an order written or transmitted by a practitioner licensed to practice in a jurisdiction other than this state, but only if the pharmacist called upon to dispense such order determines, in the exercise of his or her professional judgment, that the order is valid and necessary for the treatment of a chronic or recurrent illness. The term also includes a pharmacist’s order for a product selected from the formulary created pursuant to s. 465.186. A prescription may be retained in written form, or the pharmacist may cause it to be recorded in a data processing system, provided that such order can be produced in printed form upon lawful request.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chlorine shall not be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter when used for the treatment of water in swimming pools.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lithotripters are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Human organs are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sales of drugs to or by physicians, dentists, veterinarians, and hospitals in connection with medical treatment are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical products and supplies used in the cure, mitigation, alleviation, prevention, or treatment of injury, disease, or incapacity which are temporarily or permanently incorporated into a patient or client by a practitioner of the healing arts licensed in the state are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchase by a veterinarian of commonly recognized substances possessing curative or remedial properties which are ordered and dispensed as treatment for a diagnosed health disorder by or on the prescription of a duly licensed veterinarian, and which are applied to or consumed by animals for alleviation of pain or the cure or prevention of sickness, disease, or suffering are exempt. Also exempt are the purchase by a veterinarian of antiseptics, absorbent cotton, gauze for bandages, lotions, vitamins, and worm remedies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">X-ray opaques, also known as opaque drugs and radiopaque, such as the various opaque dyes and barium sulphate, when used in connection with medical X rays for treatment of bodies of humans and animals, are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parts, special attachments, special lettering, and other like items that are added to or attached to tangible personal property so that a handicapped person can use them are exempt when such items are purchased by a person pursuant to an individual prescription.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall be strictly construed and enforced.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; CERTAIN FARM EQUIPMENT.<EmDash />There shall be no tax on the sale, rental, lease, use, consumption, or storage for use in this state of power farm equipment used exclusively on a farm or in a forest in the agricultural production of crops or products as produced by those agricultural industries included in s. 570.02(1), or for fire prevention and suppression work with respect to such crops or products. Harvesting may not be construed to include processing activities. This exemption is not forfeited by moving farm equipment between farms or forests. However, this exemption shall not be allowed unless the purchaser, renter, or lessee signs a certificate stating that the farm equipment is to be used exclusively on a farm or in a forest for agricultural production or for fire prevention and suppression, as required by this subsection. Possession by a seller, lessor, or other dealer of a written certification by the purchaser, renter, or lessee certifying the purchaser’s, renter’s, or lessee’s entitlement to an exemption permitted by this subsection relieves the seller from the responsibility of collecting the tax on the nontaxable amounts, and the department shall look solely to the purchaser for recovery of such tax if it determines that the purchaser was not entitled to the exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; ITEMS BEARING OTHER EXCISE TAXES, ETC.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also exempt are:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water delivered to the purchaser through pipes or conduits or delivered for irrigation purposes. The sale of drinking water in bottles, cans, or other containers, including water that contains minerals or carbonation in its natural state or water to which minerals have been added at a water treatment facility regulated by the Department of Environmental Protection or the Department of Health, is exempt. This exemption does not apply to the sale of drinking water in bottles, cans, or other containers if carbonation or flavorings, except those added at a water treatment facility, have been added. Water that has been enhanced by the addition of minerals and that does not contain any added carbonation or flavorings is also exempt.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fuels used by a public or private utility, including any municipal corporation or rural electric cooperative association, in the generation of electric power or energy for sale. Fuel other than motor fuel and diesel fuel is taxable as provided in this chapter with the exception of fuel expressly exempt herein. Motor fuels and diesel fuels are taxable as provided in chapter 206, with the exception of those motor fuels and diesel fuels used by railroad locomotives or vessels to transport persons or property in interstate or foreign commerce, which are taxable under this chapter only to the extent provided herein. The basis of the tax shall be the ratio of intrastate mileage to interstate or foreign mileage traveled by the carrier’s railroad locomotives or vessels that were used in interstate or foreign commerce and that had at least some Florida mileage during the previous fiscal year of the carrier, such ratio to be determined at the close of the fiscal year of the carrier. However, during the fiscal year in which the carrier begins its initial operations in this state, the carrier’s mileage apportionment factor may be determined on the basis of an estimated ratio of anticipated miles in this state to anticipated total miles for that year, and subsequently, additional tax shall be paid on the motor fuel and diesel fuels, or a refund may be applied for, on the basis of the actual ratio of the carrier’s railroad locomotives’ or vessels’ miles in this state to its total miles for that year. This ratio shall be applied each month to the total Florida purchases made in this state of motor and diesel fuels to establish that portion of the total used and consumed in intrastate movement and subject to tax under this chapter. The basis for imposition of any discretionary surtax shall be set forth in s. 212.054. Fuels used exclusively in intrastate commerce do not qualify for the proration of tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transmission or wheeling of electricity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alcoholic beverages and malt beverages are not exempt. The terms “alcoholic beverages” and “malt beverages” as used in this paragraph have the same meanings ascribed to them in ss. 561.01(4) and 563.01, respectively. It is determined by the Legislature that the classification of alcoholic beverages made in this paragraph for the purpose of extending the tax imposed by this chapter is reasonable and just, and it is intended that such tax be separate from, and in addition to, any other tax imposed on alcoholic beverages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; ACCOUNT OF USE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Items in agricultural use and certain nets.</Font><EmDash />There are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter nets designed and used exclusively by commercial fisheries; disinfectants, fertilizers, insecticides, pesticides, herbicides, fungicides, and weed killers used for application on crops or groves, including commercial nurseries and home vegetable gardens, used in dairy barns or on poultry farms for the purpose of protecting poultry or livestock, or used directly on poultry or livestock; portable containers or movable receptacles in which portable containers are placed, used for processing farm products; field and garden seeds, including flower seeds; nursery stock, seedlings, cuttings, or other propagative material purchased for growing stock; seeds, seedlings, cuttings, and plants used to produce food for human consumption; cloth, plastic, and other similar materials used for shade, mulch, or protection from frost or insects on a farm; generators used on poultry farms; and liquefied petroleum gas or other fuel used to heat a structure in which started pullets or broilers are raised; however, such exemption shall not be allowed unless the purchaser or lessee signs a certificate stating that the item to be exempted is for the exclusive use designated herein. Also exempt are cellophane wrappers, glue for tin and glass (apiarists), mailing cases for honey, shipping cases, window cartons, and baling wire and twine used for baling hay, when used by a farmer to contain, produce, or process an agricultural commodity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Machinery and equipment used to increase productive output.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment purchased for exclusive use by a new business in spaceport activities as defined by s. 212.02 or for use in new businesses that manufacture, process, compound, or produce for sale items of tangible personal property at fixed locations are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter upon an affirmative showing by the taxpayer to the satisfaction of the department that such items are used in a new business in this state. Such purchases must be made before the date the business first begins its productive operations, and delivery of the purchased item must be made within 12 months after that date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment purchased for exclusive use by an expanding facility which is engaged in spaceport activities as defined by s. 212.02 or for use in expanding manufacturing facilities or plant units which manufacture, process, compound, or produce for sale items of tangible personal property at fixed locations in this state are exempt from any amount of tax imposed by this chapter upon an affirmative showing by the taxpayer to the satisfaction of the department that such items are used to increase the productive output of such expanded facility or business by not less than 5 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive an exemption provided by subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., a qualifying business entity shall apply to the department for a temporary tax exemption permit. The application shall state that a new business exemption or expanded business exemption is being sought. Upon a tentative affirmative determination by the department pursuant to subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., the department shall issue such permit.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall maintain all necessary books and records to support the exemption. Upon completion of purchases of qualified machinery and equipment pursuant to subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., the temporary tax permit shall be delivered to the department or returned to the department by certified or registered mail.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in a subsequent audit conducted by the department, it is determined that the machinery and equipment purchased as exempt under subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2. did not meet the criteria mandated by this paragraph or if commencement of production did not occur, the amount of taxes exempted at the time of purchase shall immediately be due and payable to the department by the business entity, together with the appropriate interest and penalty, computed from the date of purchase, in the manner prescribed by this chapter.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a qualifying business entity fails to apply for a temporary exemption permit or if the tentative determination by the department required to obtain a temporary exemption permit is negative, a qualifying business entity shall receive the exemption provided in subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2. through a refund of previously paid taxes. No refund may be made for such taxes unless the criteria mandated by subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2. have been met and commencement of production has occurred.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing applications for, issuance of, and the form of temporary tax exemption permits; provisions for recapture of taxes; and the manner and form of refund applications, and may establish guidelines as to the requisites for an affirmative showing of increased productive output, commencement of production, and qualification for exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions provided in subparagraphs 1. and 2. do not apply to machinery or equipment purchased or used by electric utility companies, communications companies, oil or gas exploration or production operations, publishing firms that do not export at least 50 percent of their finished product out of the state, any firm subject to regulation by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, or any firm that does not manufacture, process, compound, or produce for sale items of tangible personal property or that does not use such machinery and equipment in spaceport activities as required by this paragraph. The exemptions provided in subparagraphs 1. and 2. shall apply to machinery and equipment purchased for use in phosphate or other solid minerals severance, mining, or processing operations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of the exemptions provided in subparagraphs 1. and 2., these terms have the following meanings:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Industrial machinery and equipment” means tangible personal property or other property that has a depreciable life of 3 years or more and that is used as an integral part in the manufacturing, processing, compounding, or production of tangible personal property for sale or is exclusively used in spaceport activities. A building and its structural components are not industrial machinery and equipment unless the building or structural component is so closely related to the industrial machinery and equipment that it houses or supports that the building or structural component can be expected to be replaced when the machinery and equipment are replaced. Heating and air-conditioning systems are not industrial machinery and equipment unless the sole justification for their installation is to meet the requirements of the production process, even though the system may provide incidental comfort to employees or serve, to an insubstantial degree, nonproduction activities. The term includes parts and accessories only to the extent that the exemption thereof is consistent with the provisions of this paragraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Productive output” means the number of units actually produced by a single plant, operation, or product line in a single continuous 12-month period, irrespective of sales. Increases in productive output shall be measured by the output for 12 continuous months selected by the expanding business after completion of the installation of such machinery or equipment over the output for the 12 continuous months immediately preceding such installation. However, in no case may such time period begin later than 2 years after completion of the installation of the new machinery and equipment. The units used to measure productive output shall be physically comparable between the two periods, irrespective of sales.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Machinery and equipment used in production of electrical or steam energy.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchase of machinery and equipment for use at a fixed location which machinery and equipment are necessary in the production of electrical or steam energy resulting from the burning of boiler fuels other than residual oil is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. Such electrical or steam energy must be primarily for use in manufacturing, processing, compounding, or producing for sale items of tangible personal property in this state. Use of a de minimis amount of residual fuel to facilitate the burning of nonresidual fuel shall not reduce the exemption otherwise available under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In facilities where machinery and equipment are necessary to burn both residual and nonresidual fuels, the exemption shall be prorated. Such proration shall be based upon the production of electrical or steam energy from nonresidual fuels as a percentage of electrical or steam energy from all fuels. If it is determined that 15 percent or less of all electrical or steam energy generated was produced by burning residual fuel, the full exemption shall apply. Purchasers claiming a partial exemption shall obtain such exemption by refund of taxes paid, or as otherwise provided in the department’s rules.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules that provide for implementation of this exemption. Purchasers of machinery and equipment qualifying for the exemption provided in this paragraph shall furnish the vendor with an affidavit stating that the item or items to be exempted are for the use designated herein. Any person furnishing a false affidavit to the vendor for the purpose of evading payment of any tax imposed under this chapter shall be subject to the penalty set forth in s. 212.085 and as otherwise provided by law. Purchasers with self-accrual authority shall maintain all documentation necessary to prove the exempt status of purchases.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Machinery and equipment used under federal procurement contract.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment purchased by an expanding business which manufactures tangible personal property pursuant to federal procurement regulations at fixed locations in this state are exempt from the tax imposed in this chapter upon an affirmative showing by the taxpayer to the satisfaction of the department that such items are used to increase the implicit productive output of the expanded business by not less than 10 percent. The percentage of increase is measured as deflated implicit productive output for the calendar year during which the installation of the machinery or equipment is completed or during which commencement of production utilizing such items is begun divided by the implicit productive output for the preceding calendar year. In no case may the commencement of production begin later than 2 years following completion of installation of the machinery or equipment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the exemption allowed shall equal the taxes otherwise imposed by this chapter on qualifying industrial machinery or equipment reduced by the percentage of gross receipts from cost-reimbursement type contracts attributable to the plant or operation to total gross receipts so attributable, accrued for the year of completion or commencement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided by this paragraph shall inure to the taxpayer only through refund of previously paid taxes. Such refund shall be made within 30 days of formal approval by the department of the taxpayer’s application, which application may be made on an annual basis following installation of the machinery or equipment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cost-reimbursement type contracts” has the same meaning as in <Reference Number="2" />32 C.F.R. s. 3-405.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deflated implicit productive output” means the product of implicit productive output times the quotient of the national defense implicit price deflator for the preceding calendar year divided by the deflator for the year of completion or commencement.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible costs” means the total direct and indirect costs, as defined in <Reference Number="3" />32 C.F.R. ss. 15-202 and 15-203, excluding general and administrative costs, selling expenses, and profit, defined by the uniform cost-accounting standards adopted by the Cost-Accounting Standards Board created pursuant to <Reference Number="4" />50 U.S.C. s. 2168.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Implicit productive output” means the annual eligible costs attributable to all contracts or subcontracts subject to federal procurement regulations of the single plant or operation at which the machinery or equipment is used.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Industrial machinery and equipment” means tangible personal property or other property that has a depreciable life of 3 years or more, that qualifies as an eligible cost under federal procurement regulations, and that is used as an integral part of the process of production of tangible personal property. A building and its structural components are not industrial machinery and equipment unless the building or structural component is so closely related to the industrial machinery and equipment that it houses or supports that the building or structural component can be expected to be replaced when the machinery and equipment are replaced. Heating and air-conditioning systems are not industrial machinery and equipment unless the sole justification for their installation is to meet the requirements of the production process, even though the system may provide incidental comfort to employees or serve, to an insubstantial degree, nonproduction activities. The term includes parts and accessories only to the extent that the exemption of such parts and accessories is consistent with the provisions of this paragraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National defense implicit price deflator” means the national defense implicit price deflator for the gross national product as determined by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the United States Department of Commerce.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusions provided in subparagraph (b)5. apply to this exemption. This exemption applies only to machinery or equipment purchased pursuant to production contracts with the United States Department of Defense and Armed Forces, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and other federal agencies for which the contracts are classified for national security reasons. In no event shall the provisions of this paragraph apply to any expanding business the increase in productive output of which could be measured under the provisions of sub-subparagraph (b)6.b. as physically comparable between the two periods.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Gas or electricity used for certain agricultural purposes.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Butane gas, propane gas, natural gas, and all other forms of liquefied petroleum gases are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter if used in any tractor, vehicle, or other farm equipment which is used exclusively on a farm or for processing farm products on the farm and no part of which gas is used in any vehicle or equipment driven or operated on the public highways of this state. This restriction does not apply to the movement of farm vehicles or farm equipment between farms. The transporting of bees by water and the operating of equipment used in the apiary of a beekeeper is also deemed an exempt use.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electricity used directly or indirectly for production, packing, or processing of agricultural products on the farm, or used directly or indirectly in a packinghouse, is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. As used in this subsection, the term “packinghouse” means any building or structure where fruits, vegetables, or meat from cattle or hogs is packed or otherwise prepared for market or shipment in fresh form for wholesale distribution. The exemption does not apply to electricity used in buildings or structures where agricultural products are sold at retail. This exemption applies only if the electricity used for the exempt purposes is separately metered. If the electricity is not separately metered, it is conclusively presumed that some portion of the electricity is used for a nonexempt purpose, and all of the electricity used for such purposes is taxable.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Motion picture or video equipment used in motion picture or television production activities and sound recording equipment used in the production of master tapes and master records.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment purchased or leased for use in this state in production activities is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. The exemption provided by this paragraph shall inure to the taxpayer upon presentation of the certificate of exemption issued to the taxpayer under the provisions of s. 288.1258.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of the exemption provided in subparagraph 1.:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motion picture or video equipment” and “sound recording equipment” includes only tangible personal property or other property that has a depreciable life of 3 years or more and that is used by the lessee or purchaser exclusively as an integral part of production activities; however, motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment does not include supplies, tape, records, film, or video tape used in productions or other similar items; vehicles or vessels; or general office equipment not specifically suited to production activities. In addition, the term does not include equipment purchased or leased by television or radio broadcasting or cable companies licensed by the Federal Communications Commission. Furthermore, a building and its structural components are not motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment unless the building or structural component is so closely related to the motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment that it houses or supports that the building or structural component can be expected to be replaced when the motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment are replaced. Heating and air-conditioning systems are not motion picture or video equipment and sound recording equipment unless the sole justification for their installation is to meet the requirements of the production activities, even though the system may provide incidental comfort to employees or serve, to an insubstantial degree, nonproduction activities.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Production activities” means activities directed toward the preparation of a:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Master tape or master record embodying sound; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motion picture or television production which is produced for theatrical, commercial, advertising, or educational purposes and utilizes live or animated actions or a combination of live and animated actions. The motion picture or television production shall be commercially produced for sale or for showing on screens or broadcasting on television and may be on film or video tape.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Building materials used in the rehabilitation of real property located in an enterprise zone.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building materials used in the rehabilitation of real property located in an enterprise zone are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter upon an affirmative showing to the satisfaction of the department that the items have been used for the rehabilitation of real property located in an enterprise zone. Except as provided in subparagraph 2., this exemption inures to the owner, lessee, or lessor at the time the real property is rehabilitated, but only through a refund of previously paid taxes. To receive a refund pursuant to this paragraph, the owner, lessee, or lessor of the rehabilitated real property must file an application under oath with the governing body or enterprise zone development agency having jurisdiction over the enterprise zone where the business is located, as applicable. A single application for a refund may be submitted for multiple, contiguous parcels that were part of a single parcel that was divided as part of the rehabilitation of the property. All other requirements of this paragraph apply to each parcel on an individual basis. The application must include:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person claiming the refund.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An address and assessment roll parcel number of the rehabilitated real property for which a refund of previously paid taxes is being sought.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the improvements made to accomplish the rehabilitation of the real property.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of a valid building permit issued by the county or municipal building department for the rehabilitation of the real property.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, from the general contractor licensed in this state with whom the applicant contracted to make the improvements necessary to rehabilitate the real property, which lists the building materials used to rehabilitate the real property, the actual cost of the building materials, and the amount of sales tax paid in this state on the building materials. If a general contractor was not used, the applicant, not a general contractor, shall make the sworn statement required by this sub-subparagraph. Copies of the invoices that evidence the purchase of the building materials used in the rehabilitation and the payment of sales tax on the building materials must be attached to the sworn statement provided by the general contractor or by the applicant. Unless the actual cost of building materials used in the rehabilitation of real property and the payment of sales taxes is documented by a general contractor or by the applicant in this manner, the cost of the building materials is deemed to be an amount equal to 40 percent of the increase in assessed value for ad valorem tax purposes.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the rehabilitated real property is located.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification by the local building code inspector that the improvements necessary to rehabilitate the real property are substantially completed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of whether the business is a small business as defined by s. 288.703.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, the name and address of each permanent employee of the business, including, for each employee who is a resident of an enterprise zone, the identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the employee resides.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption inures to a municipality, county, other governmental unit or agency, or nonprofit community-based organization through a refund of previously paid taxes if the building materials used in the rehabilitation are paid for from the funds of a community development block grant, State Housing Initiatives Partnership Program, or similar grant or loan program. To receive a refund, a municipality, county, other governmental unit or agency, or nonprofit community-based organization must file an application that includes the same information required in subparagraph 1. In addition, the application must include a sworn statement signed by the chief executive officer of the municipality, county, other governmental unit or agency, or nonprofit community-based organization seeking a refund which states that the building materials for which a refund is sought were funded by a community development block grant, State Housing Initiatives Partnership Program, or similar grant or loan program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 working days after receipt of an application, the governing body or enterprise zone development agency shall review the application to determine if it contains all the information required by subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2. and meets the criteria set out in this paragraph. The governing body or agency shall certify all applications that contain the required information and are eligible to receive a refund. If applicable, the governing body or agency shall also certify if 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees. The certification must be in writing, and a copy of the certification shall be transmitted to the executive director of the department. The applicant is responsible for forwarding a certified application to the department within the time specified in subparagraph 4.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a refund must be submitted to the department within 6 months after the rehabilitation of the property is deemed to be substantially completed by the local building code inspector or by November 1 after the rehabilitated property is first subject to assessment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only one exemption through a refund of previously paid taxes for the rehabilitation of real property is permitted for any single parcel of property unless there is a change in ownership, a new lessor, or a new lessee of the real property. A refund may not be granted unless the amount to be refunded exceeds $500. A refund may not exceed the lesser of 97 percent of the Florida sales or use tax paid on the cost of the building materials used in the rehabilitation of the real property as determined pursuant to sub-subparagraph 1.e. or $5,000, or, if at least 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees, the amount of refund may not exceed the lesser of 97 percent of the sales tax paid on the cost of the building materials or $10,000. A refund shall be made within 30 days after formal approval by the department of the application for the refund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing the manner and form of refund applications and may establish guidelines as to the requisites for an affirmative showing of qualification for exemption under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deduct an amount equal to 10 percent of each refund granted under this paragraph from the amount transferred into the Local Government Half-cent Sales Tax Clearing Trust Fund pursuant to s. 212.20 for the county area in which the rehabilitated real property is located and shall transfer that amount to the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of the exemption provided in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building materials” means tangible personal property that becomes a component part of improvements to real property.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” has the same meaning as provided in s. 192.001(12), except that the term does not include a condominium parcel or condominium property as defined in s. 718.103.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rehabilitation of real property” means the reconstruction, renovation, restoration, rehabilitation, construction, or expansion of improvements to real property.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantially completed” has the same meaning as provided in s. 192.042(1).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph expires on the date specified in s. 290.016 for the expiration of the Florida Enterprise Zone Act.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Business property used in an enterprise zone.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business property purchased for use by businesses located in an enterprise zone which is subsequently used in an enterprise zone shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. This exemption inures to the business only through a refund of previously paid taxes. A refund shall be authorized upon an affirmative showing by the taxpayer to the satisfaction of the department that the requirements of this paragraph have been met.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive a refund, the business must file under oath with the governing body or enterprise zone development agency having jurisdiction over the enterprise zone where the business is located, as applicable, an application which includes:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the business claiming the refund.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the business is located.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific description of the property for which a refund is sought, including its serial number or other permanent identification number.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the property.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sales invoice or other proof of purchase of the property, showing the amount of sales tax paid, the date of purchase, and the name and address of the sales tax dealer from whom the property was purchased.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the business is a small business as defined by s. 288.703.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, the name and address of each permanent employee of the business, including, for each employee who is a resident of an enterprise zone, the identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the employee resides.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 working days after receipt of an application, the governing body or enterprise zone development agency shall review the application to determine if it contains all the information required pursuant to subparagraph 2. and meets the criteria set out in this paragraph. The governing body or agency shall certify all applications that contain the information required pursuant to subparagraph 2. and meet the criteria set out in this paragraph as eligible to receive a refund. If applicable, the governing body or agency shall also certify if 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees. The certification shall be in writing, and a copy of the certification shall be transmitted to the executive director of the Department of Revenue. The business shall be responsible for forwarding a certified application to the department within the time specified in subparagraph 4.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a refund pursuant to this paragraph must be submitted to the department within 6 months after the tax is due on the business property that is purchased.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount refunded on purchases of business property under this paragraph shall be the lesser of 97 percent of the sales tax paid on such business property or $5,000, or, if no less than 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees, the amount refunded on purchases of business property under this paragraph shall be the lesser of 97 percent of the sales tax paid on such business property or $10,000. A refund approved pursuant to this paragraph shall be made within 30 days after formal approval by the department of the application for the refund. A refund may not be granted under this paragraph unless the amount to be refunded exceeds $100 in sales tax paid on purchases made within a 60-day time period.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing the manner and form of refund applications and may establish guidelines as to the requisites for an affirmative showing of qualification for exemption under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines that the business property is used outside an enterprise zone within 3 years from the date of purchase, the amount of taxes refunded to the business purchasing such business property shall immediately be due and payable to the department by the business, together with the appropriate interest and penalty, computed from the date of purchase, in the manner provided by this chapter. Notwithstanding this subparagraph, business property used exclusively in:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed commercial fishing vessels,</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fishing guide boats, or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ecotourism guide boats</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">that leave and return to a fixed location within an area designated under s. 379.2353, Florida Statutes 2010, are eligible for the exemption provided under this paragraph if all requirements of this paragraph are met. Such vessels and boats must be owned by a business that is eligible to receive the exemption provided under this paragraph. This exemption does not apply to the purchase of a vessel or boat.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deduct an amount equal to 10 percent of each refund granted under this paragraph from the amount transferred into the Local Government Half-cent Sales Tax Clearing Trust Fund pursuant to s. 212.20 for the county area in which the business property is located and shall transfer that amount to the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this exemption, “business property” means new or used property defined as “recovery property” in <Reference Number="5" />s. 168(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended, except:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property classified as 3-year property under <Reference Number="6" />s. 168(c)(2)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment as defined in sub-subparagraph (b)6.a. and eligible for exemption under paragraph (b);</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building materials as defined in sub-subparagraph (g)8.a.; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business property having a sales price of under $5,000 per unit.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph expires on the date specified in s. 290.016 for the expiration of the Florida Enterprise Zone Act.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Aircraft modification services.</Font><EmDash />There shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter all charges for aircraft modification services, including parts and equipment furnished or installed in connection therewith, performed under authority of a supplemental type certificate issued by the Federal Aviation Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Machinery and equipment used in semiconductor, defense, or space technology production.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment used in semiconductor technology facilities certified under subparagraph 5. to manufacture, process, compound, or produce semiconductor technology products for sale or for use by these facilities are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. For purposes of this paragraph, industrial machinery and equipment includes molds, dies, machine tooling, other appurtenances or accessories to machinery and equipment, testing equipment, test beds, computers, and software, whether purchased or self-fabricated, and, if self-fabricated, includes materials and labor for design, fabrication, and assembly.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial machinery and equipment used in defense or space technology facilities certified under subparagraph 5. to design, manufacture, assemble, process, compound, or produce defense technology products or space technology products for sale or for use by these facilities are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building materials purchased for use in manufacturing or expanding clean rooms in semiconductor-manufacturing facilities are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to meeting the criteria mandated by subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., a business must be certified by the Department of Economic Opportunity in order to qualify for exemption under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For items purchased tax-exempt pursuant to this paragraph, possession of a written certification from the purchaser, certifying the purchaser’s entitlement to the exemption, relieves the seller of the responsibility of collecting the tax on the sale of such items, and the department shall look solely to the purchaser for recovery of the tax if it determines that the purchaser was not entitled to the exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to receive the exemption provided by subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., a qualifying business entity shall initially apply to Enterprise Florida, Inc. The original certification is valid for a period of 2 years. In lieu of submitting a new application, the original certification may be renewed biennially by submitting to the Department of Economic Opportunity a statement, certified under oath, that there has not been a material change in the conditions or circumstances entitling the business entity to the original certification. The initial application and the certification renewal statement shall be developed by the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Strategic Business Development of the Department of Economic Opportunity shall review each submitted initial application and determine whether or not the application is complete within 5 working days. Once complete, the division shall, within 10 working days, evaluate the application and recommend approval or disapproval to the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the initial application and recommendation from the division or upon receipt of a certification renewal statement, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall certify within 5 working days those applicants who are found to meet the requirements of this section and notify the applicant of the original certification or certification renewal. If the Department of Economic Opportunity finds that the applicant does not meet the requirements, it shall notify the applicant and Enterprise Florida, Inc., within 10 working days that the application for certification has been denied and the reasons for denial. The Department of Economic Opportunity has final approval authority for certification under this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application and certification renewal statement must indicate, for program evaluation purposes only, the average number of full-time equivalent employees at the facility over the preceding calendar year, the average wage and benefits paid to those employees over the preceding calendar year, the total investment made in real and tangible personal property over the preceding calendar year, and the total value of tax-exempt purchases and taxes exempted during the previous year. The department shall assist the Department of Economic Opportunity in evaluating and verifying information provided in the application for exemption.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity may use the information reported on the initial application and certification renewal statement for evaluation purposes only.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A business certified to receive this exemption may elect to designate one or more state universities or community colleges as recipients of up to 100 percent of the amount of the exemption. To receive these funds, the institution must agree to match the funds with equivalent cash, programs, services, or other in-kind support on a one-to-one basis for research and development projects requested by the certified business. The rights to any patents, royalties, or real or intellectual property must be vested in the business unless otherwise agreed to by the business and the university or community college.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Semiconductor technology products” means raw semiconductor wafers or semiconductor thin films that are transformed into semiconductor memory or logic wafers, including wafers containing mixed memory and logic circuits; related assembly and test operations; active-matrix flat panel displays; semiconductor chips; semiconductor lasers; optoelectronic elements; and related semiconductor technology products as determined by the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clean rooms” means manufacturing facilities enclosed in a manner that meets the clean manufacturing requirements necessary for high-technology semiconductor-manufacturing environments.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Defense technology products” means products that have a military application, including, but not limited to, weapons, weapons systems, guidance systems, surveillance systems, communications or information systems, munitions, aircraft, vessels, or boats, or components thereof, which are intended for military use and manufactured in performance of a contract with the United States Department of Defense or the military branch of a recognized foreign government or a subcontract thereunder which relates to matters of national defense.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Space technology products” means products that are specifically designed or manufactured for application in space activities, including, but not limited to, space launch vehicles, space flight vehicles, missiles, satellites or research payloads, avionics, and associated control systems and processing systems and components of any of the foregoing. The term does not include products that are designed or manufactured for general commercial aviation or other uses even though those products may also serve an incidental use in space applications.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Samples.</Font><EmDash />Paint color card samples, flooring and wall samples, fabric swatch samples, window covering samples, and similar samples, when such samples serve no useful purpose other than as a comparison of color, texture, or design; are provided by the manufacturer to a dealer or ultimate consumer for no charge; and are given away by the dealer to the ultimate consumer for no charge, are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Growth enhancers or performance enhancers for cattle.</Font><EmDash />There is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter the sale of performance-enhancing or growth-enhancing products for cattle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Educational materials purchased by certain child care facilities.</Font><EmDash />Educational materials, such as glue, paper, paints, crayons, unique craft items, scissors, books, and educational toys, purchased by a child care facility that meets the standards delineated in s. 402.305, is licensed under s. 402.308, holds a current Gold Seal Quality Care designation pursuant to s. 402.281, and provides basic health insurance to all employees are exempt from the taxes imposed by this chapter. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “basic health insurance” shall be defined and promulgated in rules developed jointly by the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Health Care Administration, and the Financial Services Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Materials for construction of single-family homes in certain areas.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building materials” means tangible personal property that becomes a component part of a qualified home.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified home” means a single-family home having an appraised value of no more than $160,000 which is located in an enterprise zone, empowerment zone, or Front Porch Florida Community and which is constructed and occupied by the owner thereof for residential purposes.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantially completed” has the same meaning as provided in s. 192.042(1).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building materials used in the construction of a qualified home and the costs of labor associated with the construction of a qualified home are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter upon an affirmative showing to the satisfaction of the department that the requirements of this paragraph have been met. This exemption inures to the owner through a refund of previously paid taxes. To receive this refund, the owner must file an application under oath with the department which includes:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address and assessment roll parcel number of the home for which a refund is sought.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the building permit issued for the home.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification by the local building code inspector that the home is substantially completed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, from the general contractor licensed in this state with whom the owner contracted to construct the home, which statement lists the building materials used in the construction of the home and the actual cost thereof, the labor costs associated with such construction, and the amount of sales tax paid on these materials and labor costs. If a general contractor was not used, the owner shall provide this information in a sworn statement, under penalty of perjury. Copies of invoices evidencing payment of sales tax must be attached to the sworn statement.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, from the owner affirming that he or she is occupying the home for residential purposes.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a refund under this paragraph must be submitted to the department within 6 months after the date the home is deemed to be substantially completed by the local building code inspector. Within 30 working days after receipt of the application, the department shall determine if it meets the requirements of this paragraph. A refund approved pursuant to this paragraph shall be made within 30 days after formal approval of the application by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule an application form and criteria for establishing eligibility for exemption under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption shall apply to purchases of materials on or after July 1, 2000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Building materials in redevelopment projects.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building materials” means tangible personal property that becomes a component part of a housing project or a mixed-use project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Housing project” means the conversion of an existing manufacturing or industrial building to housing units in an urban high-crime area, enterprise zone, empowerment zone, Front Porch Community, designated brownfield area, or urban infill area and in which the developer agrees to set aside at least 20 percent of the housing units in the project for low-income and moderate-income persons or the construction in a designated brownfield area of affordable housing for persons described in s. 420.0004(9), (11), (12), or (17) or in s. 159.603(7).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mixed-use project” means the conversion of an existing manufacturing or industrial building to mixed-use units that include artists’ studios, art and entertainment services, or other compatible uses. A mixed-use project must be located in an urban high-crime area, enterprise zone, empowerment zone, Front Porch Community, designated brownfield area, or urban infill area, and the developer must agree to set aside at least 20 percent of the square footage of the project for low-income and moderate-income housing.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantially completed” has the same meaning as provided in s. 192.042(1).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building materials used in the construction of a housing project or mixed-use project are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter upon an affirmative showing to the satisfaction of the department that the requirements of this paragraph have been met. This exemption inures to the owner through a refund of previously paid taxes. To receive this refund, the owner must file an application under oath with the department which includes:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address and assessment roll parcel number of the project for which a refund is sought.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the building permit issued for the project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification by the local building code inspector that the project is substantially completed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, from the general contractor licensed in this state with whom the owner contracted to construct the project, which statement lists the building materials used in the construction of the project and the actual cost thereof, and the amount of sales tax paid on these materials. If a general contractor was not used, the owner shall provide this information in a sworn statement, under penalty of perjury. Copies of invoices evidencing payment of sales tax must be attached to the sworn statement.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a refund under this paragraph must be submitted to the department within 6 months after the date the project is deemed to be substantially completed by the local building code inspector. Within 30 working days after receipt of the application, the department shall determine if it meets the requirements of this paragraph. A refund approved pursuant to this paragraph shall be made within 30 days after formal approval of the application by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule an application form and criteria for establishing eligibility for exemption under this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption shall apply to purchases of materials on or after July 1, 2000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Community contribution tax credit for donations.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorization.<EmDash />Persons who are registered with the department under s. 212.18 to collect or remit sales or use tax and who make donations to eligible sponsors are eligible for tax credits against their state sales and use tax liabilities as provided in this paragraph:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit shall be computed as 50 percent of the person’s approved annual community contribution.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit shall be granted as a refund against state sales and use taxes reported on returns and remitted in the 12 months preceding the date of application to the department for the credit as required in sub-subparagraph 3.c. If the annual credit is not fully used through such refund because of insufficient tax payments during the applicable 12-month period, the unused amount may be included in an application for a refund made pursuant to sub-subparagraph 3.c. in subsequent years against the total tax payments made for such year. Carryover credits may be applied for a 3-year period without regard to any time limitation that would otherwise apply under s. 215.26.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not receive more than $200,000 in annual tax credits for all approved community contributions made in any one year.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All proposals for the granting of the tax credit require the prior approval of the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of tax credits which may be granted for all programs approved under this paragraph, s. 220.183, and s. 624.5105 is $10.5 million annually for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) and $3.5 million annually for all other projects.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is eligible to receive the credit provided for in this paragraph, s. 220.183, or s. 624.5105 may receive the credit only under the one section of the person’s choice.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligibility requirements.<EmDash /></Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community contribution by a person must be in the following form:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash or other liquid assets;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Goods or inventory; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other physical resources as identified by the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All community contributions must be reserved exclusively for use in a project. As used in this sub-subparagraph, the term “project” means any activity undertaken by an eligible sponsor which is designed to construct, improve, or substantially rehabilitate housing that is affordable to low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28); designed to provide commercial, industrial, or public resources and facilities; or designed to improve entrepreneurial and job-development opportunities for low-income persons. A project may be the investment necessary to increase access to high-speed broadband capability in rural communities with enterprise zones, including projects that result in improvements to communications assets that are owned by a business. A project may include the provision of museum educational programs and materials that are directly related to any project approved between January 1, 1996, and December 31, 1999, and located in an enterprise zone designated pursuant to s. 290.0065. This paragraph does not preclude projects that propose to construct or rehabilitate housing for low-income or very-low-income households on scattered sites. With respect to housing, contributions may be used to pay the following eligible low-income and very-low-income housing-related activities:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Project development impact and management fees for low-income or very-low-income housing projects;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Down payment and closing costs for eligible persons, as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28);</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative costs, including housing counseling and marketing fees, not to exceed 10 percent of the community contribution, directly related to low-income or very-low-income projects; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removal of liens recorded against residential property by municipal, county, or special district local governments when satisfaction of the lien is a necessary precedent to the transfer of the property to an eligible person, as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28), for the purpose of promoting home ownership. Contributions for lien removal must be received from a nonrelated third party.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project must be undertaken by an “eligible sponsor,” which includes:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community action program;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonprofit community-based development organization whose mission is the provision of housing for low-income or very-low-income households or increasing entrepreneurial and job-development opportunities for low-income persons;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A neighborhood housing services corporation;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local housing authority created under chapter 421;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="V">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community redevelopment agency created under s. 163.356;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A historic preservation district agency or organization;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A regional workforce board;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VIII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A direct-support organization as provided in s. 1009.983;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IX">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An enterprise zone development agency created under s. 290.0056;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="X">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community-based organization incorporated under chapter 617 which is recognized as educational, charitable, or scientific pursuant to s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and whose bylaws and articles of incorporation include affordable housing, economic development, or community development as the primary mission of the corporation;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Units of local government;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Units of state government; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XIII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other agency that the Department of Economic Opportunity designates by rule.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In no event may a contributing person have a financial interest in the eligible sponsor.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project must be located in an area designated an enterprise zone or a Front Porch Florida Community, unless the project increases access to high-speed broadband capability for rural communities with enterprise zones but is physically located outside the designated rural zone boundaries. Any project designed to construct or rehabilitate housing for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) is exempt from the area requirement of this sub-subparagraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for less than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant tax credits for those applications and shall grant remaining tax credits on a first-come, first-served basis for any subsequent eligible applications received before the end of the state fiscal year. If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for more than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant the tax credits for those applications as follows:</Text>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If tax credit applications submitted for approved projects of an eligible sponsor do not exceed $200,000 in total, the credits shall be granted in full if the tax credit applications are approved.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If tax credit applications submitted for approved projects of an eligible sponsor exceed $200,000 in total, the amount of tax credits granted pursuant to sub-sub-sub-subparagraph (A) shall be subtracted from the amount of available tax credits, and the remaining credits shall be granted to each approved tax credit application on a pro rata basis.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects other than those that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for less than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant tax credits for those applications and shall grant remaining tax credits on a first-come, first-served basis for any subsequent eligible applications received before the end of the state fiscal year. If, during the first 10 business days of the state fiscal year, eligible tax credit applications for projects other than those that provide homeownership opportunities for low-income or very-low-income households as defined in s. 420.9071(19) and (28) are received for more than the annual tax credits available for those projects, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall grant the tax credits for those applications on a pro rata basis.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application requirements.<EmDash /></Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any eligible sponsor seeking to participate in this program must submit a proposal to the Department of Economic Opportunity which sets forth the name of the sponsor, a description of the project, and the area in which the project is located, together with such supporting information as is prescribed by rule. The proposal must also contain a resolution from the local governmental unit in which the project is located certifying that the project is consistent with local plans and regulations.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person seeking to participate in this program must submit an application for tax credit to the Department of Economic Opportunity which sets forth the name of the sponsor, a description of the project, and the type, value, and purpose of the contribution. The sponsor shall verify the terms of the application and indicate its receipt of the contribution, which verification must be in writing and accompany the application for tax credit. The person must submit a separate tax credit application to the Department of Economic Opportunity for each individual contribution that it makes to each individual project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has received notification from the Department of Economic Opportunity that a tax credit has been approved must apply to the department to receive the refund. Application must be made on the form prescribed for claiming refunds of sales and use taxes and be accompanied by a copy of the notification. A person may submit only one application for refund to the department within any 12-month period.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration.<EmDash /></Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 necessary to administer this paragraph, including rules for the approval or disapproval of proposals by a person.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision of the Department of Economic Opportunity must be in writing, and, if approved, the notification shall state the maximum credit allowable to the person. Upon approval, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall transmit a copy of the decision to the Department of Revenue.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall periodically monitor all projects in a manner consistent with available resources to ensure that resources are used in accordance with this paragraph; however, each project must be reviewed at least once every 2 years.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall, in consultation with the statewide and regional housing and financial intermediaries, market the availability of the community contribution tax credit program to community-based organizations.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expiration.<EmDash />This paragraph expires June 30, 2015; however, any accrued credit carryover that is unused on that date may be used until the expiration of the 3-year carryover period for such credit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Entertainment industry tax credit; authorization; eligibility for credits.</Font><EmDash />The credits against the state sales tax authorized pursuant to s. 288.1254 shall be deducted from any sales and use tax remitted by the dealer to the department by electronic funds transfer and may only be deducted on a sales and use tax return initiated through electronic data interchange. The dealer shall separately state the credit on the electronic return. The net amount of tax due and payable must be remitted by electronic funds transfer. If the credit for the qualified expenditures is larger than the amount owed on the sales and use tax return that is eligible for the credit, the unused amount of the credit may be carried forward to a succeeding reporting period as provided in s. 288.1254(4)(e). A dealer may only obtain a credit using the method described in this subparagraph. A dealer is not authorized to obtain a credit by applying for a refund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Reference Number="7" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; POLITICAL SUBDIVISIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter sales made to the United States Government, a state, or any county, municipality, or political subdivision of a state when payment is made directly to the dealer by the governmental entity. This exemption shall not inure to any transaction otherwise taxable under this chapter when payment is made by a government employee by any means, including, but not limited to, cash, check, or credit card when that employee is subsequently reimbursed by the governmental entity. This exemption does not include sales, rental, use, consumption, or storage for use in any political subdivision or municipality in this state of machines and equipment and parts and accessories therefor used in the generation, transmission, or distribution of electrical energy by systems owned and operated by a political subdivision in this state for transmission or distribution expansion. Likewise exempt are charges for services rendered by radio and television stations, including line charges, talent fees, or license fees and charges for films, videotapes, and transcriptions used in producing radio or television broadcasts. The exemption provided in this subsection does not include sales, rental, use, consumption, or storage for use in any political subdivision or municipality in this state of machines and equipment and parts and accessories therefor used in providing two-way telecommunications services to the public for hire by the use of a telecommunications facility, as defined in s. 364.02(14), and for which a certificate is required under chapter 364, which facility is owned and operated by any county, municipality, or other political subdivision of the state. Any immunity of any political subdivision of the state or other entity of local government from taxation of the property used to provide telecommunication services that is taxed as a result of this section is hereby waived. However, the exemption provided in this subsection includes transactions taxable under this chapter which are for use by the operator of a public-use airport, as defined in s. 332.004, in providing such telecommunications services for the airport or its tenants, concessionaires, or licensees, or which are for use by a public hospital for the provision of such telecommunications services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided under this subsection does not include sales of tangible personal property made to contractors employed directly to or as agents of any such government or political subdivision when such tangible personal property goes into or becomes a part of public works owned by such government or political subdivision. A determination of whether a particular transaction is properly characterized as an exempt sale to a government entity or a taxable sale to a contractor shall be based upon the substance of the transaction rather than the form in which the transaction is cast. However, for sales of tangible personal property that go into or become a part of public works owned by a governmental entity, other than the Federal Government, a governmental entity claiming the exemption provided under this subsection shall certify to the dealer and the contractor the entity’s claim to the exemption by providing the dealer and the contractor a certificate of entitlement to the exemption for such sales. If the department later determines that such sales, in which the governmental entity provided the dealer and the contractor with a certificate of entitlement to the exemption, were not exempt sales to the governmental entity, the governmental entity shall be liable for any tax, penalty, and interest determined to be owed on such transactions. Possession by a dealer or contractor of a certificate of entitlement to the exemption from the governmental entity relieves the dealer from the responsibility of collecting tax on the sale and the contractor for any liability for tax, penalty, or interest related to the sale, and the department shall look solely to the governmental entity for recovery of tax, penalty, and interest if the department determines that the transaction was not an exempt sale to the governmental entity. The governmental entity may not transfer liability for such tax, penalty, and interest to another party by contract or agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules for determining whether a particular transaction is properly characterized as an exempt sale to a governmental entity or a taxable sale to a contractor which give special consideration to factors that govern the status of the tangible personal property before being affixed to real property. In developing such rules, assumption of the risk of damage or loss is of paramount consideration in the determination. The department shall also adopt, by rule, a certificate of entitlement to exemption for use as provided in paragraph (b). The certificate shall require the governmental entity to affirm that it will comply with the requirements of this subsection and the rules adopted under paragraph (b) in order to qualify for the exemption and that it acknowledges its liability for any tax, penalty, or interest later determined by the department to be owed on such transactions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISCELLANEOUS EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash />Exemptions provided to any entity by this chapter do not inure to any transaction that is otherwise taxable under this chapter when payment is made by a representative or employee of the entity by any means, including, but not limited to, cash, check, or credit card, even when that representative or employee is subsequently reimbursed by the entity. In addition, exemptions provided to any entity by this subsection do not inure to any transaction that is otherwise taxable under this chapter unless the entity has obtained a sales tax exemption certificate from the department or the entity obtains or provides other documentation as required by the department. Eligible purchases or leases made with such a certificate must be in strict compliance with this subsection and departmental rules, and any person who makes an exempt purchase with a certificate that is not in strict compliance with this subsection and the rules is liable for and shall pay the tax. The department may adopt rules to administer this subsection.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Artificial commemorative flowers.</Font><EmDash />Exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter is the sale of artificial commemorative flowers by bona fide nationally chartered veterans’ organizations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Boiler fuels.</Font><EmDash />When purchased for use as a combustible fuel, purchases of natural gas, residual oil, recycled oil, waste oil, solid waste material, coal, sulfur, wood, wood residues or wood bark used in an industrial manufacturing, processing, compounding, or production process at a fixed location in this state are exempt from the taxes imposed by this chapter; however, such exemption shall not be allowed unless the purchaser signs a certificate stating that the fuel to be exempted is for the exclusive use designated herein. This exemption does not apply to the use of boiler fuels that are not used in manufacturing, processing, compounding, or producing items of tangible personal property for sale, or to the use of boiler fuels used by any firm subject to regulation by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Crustacea bait.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter is the purchase by commercial fishers of bait intended solely for use in the entrapment of <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Callinectes sapidus</Font> and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Menippe mercenaria</Font>.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Feeds.</Font><EmDash />Feeds for poultry, ostriches, and livestock, including racehorses and dairy cows, are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Film rentals.</Font><EmDash />Film rentals are exempt when an admission is charged for viewing such film, and license fees and direct charges for films, videotapes, and transcriptions used by television or radio stations or networks are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Flags.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are sales of the flag of the United States and the official state flag of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Retired Educators Association and its local chapters.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from payment of the tax imposed by this chapter are purchases of office supplies, equipment, and publications made by the Florida Retired Educators Association and its local chapters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Guide dogs for the blind.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are the sale or rental of guide dogs for the blind, commonly referred to as “seeing-eye dogs,” and the sale of food or other items for such guide dogs.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a consumer’s certificate of exemption to any blind person who holds an identification card as provided for in s. 413.091 and who either owns or rents, or contemplates the ownership or rental of, a guide dog for the blind. The consumer’s certificate of exemption shall be issued without charge and shall be of such size as to be capable of being carried in a wallet or billfold.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall make such rules concerning items exempt from tax under the provisions of this paragraph as may be necessary to provide that any person authorized to have a consumer’s certificate of exemption need only present such a certificate at the time of paying for exempt goods and shall not be required to pay any tax thereon.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Hospital meals and rooms.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from payment of the tax imposed by this chapter on rentals and meals are patients and inmates of any hospital or other physical plant or facility designed and operated primarily for the care of persons who are ill, aged, infirm, mentally or physically incapacitated, or otherwise dependent on special care or attention. Residents of a home for the aged are exempt from payment of taxes on meals provided through the facility. A home for the aged is defined as a facility that is licensed or certified in part or in whole under chapter 400, chapter 429, or chapter 651, or that is financed by a mortgage loan made or insured by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development under s. 202, s. 202 with a s. 8 subsidy, s. 221(d)(3) or (4), s. 232, or s. 236 of the National Housing Act, or other such similar facility designed and operated primarily for the care of the aged.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Household fuels.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from payment of the tax imposed by this chapter are sales of utilities to residential households or owners of residential models in this state by utility companies who pay the gross receipts tax imposed under s. 203.01, and sales of fuel to residential households or owners of residential models, including oil, kerosene, liquefied petroleum gas, coal, wood, and other fuel products used in the household or residential model for the purposes of heating, cooking, lighting, and refrigeration, regardless of whether such sales of utilities and fuels are separately metered and billed direct to the residents or are metered and billed to the landlord. If any part of the utility or fuel is used for a nonexempt purpose, the entire sale is taxable. The landlord shall provide a separate meter for nonexempt utility or fuel consumption. For the purposes of this paragraph, licensed family day care homes shall also be exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Meals provided by certain nonprofit organizations.</Font><EmDash />There is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter the sale of prepared meals by a nonprofit volunteer organization to handicapped, elderly, or indigent persons when such meals are delivered as a charitable function by the organization to such persons at their places of residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Organizations providing special educational, cultural, recreational, and social benefits to minors.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are sales or leases to and sales of donated property by nonprofit organizations which are incorporated pursuant to chapter 617 the primary purpose of which is providing activities that contribute to the development of good character or good sportsmanship, or to the educational or cultural development, of minors. This exemption is extended only to that level of the organization that has a salaried executive officer or an elected nonsalaried executive officer. For the purpose of this paragraph, the term “donated property” means any property transferred to such nonprofit organization for less than 50 percent of its fair market value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Religious institutions.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter transactions involving sales or leases directly to religious institutions when used in carrying on their customary nonprofit religious activities or sales or leases of tangible personal property by religious institutions having an established physical place for worship at which nonprofit religious services and activities are regularly conducted and carried on.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “religious institutions” means churches, synagogues, and established physical places for worship at which nonprofit religious services and activities are regularly conducted and carried on. The term “religious institutions” includes nonprofit corporations the sole purpose of which is to provide free transportation services to church members, their families, and other church attendees. The term “religious institutions” also includes nonprofit state, nonprofit district, or other nonprofit governing or administrative offices the function of which is to assist or regulate the customary activities of religious institutions. The term “religious institutions” also includes any nonprofit corporation that is qualified as nonprofit under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and that owns and operates a Florida television station, at least 90 percent of the programming of which station consists of programs of a religious nature and the financial support for which, exclusive of receipts for broadcasting from other nonprofit organizations, is predominantly from contributions from the general public. The term “religious institutions” also includes any nonprofit corporation that is qualified as nonprofit under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, the primary activity of which is making and distributing audio recordings of religious scriptures and teachings to blind or visually impaired persons at no charge. The term “religious institutions” also includes any nonprofit corporation that is qualified as nonprofit under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, the sole or primary function of which is to provide, upon invitation, nonprofit religious services, evangelistic services, religious education, administrative assistance, or missionary assistance for a church, synagogue, or established physical place of worship at which nonprofit religious services and activities are regularly conducted.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Veterans’ organizations.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter transactions involving sales or leases to qualified veterans’ organizations and their auxiliaries when used in carrying on their customary veterans’ organization activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “veterans’ organizations” means nationally chartered or recognized veterans’ organizations, including, but not limited to, Florida chapters of the Paralyzed Veterans of America, Catholic War Veterans of the U.S.A., Jewish War Veterans of the U.S.A., and the Disabled American Veterans, Department of Florida, Inc., which hold current exemptions from federal income tax under s. 501(c)(4) or (19) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Schools, colleges, and universities.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are sales or leases to state tax-supported schools, colleges, or universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Section 501(c)(3) organizations.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are sales or leases to organizations determined by the Internal Revenue Service to be currently exempt from federal income tax pursuant to s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, when such leases or purchases are used in carrying on their customary nonprofit activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Resource recovery equipment.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt is resource recovery equipment which is owned and operated by or on behalf of any county or municipality, certified by the Department of Environmental Protection under the provisions of s. 403.715.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">School books and school lunches.</Font><EmDash />This exemption applies to school books used in regularly prescribed courses of study, and to school lunches served in public, parochial, or nonprofit schools operated for and attended by pupils of grades K through 12. Yearbooks, magazines, newspapers, directories, bulletins, and similar publications distributed by such educational institutions to their students are also exempt. School books and food sold or served at community colleges and other institutions of higher learning are taxable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Tasting beverages.</Font><EmDash />Vinous and alcoholic beverages provided by distributors or vendors for the purpose of “wine tasting” and “spirituous beverage tasting” as contemplated under the provisions of <Reference Number="8" />ss. 564.06 and 565.12, respectively, are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Boats temporarily docked in state.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 328, pertaining to the registration of vessels, a boat upon which the state sales or use tax has not been paid is exempt from the use tax under this chapter if it enters and remains in this state for a period not to exceed a total of 20 days in any calendar year calculated from the date of first dockage or slippage at a facility, registered with the department, that rents dockage or slippage space in this state. If a boat brought into this state for use under this paragraph is placed in a facility, registered with the department, for repairs, alterations, refitting, or modifications and such repairs, alterations, refitting, or modifications are supported by written documentation, the 20-day period shall be tolled during the time the boat is physically in the care, custody, and control of the repair facility, including the time spent on sea trials conducted by the facility. The 20-day time period may be tolled only once within a calendar year when a boat is placed for the first time that year in the physical care, custody, and control of a registered repair facility; however, the owner may request and the department may grant an additional tolling of the 20-day period for purposes of repairs that arise from a written guarantee given by the registered repair facility, which guarantee covers only those repairs or modifications made during the first tolled period. Within 72 hours after the date upon which the registered repair facility took possession of the boat, the facility must have in its possession, on forms prescribed by the department, an affidavit which states that the boat is under its care, custody, and control and that the owner does not use the boat while in the facility. Upon completion of the repairs, alterations, refitting, or modifications, the registered repair facility must, within 72 hours after the date of release, have in its possession a copy of the release form which shows the date of release and any other information the department requires. The repair facility shall maintain a log that documents all alterations, additions, repairs, and sea trials during the time the boat is under the care, custody, and control of the facility. The affidavit shall be maintained by the registered repair facility as part of its records for as long as required by s. 213.35. When, within 6 months after the date of its purchase, a boat is brought into this state under this paragraph, the 6-month period provided in s. 212.05(1)(a)2. or s. 212.06(8) shall be tolled.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the period of repairs, alterations, refitting, or modifications and during the 20-day period referred to in subparagraph 1., the boat may be listed for sale, contracted for sale, or sold exclusively by a broker or dealer registered with the department without incurring a use tax under this chapter; however, the sales tax levied under this chapter applies to such sale.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mere storage of a boat at a registered repair facility does not qualify as a tax-exempt use in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, “registered repair facility” means:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A full-service facility that:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located on a navigable body of water;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has haulout capability such as a dry dock, travel lift, railway, or similar equipment to service craft under the care, custody, and control of the facility;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has adequate piers and storage facilities to provide safe berthing of vessels in its care, custody, and control; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has necessary shops and equipment to provide repair or warranty work on vessels under the care, custody, and control of the facility;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A marina that:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located on a navigable body of water;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has adequate piers and storage facilities to provide safe berthing of vessels in its care, custody, and control; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has necessary shops and equipment to provide repairs or warranty work on vessels; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A shoreside facility that:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located on a navigable body of water;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has adequate piers and storage facilities to provide safe berthing of vessels in its care, custody, and control; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has necessary shops and equipment to provide repairs or warranty work.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Volunteer fire departments.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are firefighting and rescue service equipment and supplies purchased by volunteer fire departments, duly chartered under the Florida Statutes as corporations not for profit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Professional services.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also exempted are professional, insurance, or personal service transactions that involve sales as inconsequential elements for which no separate charges are made.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal service transactions exempted pursuant to subparagraph 1. do not exempt the sale of information services involving the furnishing of printed, mimeographed, or multigraphed matter, or matter duplicating written or printed matter in any other manner, other than professional services and services of employees, agents, or other persons acting in a representative or fiduciary capacity or information services furnished to newspapers and radio and television stations. As used in this subparagraph, the term “information services” includes the services of collecting, compiling, or analyzing information of any kind or nature and furnishing reports thereof to other persons.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption does not apply to any service warranty transaction taxable under s. 212.0506.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption does not apply to any service transaction taxable under s. 212.05(1)(i).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Certain newspaper, magazine, and newsletter subscriptions, shoppers, and community newspapers.</Font><EmDash />Likewise exempt are newspaper, magazine, and newsletter subscriptions in which the product is delivered to the customer by mail. Also exempt are free, circulated publications that are published on a regular basis, the content of which is primarily advertising, and that are distributed through the mail, home delivery, or newsstands. The exemption for newspaper, magazine, and newsletter subscriptions which is provided in this paragraph applies only to subscriptions entered into after March 1, 1997.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Sporting equipment brought into the state.</Font><EmDash />Sporting equipment brought into Florida, for a period of not more than 4 months in any calendar year, used by an athletic team or an individual athlete in a sporting event is exempt from the use tax if such equipment is removed from the state within 7 days after the completion of the event.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Charter fishing vessels.</Font><EmDash />The charge for chartering any boat or vessel, with the crew furnished, solely for the purpose of fishing is exempt from the tax imposed under s. 212.04 or s. 212.05. This exemption does not apply to any charge to enter or stay upon any “head-boat,” party boat, or other boat or vessel. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to exempt any boat from sales or use tax upon the purchase thereof except as provided in paragraph (t) and s. 212.05.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="z">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Vending machines sponsored by nonprofit or charitable organizations.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are food or drinks for human consumption sold for 25 cents or less through a coin-operated vending machine sponsored by a nonprofit corporation qualified as nonprofit pursuant to s. 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Certain commercial vehicles.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt is the sale, lease, or rental of a commercial motor vehicle as defined in s. 207.002(2), when the following conditions are met:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, lease, or rental occurs between two commonly owned and controlled corporations;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such vehicle was titled and registered in this state at the time of the sale, lease, or rental; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida sales tax was paid on the acquisition of such vehicle by the seller, lessor, or renter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Community cemeteries.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are purchases by any nonprofit corporation that has qualified under s. 501(c)(13) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and is operated for the purpose of maintaining a cemetery that was donated to the community by deed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="cc">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Works of art.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also exempt are works of art sold to or used by an educational institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption also applies to the sale to or use in this state of any work of art by any person if it was purchased or imported exclusively for the purpose of being donated to any educational institution, or loaned to and made available for display by any educational institution, provided that the term of the loan agreement is for at least 10 years.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided by this paragraph for donations is allowed only if the person who purchased the work of art transfers title to the donated work of art to an educational institution. Such transfer of title shall be evidenced by an affidavit meeting requirements established by rule to document entitlement to the exemption. Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude a work of art donated to an educational institution from remaining in the possession of the donor or purchaser, as long as title to the work of art lies with the educational institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A work of art is presumed to have been purchased in or imported into this state exclusively for loan as provided in subparagraph 2., if it is so loaned or placed in storage in preparation for such a loan within 90 days after purchase or importation, whichever is later; but a work of art is not deemed to be placed in storage in preparation for loan for purposes of this exemption if it is displayed at any place other than an educational institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions provided by this paragraph are allowed only if the person who purchased the work of art gives to the vendor an affidavit meeting the requirements, established by rule, to document entitlement to the exemption. The person who purchased the work of art shall forward a copy of such affidavit to the Department of Revenue at the time it is issued to the vendor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption for loans provided by subparagraph 2. applies only for the period during which a work of art is in the possession of the educational institution or is in storage before transfer of possession to that institution; and when it ceases to be so possessed or held, tax based upon the sales price paid by the owner is payable, and the statute of limitations provided in s. 95.091 shall begin to run at that time. However, tax shall not become due if the work of art is donated to an educational institution after the loan ceases.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any educational institution to which a work of art has been donated pursuant to this paragraph shall make available to the department the title to the work of art and any other relevant information. Any educational institution which has received a work of art on loan pursuant to this paragraph shall make available to the department information relating to the work of art. Any educational institution that transfers from its possession a work of art as defined by this paragraph which has been loaned to it must notify the Department of Revenue within 60 days after the transfer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of the exemptions provided by this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational institutions” includes state tax-supported, parochial, church, and nonprofit private schools, colleges, or universities that conduct regular classes and courses of study required for accreditation by or membership in the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, the Florida Council of Independent Schools, or the Florida Association of Christian Colleges and Schools, Inc.; nonprofit private schools that conduct regular classes and courses of study accepted for continuing education credit by a board of the Division of Medical Quality Assurance of the Department of Health; or nonprofit libraries, art galleries, performing arts centers that provide educational programs to school children, which programs involve performances or other educational activities at the performing arts center and serve a minimum of 50,000 school children a year, and museums open to the public.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Work of art” includes pictorial representations, sculpture, jewelry, antiques, stamp collections and coin collections, and other tangible personal property, the value of which is attributable predominantly to its artistic, historical, political, cultural, or social importance.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="dd">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Taxicab leases.</Font><EmDash />The lease of or license to use a taxicab or taxicab-related equipment and services provided by a taxicab company to an independent taxicab operator are exempt, provided, however, the exemptions provided under this paragraph only apply if sales or use tax has been paid on the acquisition of the taxicab and its related equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ee"><Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Aircraft repair and maintenance labor charges.</Font><EmDash />There shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter all labor charges for the repair and maintenance of qualified aircraft, aircraft of more than 2,000 pounds maximum certified takeoff weight, and rotary wing aircraft of more than 10,000 pounds maximum certified takeoff weight. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, charges for parts and equipment furnished in connection with such labor charges are taxable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ff">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Certain electricity or steam uses.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph 4., charges for electricity or steam used to operate machinery and equipment at a fixed location in this state when such machinery and equipment is used to manufacture, process, compound, produce, or prepare for shipment items of tangible personal property for sale, or to operate pollution control equipment, recycling equipment, maintenance equipment, or monitoring or control equipment used in such operations are exempt to the extent provided in this paragraph. If 75 percent or more of the electricity or steam used at the fixed location is used to operate qualifying machinery or equipment, 100 percent of the charges for electricity or steam used at the fixed location are exempt. If less than 75 percent but 50 percent or more of the electricity or steam used at the fixed location is used to operate qualifying machinery or equipment, 50 percent of the charges for electricity or steam used at the fixed location are exempt. If less than 50 percent of the electricity or steam used at the fixed location is used to operate qualifying machinery or equipment, none of the charges for electricity or steam used at the fixed location are exempt.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies only to industries classified under SIC Industry Major Group Numbers 10, 12, 13, 14, 20, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, and 39 and Industry Group Number 212. As used in this paragraph, “SIC” means those classifications contained in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual, 1987, as published by the Office of Management and Budget, Executive Office of the President.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possession by a seller of a written certification by the purchaser, certifying the purchaser’s entitlement to an exemption permitted by this subsection, relieves the seller from the responsibility of collecting the tax on the nontaxable amounts, and the department shall look solely to the purchaser for recovery of such tax if it determines that the purchaser was not entitled to the exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such exemption shall be applied as follows: beginning July 1, 2000, 100 percent of the charges for such electricity or steam shall be exempt.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="gg">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Fair associations.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter is the sale, use, lease, rental, or grant of a license to use, made directly to or by a fair association, of real or tangible personal property; any charge made by a fair association, or its agents, for parking, admissions, or for temporary parking of vehicles used for sleeping quarters; rentals, subleases, and sublicenses of real or tangible personal property between the owner of the central amusement attraction and any owner of an amusement ride, as those terms are used in ss. 616.15(1)(b) and 616.242(3)(a), for the furnishing of amusement rides at a public fair or exposition; and other transactions of a fair association which are incurred directly by the fair association in the financing, construction, and operation of a fair, exposition, or other event or facility that is authorized by s. 616.08. As used in this paragraph, the terms “fair association” and “public fair or exposition” have the same meaning as those terms are defined in s. 616.001. This exemption does not apply to the sale of tangible personal property made by a fair association through an agent or independent contractor; sales of admissions and tangible personal property by a concessionaire, vendor, exhibitor, or licensee; or rentals and subleases of tangible personal property or real property between the owner of the central amusement attraction and a concessionaire, vendor, exhibitor, or licensee, except for the furnishing of amusement rides, which transactions are exempt.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="hh">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Solar energy systems.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are solar energy systems or any component thereof. The Florida Solar Energy Center shall from time to time certify to the department a list of equipment and requisite hardware considered to be a solar energy system or a component thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ii">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Nonprofit cooperative hospital laundries.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are sales or leases to nonprofit organizations that are incorporated under chapter 617 and which are treated, for federal income tax purposes, as cooperatives under subchapter T of the Internal Revenue Code, whose sole purpose is to offer laundry supplies and services to their members who must all be exempt from federal income tax pursuant to s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. A member of a nonprofit cooperative hospital laundry whose Internal Revenue Code status changes shall, within 90 days after such change, divest all participation in the cooperative. The provision of laundry supplies and services to a nonmember business pursuant to a declaration of emergency under s. 252.36(2) and a written emergency plan of operation executed by the members of the cooperative does not invalidate or cause the denial of a cooperative’s certificate of exemption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="jj">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Complimentary meals.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are food or drinks that are furnished as part of a packaged room rate by any person offering for rent or lease any transient living accommodations as described in s. 509.013(4)(a) which are licensed under part I of chapter 509 and which are subject to the tax under s. 212.03, if a separate charge or specific amount for the food or drinks is not shown. Such food or drinks are considered to be sold at retail as part of the total charge for the transient living accommodations. Moreover, the person offering the accommodations is not considered to be the consumer of items purchased in furnishing such food or drinks and may purchase those items under conditions of a sale for resale.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="kk">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Nonprofit corporation conducting the correctional work programs.</Font><EmDash />Products sold pursuant to s. 946.515 by the corporation organized pursuant to part II of chapter 946 are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. This exemption applies retroactively to July 1, 1983.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ll">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Parent-teacher organizations, parent-teacher associations, and schools having grades K through 12.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sales or leases to parent-teacher organizations and associations the purpose of which is to raise funds for schools that teach grades K through 12 and that are associated with schools having grades K through 12 are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parent-teacher organizations and associations described in subparagraph 1., and schools having grades K through 12, may pay tax to their suppliers on the cost price of school materials and supplies purchased, rented, or leased for resale or rental to students in grades K through 12, of items sold for fundraising purposes, and of items sold through vending machines located on the school premises, in lieu of collecting the tax imposed by this chapter from the purchaser. This paragraph also applies to food or beverages sold through vending machines located in the student lunchroom or dining room of a school having kindergarten through grade 12.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="mm">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Mobile home lot improvements.</Font><EmDash />Items purchased by developers for use in making improvements to a mobile home lot owned by the developer may be purchased tax-exempt as a sale for resale if made pursuant to a contract that requires the developer to sell a mobile home to a purchaser, place the mobile home on the lot, and make the improvements to the lot for a single lump-sum price. The developer must collect and remit sales tax on the entire lump-sum price.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="nn">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Veterans Administration.</Font><EmDash />When a veteran of the armed forces purchases an aircraft, boat, mobile home, motor vehicle, or other vehicle from a dealer pursuant to the provisions of 38 U.S.C. s. 3902(a), or any successor provision of the United States Code, the amount that is paid directly to the dealer by the Veterans Administration is not taxable. However, any portion of the purchase price which is paid directly to the dealer by the veteran is taxable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="oo">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Complimentary items.</Font><EmDash />There is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any food or drink, whether or not cooked or prepared on the premises, provided without charge as a sample or for the convenience of customers by a dealer that primarily sells food product items at retail.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any item given to a customer as part of a price guarantee plan related to point-of-sale errors by a dealer that primarily sells food products at retail.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The exemptions in this paragraph do not apply to businesses with the primary activity of serving prepared meals or alcoholic beverages for immediate consumption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="pp">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Donated foods or beverages.</Font><EmDash />Any food or beverage donated by a dealer that sells food products at retail to a food bank or an organization that holds a current exemption from federal corporate income tax pursuant to s. 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="qq">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Racing dogs.</Font><EmDash />The sale of a racing dog by its owner is exempt if the owner is also the breeder of the animal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="rr">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Equipment used in aircraft repair and maintenance.</Font><EmDash />There shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter replacement engines, parts, and equipment used in the repair or maintenance of qualified aircraft, aircraft of more than 2,000 pounds maximum certified takeoff weight, and rotary wing aircraft of more than 10,300 pounds maximum certified takeoff weight, when such parts or equipment are installed on such aircraft that is being repaired or maintained in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ss">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Aircraft sales or leases.</Font><EmDash />The sale or lease of a qualified aircraft or an aircraft of more than 15,000 pounds maximum certified takeoff weight for use by a common carrier is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. As used in this paragraph, “common carrier” means an airline operating under Federal Aviation Administration regulations contained in Title 14, chapter I, part 121 or part 129 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="tt">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Nonprofit water systems.</Font><EmDash />Sales or leases to a not-for-profit corporation which holds a current exemption from federal income tax under s. 501(c)(4) or (12) of the Internal Revenue Code, as amended, are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter if the sole or primary function of the corporation is to construct, maintain, or operate a water system in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="uu">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Library cooperatives.</Font><EmDash />Sales or leases to library cooperatives certified under s. 257.41(2) are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="vv">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Advertising agencies.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “advertising agency” means any firm that is primarily engaged in the business of providing advertising materials and services to its clients.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of advertising services by an advertising agency to a client is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are items of tangible personal property such as photographic negatives and positives, videos, films, galleys, mechanicals, veloxes, illustrations, digital audiotapes, analog tapes, printed advertisement copies, compact discs for the purpose of recording, digital equipment, and artwork and the services used to produce those items if the items are:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sold to an advertising agency that is acting as an agent for its clients pursuant to contract, and are created for the performance of advertising services for the clients;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Produced, fabricated, manufactured, or otherwise created by an advertising agency for its clients, and are used in the performance of advertising services for the clients; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sold by an advertising agency to its clients in the performance of advertising services for the clients, whether or not the charges for these items are marked up or separately stated.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The exemption provided by this subparagraph does not apply when tangible personal property such as film, paper, and videotapes is purchased to create items such as photographic negatives and positives, videos, films, galleys, mechanicals, veloxes, illustrations, and artwork that are sold to an advertising agency or produced in-house by an advertising agency on behalf of its clients.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The items exempted from tax under subparagraph 2. and the creative services used by an advertising agency to design the advertising for promotional goods such as displays, display containers, exhibits, newspaper inserts, brochures, catalogues, direct mail letters or flats, shirts, hats, pens, pencils, key chains, or other printed goods or materials are not subject to tax. However, when such promotional goods are produced or reproduced for distribution, tax applies to the sales price charged to the client for such promotional goods.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For items purchased by an advertising agency and exempt from tax under this paragraph, possession of an exemption certificate from the advertising agency certifying the agency’s entitlement to exemption relieves the vendor of the responsibility of collecting the tax on the sale of such items to the advertising agency, and the department shall look solely to the advertising agency for recovery of tax if it determines that the advertising agency was not entitled to the exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions provided by this paragraph apply retroactively, except that all taxes that have been collected must be remitted, and taxes that have been remitted before July 1, 1999, on transactions that are subject to exemption under this paragraph are not subject to refund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules that interpret or define the provisions of these exemptions and provide examples regarding the application of these exemptions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ww">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Bullion.</Font><EmDash />The sale of gold, silver, or platinum bullion, or any combination thereof, in a single transaction is exempt if the sales price exceeds $500. The dealer must maintain proper documentation, as prescribed by rule of the department, to identify that portion of a transaction which involves the sale of gold, silver, or platinum bullion and is exempt under this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="xx">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Certain repair and labor charges.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of subparagraphs 2. and 3., there is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter all labor charges for the repair of, and parts and materials used in the repair of and incorporated into, industrial machinery and equipment which is used for the manufacture, processing, compounding, production, or preparation for shipping of items of tangible personal property at a fixed location within this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies only to industries classified under SIC Industry Major Group Numbers 10, 12, 13, 14, 20, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, and 39 and Industry Group Number 212. As used in this subparagraph, “SIC” means those classifications contained in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual, 1987, as published by the Office of Management and Budget, Executive Office of the President.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption shall be applied as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2000, 50 percent of such charges for repair parts and labor shall be exempt.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2001, 75 percent of such charges for repair parts and labor shall be exempt.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2002, 100 percent of such charges for repair parts and labor shall be exempt.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="yy">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Film and other printing supplies.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt are the following materials purchased, produced, or created by businesses classified under SIC Industry Numbers 275, 276, 277, 278, or 279 for use in producing graphic matter for sale: film, photographic paper, dyes used for embossing and engraving, artwork, typography, lithographic plates, and negatives. As used in this paragraph, “SIC” means those classifications contained in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual, 1987, as published by the Office of Management and Budget, Executive Office of the President.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="zz">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">People-mover systems.</Font><EmDash />People-mover systems, and parts thereof, which are purchased or manufactured by contractors employed either directly by or as agents for the United States Government, the state, a county, a municipality, a political subdivision of the state, or the public operator of a public-use airport as defined by s. 332.004(14) are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter when the systems or parts go into or become part of publicly owned facilities. In the case of contractors who manufacture and install such systems and parts, this exemption extends to the purchase of component parts and all other manufacturing and fabrication costs. The department may provide a form to be used by contractors to provide to suppliers of people-mover systems or parts to certify the contractors’ eligibility for the exemption provided under this paragraph. As used in this paragraph, “people-mover systems” includes wheeled passenger vehicles and related control and power distribution systems that are part of a transportation system for use by the general public, regardless of whether such vehicles are operator-controlled or driverless, self-propelled or propelled by external power and control systems, or conducted on roads, rails, guidebeams, or other permanent structures that are an integral part of such transportation system. “Related control and power distribution systems” includes any electrical or electronic control or signaling equipment, but does not include the embedded wiring, conduits, or cabling used to transmit electrical or electronic signals among such control equipment, power distribution equipment, signaling equipment, and wheeled vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aaa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Fire and Emergency Services Foundation.</Font><EmDash />Sales or leases to the Florida Fire and Emergency Services Foundation are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bbb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Railroad roadway materials.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter are railroad roadway materials used in the construction, repair, or maintenance of railways. Railroad roadway materials shall include rails, ties, ballasts, communication equipment, signal equipment, power transmission equipment, and any other track materials.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ccc">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Advertising materials distributed free of charge by mail in an envelope.</Font><EmDash />Likewise exempt are materials consisting exclusively of advertisements, such as individual coupons or other individual cards, sheets, or pages of printed advertising, that are distributed free of charge by mail in an envelope for 10 or more persons on a monthly, bimonthly, or other regular basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ddd">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Certain delivery charges.</Font><EmDash />Separately stated charges that can be avoided at the option of the purchaser for the delivery, inspection, placement, or removal from packaging or shipping materials of furniture or appliances by the selling dealer at the premises of the purchaser or the removal of similar items from the premises of the purchaser are exempt. If any charge for delivery, inspection, placement, or removal of furniture or appliances includes the modification, assembly, or construction of such furniture or appliances, then all of the charges are taxable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="eee">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Bookstore operations at a postsecondary educational institution.</Font><EmDash />Also exempt from payment of the tax imposed by this chapter on renting, leasing, letting, or granting a license for the use of any real property are payments to a postsecondary educational institution made by any person pursuant to a grant of the right to conduct bookstore operations on real property owned or leased by the postsecondary educational institution. As used in this paragraph, the term “bookstore operations” means activities consisting predominantly of sales, distribution, and provision of textbooks, merchandise, and services traditionally offered in college and university bookstores for the benefit of the institution’s students, faculty, and staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="fff">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Aircraft temporarily in the state.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An aircraft owned by a nonresident is exempt from the use tax imposed under this chapter if the aircraft enters and remains in this state for less than a total of 21 days during the 6-month period after the date of purchase. The temporary use of the aircraft and subsequent removal from this state may be proven by invoices for fuel, tie-down, or hangar charges issued by out-of-state vendors or suppliers or similar documentation that clearly and specifically identifies the aircraft. The exemption provided in this subparagraph is in addition to the exemptions provided in subparagraph 2. and s. 212.05(1)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An aircraft owned by a nonresident is exempt from the use tax imposed under this chapter if the aircraft enters or remains in this state exclusively for purposes of flight training, repairs, alterations, refitting, or modification. Such purposes shall be supported by written documentation issued by in-state vendors or suppliers which clearly and specifically identifies the aircraft. The exemption provided in this subparagraph is in addition to the exemptions provided in subparagraph 1. and s. 212.05(1)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ggg">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Fractional aircraft ownership programs.</Font><EmDash />The sale or use of aircraft primarily used in a fractional aircraft ownership program or of any parts or labor used in the completion, maintenance, repair, or overhaul of such aircraft is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. The exemption is not allowed unless the program manager of the fractional aircraft ownership program furnishes the dealer with a certificate stating that the lease, purchase, repair, or maintenance is for aircraft primarily used in a fractional aircraft ownership program and that the program manager qualifies for the exemption. If a program manager makes tax-exempt purchases on a continual basis, the program manager may allow the dealer to keep the certificate on file. The program manager must inform a dealer that keeps the certificate on file if the program manager no longer qualifies for the exemption. The department may adopt rules to administer this paragraph, including rules determining the format of the certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="hhh">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Equipment, machinery, and other materials for renewable energy technologies.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Biodiesel” means the mono-alkyl esters of long-chain fatty acids derived from plant or animal matter for use as a source of energy and meeting the specifications for biodiesel and biodiesel blends with petroleum products as adopted by rule of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. “Biodiesel” may refer to biodiesel blends designated BXX, where XX represents the volume percentage of biodiesel fuel in the blend.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ethanol” means an anhydrous denatured alcohol produced by the conversion of carbohydrates meeting the specifications for fuel ethanol and fuel ethanol blends with petroleum products as adopted by rule of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. “Ethanol” may refer to fuel ethanol blends designated EXX, where XX represents the volume percentage of fuel ethanol in the blend.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renewable fuel” means a fuel produced from biomass that is used to replace or reduce the quantity of fossil fuel present in motor fuel or diesel fuel. “Biomass” means biomass as defined in s. 366.91, “motor fuel” means motor fuel as defined in s. 206.01, and “diesel fuel” means diesel fuel as defined in s. 206.86.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale or use in the state of the following is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter: materials used in the distribution of biodiesel (B10-B100), ethanol (E10-E100), and other renewable fuels, including fueling infrastructure, transportation, and storage, up to a limit of $1 million in tax each state fiscal year for all taxpayers. Gasoline fueling station pump retrofits for biodiesel (B10-B100), ethanol (E10-E100), and other renewable fuel distribution qualify for the exemption provided in this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall provide to the department a list of items eligible for the exemption provided in this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided in this paragraph shall be available to a purchaser only through a refund of previously paid taxes. An eligible item is subject to refund one time. A person who has received a refund on an eligible item shall notify the next purchaser of the item that the item is no longer eligible for a refund of paid taxes. The notification shall be provided to each subsequent purchaser on the sales invoice or other proof of purchase.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to receive the exemption provided in this paragraph, a purchaser shall file an application with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. The application shall be developed by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in consultation with the department, and shall require:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person claiming the refund.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific description of the purchase for which a refund is sought, including, when applicable, a serial number or other permanent identification number.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sales invoice or other proof of purchase showing the amount of sales tax paid, the date of purchase, and the name and address of the sales tax dealer from whom the property was purchased.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement that the information provided is accurate and that the requirements of this paragraph have been met.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of an application, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall review the application and notify the applicant of any deficiencies. Upon receipt of a completed application, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall evaluate the application for the exemption and issue a written certification that the applicant is eligible for a refund or issue a written denial of such certification. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall provide the department a copy of each certification issued upon approval of an application.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certified applicant is responsible for applying for the refund and forwarding the certification that the applicant is eligible to the department within 6 months after certification by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A refund approved pursuant to this paragraph shall be made within 30 days after formal approval by the department.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services may adopt by rule the form for the application for a certificate, requirements for the content and format of information submitted to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services in support of the application, other procedural requirements, and criteria by which the application will be determined. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services may adopt other rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer this paragraph, including rules establishing additional forms and procedures for claiming the exemption.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall be responsible for ensuring that the total amount of the exemptions authorized does not exceed the limits specified in subparagraph 2.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approval of the exemptions under this paragraph is on a first-come, first-served basis, based upon the date complete applications are received by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. Incomplete placeholder applications shall not be accepted and shall not secure a place in the first-come, first-served application line. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall determine and publish on its website on a regular basis the amount of sales tax funds remaining in each fiscal year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph expires July 1, 2016.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="iii">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Items used in manufacturing and fabricating aircraft and gas turbine engines.</Font><EmDash />Chemicals, machinery, parts, and equipment used and consumed in the manufacture or fabrication of aircraft engines and gas turbine engines, including cores, electrical discharge machining supplies, brass electrodes, ceramic guides, reamers, grinding and deburring wheels, Norton vortex wheels, argon, nitrogen, helium, fluid abrasive cutters, solvents and soaps, boroscopes, penetrants, patterns, dies, and molds consumed in the production of castings are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="jjj">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Accessible taxicabs.</Font><EmDash />The sale or lease of accessible taxicabs is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter. As used in this paragraph, the term “accessible taxicab” means a chauffer-driven taxi, limousine, sedan, van, or other passenger vehicle for which an operator is hired to use for the transportation of persons for compensation; which transports eight passengers or fewer; is equipped with a lift or ramp designed specifically to transport physically disabled persons or contains any other device designed to permit access to, and enable the transportation of, physically disabled persons, including persons who use wheelchairs, motorized wheelchairs, or similar mobility aids; which complies with the accessibility requirements of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, 49 C.F.R. ss. 38.23, 38.25, and 38.31, as amended, regardless of whether such requirements would apply under federal law; and meets all applicable federal motor vehicle safety standards and regulations adopted thereunder. If the lift or ramp or any other device is installed through an aftermarket conversion of a stock vehicle, only the value of the conversion is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL EXEMPTIONS; VESSELS ENGAGED IN INTERSTATE OR FOREIGN COMMERCE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale or use of vessels and parts thereof used to transport persons or property in interstate or foreign commerce, including commercial fishing vessels, is subject to the taxes imposed in this chapter only to the extent provided herein. The basis of the tax shall be the ratio of intrastate mileage to interstate or foreign mileage traveled by the carrier’s vessels which were used in interstate or foreign commerce and which had at least some Florida mileage during the previous fiscal year. The ratio would be determined at the close of the carrier’s fiscal year. However, during the fiscal year in which the vessel begins its initial operations in this state, the vessel’s mileage apportionment factor may be determined on the basis of an estimated ratio of anticipated miles in this state to anticipated total miles for that year and, subsequently, additional tax shall be paid on the vessel, or a refund may be applied for, on the basis of the actual ratio of the vessel’s miles in this state to its total miles for that year. This ratio shall be applied each month to the total Florida purchases of such vessels and parts thereof which are used in Florida to establish that portion of the total used and consumed in intrastate movement and subject to the tax at the applicable rate. The basis for imposition of any discretionary surtax shall be as set forth in s. 212.054. Items, appropriate to carry out the purposes for which a vessel is designed or equipped and used, purchased by the owner, operator, or agent of a vessel for use on board such vessel shall be deemed to be parts of the vessel upon which the same are used or consumed. Vessels and parts thereof used to transport persons or property in interstate and foreign commerce are hereby determined to be susceptible to a distinct and separate classification for taxation under the provisions of this chapter. Vessels and parts thereof used exclusively in intrastate commerce do not qualify for the proration of tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The partial exemption provided for in this subsection shall not be allowed unless the purchaser signs an affidavit stating that the item or items to be partially exempted are for the exclusive use designated herein and setting forth the extent of such partial exemption. Any person furnishing a false affidavit to such effect for the purpose of evading payment of any tax imposed under this chapter is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 212.12 and as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that neither subsection (4) nor this subsection shall be construed as imposing the tax provided by this chapter on vessels used as common carriers, contract carriers, or private carriers, engaged in interstate or foreign commerce, except to the extent provided by the pro rata formula provided in subsection (4) and in paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL EXEMPTIONS; RAILROADS AND MOTOR VEHICLES ENGAGED IN INTERSTATE OR FOREIGN COMMERCE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Railroads that are licensed as common carriers by the Surface Transportation Board and parts thereof used to transport persons or property in interstate or foreign commerce are subject to tax imposed in this chapter only to the extent provided herein. The basis of the tax shall be the ratio of intrastate mileage to interstate or foreign mileage traveled by the carrier during the previous fiscal year of the carrier. Such ratio is to be determined at the close of the carrier’s fiscal year. However, during the fiscal year in which the railroad begins its initial operations in this state, the railroad’s mileage apportionment factor may be determined on the basis of an estimated ratio of anticipated miles in this state to anticipated total miles for that year and, subsequently, additional tax shall be paid on the railroad, or a refund may be applied for, on the basis of the actual ratio of the railroad’s miles in this state to its total miles for that year. This ratio shall be applied each month to the purchases of the railroad in this state which are used in this state to establish that portion of the total used and consumed in intrastate movement and subject to tax under this chapter. The basis for imposition of any discretionary surtax is set forth in s. 212.054. Railroads that are licensed as common carriers by the Surface Transportation Board and parts thereof used to transport persons or property in interstate and foreign commerce are hereby determined to be susceptible to a distinct and separate classification for taxation under the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motor vehicles that are engaged in interstate commerce as common carriers, and parts thereof, used to transport persons or property in interstate or foreign commerce are subject to tax imposed in this chapter only to the extent provided herein. The basis of the tax shall be the ratio of intrastate mileage to interstate or foreign mileage traveled by the carrier’s motor vehicles which were used in interstate or foreign commerce and which had at least some Florida mileage during the previous fiscal year of the carrier. Such ratio is to be determined at the close of the carrier’s fiscal year. However, during the fiscal year in which the carrier begins its initial operations in this state, the carrier’s mileage apportionment factor may be determined on the basis of an estimated ratio of anticipated miles in this state to anticipated total miles for that year and, subsequently, additional tax shall be paid on the carrier, or a refund may be applied for, on the basis of the actual ratio of the carrier’s miles in this state to its total miles for that year. This ratio shall be applied each month to the purchases in this state of such motor vehicles and parts thereof which are used in this state to establish that portion of the total used and consumed in intrastate movement and subject to tax under this chapter. The basis for imposition of any discretionary surtax is set forth in s. 212.054. Motor vehicles that are engaged in interstate commerce, and parts thereof, used to transport persons or property in interstate and foreign commerce are hereby determined to be susceptible to a distinct and separate classification for taxation under the provisions of this chapter. Motor vehicles and parts thereof used exclusively in intrastate commerce do not qualify for the proration of tax. For purposes of this paragraph, parts of a motor vehicle engaged in interstate commerce include a separate tank not connected to the fuel supply system of the motor vehicle into which diesel fuel is placed to operate a refrigeration unit or other equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL EXEMPTION; MOTOR VEHICLE SOLD TO RESIDENT OF ANOTHER STATE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax collected on the sale of a new or used motor vehicle in this state to a resident of another state shall be an amount equal to the sales tax which would be imposed on such sale under the laws of the state of which the purchaser is a resident, except that such tax shall not exceed the tax that would otherwise be imposed under this chapter. At the time of the sale, the purchaser shall execute a notarized statement of his or her intent to license the vehicle in the state of which the purchaser is a resident within 45 days of the sale and of the fact of the payment to the State of Florida of a sales tax in an amount equivalent to the sales tax of his or her state of residence and shall submit the statement to the appropriate sales tax collection agency in his or her state of residence. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the removal of the vehicle from this state following the filing of an intent to license the vehicle in the purchaser’s home state if the purchaser licenses the vehicle in his or her home state within 45 days after the date of sale.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the partial exemption allowed in paragraph (a), a vehicle is subject to this state’s sales tax at the applicable state sales tax rate plus authorized surtaxes when the vehicle is purchased by a nonresident corporation or partnership and:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer of the corporation is a resident of this state;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stockholder of the corporation who owns at least 10 percent of the corporation is a resident of this state; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partner in the partnership who has at least 10 percent ownership is a resident of this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, if the vehicle is removed from this state within 45 days after purchase and remains outside the state for a minimum of 180 days, the vehicle may qualify for the partial exemption allowed in paragraph (a) despite the residency of owners or stockholders of the purchasing entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein shall require the payment of tax to the State of Florida for assessments made prior to July 1, 2001, if the tax imposed by this section has been paid to the state in which the vehicle was licensed and the department has assessed a like amount of tax on the same transactions. This provision shall apply retroactively to assessments that have been protested prior to August 1, 1999, and have not been paid on the date this act takes effect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL EXEMPTION; FLYABLE AIRCRAFT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax imposed on the sale by a manufacturer of flyable aircraft, who designs such aircraft, which sale may include necessary equipment and modifications placed on such flyable aircraft prior to delivery by the manufacturer, shall be an amount equal to the sales tax which would be imposed on such sale under the laws of the state in which the aircraft will be domiciled.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This partial exemption applies only if the purchaser is a resident of another state who will not use the aircraft in this state, or if the purchaser is a resident of another state and uses the aircraft in interstate or foreign commerce, or if the purchaser is a resident of a foreign country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum tax collectible under this subsection may not exceed 6 percent of the sales price of such aircraft. No Florida tax may be imposed on the sale of such aircraft if the state in which the aircraft will be domiciled does not allow Florida sales or use tax to be credited against its sales or use tax. Furthermore, no tax may be imposed on the sale of such aircraft if the state in which the aircraft will be domiciled has enacted a sales and use tax exemption for flyable aircraft or if the aircraft will be domiciled outside the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser shall execute a sworn affidavit attesting that he or she is not a resident of this state and stating where the aircraft will be domiciled. If the aircraft is subsequently used in this state within 6 months of the time of purchase, in violation of the intent of this subsection, the purchaser shall be liable for payment of the full use tax imposed by this chapter and shall be subject to the penalty imposed by s. 212.12(2), which penalty shall be mandatory. Notwithstanding the provisions of this paragraph, the owner of an aircraft purchased pursuant to this subsection may permit the aircraft to be returned to this state for repairs within 6 months after the date of sale without the aircraft being in violation of the law and without incurring liability for payment of tax or penalty on the purchase price of the aircraft, so long as the aircraft is removed from this state within 20 days after the completion of the repairs and such removal can be proven by invoices for fuel, tie-down, or hangar charges issued by out-of-state vendors or suppliers or similar documentation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL EXEMPTION; MASTER TAPES, RECORDS, FILMS, OR VIDEO TAPES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are exempt from the taxes imposed by this chapter the gross receipts from the sale or lease of, and the storage, use, or other consumption in this state of, master tapes or master records embodying sound, or master films or master video tapes; except that amounts paid to recording studios or motion picture or television studios for the tangible elements of such master tapes, records, films, or video tapes are taxable as otherwise provided in this chapter. This exemption will inure to the taxpayer upon presentation of the certificate of exemption issued to the taxpayer under the provisions of s. 288.1258.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Amounts paid for the tangible elements” does not include any amounts paid for the copyrightable, artistic, or other intangible elements of such master tapes, records, films, or video tapes, whether designated as royalties or otherwise, including, but not limited to, services rendered in producing, fabricating, processing, or imprinting tangible personal property or any other services or production expenses in connection therewith which may otherwise be construed as constituting a “sale” under s. 212.02.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Master films or master video tapes” means films or video tapes utilized by the motion picture and television production industries in making visual images for reproduction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Master tapes or master records embodying sound” means tapes, records, and other devices utilized by the recording industry in making recordings embodying sound.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motion picture or television studio” means a facility in which film or video tape productions or parts of productions are made and which contains the necessary equipment and personnel for this purpose and includes a mobile unit or vehicle that is equipped in much the same manner as a stationary studio and used in the making of film or video tape productions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recording studio” means a place where, by means of mechanical or electronic devices, voices, music, or other sounds are transmitted to tapes, records, or other devices capable of reproducing sound.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recording industry” means any person engaged in an occupation or business of making recordings embodying sound for a livelihood or for a profit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motion picture or television production industry” means any person engaged in an occupation or business for a livelihood or for profit of making visual motion picture or television visual images for showing on screen or television for theatrical, commercial, advertising, or educational purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No transactions shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter except those expressly exempted herein. All laws granting tax exemptions, to the extent they may be inconsistent or in conflict with this chapter, including, but not limited to, the following designated laws, shall yield to and be superseded by the provisions of this subsection: ss. 125.019, 153.76, 154.2331, 159.15, 159.31, 159.50, 159.708, 163.385, 163.395, 215.76, 243.33, 315.11, 348.65, 348.762, 349.13, 403.1834, 616.07, and 623.09, and the following Laws of Florida, acts of the year indicated: s. 31, chapter 30843, 1955; s. 19, chapter 30845, 1955; s. 12, chapter 30927, 1955; s. 8, chapter 31179, 1955; s. 15, chapter 31263, 1955; s. 13, chapter 31343, 1955; s. 16, chapter 59-1653; s. 13, chapter 59-1356; s. 12, chapter 61-2261; s. 19, chapter 61-2754; s. 10, chapter 61-2686; s. 11, chapter 63-1643; s. 11, chapter 65-1274; s. 16, chapter 67-1446; and s. 10, chapter 67-1681. This subsection does not supersede the authority of a local government to adopt financial and local government incentives pursuant to s. 163.2517.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE ADVISORY COMMITTEE.<EmDash />The department shall establish a technical assistance advisory committee with public and private sector members, including representatives of both manufacturers and retailers, to advise the Department of Revenue and the <Reference Number="9"/>Department of Health in determining the taxability of specific products and product lines pursuant to subsection (1) and paragraph (2)(a). In determining taxability and in preparing a list of specific products and product lines that are or are not taxable, the committee shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 120. Private sector members shall not be compensated for serving on the committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELECTRICAL ENERGY USED IN AN ENTERPRISE ZONE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 1995, charges for electrical energy used by a qualified business at a fixed location in an enterprise zone in a municipality which has enacted an ordinance pursuant to s. 166.231(8) which provides for exemption of municipal utility taxes on such businesses or in an enterprise zone jointly authorized by a county and a municipality which has enacted an ordinance pursuant to s. 166.231(8) which provides for exemption of municipal utility taxes on such businesses shall receive an exemption equal to 50 percent of the tax imposed by this chapter, or, if no less than 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees, the exemption shall be equal to 100 percent of the tax imposed by this chapter. A qualified business may receive such exemption for a period of 5 years from the billing period beginning not more than 30 days following notification to the applicable utility company by the department that an exemption has been authorized pursuant to this subsection and s. 166.231(8).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive this exemption, a business must file an application, with the enterprise zone development agency having jurisdiction over the enterprise zone where the business is located, on a form provided by the department for the purposes of this subsection and s. 166.231(8). The application shall be made under oath and shall include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and location of the business.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the business is located.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date on which electrical service is to be first initiated to the business.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and mailing address of the entity from which electrical energy is to be purchased.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the application.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the city in which the business is located.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, the name and address of each permanent employee of the business including, for each employee who is a resident of an enterprise zone, the identifying number assigned pursuant to s. 290.0065 to the enterprise zone in which the employee resides.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the business is a small business as defined by s. 288.703.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 working days after receipt of an application, the enterprise zone development agency shall review the application to determine if it contains all information required pursuant to paragraph (b) and meets the criteria set out in this subsection. The agency shall certify all applications that contain the information required pursuant to paragraph (b) and meet the criteria set out in this subsection as eligible to receive an exemption. If applicable, the agency shall also certify if 20 percent of the employees of the business are residents of an enterprise zone, excluding temporary and part-time employees. The certification shall be in writing, and a copy of the certification shall be transmitted to the executive director of the Department of Revenue. The applicant shall be responsible for forwarding a certified application to the department within 6 months after the occurrence of the appropriate qualifying provision set out in paragraph (f).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in a subsequent audit conducted by the department, it is determined that the business did not meet the criteria mandated in this subsection, the amount of taxes exempted shall immediately be due and payable to the department by the business, together with the appropriate interest and penalty, computed from the due date of each bill for the electrical energy purchased as exempt under this subsection, in the manner prescribed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing applications for, issuance of, and the form of applications for the exemption authorized in this subsection and provisions for recapture of taxes exempted under this subsection, and the department may establish guidelines as to qualifications for exemption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of the exemption provided in this subsection, the term “qualified business” means a business which is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">First occupying a new structure to which electrical service, other than that used for construction purposes, has not been previously provided or furnished;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Newly occupying an existing, remodeled, renovated, or rehabilitated structure to which electrical service, other than that used for remodeling, renovation, or rehabilitation of the structure, has not been provided or furnished in the three preceding billing periods; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Occupying a new, remodeled, rebuilt, renovated, or rehabilitated structure for which a refund has been granted pursuant to paragraph (5)(g).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection expires on the date specified in s. 290.016 for the expiration of the Florida Enterprise Zone Act, except that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (d) shall not expire; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any qualified business which has been granted an exemption under this subsection prior to that date shall be allowed the full benefit of this exemption as if this subsection had not expired on that date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; SPACE ACTIVITIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, lease, use, storage, consumption, or distribution in this state of any orbital space facility, space propulsion system, or space vehicle, satellite, or station of any kind possessing space flight capacity, including the components thereof.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, lease, use, storage, consumption, or distribution in this state of tangible personal property placed on or used aboard any orbital space facility, space propulsion system, or space vehicle, satellite, or station of any kind, irrespective of whether such tangible personal property is returned to this state for subsequent use, storage, or consumption in any manner. This exemption is not affected by the failure of a launch to occur, or the destruction of a launch vehicle or any components thereof.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall be strictly construed and enforced.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS; CERTAIN GOVERNMENT CONTRACTORS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to paragraph (d), the tax imposed by this chapter does not apply to the sale to or use by a government contractor of overhead materials. The term “government contractor” includes prime contractors and subcontractors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “overhead materials” means all tangible personal property, other than qualifying property as defined in s. 212.02(14)(a) and electricity, which is used or consumed in the performance of a qualifying contract, title to which property vests in or passes to the government under the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection and in s. 212.02(14)(a), the term “qualifying contract” means a contract with the United States Department of Defense or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or a subcontract thereunder, but does not include a contract or subcontract for the repair, alteration, improvement, or construction of real property, except to the extent that purchases under such a contract would otherwise be exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided in this subsection applies as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2000, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be applicable to 60 percent of the sales price or cost price of such overhead materials.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2001, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be applicable to 40 percent of the sales price or cost price of such overhead materials.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2002, the tax imposed by this chapter shall be applicable to 20 percent of the sales price or cost price of such overhead materials.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2003, the entire sales price or cost price of such overhead materials is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The exemption provided in this subsection does not apply to any part of the cost of overhead materials allocated to a contract that is not a qualifying contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possession by a seller of a resale certificate or direct-pay permit relieves the seller from the responsibility of collecting the tax, and the department shall look solely to the contractor for recovery of such tax if it determines that the contractor was not entitled to the exemption. The contractor shall self-accrue and remit any applicable sales or use tax due with respect to overhead materials and with respect to costs allocable to contracts that are not qualifying contracts. The department may amend its rules to reflect the use of resale certificates and direct-pay permits with respect to the exemption provided for in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is not an expression of legislative intent as to the applicability of any tax to any sale or use of overhead materials prior to July 1, 1999. In addition, this subsection does not imply that transactions or costs that are not described in this subsection are taxable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MACHINERY AND EQUIPMENT USED PREDOMINANTLY FOR RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Machinery and equipment used predominantly for research and development as defined in this subsection are exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Machinery and equipment” includes, but is not limited to, molds, dies, machine tooling, other appurtenances or accessories to machinery and equipment, testing and measuring equipment, test beds, computers, and software, whether purchased or self-fabricated, and, if self-fabricated, includes materials and labor for design, fabrication, and assembly.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Predominantly” means at least 50 percent of the time.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Research and development” means research that has one of the following as its ultimate goal:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic research in a scientific field of endeavor;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advancing knowledge or technology in a scientific or technical field of endeavor;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of a new product, whether or not the new product is offered for sale;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The improvement of an existing product, whether or not the improved product is offered for sale;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of new uses of an existing product, whether or not a new use is offered as a rationale to purchase the product; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The design and development of prototypes, whether or not a resulting product is offered for sale.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term “research and development” does not include ordinary testing or inspection of materials or products used for quality control, market research, efficiency surveys, consumer surveys, advertising and promotions, management studies, or research in connection with literary, historical, social science, psychological, or other similar nontechnical activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 that provide for administering and implementing this exemption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who claims the exemption provided in this subsection shall furnish the vendor of the machinery or equipment, including the vendor of materials and labor used in self-fabrication of the machinery or equipment, an affidavit stating that the item or items for which an exemption is claimed are machinery and equipment that will be used predominantly for research and development as required by this subsection. A purchaser who claims the exemption by refund shall include the affidavit with the refund application. The affidavit must contain the purchaser’s name, address, sales and use tax registration number, and, if applicable, federal employer’s identification number. Any person fraudulently furnishing an affidavit to the vendor for the purpose of evading payment of any tax imposed under this chapter shall be subject to the penalty set forth in s. 212.085 and as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of furnishing an affidavit, a purchaser claiming the exemption provided in this subsection who has a direct-pay permit may furnish the vendor with a copy of the direct-pay permit and shall maintain all documentation necessary to prove the exempt status of the purchases and fabrication activity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchasers shall maintain all documentation necessary to prove the exempt status of purchases and fabrication activity and make such documentation available for inspection pursuant to the requirements of s. 212.13(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 26319, 1949; ss. 1, 2, ch. 26323, 1949; s. 9, ch. 26871, 1951; s. 1, ch. 28082, 1953; ss. 7, 33, ch. 29615, 1955; ss. 6-8, ch. 29883, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-76; s. 1, ch. 57-398; s. 1, ch. 57-821; s. 1, ch. 57-1968; s. 1, ch. 57-1971; s. 1, ch. 59-287; ss. 1, 2, ch. 59-402; ss. 1, 2, ch. 59-448; s. 1, ch. 61-464; s. 2, ch. 61-276; s. 1, ch. 61-274; s. 7, ch. 63-253; ss. 5, 6, ch. 63-526; s. 1, ch. 63-565; s. 6, ch. 65-190; ss. 7-9, ch. 65-329; s. 1, ch. 65-331; s. 1, ch. 65-358; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; s. 4, ch. 67-180; ss. 8-12, 15, ch. 68-27; s. 1, ch. 69-99; ss. 15, 16, 19, 21, 24, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 12-16, 19, ch. 69-222; ss. 2, 3, ch. 70-206; s. 2, ch. 70-373; s. 7, ch. 71-360; s. 1, ch. 71-985; s. 70, ch. 72-221; s. 1, ch. 72-289; s. 1, ch. 73-240; s. 1, ch. 74-4; s. 1, ch. 74-134; s. 1, ch. 74-305; ss. 1, 4, ch. 75-65; s. 35, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-193; s. 1, ch. 77-194; s. 2, ch. 77-412; s. 1, ch. 78-59; s. 1, ch. 78-67; s. 1, ch. 78-77; s. 1, ch. 78-176; s. 1, ch. 78-220; s. 1, ch. 78-249; s. 1, ch. 78-270; s. 1, ch. 78-299; s. 1, ch. 78-329; s. 1, ch. 78-411; s. 41, ch. 79-164; ss. 2, 3, ch. 79-339; s. 96, ch. 79-400; ss. 1, 3, 4, ch. 80-163; s. 2, ch. 80-213; s. 10, ch. 81-151; s. 115, ch. 81-259; s. 3, ch. 81-319; s. 7, ch. 82-154; s. 1, ch. 82-206; s. 2, ch. 82-219; s. 5, ch. 83-3; s. 3, ch. 83-138; ss. 1, 2, ch. 83-154; ss. 1, 3, 8, ch. 83-297; s. 29, ch. 83-315; s. 29, ch. 83-317; ss. 2, 6, ch. 83-338; s. 265, ch. 84-309; ss. 3, 4, 5, ch. 84-324; s. 3, ch. 84-350; s. 34, ch. 84-356; s. 1, ch. 84-362; s. 30, ch. 85-80; ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-230; ss. 61, 64, 220, ch. 85-342; s. 74, ch. 86-152; ss. 5, 8, ch. 86-166; ss. 14, 25, 59, ch. 87-6; s. 4, ch. 87-72; s. 4, ch. 87-99; ss. 13, 34, ch. 87-101; s. 2, ch. 87-370; ss. 26, 27, 28, ch. 87-548; s. 1, ch. 88-123; s. 78, ch. 88-130; s. 27, ch. 88-201; ss. 2, 3, ch. 88-243; ss. 28, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 35, 42, ch. 89-356; ss. 86, 93, ch. 90-132; s. 8, ch. 90-192; s. 1, ch. 90-203; s. 87, ch. 91-45; s. 3, ch. 92-113; s. 1, ch. 92-164; s. 1, ch. 92-168; s. 10, ch. 92-173; s. 2, ch. 92-206; s. 1, ch. 92-302; ss. 11, 17, ch. 92-319; s. 5, ch. 93-46; s. 11, ch. 93-233; ss. 42, 43, ch. 94-136; s. 1, ch. 94-186; s. 21, ch. 94-218; ss. 1, 16, ch. 94-314; s. 10, ch. 94-353; s. 52, ch. 94-356; s. 32, ch. 95-145; s. 1497, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 95-232; s. 3, ch. 95-302; s. 12, ch. 95-333; s. 114, ch. 95-417; s. 92, ch. 95-418; s. 56, ch. 96-175; ss. 15, 161, 162, ch. 96-320; s. 23, ch. 96-323; s. 1, ch. 96-395; s. 26, ch. 96-397; s. 14, ch. 97-54; s. 1, ch. 97-86; s. 23, ch. 97-99; s. 5, ch. 97-197; s. 1, ch. 97-205; ss. 3, 5, 6, 7, ch. 97-221; s. 1, ch. 97-227; s. 11, ch. 97-278; s. 1, ch. 98-60; s. 2, ch. 98-133; s. 3, ch. 98-142; s. 1, ch. 98-143; s. 1, ch. 98-144; s. 14, ch. 98-166; s. 1, ch. 98-205; s. 2, ch. 98-220; s. 1, ch. 98-252; s. 2, ch. 98-273; s. 1, ch. 98-291; s. 2, ch. 98-294; s. 1, ch. 98-318; s. 1, ch. 98-328; s. 1, ch. 98-408; ss. 1, 2, ch. 98-416; s. 78, ch. 99-2; s. 1, ch. 99-171; s. 25, ch. 99-208; s. 3, ch. 99-238; s. 12, ch. 99-256; s. 1, ch. 99-269; s. 3, ch. 99-273; s. 3, ch. 99-304; s. 2, ch. 99-337; s. 1, ch. 99-364; s. 1, ch. 99-368; s. 42, ch. 2000-151; s. 37, ch. 2000-164; s. 54, ch. 2000-165; s. 4, ch. 2000-182; s. 6, ch. 2000-197; s. 13, ch. 2000-210; s. 3, ch. 2000-211; ss. 1, 3, ch. 2000-223; s. 1, ch. 2000-228; s. 2, ch. 2000-276; s. 7, ch. 2000-290; s. 3, ch. 2000-310; s. 19, ch. 2000-317; s. 10, ch. 2000-351; s. 1, ch. 2000-353; s. 15, ch. 2000-355; s. 25, ch. 2000-372; s. 34, ch. 2001-60; s. 38, ch. 2001-196; s. 2, ch. 2001-201; s. 10, ch. 2001-225; s. 52, ch. 2001-266; s. 6, ch. 2002-2; s. 9, ch. 2002-48; ss. 17, 18, 20, 22, ch. 2002-218; s. 918, ch. 2002-387; s. 5, ch. 2002-392; s. 22, ch. 2003-32; ss. 19, 41, ch. 2003-254; s. 186, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2004-243; s. 1, ch. 2005-83; s. 22, ch. 2005-132; s. 2, ch. 2005-197; s. 1, ch. 2005-282; s. 21, ch. 2005-287; s. 2, ch. 2006-2; s. 3, ch. 2006-56; s. 2, ch. 2006-57; s. 58, ch. 2006-60; s. 30, ch. 2006-69; s. 1, ch. 2006-78; s. 3, ch. 2006-113; s. 2, ch. 2006-144; s. 11, ch. 2006-197; s. 9, ch. 2006-230; s. 19, ch. 2006-289; s. 18, ch. 2007-5; s. 1, ch. 2007-53; s. 1, ch. 2007-56; s. 23, ch. 2007-106; s. 38, ch. 2008-4; s. 37, ch. 2008-153; s. 1, ch. 2008-201; s. 9, ch. 2008-227; s. 189, ch. 2008-247; s. 4, ch. 2010-4; s. 51, ch. 2010-102; s. 2, ch. 2010-128; ss. 7, 8, ch. 2010-138; s. 9, ch. 2010-147; s. 1, ch. 2011-3; s. 56, ch. 2011-36; s. 33, ch. 2011-64; s. 2, ch. 2011-97; s. 75, ch. 2011-142; s. 14, ch. 2011-189; s. 8, ch. 2012-32; s. 4, ch. 2012-117; s. 4, ch. 2012-184.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 25, ch. 2012-32, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">32 C.F.R. s. 3-405 no longer exists.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">32 C.F.R. ss. 15-202 and 15-203 no longer exist.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="4">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by Pub. L. No. 100-679, s. 5(b), 102 Stat. 4063.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="5">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 168(c) no longer defines “recovery property.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="6">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 168(c)(2)(A) no longer classifies 3-year property.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="7">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 8(2), ch. 2010-138, provides that “[t]he Department of Revenue may, and all conditions are deemed met to, adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, to implement the amendment to s. 212.08(6), Florida Statutes, made by this section. The emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="8">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">See ss. 564.08 and 565.17 for specific references to beverage tastings.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="9">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 27, ch. 2010-161, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All of the statutory powers, duties, and functions, records, personnel, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds for the administration of chapter 499, Florida Statutes, relating to drugs, devices, cosmetics, and household products shall be transferred by a type two transfer, as defined in s. 20.06(2), Florida Statutes, from the Department of Health to the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The transfer of regulatory authority under chapter 499, Florida Statutes, provided by this section shall not affect the validity of any judicial or administrative action pending as of 11:59 p.m. on the day before the effective date of this section to which the Department of Health is at that time a party, and the Department of Business and Professional Regulation shall be substituted as a party in interest in any such action.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) All lawful orders issued by the Department of Health implementing or enforcing or otherwise in regard to any provision of chapter 499, Florida Statutes, issued prior to the effective date of this section shall remain in effect and be enforceable after the effective date of this section unless thereafter modified in accordance with law.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The rules of the Department of Health relating to the implementation of chapter 499, Florida Statutes, that were in effect at 11:59 p.m. on the day prior to the effective date of this section shall become the rules of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation and shall remain in effect until amended or repealed in the manner provided by law.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Notwithstanding the transfer of regulatory authority under chapter 499, Florida Statutes, provided by this section, persons and entities holding in good standing any permit under chapter 499, Florida Statutes, as of 11:59 p.m. on the day prior to the effective date of this section shall, as of the effective date of this section, be deemed to hold in good standing a permit in the same capacity as that for which the permit was formerly issued.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) Notwithstanding the transfer of regulatory authority under chapter 499, Florida Statutes, provided by this section, persons holding in good standing any certification under chapter 499, Florida Statutes, as of 11:59 p.m. on the day prior to the effective date of this section shall, as of the effective date of this section, be deemed to be certified in the same capacity in which they were formerly certified.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(7) This section shall take effect October 1, 2011.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>