<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0212.0606" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rental car surcharge.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A surcharge of $2.00 per day or any part of a day is imposed upon the lease or rental of a motor vehicle licensed for hire and designed to carry less than nine passengers regardless of whether such motor vehicle is licensed in Florida. The surcharge applies to only the first 30 days of the term of any lease or rental. The surcharge is subject to all applicable taxes imposed by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of section 212.20, and less costs of administration, 80 percent of the proceeds of this surcharge shall be deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund, 15.75 percent of the proceeds of this surcharge shall be deposited in the Tourism Promotional Trust Fund created in s. 288.122, and 4.25 percent of the proceeds of this surcharge shall be deposited in the Florida International Trade and Promotion Trust Fund. For the purposes of this subsection, “proceeds” of the surcharge means all funds collected and received by the department under this section, including interest and penalties on delinquent surcharges. The department shall provide the Department of Transportation rental car surcharge revenue information for the previous state fiscal year by September 1 of each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in fiscal year 2007-2008 and each year thereafter, the proceeds deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund shall be allocated on an annual basis in the Department of Transportation’s work program to each department district, except the Turnpike District. The amount allocated for each district shall be based upon the amount of proceeds attributed to the counties within each respective district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, the department shall administer, collect, and enforce the surcharge as provided in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require dealers to report surcharge collections according to the county to which the surcharge was attributed. For purposes of this section, the surcharge shall be attributed to the county where the rental agreement was entered into.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dealers who collect the rental car surcharge shall report to the department all surcharge revenues attributed to the county where the rental agreement was entered into on a timely filed return for each required reporting period. The provisions of this chapter which apply to interest and penalties on delinquent taxes shall apply to the surcharge. The surcharge shall not be included in the calculation of estimated taxes pursuant to s. 212.11. The dealer’s credit provided in s. 212.12 shall not apply to any amount collected under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surcharge imposed by this section does not apply to a motor vehicle provided at no charge to a person whose motor vehicle is being repaired, adjusted, or serviced by the entity providing the replacement motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 89-364; ss. 32, 90, ch. 90-132; s. 109, ch. 90-136; s. 3, ch. 91-79; s. 5, ch. 92-299; s. 7, ch. 97-99; s. 6, ch. 98-342; s. 1, ch. 2000-257; s. 60, ch. 2002-20; s. 18, ch. 2003-254.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 22, ch. 2000-257, provides that “[n]otwithstanding any other law to the contrary the requirements of sections 206.46(3) and 206.606(2), Florida Statutes, shall not apply to any funding, programs, or other provisions contained in this act.”</Text></Note></Section>