<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0212.0305" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Convention development taxes; intent; administration; authorization; use of proceeds.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “Convention Development Tax Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />No convention development tax on transient rentals shall be imposed by the governing body of any county unless specifically authorized herein. Any tax authorized pursuant to this section shall be administered and collected exclusively as provided herein and may consist of one or more component levies as enumerated in subsection (4). It is the legislative intent that any authorization for imposition of a convention development tax shall be published in the Florida Statutes as a paragraph of subsection (4), irrespective of the duration of the levy. Each enactment shall specify the types of local governments authorized to levy a convention development tax; the rate or rates which may be imposed; the maximum length of time the tax may be imposed, if any; the procedure which must be followed to secure voter approval, if required; the purpose for which the proceeds may be expended; and such other requirements as the Legislature may provide. One of the principal purposes of the convention development tax is to promote tourism and the use of hotel facilities by facilitating the improvement and construction of convention centers. Any municipality or county wherein the convention development tax is levied is specifically authorized to adopt and implement a convention center booking policy to apply to convention centers owned or operated by a municipality or county which gives priority to bookings after July 1, 1993, in accordance with the minimum number of hotel rooms to be utilized in connection with such convention center bookings or in accordance with the impact of such bookings on the convention development tax generated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION; ADMINISTRATION; PENALTIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The convention development tax on transient rentals imposed by the governing body of any county authorized to so levy shall apply to the amount of any payment made by any person to rent, lease, or use for a period of 6 months or less any living quarters or accommodations in a hotel, apartment hotel, motel, resort motel, apartment, apartment motel, roominghouse, tourist or trailer camp, mobile home park, recreational vehicle park, condominium, or timeshare resort. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary consideration. Any payment made by a person to rent, lease, or use any living quarters or accommodations which are exempt from the tax imposed under s. 212.03 shall likewise be exempt from any tax imposed under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax shall be due on the consideration paid for occupancy in the county pursuant to a regulated short-term product, as defined in s. 721.05, or occupancy in the county pursuant to a product that would be deemed a regulated short-term product if the agreement to purchase the short-term right was executed in this state. Such tax shall be collected on the last day of occupancy within the county unless such consideration is applied to the purchase of a timeshare estate. The occupancy of an accommodation of a timeshare resort pursuant to a timeshare plan, a multisite timeshare plan, or an exchange transaction in an exchange program, as defined in s. 721.05, by the owner of a timeshare interest or such owner’s guest, which guest is not paying monetary consideration to the owner or to a third party for the benefit of the owner, is not a privilege subject to taxation under this section. A membership or transaction fee paid by a timeshare owner that does not provide the timeshare owner with the right to occupy any specific timeshare unit but merely provides the timeshare owner with the opportunity to exchange a timeshare interest through an exchange program is a service charge and not subject to taxation under this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consideration paid for the purchase of a timeshare license in a timeshare plan, as defined in s. 721.05, is rent subject to taxation under this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the lease or rental, and the tax shall be collected from the lessee, tenant, or customer at the time of payment of the consideration for such lease or rental.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person receiving the consideration for such rental or lease shall receive, account for, and remit the tax to the department at the time and in the manner provided for persons who collect and remit taxes under s. 212.03. The same duties and privileges imposed by this chapter upon dealers in tangible property respecting the collection and remission of tax; the making of returns; the keeping of books, records, and accounts; and compliance with the rules of the department in the administration of this chapter apply to and are binding upon all persons who are subject to the provisions of this section. However, the department may authorize a quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted by the dealer for the preceding quarter did not exceed $25.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall keep records showing the amount of taxes collected, which records shall disclose the taxes collected from each county in which a local government resort tax is levied. These records shall be subject to the provisions of s. 213.053 and are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The collections received by the department from the tax, less costs of administration, shall be paid and returned monthly to the county which imposed the tax, for use by the county as provided in this section. Such receipts shall be placed in a specific trust fund or funds created by the county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall promulgate such rules and shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section. The department is authorized to establish audit procedures and to assess for delinquent taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated tax provisions contained in s. 212.11 do not apply to the administration of any tax levied under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person taxable under this section who, either by himself or herself or through the person’s agents or employees, fails or refuses to charge and collect the taxes herein provided from the person paying any rental or lease is, in addition to being personally liable for the payment of the tax, guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall advertise or hold out to the public in any manner, directly or indirectly, that he or she will absorb all or any part of the tax; that he or she will relieve the person paying the rental of the payment of all or any part of the tax; or that the tax will not be added to the rental or lease consideration or, if added, that the tax or any part thereof will be refunded or refused, either directly or indirectly, by any method whatsoever. Any person who willfully violates any provision of this paragraph is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax shall constitute a lien on the property of the lessee, customer, or tenant in the same manner as, and shall be collectible as are, liens authorized and imposed by ss. 713.67, 713.68, and 713.69.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any tax levied pursuant to this section shall be in addition to any other tax imposed pursuant to this chapter and in addition to all other taxes and fees and the consideration for the rental or lease.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer the taxes levied herein as increases in the rate of the tax authorized in s. 125.0104. The department shall collect and enforce the provisions of this section and s. 125.0104 in conjunction with each other in those counties authorized to levy the taxes authorized herein. The department shall distribute the proceeds received from the taxes levied pursuant to this section and s. 125.0104 in proportion to the rates of the taxes authorized to the appropriate trust funds as provided by law. In the event of underpayment of the total amount due by a taxpayer pursuant to this section and s. 125.0104, the department shall distribute the amount received in proportion to the rates of the taxes authorized to the appropriate trust funds as provided by law and the penalties and interest due on both of said taxes shall be applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZATION TO LEVY; USE OF PROCEEDS; OTHER REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Consolidated government levy for convention development.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county that operates under a government consolidated with that of one or more municipalities in the county may impose, pursuant to an ordinance enacted by the governing body of the county, a levy on the exercise within its boundaries of the taxable privilege of leasing or letting transient rental accommodations described in subsection (3) at the rate of 2 percent of each dollar and major fraction of each dollar of the total consideration charged therefor. The proceeds of this levy shall be known as the consolidated county convention development tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county shall furnish to the department, within 10 days after approval of the ordinance imposing the levy, a copy of the ordinance. The effective date of imposition of the levy must be the first day of any month that is at least 60 days after enactment of the ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All consolidated county convention development moneys, including any interest accrued thereon, received by a county imposing the levy must be used in any of the following manners, although the utilization authorized in sub-subparagraph a. shall apply only to municipalities with a population of 10,000 or more:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and advertise tourism;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To extend, enlarge, and improve existing publicly owned convention centers in the county;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct a multipurpose convention/coliseum/exhibition center or the maximum components thereof as funds permit in the county; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, or maintain one or more convention centers, stadiums, exhibition halls, arenas, coliseums, or auditoriums.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of completion of any project under this paragraph, tax revenues and interest accrued may be used:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As collateral, pledged, or hypothecated for projects authorized by this paragraph, including bonds issued in connection therewith; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a pledge or capital contribution in conjunction with a partnership, joint venture, or other business arrangement between the county and one or more business entities for projects authorized by this paragraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county may designate or appoint an authority to administer and disburse such proceeds and any other related source of revenue. However, the annual budget of the authority is subject to approval of the governing body of the county.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, one-half of the proceeds of the tax which are collected within a municipality the government of which is not consolidated with that of the county must, at the request of the governing body of the municipality, be remitted to the municipality. The revenue remitted to a municipality under this sub-subparagraph may be used by the municipality only for the purposes and in the manner authorized in this paragraph, but the municipality may enter into an interlocal agreement with the county or with any other municipality in the county to use such revenue to jointly finance any project authorized by this paragraph. This sub-subparagraph does not apply to the distribution to the county of any convention development tax revenues necessary to repay the principal of or the interest on any bonds issued under sub-subparagraph 4.a. before May 29, 1984. Notwithstanding this sub-subparagraph, if the governing body of such a municipality adopts a resolution stating that the municipality is unable to use such revenue for any purpose authorized in this paragraph, the municipality may use the revenue to acquire and develop municipal parks, lifeguard stations, or athletic fields.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consolidated county convention development tax shall be in addition to any other levy imposed under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues collected and returned to the county must be deposited in a convention development trust fund, which must be established by the county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Charter county levy for convention development.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county, as defined in s. 125.011(1), may impose, under an ordinance enacted by the governing body of the county, a levy on the exercise within its boundaries of the taxable privilege of leasing or letting transient rental accommodations described in subsection (3) at the rate of 3 percent of the total consideration charged therefor. The proceeds of this levy shall be known as the charter county convention development tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All charter county convention development moneys, including any interest accrued thereon, received by a county imposing the levy shall be used as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two-thirds of the proceeds shall be used to extend, enlarge, and improve the largest existing publicly owned convention center in the county.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-third of the proceeds shall be used to construct a new multipurpose convention/coliseum/exhibition center/stadium or the maximum components thereof as funds permit in the most populous municipality in the county.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the completion of any project under sub-subparagraph a., the tax revenues and interest accrued under sub-subparagraph a. may be used to acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, plan for, operate, manage, or maintain one or more convention centers, stadiums, exhibition halls, arenas, coliseums, auditoriums, or golf courses, and may be used to acquire and construct an intercity light rail transportation system as described in the Light Rail Transit System Status Report to the Legislature dated April 1988, which shall provide a means to transport persons to and from the largest existing publicly owned convention center in the county and the hotels north of the convention center and to and from the downtown area of the most populous municipality in the county as determined by the county.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After completion of any project under sub-subparagraph b., the tax revenues and interest accrued under sub-subparagraph b. may be used, as determined by the county, to operate an authority created pursuant to subparagraph 4. or to acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, operate, or maintain one or more convention centers, stadiums, exhibition halls, arenas, coliseums, auditoriums, golf courses, or related buildings and parking facilities in the most populous municipality in the county.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of completion of any project pursuant to this paragraph, tax revenues and interest accrued may be used:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As collateral, pledged, or hypothecated for projects authorized by this paragraph, including bonds issued in connection therewith; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a pledge or capital contribution in conjunction with a partnership, joint venture, or other business arrangement between a municipality and one or more business entities for projects authorized by this paragraph.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of each municipality in which a municipal tourist tax is levied may adopt a resolution prohibiting imposition of the charter county convention development levy within such municipality. If the governing body adopts such a resolution, the convention development levy shall be imposed by the county in all other areas of the county except such municipality. No funds collected pursuant to this paragraph may be expended in a municipality which has adopted such a resolution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the county enacts an ordinance imposing the levy, the county shall notify the governing body of each municipality in which projects are to be developed pursuant to sub-subparagraph 2.a., sub-subparagraph 2.b., sub-subparagraph 2.c., or sub-subparagraph 2.d. As a condition precedent to receiving funding, the governing bodies of such municipalities shall designate or appoint an authority that shall have the sole power to:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve the concept, location, program, and design of the facilities or improvements to be built in accordance with this paragraph and to administer and disburse such proceeds and any other related source of revenue.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint and dismiss the authority’s executive director, general counsel, and any other consultants retained by the authority. The governing body shall have the right to approve or disapprove the initial appointment of the authority’s executive director and general counsel.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of each such authority shall serve for a term of not less than 1 year and shall be appointed by the governing body of such municipality. The annual budget of such authority shall be subject to approval of the governing body of the municipality. If the governing body does not approve the budget, the authority shall use as the authority’s budget the previous fiscal year budget.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority, by resolution to be adopted from time to time, may invest and reinvest the proceeds from the convention development tax and any other revenues generated by the authority in the same manner that the municipality in which the authority is located may invest surplus funds.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The charter county convention development levy shall be in addition to any other levy imposed pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the ordinance imposing the levy shall be furnished by the county to the department within 10 days after approval of such ordinance. The effective date of imposition of the levy shall be the first day of any month at least 60 days after enactment of the ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues collected pursuant to this paragraph shall be deposited in a convention development trust fund, which shall be established by the county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Special district levy for convention development.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county which was chartered under Art. VIII of the State Constitution and which on January 1, 1984, levied a tourist advertising ad valorem tax within a special taxing district in that county may impose, pursuant to an ordinance enacted by the governing body of the county, a levy within the boundaries of such special taxing district on the exercise of the taxable privilege of leasing or letting transient rental accommodations described in subsection (3) at a rate of up to 3 percent of each dollar and major fraction of each dollar of the total consideration charged therefor. The proceeds of this levy shall be known as the special district convention development tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county shall designate or appoint an authority to administer and disburse the proceeds of such levy and any revenue related to the levy authorized by this paragraph. The members of such authority shall be selected from persons involved in the tourism and lodging industries doing business within such special district. Not less than a majority of the members shall be selected from persons doing business in the lodging industry. Members shall serve at the pleasure of the governing body of such county and shall serve without compensation. The annual budget of such authority shall be subject to approval of the governing body of the county. The authority shall consist of 11 members, who shall annually select a chair from among their members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county shall have no power to levy and impose the tourist advertising ad valorem tax in such district on or after January 1 of the year following the date of the adoption of the levy authorized in this paragraph. All special district convention development moneys, including any interest accrued thereon, received by a county imposing the special district convention development levy shall be used for the following purposes only:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and advertise tourism;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers, and news bureaus.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The special district convention development tax shall be in addition to any other levy imposed pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the ordinance imposing the levy shall be furnished by the county to the department within 10 days after approval of such ordinance. The effective date of the levy shall be the first day of any month at least 60 days after enactment of the ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues collected and returned to the county shall be deposited in a convention development trust fund, which shall be established by the county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Special levy for convention development.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county which was chartered under Art. VIII of the State Constitution and which on January 1, 1984, levied a tourist advertising ad valorem tax within a special taxing district in that county may impose, pursuant to an ordinance enacted by the governing body of the county, a levy outside the boundaries of such special taxing district and to the southeast of State Road 415, on the exercise of the taxable privilege of leasing or letting transient rental accommodations described in subsection (3), at a rate of up to 3 percent of each dollar and major fraction of each dollar of the total consideration charged therefor. The proceeds of this levy shall be known as the special convention development tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county shall designate or appoint an authority to administer and disburse the proceeds of such levy and any revenue related to the levy authorized by this paragraph. The members of the authority shall be selected from persons doing business within the area in which the tax is levied. Not less than three of the members shall be selected from persons doing business in the lodging industry. Members shall serve at the pleasure of the governing body of the county and shall serve without compensation. The annual budget of the authority shall be subject to approval of the governing body of the county. The authority shall consist of seven members, who shall annually select a chair from among their members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All special convention development moneys, including any interest accrued thereon, received by a county imposing the special convention development levy shall be used for the following purposes only:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and advertise tourism;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers, and news bureaus.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The special convention development tax shall be in addition to any other levy imposed pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the ordinance imposing the levy shall be furnished by the county to the department within 10 days after approval of the ordinance. The effective date of the levy shall be the first day of any month at least 60 days after enactment of the ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues collected and returned to the county shall be deposited in a separate convention development trust fund, which shall be established by the county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Subcounty levy for convention development.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county which was chartered under Art. VIII of the State Constitution and which on January 1, 1984, levied a tourist advertising ad valorem tax within a special taxing district in that county may impose, pursuant to an ordinance enacted by the governing body of the county, a levy outside the boundaries of such special taxing district and to the northwest of State Road 415, on the exercise of the taxable privilege of leasing or letting transient rental accommodations described in subsection (3), at a rate of up to 3 percent of each dollar and major fraction of each dollar of the total consideration charged therefor. The proceeds of this levy shall be known as the subcounty convention development tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county shall designate or appoint an authority to administer and disburse the proceeds of such levy and any revenue related to the levy authorized by this paragraph. The members of the authority shall be selected from persons doing business within the area in which the tax is levied. Not less than three of the members shall be selected from persons doing business in the lodging industry. Members shall serve at the pleasure of the governing body of the county and shall serve without compensation. The annual budget of the authority shall be subject to approval of the governing body of the county. The authority shall consist of seven members, who shall annually select a chair from among their members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All subcounty convention development moneys, including any interest accrued thereon, received by a county imposing the subcounty convention development levy shall be used for the following purposes only:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and advertise tourism;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers, and news bureaus.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The subcounty convention development tax shall be in addition to any other levy imposed pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the ordinance imposing the levy shall be furnished by the county to the department within 10 days after approval of the ordinance. The effective date of the levy shall be the first day of any month at least 60 days after enactment of the ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues collected and returned to the county shall be deposited in a separate convention development trust fund, which shall be established by the county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL ADMINISTRATION OF TAX.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county levying a tax under the provisions of this section may be exempt from the requirements of this section that the tax collected be remitted to the Department of Revenue before being returned to the county and that such tax be administered according to the provisions of this chapter, if the county adopts an ordinance providing for the collection and administration of the tax on a local basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ordinance shall include provision for, but need not be limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial collection of the tax to be made in the same manner as the tax imposed under this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of the local official to whom the tax shall be remitted and that official’s powers and duties with respect thereto. Tax revenues may be used only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements respecting the keeping of appropriate books, records, and accounts by those responsible for collecting and administering the tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of a dealer’s credit as required under this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A portion of the tax collected may be retained by the county for costs of administration, but such portion shall not exceed 2 percent of collections.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county adopting an ordinance providing for the collection and administration of the tax on a local basis shall also adopt an ordinance electing either to assume all responsibility for auditing the records and accounts of dealers, and assessing, collecting, and enforcing payments of delinquent taxes, or to delegate such authority to the Department of Revenue. If the county elects to assume such responsibility, it shall be bound by the rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue pursuant to paragraph (3)(f), as well as those rules pertaining to the sales and use tax on transient rentals imposed by s. 212.03. The county may use any power granted in this chapter to the department to determine the amount of tax, penalties, and interest to be paid by each dealer and to enforce payment of such tax, penalties, and interest. The county may use a certified public accountant licensed in this state in the administration of its statutory duties and responsibilities. Such certified public accountants are bound by the same confidentiality requirements and subject to the same penalties as the county under s. 213.053. If the county delegates such authority to the department, the department shall distribute any collections so received, less costs of administration, to the county. The amount deducted for costs of administration by the department shall be used only for those costs which are solely and directly attributable to auditing, assessing, collecting, processing, and enforcing payments of delinquent taxes authorized in this section. If a county elects to delegate such authority to the department, the department shall audit only those businesses in the county that it audits pursuant to this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-356; ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-67; s. 70, ch. 86-152; s. 82, ch. 87-6; s. 11, ch. 87-99; s. 51, ch. 87-101; s. 1, ch. 87-258; s. 30, ch. 88-119; s. 1, ch. 88-401; s. 32, ch. 89-356; s. 30, ch. 90-132; s. 2, ch. 90-349; s. 47, ch. 90-360; s. 85, ch. 91-45; s. 25, ch. 91-112; s. 1, ch. 91-155; s. 238, ch. 91-224; s. 8, ch. 93-286; s. 3, ch. 94-351; s. 1493, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 95-290; ss. 1, 47, ch. 96-397; s. 61, ch. 96-406; s. 18, ch. 97-99; s. 9, ch. 2000-210; ss. 7, 11, ch. 2000-312; s. 1, ch. 2005-96; s. 12, ch. 2005-280; s. 4, ch. 2009-133.</History>
</Section>