<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0212.183" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules for self-accrual of sales tax.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to provide by rule for self-accrual of the sales tax under one or more of the following circumstances:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where authorized by law for holders of direct pay permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where tangible personal property is subject to tax on a prorated basis, and the proration factor is based upon characteristics of the purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the taxable status of types of tangible personal property will be known only upon use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For commercial rentals where the purchaser rents from a number of independent property owners who, apart from rentals to the purchaser in question, would otherwise not be obligated to register as dealers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the purchaser makes purchases in excess of $10 million per year of tangible personal property in any county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the purchaser makes purchases of promotional materials as defined in s. 212.06(11) and at the time of purchase, the purchaser does not know whether the materials will be exported outside this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For commercial rentals where the purchaser, who is required to remit sales tax electronically as provided under s. 213.755, rents from a number of independent property owners.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 87-6; s. 19, ch. 87-101; s. 36, ch. 87-548; s. 3, ch. 92-168; s. 14, ch. 93-233; s. 32, ch. 96-397.</History></Section>