<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0212.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credits for returned goods, rentals, or admissions; goods acquired for dealer’s own use and subsequently resold; additional powers of department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event purchases are returned to a dealer by the purchaser or consumer after the tax imposed by this chapter has been collected from or charged to the account of the consumer or user, the dealer shall be entitled to reimbursement of the amount of tax collected or charged by the dealer, in the manner prescribed by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered dealer that purchases property for the dealer’s own use, pays tax on acquisition, and sells the property subsequent to acquisition without ever having used the property is entitled to reimbursement, in the manner prescribed by the department, of the amount of tax paid on the property’s acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the tax has not been remitted by a dealer to the department, the dealer may deduct the same in submitting his or her return upon receipt of a signed statement of the dealer as to the gross amount of such refunds during the period covered by said signed statement, which period shall not be longer than 90 days. The department shall issue to the dealer an official credit memorandum equal to the net amount remitted by the dealer for such tax collected or paid. Such memorandum shall be accepted by the department at full face value from the dealer to whom it is issued, in the remittance for subsequent taxes accrued under the provisions of this chapter. If a dealer has retired from business and has filed a final return, a refund of tax may be made if it can be established to the satisfaction of the department that the tax was not due.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer who has paid the tax imposed by this chapter on tangible personal property sold under a retained title, conditional sale, or similar contract, or under a contract wherein the dealer retains a security interest in the property pursuant to chapter 679, may take credit or obtain a refund for the tax paid by the dealer on the unpaid balance due him or her when he or she repossesses (with or without judicial process) the property within 12 months following the month in which the property was repossessed. When such repossessed property is resold, the sale is subject in all respects to the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer who has paid the tax imposed by this chapter on tangible personal property or services may take a credit or obtain a refund for any tax paid by the dealer on the unpaid balance due on worthless accounts within 12 months following the month in which the bad debt has been charged off for federal income tax purposes. If any accounts so charged off for which a credit or refund has been obtained are thereafter in whole or in part paid to the dealer, the amount so paid shall be included in the first return filed after such collection and the tax paid accordingly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall design, prepare, print and furnish to all dealers, except dealers filing through electronic data interchange, or make available or prescribe to the dealers, all necessary forms for filing returns and instructions to ensure a full collection from dealers and an accounting for the taxes due, but failure of any dealer to secure such forms does not relieve the dealer from the payment of the tax at the time and in the manner provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe the format and instructions necessary for filing returns in a manner that is initiated through an electronic data interchange to ensure a full collection from dealers and an accounting for the taxes due. The failure of any dealer to use such format does not relieve the dealer from the payment of the tax at the time and in the manner provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and its assistants are hereby authorized and empowered to administer the oath for the purpose of enforcing and administering the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, where admissions, license fees, or rental payments or payments for services are made and thereafter returned to the payors after the taxes thereon have been paid, shall return or credit the taxpayer for taxes so paid on the moneys returned in the same manner as is provided for returns or credits of taxes where purchases or tangible personal property are returnable to a dealer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 26319, 1949; s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; s. 14, ch. 67-180; s. 1, ch. 67-518; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 78-23; s. 4, ch. 78-59; s. 78, ch. 86-152; s. 20, ch. 87-6; s. 1122, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 98-142; s. 20, ch. 98-200; s. 14, ch. 98-342.</History></Section>