<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0395.1056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plan components addressing a hospital’s response to terrorism; public records exemption; public meetings exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those portions of a comprehensive emergency management plan that address the response of a public or private hospital to an act of terrorism as defined by s. 775.30 held by the agency, a state or local law enforcement agency, a county or municipal emergency management agency, the Executive Office of the Governor, the Department of Health, or the Division of Emergency Management are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information made confidential and exempt by this subsection may be disclosed by a custodial agency to another state or federal agency to prevent, detect, guard against, respond to, investigate, or manage the consequences of any attempted or actual act of terrorism, or to prosecute those persons who are responsible for such attempts or acts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Portions of a comprehensive emergency management plan that address the response of a public or private hospital to an act of terrorism include those portions addressing:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security systems or plans;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vulnerability analyses;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency evacuation transportation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sheltering arrangements;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postdisaster activities, including provisions for emergency power, communications, food, and water;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postdisaster transportation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supplies, including drug caches;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Staffing;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency equipment; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual identification of residents, transfer of records, and methods of responding to family inquiries.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those portions of a comprehensive emergency management plan that address the response of a public hospital to an act of terrorism as defined by s. 775.30 held by that public hospital are exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. Portions of a comprehensive emergency management plan that address the response of a public hospital to an act of terrorism include those portions addressing:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security systems or plans;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vulnerability analyses;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency evacuation transportation;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sheltering arrangements;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postdisaster activities, including provisions for emergency power, communications, food, and water;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postdisaster transportation;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supplies, including drug caches;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Staffing;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency equipment; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual identification of residents, transfer of records, and methods of responding to family inquiries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public records exemptions provided by this section are remedial in nature, and it is the intent of the Legislature that the exemptions apply to plans held by a custodial agency before, on, or after the effective date of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That portion of a public meeting which would reveal information contained in a comprehensive emergency management plan that addresses the response of a hospital to an act of terrorism is exempt from s. 286.011 and s. 24(b), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certification by the Governor, in coordination with the Department of Health, of the sufficiency of a comprehensive emergency management plan that addresses the response of a hospital to an act of terrorism is not exempt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-362; s. 1, ch. 2006-109; s. 272, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>