<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.0161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirement of s. 408.811, the agency shall make or cause to be made such inspections and investigations as it deems necessary, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspections directed by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Validation inspections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lifesafety inspections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure complaint investigations, including full licensure investigations with a review of all licensure standards as outlined in the administrative rules. Complaints received by the agency from individuals, organizations, or other sources are subject to review and investigation by the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency access complaint investigations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspections of mobile surgical facilities at each time a facility establishes a new location, prior to the admission of patients. However, such inspections shall not be required when a mobile surgical facility is moved temporarily to a location where medical treatment will not be provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall accept, in lieu of its own periodic inspections for licensure, the survey or inspection of an accrediting organization, provided the accreditation of the licensed facility is not provisional and provided the licensed facility authorizes release of, and the agency receives the report of, the accrediting organization. The agency shall develop, and adopt by rule, criteria for accepting survey reports of accrediting organizations in lieu of conducting a state licensure inspection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. With the exception of state-operated licensed facilities, each facility licensed under this part shall pay to the agency, at the time of inspection, the following fees:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Inspection for licensure.</Font><EmDash />A fee shall be paid which is not less than $8 per hospital bed, nor more than $12 per hospital bed, except that the minimum fee shall be $400 per facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Inspection for lifesafety only.</Font><EmDash />A fee shall be paid which is not less than 75 cents per hospital bed, nor more than $1.50 per hospital bed, except that the minimum fee shall be $40 per facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall coordinate all periodic inspections for licensure made by the agency to ensure that the cost to the facility of such inspections and the disruption of services by such inspections is minimized.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 26, 30, ch. 82-182; s. 28, ch. 90-344; ss. 7, 98, ch. 92-289; s. 5, ch. 98-303; s. 41, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 395.006.</Text></Note></Section>