<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.4001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Charity care” or “uncompensated trauma care” means that portion of hospital charges reported to the agency for which there is no compensation, other than restricted or unrestricted revenues provided to a hospital by local governments or tax districts regardless of method of payment, for care provided to a patient whose family income for the 12 months preceding the determination is less than or equal to 200 percent of the federal poverty level, unless the amount of hospital charges due from the patient exceeds 25 percent of the annual family income. However, in no case shall the hospital charges for a patient whose family income exceeds four times the federal poverty level for a family of four be considered charity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interfacility trauma transfer” means the transfer of a trauma victim between two facilities licensed under this chapter, pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“International Classification Injury Severity Score” means the statistical method for computing the severity of injuries sustained by trauma patients. The International Classification Injury Severity Score shall be the methodology used by the department and trauma centers to report the severity of an injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Level I trauma center” means a trauma center that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has formal research and education programs for the enhancement of trauma care; is verified by the department to be in substantial compliance with Level I trauma center and pediatric trauma center standards; and has been approved by the department to operate as a Level I trauma center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serves as a resource facility to Level II trauma centers, pediatric trauma centers, and general hospitals through shared outreach, education, and quality improvement activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participates in an inclusive system of trauma care, including providing leadership, system evaluation, and quality improvement activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Level II trauma center” means a trauma center that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is verified by the department to be in substantial compliance with Level II trauma center standards and has been approved by the department to operate as a Level II trauma center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serves as a resource facility to general hospitals through shared outreach, education, and quality improvement activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participates in an inclusive system of trauma care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local funding contribution” means local municipal, county, or tax district funding exclusive of any patient-specific funds received pursuant to ss. 154.301-154.316, private foundation funding, or public or private grant funding of at least $150,000 received by a hospital or health care system that operates a trauma center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pediatric trauma center” means a hospital that is verified by the department to be in substantial compliance with pediatric trauma center standards as established by rule of the department and has been approved by the department to operate as a pediatric trauma center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Provisional trauma center” means a hospital that has been verified by the department to be in substantial compliance with the requirements in s. 395.4025 and has been approved by the department to operate as a provisional Level I trauma center, Level II trauma center, or pediatric trauma center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma agency” means a department-approved agency established and operated by one or more counties, or a department-approved entity with which one or more counties contract, for the purpose of administering an inclusive regional trauma system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma alert victim” means a person who has incurred a single or multisystem injury due to blunt or penetrating means or burns, who requires immediate medical intervention or treatment, and who meets one or more of the adult or pediatric scorecard criteria established by the department by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma caseload volume” means the number of trauma patients reported by individual trauma centers to the Trauma Registry and validated by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma center” means a hospital that has been verified by the department to be in substantial compliance with the requirements in s. 395.4025 and has been approved by the department to operate as a Level I trauma center, Level II trauma center, or pediatric trauma center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma patient” means a person who has incurred a physical injury or wound caused by trauma and has accessed a trauma center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma scorecard” means a statewide methodology adopted by the department by rule under which a person who has incurred a traumatic injury is graded as to the severity of his or her injuries or illness and which methodology is used as the basis for making destination decisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma transport protocol” means a document which describes the policies, processes, and procedures governing the dispatch of vehicles, the triage, prehospital transport, and interfacility trauma transfer of trauma victims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma victim” means any person who has incurred a single or multisystem injury due to blunt or penetrating means or burns and who requires immediate medical intervention or treatment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-189; s. 3, ch. 2004-259; s. 58, ch. 2005-2; s. 14, ch. 2006-192.</History></Section>