<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.402" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trauma service areas; number and location of trauma centers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes the need for a statewide, cohesive, uniform, and integrated trauma system. Within the trauma service areas, Level I and Level II trauma centers shall each be capable of annually treating a minimum of 1,000 and 500 patients, respectively, with an injury severity score (ISS) of 9 or greater. Level II trauma centers in counties with a population of more than 500,000 shall have the capacity to care for 1,000 patients per year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service areas as defined in this section are to be utilized until the Department of Health completes an assessment of the trauma system and reports its finding to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the substantive legislative committees. The report shall be submitted by February 1, 2005. The department shall review the existing trauma system and determine whether it is effective in providing trauma care uniformly throughout the state. The assessment shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider aligning trauma service areas within the trauma region boundaries as established in July 2004.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the number and level of trauma centers needed for each trauma service area to provide a statewide integrated trauma system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish criteria for determining the number and level of trauma centers needed to serve the population in a defined trauma service area or region.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider including criteria within trauma center approval standards based upon the number of trauma victims served within a service area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the Regional Domestic Security Task Force structure and determine whether integrating the trauma system planning with interagency regional emergency and disaster planning efforts is feasible and identify any duplication of efforts between the two entities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make recommendations regarding a continued revenue source which shall include a local participation requirement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make recommendations regarding a formula for the distribution of funds identified for trauma centers which shall address incentives for new centers where needed and the need to maintain effective trauma care in areas served by existing centers, with consideration for the volume of trauma patients served, and the amount of charity care provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting such assessment and subsequent annual reviews, the department shall consider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recommendations made as part of the regional trauma system plans submitted by regional trauma agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stakeholder recommendations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The geographical composition of an area to ensure rapid access to trauma care by patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Historical patterns of patient referral and transfer in an area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inventories of available trauma care resources, including professional medical staff.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Population growth characteristics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation capabilities, including ground and air transport.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medically appropriate ground and air travel times.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations of the Regional Domestic Security Task Force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actual number of trauma victims currently being served by each trauma center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other appropriate criteria.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually thereafter, the department shall review the assignment of the 67 counties to trauma service areas, in addition to the requirements of paragraphs (2)(b)-(g) and subsection (3). County assignments are made for the purpose of developing a system of trauma centers. Revisions made by the department shall take into consideration the recommendations made as part of the regional trauma system plans approved by the department and the recommendations made as part of the state trauma system plan. In cases where a trauma service area is located within the boundaries of more than one trauma region, the trauma service area’s needs, response capability, and system requirements shall be considered by each trauma region served by that trauma service area in its regional system plan. Until the department completes the February 2005 assessment, the assignment of counties shall remain as established in this section.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following trauma service areas are hereby established:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 1 shall consist of Escambia, Okaloosa, Santa Rosa, and Walton Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 2 shall consist of Bay, Gulf, Holmes, and Washington Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 3 shall consist of Calhoun, Franklin, Gadsden, Jackson, Jefferson, Leon, Liberty, Madison, Taylor, and Wakulla Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 4 shall consist of Alachua, Bradford, Columbia, Dixie, Gilchrist, Hamilton, Lafayette, Levy, Putnam, Suwannee, and Union Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 5 shall consist of Baker, Clay, Duval, Nassau, and St. Johns Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 6 shall consist of Citrus, Hernando, and Marion Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 7 shall consist of Flagler and Volusia Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 8 shall consist of Lake, Orange, Osceola, Seminole, and Sumter Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 9 shall consist of Pasco and Pinellas Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 10 shall consist of Hillsborough County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 11 shall consist of Hardee, Highlands, and Polk Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 12 shall consist of Brevard and Indian River Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 13 shall consist of DeSoto, Manatee, and Sarasota Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 14 shall consist of Martin, Okeechobee, and St. Lucie Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 15 shall consist of Charlotte, Glades, Hendry, and Lee Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 16 shall consist of Palm Beach County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 17 shall consist of Collier County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 18 shall consist of Broward County.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma service area 19 shall consist of Miami-Dade and Monroe Counties.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each trauma service area should have at least one Level I or Level II trauma center. The department shall allocate, by rule, the number of trauma centers needed for each trauma service area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no more than a total of 44 trauma centers in the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 15, ch. 90-284; ss. 37, 98, ch. 92-289; s. 195, ch. 99-397; s. 26, ch. 2000-242; s. 6, ch. 2004-259; s. 100, ch. 2008-4.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 395.033.</Text></Note></Section>