<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review of trauma registry data; report to central registry; confidentiality and limited release.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each trauma center shall furnish, and, upon request of the department, all acute care hospitals shall furnish for department review trauma registry data as prescribed by rule of the department for the purpose of monitoring patient outcome and ensuring compliance with the standards of approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trauma registry data obtained pursuant to this subsection are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. However, the department may provide such trauma registry data to the person, trauma center, hospital, emergency medical service provider, local or regional trauma agency, medical examiner, or other entity from which the data were obtained. The department may also use or provide trauma registry data for purposes of research in accordance with the provisions of chapter 405.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each trauma center, pediatric trauma center, and acute care hospital shall report to the department’s brain and spinal cord injury central registry, consistent with the procedures and timeframes of s. 381.74, any person who has a moderate-to-severe brain or spinal cord injury, and shall include in the report the name, age, residence, and type of disability of the individual and any additional information that the department finds necessary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 87-399; s. 3, ch. 88-186; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 10, ch. 90-344; ss. 41, 98, ch. 92-289; s. 3, ch. 94-324; s. 4, ch. 95-387; s. 28, ch. 95-398; s. 219, ch. 96-406; s. 16, ch. 2000-153; s. 21, ch. 2002-22; s. 25, ch. 2004-350; s. 59, ch. 2005-2.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 395.035.</Text></Note></Section>