<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0395.3036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality of records and meetings of entities that lease public hospitals or other public health care facilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records of a private entity that leases a public hospital or other public health care facility are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution, and the meetings of the governing board of a private entity are exempt from s. 286.011 and s. 24(b), Art. I of the State Constitution if the public lessor complies with the public finance accountability provisions of s. 155.40(18) with respect to the transfer of any public funds to the private lessee and if the private lessee meets at least three of the five following criteria:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public lessor that owns the public hospital or other public health care facility was not the incorporator or initial member of the private entity that leases the public hospital or other health care facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public lessor and the private lessee do not commingle any of their funds in any account maintained by either of them, other than the payment of the rent and administrative fees or the transfer of funds pursuant to subsection (5).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, the private lessee is not allowed to participate, except as a member of the public, in the decisionmaking process of the public lessor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease agreement does not expressly require the lessee to comply with ss. 119.07(1) and 286.011.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public lessor is not entitled to receive any revenues from the lessee, except for rental or administrative fees due under the lease, and the lessor is not responsible for the debts or other obligations of the lessee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-330; s. 6, ch. 2012-66.</History>
</Section>