<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.7015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual assessment on health care entities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Net operating revenue” means gross revenue less deductions from revenue.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gross revenue” means the sum of daily service charges, ambulatory service charges, ancillary service charges, and other operating revenue, except revenues received for testing or analysis of samples received from outside the state or from product sales outside the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deductions from revenue” means reductions from gross revenue resulting from inability to collect payment of charges. Such reductions include bad debts; contractual adjustments; uncompensated care; administrative, courtesy, and policy discounts and adjustments; and other such revenue deductions, and includes the offset of restricted donations and grants for indigent care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is imposed an annual assessment against certain health care entities as described in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessment shall be equal to 1 percent of the annual net operating revenues of health care entities. The assessment shall be payable to and collected by the agency. Assessments shall be based on annual net operating revenues for the entity’s most recently completed fiscal year as provided in subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, “health care entities” include the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ambulatory surgical centers and mobile surgical facilities licensed under s. 395.003. This subsection shall only apply to mobile surgical facilities operating under contracts entered into on or after July 1, 1998.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical laboratories licensed under s. 483.091, excluding any hospital laboratory defined under s. 483.041(6), any clinical laboratory operated by the state or a political subdivision of the state, any clinical laboratory which qualifies as an exempt organization under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and which receives 70 percent or more of its gross revenues from services to charity patients or Medicaid patients, and any blood, plasma, or tissue bank procuring, storing, or distributing blood, plasma, or tissue either for future manufacture or research or distributed on a nonprofit basis, and further excluding any clinical laboratory which is wholly owned and operated by 6 or fewer physicians who are licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459 and who practice in the same group practice, and at which no clinical laboratory work is performed for patients referred by any health care provider who is not a member of the same group.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diagnostic-imaging centers that are freestanding outpatient facilities that provide specialized services for the identification or determination of a disease through examination and also provide sophisticated radiological services, and in which services are rendered by a physician licensed by the Board of Medicine under s. 458.311, s. 458.313, or s. 458.317, or by an osteopathic physician licensed by the Board of Osteopathic Medicine under s. 459.0055 or s. 459.0075. For purposes of this paragraph, “sophisticated radiological services” means the following: magnetic resonance imaging; nuclear medicine; angiography; arteriography; computed tomography; positron emission tomography; digital vascular imaging; bronchography; lymphangiography; splenography; ultrasound, excluding ultrasound providers that are part of a private physician’s office practice or when ultrasound is provided by two or more physicians licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who are members of the same professional association and who practice in the same medical specialties; and such other sophisticated radiological services, excluding mammography, as adopted in rule by the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 1993, the assessment shall be on the actual experience of the entity as reported to the agency within 120 days after the end of its fiscal year in the preceding calendar year based upon reports developed by the board in a rule after consultation with appropriate professional and governmental advisory bodies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 6 months after the end of each entity’s fiscal year, the agency shall certify the amount of the assessment to each entity. The assessment shall be payable to and collected by the agency in equal quarterly amounts on or before the first day of each calendar quarter, beginning with the first full calendar quarter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the Public Medical Assistance Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may use its authority under chapter 408 in administering this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 177, ch. 91-112; s. 94, ch. 92-33; s. 33, ch. 92-58; s. 74, ch. 92-149; s. 52, ch. 92-289; s. 73, ch. 95-143; s. 2, ch. 98-192; s. 9, ch. 98-303; s. 17, ch. 2000-256; s. 30, ch. 2001-62; s. 81, ch. 2001-277; s. 3, ch. 2007-229.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 395.1015.</Text></Note></Section>