<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency care hospitals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only rural hospitals meeting the criteria in s. 395.602(2)(e) may be licensed as emergency care hospitals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of Medicaid swing-bed reimbursement pursuant to the Medicaid program, the department shall treat emergency care hospitals in the same manner as rural hospitals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of participation in the Medical Education Reimbursement and Loan Repayment Program as defined in s. 1009.65 or other loan repayment or incentive programs designed to relieve medical workforce shortages, the department shall treat emergency care hospitals in the same manner as rural hospitals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of coordinating primary care services described in s. 154.011(1)(c)10., the department shall treat emergency care hospitals in the same manner as rural hospitals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rural hospitals that make application under the certificate-of-need program to be licensed as emergency care hospitals shall receive expedited review as defined in s. 408.032. Emergency care hospitals seeking relicensure as acute care general hospitals shall also receive expedited review.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall treat emergency care hospitals in the same manner as hospitals defined in s. 408.07.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency care hospitals are exempt from certificate-of-need requirements for home health and hospice services and for swing beds in a number that does not exceed one-half of the facility’s licensed beds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules for facility licensure that conform to s. 395.1055. Rules shall include the following provisions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency care hospitals shall have agreements with other hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, home health agencies, and with providers of diagnostic-imaging and laboratory services that are not provided on site but are needed by patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All patients shall be under the care of a physician or under the care of a nurse practitioner or physician assistant supervised by a physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant shall be on duty at all times, or a physician shall be on call and available within 30 minutes at all times.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All compounding, packaging, and dispensing of drugs and biologicals shall be under the supervision of a pharmacist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diagnostic radiologic services and clinical laboratory services shall be maintained at the facility or shall be available to meet the needs of its patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical laboratory services provided by the facility shall, at a minimum, include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chemical examinations of urine by stick or tablet methods, or both (including urine ketones).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Microscopic examinations of urine sediment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hemoglobin or hematocrit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blood sugar.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gram stain.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examination of stool specimens for occult blood.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pregnancy tests.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Primary culturing for transmittal to a certified laboratory.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sediment rate, CBC.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may use specific diagnosis-related groups, ICD-9 codes, or similar patient illness-severity classification schemes to define the scope of inpatient care in emergency care hospitals in lieu of the 96-hour inpatient care limitation. The methodology used for determining the scope of inpatient care permitted in emergency care hospitals shall be included in rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 89-527; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 13, ch. 90-295; s. 56, ch. 91-282; s. 91, ch. 92-33; ss. 49, 98, ch. 92-289; s. 732, ch. 95-148; s. 207, ch. 99-13; s. 984, ch. 2002-387.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 395.01465.</Text></Note></Section>