<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.10974" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health care risk managers; qualifications, licensure, fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to ss. 395.10971-395.10975, and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to ss. 395.10971-395.10975. A license issued by the agency is required in order to perform as a health care risk manager in this state. In order to qualify for licensure, the applicant shall submit evidence satisfactory to the agency which demonstrates the applicant’s competence, by education or experience, in the following areas:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable standards of health care risk management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable federal, state, and local health and safety laws and rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General risk management administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patient care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal and social care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accident prevention.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Departmental organization and management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community interrelationships.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical terminology.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Each applicant for licensure and each licensee must comply with all provisions of part II of chapter 408. The agency may require such additional information, from the applicant or any other person, as may be reasonably required to verify the information contained in the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall not grant or issue a license as a health care risk manager to any individual unless from the application it affirmatively appears that the applicant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or over;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a high school graduate or equivalent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has fulfilled the requirements of a 1-year program or its equivalent in health care risk management training which may be developed or approved by the agency;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed 2 years of college-level studies which would prepare the applicant for health care risk management, to be further defined by rule; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has obtained 1 year of practical experience in health care risk management.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall issue a license to practice health care risk management to any applicant who qualifies under this section. In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The amount of the fee shall be established by rule as follows: an application fee of not more than $75, a background-screening fee of not more than $75, and a license fee of not more than $100.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 38, 53, ch. 85-175; s. 4, ch. 86-287; s. 33, ch. 88-166; s. 184, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 29, ch. 98-89; s. 75, ch. 98-199; s. 50, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 626.944.</Text></Note></Section>