<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0395.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Urgent care centers; publishing and posting schedule of charges; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An urgent care center must publish and post a schedule of charges for the medical services offered to patients.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The schedule of charges must describe the medical services in language comprehensible to a layperson. The schedule must include the prices charged to an uninsured person paying for such services by cash, check, credit card, or debit card. The schedule must be posted in a conspicuous place in the reception area and must include, but is not limited to, the 50 services most frequently provided. The schedule may group services by three price levels, listing services in each price level. The posting may be a sign, which must be at least 15 square feet in size, or may be through an electronic messaging board. If an urgent care center is affiliated with a facility licensed under this chapter, the schedule must include text that notifies the insured patients whether the charges for medical services received at the center will be the same as, or more than, charges for medical services received at the affiliated hospital. The text notifying the patient of the schedule of charges shall be in a font size equal to or greater than the font size used for prices and must be in a contrasting color. The text that notifies the insured patients whether the charges for medical services received at the center will be the same as, or more than, charges for medical services received at the affiliated hospital shall be included in all media and Internet advertisements for the center and in language comprehensible to a layperson.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The posted text describing the medical services must fill at least 12 square feet of the posting. A center may use an electronic device or messaging board to post the schedule of charges. Such a device must be at least 3 square feet, and patients must be able to access the schedule during all hours of operation of the urgent care center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An urgent care center that is operated and used exclusively for employees and the dependents of employees of the business that owns or contracts for the urgent care center is exempt from this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of an urgent care center to publish and post a schedule of charges as required by this section shall result in a fine of not more than $1,000, per day, until the schedule is published and posted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2011-122; s. 2, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>