<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.10973" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the agency.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the function of the agency to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this part and part II of chapter 408 conferring duties upon it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, impose, and enforce specific standards within the scope of the general qualifications established by this part which must be met by individuals in order to receive licenses as health care risk managers. These standards shall be designed to ensure that health care risk managers are individuals of good character and otherwise suitable and, by training or experience in the field of health care risk management, qualified in accordance with the provisions of this part to serve as health care risk managers, within statutory requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a method for determining whether an individual meets the standards set forth in s. 395.10974.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue licenses to qualified individuals meeting the standards set forth in s. 395.10974.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive, investigate, and take appropriate action with respect to any charge or complaint filed with the agency to the effect that a certified health care risk manager has failed to comply with the requirements or standards adopted by rule by the agency or to comply with the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for providing periodic reports on persons certified or disciplined by the agency under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a model risk management program for health care facilities which will satisfy the requirements of s. 395.0197.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the special-occupancy provisions of the Florida Building Code which apply to hospitals, intermediate residential treatment facilities, and ambulatory surgical centers in conducting any inspection authorized by this chapter and part II of chapter 408.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 38, 53, ch. 85-175; s. 32, ch. 88-166; s. 183, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 88, ch. 92-289; s. 28, ch. 98-89; s. 203, ch. 98-200; s. 23, ch. 2000-141; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 49, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 626.943.</Text></Note></Section>