<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0395.3038" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State-listed primary stroke centers and comprehensive stroke centers; notification of hospitals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall make available on its website and to the department a list of the name and address of each hospital that meets the criteria for a primary stroke center and the name and address of each hospital that meets the criteria for a comprehensive stroke center. The list of primary and comprehensive stroke centers shall include only those hospitals that attest in an affidavit submitted to the agency that the hospital meets the named criteria, or those hospitals that attest in an affidavit submitted to the agency that the hospital is certified as a primary or a comprehensive stroke center by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a hospital no longer chooses to meet the criteria for a primary or comprehensive stroke center, the hospital shall notify the agency and the agency shall immediately remove the hospital from the list.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply if the hospital is unable to provide stroke treatment services for a period of time not to exceed 2 months. The hospital shall immediately notify all local emergency medical services providers when the temporary unavailability of stroke treatment services begins and when the services resume.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If stroke treatment services are unavailable for more than 2 months, the agency shall remove the hospital from the list of primary or comprehensive stroke centers until the hospital notifies the agency that stroke treatment services have been resumed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall notify all hospitals in this state by February 15, 2005, that the agency is compiling a list of primary stroke centers and comprehensive stroke centers in this state. The notice shall include an explanation of the criteria necessary for designation as a primary stroke center and the criteria necessary for designation as a comprehensive stroke center. The notice shall also advise hospitals of the process by which a hospital might be added to the list of primary or comprehensive stroke centers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt by rule criteria for a primary stroke center which are substantially similar to the certification standards for primary stroke centers of the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt by rule criteria for a comprehensive stroke center. However, if the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations establishes criteria for a comprehensive stroke center, the agency shall establish criteria for a comprehensive stroke center which are substantially similar to those criteria established by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act is not a medical practice guideline and may not be used to restrict the authority of a hospital to provide services for which it has received a license under chapter 395. The Legislature intends that all patients be treated individually based on each patient’s needs and circumstances.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2004-325.</History></Section>