<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0478.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewal of license; delinquent status; address notification; continuing education requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide, by rule, a method for biennial license renewal at fees set forth in s. 478.55.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license that is not renewed at the end of the biennium prescribed by the department automatically reverts to delinquent status. The board shall adopt rules establishing procedures, criteria, and fees as set forth in s. 478.55 for reactivation of an inactive license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee shall file with the department the address of his or her primary place of practice within the state prior to engaging in practice and shall notify the department of any change in this address prior to the change.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for license renewal must be accompanied by proof of the successful completion of 20 hours of continuing education courses or proof of successfully passing a reexamination for licensure within the immediately preceding biennium which meets the criteria established by the board. Both the continuing education and reexamination shall contain education on blood-borne diseases.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, with the assistance of the council, shall approve criteria for, and content of, electrolysis training programs and continuing education courses required for licensure and renewal as set forth in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continuing education programs shall be approved by the board. Applications for approval shall be submitted to the board not less than 60 days nor more than 360 days before they are held.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 92-172; s. 229, ch. 94-119; s. 408, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>