<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0478.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant applying for licensure as an electrologist shall file a written application, accompanied by the application for licensure fee prescribed in s. 478.55, on a form provided by the board, showing to the satisfaction of the board that the applicant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years old.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a high school diploma or a graduate equivalency diploma.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed an act in any jurisdiction which would constitute grounds for disciplining an electrologist in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed the academic requirements of an electrolysis training program, not to exceed 120 hours, and the practical application thereof as approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant for licensure shall successfully pass a written examination developed by the department or a national examination that has been approved by the board. The examinations shall test the applicant’s knowledge relating to the practice of electrology, including the applicant’s professional skills and judgment in the use of electrolysis techniques and methods, and any other subjects which are useful to determine the applicant’s fitness to practice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, upon approval of the board, may adopt a national examination in lieu of any part of the examination required by this section. The board, with the assistance of the council, shall establish standards for acceptable performance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to practice electrology to any applicant who passes the examination, pays the licensure fee as set forth in s. 478.55, and otherwise meets the requirements of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct licensure examinations at least two times a year. The department shall give public notice of the time and place of each examination at least 60 days before it is administered and shall mail notice of such examination to each applicant whose application is timely filed, pursuant to board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license to any applicant who is under investigation in another jurisdiction for an offense which would be a violation of this chapter, until such investigation is complete. Upon completion of such investigation, if the applicant is found guilty of such offense, the board shall apply the applicable provisions of s. 478.52.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 92-172; s. 2, ch. 95-221; s. 145, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>