<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0478.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary permits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines that an applicant is qualified to be licensed under s. 478.47, the department may issue the applicant a temporary permit to practice electrolysis until the next board meeting at which license applications are to be considered, but not for a longer period of time. Only one temporary permit shall be issued to an applicant, and it shall not be renewable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the executive director of the board determines that an applicant is qualified for licensure by examination except for passage of the examination and has applied for the next scheduled examination, the executive director may issue the applicant a nonrenewable temporary permit to practice electrology under the supervision of a licensed electrologist until notification of the results of the examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The temporary permit of a person who fails such examination is automatically revoked upon notification of the examination results, and the applicant shall cease the practice of electrology immediately upon receipt of such notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant with a temporary permit who passes such examination may continue to practice under such temporary permit until the next meeting of the board at which license applications are to be considered.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in subsection (2), “supervision” means responsible control by a licensed electrologist who provides the initial direction in developing a treatment plan and also periodically inspects the permittee’s implementation of such plan, which plan may not be altered by the permittee without the prior consultation and approval of the supervisor. A supervisor shall be available to consult with and direct a permittee in an emergency, although the supervisor does not have to be on the premises while the permittee is delivering electrolysis services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 92-172; s. 146, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>