<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0478.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining or attempting to obtain a license by bribery, fraud, or knowing misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license or other authority to deliver electrolysis services revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including denial of licensure, in another jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime, in any jurisdiction, which directly relates to the practice of electrology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully making or filing a false report or record, willfully failing to file a report or record required for electrologists, or willfully impeding or obstructing the filing of a report or record required by this act or inducing another person to do so.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Circulating false, misleading, or deceptive advertising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unprofessional conduct, including any departure from, or failure to conform to, acceptable standards related to the delivery of electrolysis services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging or attempting to engage in the illegal possession, sale, or distribution of any illegal or controlled substance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully failing to report any known violation of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully or repeatedly violating a rule adopted under this chapter, or an order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in the delivery of electrolysis services without an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employing an unlicensed person to practice electrology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon an electrologist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows, or has reason to know, she or he is not competent to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person the licensee knows, or has reason to know, is unqualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the inability to practice electrology with reasonable skill and safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Judicially determined mental incompetency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or attempting to practice electrology under a name other than her or his own.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice electrology with reasonable skill and safety because of a mental or physical condition or illness, or the use of alcohol, controlled substances, or any other substance which impairs one’s ability to practice.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, upon probable cause, compel a licensee to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. The cost of an examination shall be borne by the licensee, and her or his failure to submit to such an examination constitutes an admission of the allegations against her or him, consequent upon which a default and a final order may be entered without the taking of testimony or presentation of evidence, unless the failure was due to circumstances beyond her or his control.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee who is disciplined under this paragraph shall, at reasonable intervals, be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that she or he can resume the practice of electrology with reasonable skill and safety.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any proceeding under this paragraph, the record of proceedings or the orders entered by the board may not be used against a licensee in any other proceeding.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosing the identity of or information about a patient without written permission, except for information which does not identify a patient and which is used for training purposes in an approved electrolysis training program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or attempting to practice any permanent hair removal except as described in s. 478.42(5).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating any electrolysis facility unless it has been duly licensed as provided in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may not issue or reinstate a license to a person it has deemed unqualified until it is satisfied that such person has complied with the terms and conditions of the final order and that the licensee can safely practice electrology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, with the assistance of the council, may, by rule, establish guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. The guidelines may include minimum and maximum fines, periods of supervision on probation, or conditions upon probation or reissuance of a license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 92-172; s. 409, ch. 97-103; s. 148, ch. 97-264; s. 44, ch. 2001-277; s. 20, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>