<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0478.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electrolysis Council; creation; function; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Electrolysis Council under the supervision of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall consist of five members, appointed by the board. Three members must be licensed electrologists who have been actively engaged in the delivery of electrolysis services in this state for at least 4 consecutive years prior to their appointment and who are not affiliated with an electrolysis school or manufacturer or supplier of electrolysis equipment or supplies. Two consumer members must be residents of this state who have never been licensed electrologists, have no financial interest in the practice of electrology, and are not affiliated with an electrolysis school or a manufacturer or supplier of electrolysis equipment or supplies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial council members who are licensed electrologists must be eligible for licensure at the time of their appointment. Electrologist members appointed after October 1, 1996, must have been licensed in this state for at least 3 years prior to their appointment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of office for each council member is 4 years. A member may not serve more than two consecutive terms. When a vacancy occurs on the council, any licensed electrologist may recommend one person to fill the vacancy, and any professional organization dealing with electrolysis, incorporated within the state as not for profit, which registers its interest with the board shall recommend at least twice as many persons to fill the vacancy as the number of vacancies to be filled, and the board, in its discretion, may appoint from the submitted names any of those persons so recommended. The board shall, when possible, appoint persons from different geographic areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall annually elect from among its members a chair and vice chair.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet at least twice a year and shall hold such additional meetings as are considered necessary by the board. Three members of the council constitute a quorum.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided by law, a council member shall be compensated $50 for each day the member attends an official meeting of the council or participates in official council business. A council member is also entitled to reimbursement for expenses pursuant to s. 112.061. Travel out of state requires the prior approval of the State Surgeon General.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 92-172; s. 1, ch. 95-221; s. 406, ch. 97-103; s. 67, ch. 2000-158; s. 20, ch. 2000-305; s. 95, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>