<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Boundaries of preserves.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The submerged lands included within the boundaries of Nassau, Duval, St. Johns, Flagler, Volusia, Brevard, Indian River, St. Lucie, Charlotte, Pinellas, Martin, Palm Beach, Miami-Dade, Monroe, Collier, Lee, Citrus, Franklin, Gulf, Bay, Okaloosa, Marion, Santa Rosa, Hernando, and Escambia Counties, as hereinafter described, with the exception of privately held submerged lands lying landward of established bulkheads and of privately held submerged lands within Monroe County where the establishment of bulkhead lines is not required, are hereby declared to be aquatic preserves. Such aquatic preserve areas include:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fort Clinch State Park Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Nassau County in Book 108, pages 343-346, and in Book 111, page 409.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nassau River-St. Johns River Marshes Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Duval County in Volume 3183, pages 547-552, and in the Official Records of Nassau County in Book 108, pages 232-237.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pellicer Creek Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of St. Johns County in Book 181, pages 363-366, and in the Official Records of Flagler County in Book 33, pages 131-134.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tomoka Marsh Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Flagler County in Book 33, pages 135-138, and in the Official Records of Volusia County in Book 1244, pages 615-618.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mosquito Lagoon Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Volusia County in Book 1244, pages 619-623, and in the Official Records of Brevard County in Book 1143, pages 190-194.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Banana River Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Brevard County in Book 1143, pages 195-198, and the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries: BEGIN at the intersection of the westerly ordinary high water line of Newfound Harbor with the North line of Section 12, Township 25 South, Range 36 East, Brevard County: Thence proceed northeasterly crossing Newfound Harbor to the intersection of the South line of Section 31, Township 24 South, Range 37 East, with the easterly ordinary high water line of said Newfound Harbor; thence proceed northerly along the easterly ordinary high water line of Newfound Harbor to its intersection with the easterly ordinary high water line of Sykes Creek; thence proceed northerly along the easterly ordinary high water line of said creek to its intersection with the southerly right-of-way of Hall Road; thence proceed westerly along said right-of-way to the westerly ordinary high water line of Sykes Creek; thence southerly along said ordinary high water line to its intersection with the ordinary high water line of Newfound Harbor; thence proceed southerly along the westerly ordinary high water line of Newfound Harbor to the POINT OF BEGINNING.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indian River-Malabar to Vero Beach Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Brevard County in Book 1143, pages 199-202, and in the Official Records of Indian River County in Book 368, pages 5-8 and the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries, excluding those lands contained within the corporate boundary of the City of Vero Beach as of the effective date of this act: Commence at the intersection of the north line of Section 31, Township 28 South, Range 38 East, and the westerly mean high water line of Indian River for a point of beginning; thence from the said point of beginning proceed northerly, westerly, and easterly along the mean high water line of Indian River and its navigable tributaries to an intersection with the north line of Section 24, Township 28 South, Range 37 East; thence proceed easterly, to a point on the easterly mean high water line of Indian River at its intersection with the north line of Section 20, Township 28 South, Range 38 East; thence proceed southerly, along the easterly mean high water line of Indian River to the most westerly tip of Blue Fish Point in said Section 20, thence proceed southwesterly to the intersection of the westerly mean high water line of Indian River with the north line of Section 31, Township 28 South, Range 38 East and the point of beginning: And also commence at the intersection of the northern Vero Beach city limits line in Section 25, Township 32 South, Range 39 East, and the westerly mean high water line of Indian River for the point of beginning: Thence from the said point of beginning proceed northerly, along the westerly mean high water line of Indian River and its navigable tributaries to an intersection with the south line of Section 14, Township 30 South, Range 38 East; thence proceed easterly, along the easterly projection of the south line of said Section 14, to an intersection with the easterly right-of-way line of the Intracoastal Waterway; thence proceed southerly, along the easterly right-of-way line of the Intracoastal Waterway, to an intersection with the northerly line of the Pelican Island National Wildlife Refuge; thence proceed easterly, along the northerly line of the Pelican Island National Wildlife Refuge, to an intersection with the easterly mean high water line of Indian River; thence proceed southerly along the easterly mean high water line of Indian River and its tributaries, to an intersection with the northern Vero Beach city limits line in Section 30, Township 32 South, Range 40 East; thence proceed westerly and southerly, along the northern Vero Beach city limits line to an intersection with the easterly mean high water line of Indian River and the point of beginning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of the Indian River-Malabar to Vero Beach Aquatic Preserve, a lease of sovereign submerged lands for a noncommercial dock may be deemed to be in the public interest when the noncommercial dock constitutes a reasonable exercise of riparian rights and is consistent with the preservation of the exceptional biological, aesthetic, or scientific values which the aquatic preserve was created to protect.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indian River-Vero Beach to Fort Pierce Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Indian River County in Book 368, pages 9-12, and in the Official Records of St. Lucie County in Book 187, pages 1083-1086. More specifically, within that description, the southern corporate line of Vero Beach refers to the southerly corporate boundary line of Vero Beach as it existed on June 3, 1970, which is also a westerly projection of the south boundary of “Indian Bay” subdivision as recorded in Plat Book 3, page 43, Docket No. 59267, Public Records of Indian River County, and State Road A1A refers to State Road A1A, North Beach Causeway, located north of Fort Pierce Inlet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jensen Beach to Jupiter Inlet Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of St. Lucie County in Book 218, pages 2865-2869. More specifically, within that description, the southerly corporate line of the City of Fort Pierce refers to the southerly corporate boundary line of the City of Fort Pierce as it existed in 1969; and the western boundary of the preserve as it crosses the St. Lucie River is more specifically described as a line which connects the intersection point of the westerly mean high-water line of the Indian River and the northerly mean high-water line of the St. Lucie River to the intersection point of the intersection of the westerly mean high-water line of the Intracoastal Waterway and the southerly mean high-water line of the St. Lucie River, lands within this preserve are more particularly described as lying and being in Sections 12, 13, 26, 35, and 36, Township 35 South, Range 40 East, and Sections 18, 19, 29, 30, and 32, Township 35 South, Range 41 East, and Sections 1 and 12, Township 36 South, Range 40 East, and Sections 5, 7, 8, 9, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, 27, 29, 32, and 34, Township 36 South, Range 41 East, and Sections 2, 3, 4, 9, 10, 11, 13, 14, 15, 22, 23, 24, 26, 35, and 36, Township 37 South, Range 41 East, and Sections 19, 30, 31, and 32, Township 37 South, Range 42 East, and Sections 1 and 12, Township 38 South, Range 41 East, and Sections 5, 6, 8, 16, 17, 19, 20, 21, 28, 29, 32, and 33, Township 38 South, Range 42 East, including the eastern portion of the Hanson Grant, east of Rocky Point Cove, and west of St. Lucie Inlet State Park, and portions of the Gomez Grant lying adjacent to Peck Lake and South Jupiter Narrows, and Sections 25, 26, 35, and 36, Township 39 South, Range 42 East, and Sections 1, 12, and 13, Township 40 South, Range 42 East, and Sections 7, 18, 19, 30, 31, and 32, Township 40 South, Range 43 East.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loxahatchee River-Lake Worth Creek Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Martin County in Book 320, pages 193-196, and in the Official Records of Palm Beach County in Volume 1860, pages 806-809, and the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries: Begin at the intersection of the easterly mean high water line of the North Fork of the Loxahatchee River with the northerly mean high water line of the Loxahatchee River, being in Section 36, Township 40 South, Range 43 East, Palm Beach County: Thence proceed easterly along the northerly mean high water line of the Loxahatchee River to the westerly right-of-way of U.S. Highway 1; thence proceed southerly along said right-of-way to the southerly mean high water line of said river; thence proceed easterly along the southerly mean high water line of said river to its intersection with the easterly mean high water line of the Lake Worth Creek; thence proceed northwesterly crossing the Loxahatchee River to the point of beginning: And also: Commence at the southwest corner of Section 16, Township 40 South, Range 42 East Martin County; thence proceed north along the west line of Section 16 to the mean high water line of the Loxahatchee River being the point of beginning: Thence proceed southerly along the easterly mean high water line of said river and its tributaries to a point of nonnavigability; thence proceed westerly to the westerly mean high water line of said river; thence proceed northerly along the westerly mean high water line of said river and its tributaries to its intersection with the westerly line of Section 16, Township 40 South, Range 42 East; thence proceed southerly along the said westerly section line to the point of beginning: And also begin where the southerly mean high water line of the Southwest Fork of the Loxahatchee River intersects the westerly line of Section 35, Township 40 South, Range 42 East: Thence proceed southwesterly along the southerly mean high water line of the Southwest Fork to the northeasterly face of structure #46; thence proceed northwesterly along the face of said structure to the northerly mean high water line of the Southwest Fork; thence proceed northeasterly along said mean high water line to its intersection with the westerly line of Section 35, Township 40 South, Range 42 East; thence proceed southerly along westerly line of said section to the point of beginning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Biscayne Bay-Cape Florida to Monroe County Line Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Miami-Dade County in Book 7055, pages 852-856, less, however, those lands and waters as described in s. 258.397.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">North Fork, St. Lucie Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Martin County in Book 337, pages 2159-2162, and in the Official Records of St. Lucie County in Book 201, pages 1676-1679.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Yellow River Marsh Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Santa Rosa County in Book 206, pages 568-571.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fort Pickens State Park Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Santa Rosa County in Book 220, pages 60-63, and in the Official Records of Escambia County in Book 518, pages 659-662.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rocky Bayou State Park Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Okaloosa County in Book 593, pages 742-745.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Andrews State Park Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Bay County in Book 379, pages 547-550.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Joseph Bay Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Gulf County in Book 46, pages 73-76.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apalachicola Bay Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Gulf County in Book 46, pages 77-81, and in the Official Records of Franklin County in Volume 98, pages 102-106.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alligator Harbor Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Franklin County in Volume 98, pages 82-85.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Martins Marsh Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Citrus County in Book 276, pages 238-241.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Matlacha Pass Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Lee County in Book 800, pages 725-728.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pine Island Sound Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Lee County in Book 648, pages 732-736.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cape Romano-Ten Thousand Islands Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Collier County in Book 381, pages 298-301.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lignumvitae Key Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Monroe County in Book 502, pages 139-142.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coupon Bight Aquatic Preserve, as described in the Official Records of Monroe County in Book 502, pages 143-146.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lake Jackson Aquatic Preserve, as established by chapter 73-534, Laws of Florida, and defined as authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pinellas County Aquatic Preserve, as established by chapter 72-663, Laws of Florida; Boca Ciega Aquatic Preserve, as established by s. 258.396; and the Biscayne Bay Aquatic Preserve, as established by s. 258.397. If any provision of this act is in conflict with an aquatic preserve established by s. 258.396, chapter 72-663, Laws of Florida, or s. 258.397, the stronger provision for the maintenance of the aquatic preserve shall prevail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Estero Bay Aquatic Preserve, the boundaries of which are generally: All of those sovereignty submerged lands located bayward of the mean high-water line being in Sections 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 35, and 36, Township 46 South, Range 24 East; and in Sections 19, 20, 28, 29, and 34, Township 46 South, Range 24 East, lying north and east of Matanzas Pass Channel; and in Sections 19, 30, and 31, Township 46 South, Range 25 East; and in Sections 6, 7, 17, 18, 19, 20, 29, 30, 31, and 32, Township 47 South, Range 25 East; and in Sections 1, 2, 3, 11, 12, 13, 14, 24, and 25, Township 47 South, Range 24 East, in Lee County, Florida. Any and all submerged lands conveyed by the Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund prior to October 12, 1966, and any and all uplands now in private ownership are specifically exempted from this preserve.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cape Haze Aquatic Preserve, the boundaries of which are generally: That part of Gasparilla Sound, Catfish Creek, Whiddon Creek, “The Cutoff,” Turtle Bay, and Charlotte Harbor lying within the following described limits: Northerly limits: Commence at the northwest corner of Section 18, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence south along the west line of said Section 18 to its intersection with the Government Meander Line of 1843-1844, and the point of beginning, thence southeasterly along said meander line to the northwesterly shoreline of Catfish Creek, thence northeasterly along said shoreline to the north line of said Section 18, thence east along said north line to the easterly shoreline of Catfish Creek, thence southeasterly along said shoreline to the east line of said Section 18, thence south along said east line, crossing an arm of said Catfish Creek to the southerly shoreline of said creek, thence westerly along said southerly shoreline and southerly along the easterly shoreline of Catfish Creek to said Government Meander Line, thence easterly and southeasterly along said meander line to the northerly shoreline of Gasparilla Sound in Section 21, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence easterly along said northerly shoreline and northeasterly along the westerly shoreline of Whiddon Creek to the east west quarter line in Section 16, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence east along said quarter line and the quarter Section line of Section 15, Township 42 South, Range 21 East to the easterly shoreline of Whiddon Creek, thence southerly along said shoreline to the northerly shoreline of “The Cutoff,” thence easterly along said shoreline to the westerly shoreline of Turtle Bay, thence northeasterly along said shoreline to its intersection with said Government Meander Line in Section 23, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence northeasterly along said meander line to the east line of Section 12, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence north along the east line of said Section 12, and the east line of Section 1, Township 42 South, Range 21 East to the northwest corner of Section 6, Township 42 South, Range 22 East, thence east along the north line and extension thereof of said Section 6 to a point 2,640 feet east of the westerly shoreline of Charlotte Harbor and the end of the northerly limits. Easterly limits: Commence at the northwest corner of Section 6, Township 42 South, Range 22 East, thence east along the north line of said Section 6 and extension thereof to a point 2,640 feet east of the westerly shoreline of Charlotte Harbor and the point of beginning, thence southerly along a line 2,640 feet easterly of and parallel with the westerly shoreline of Charlotte Harbor and along a southerly extension of said line to the line dividing Charlotte and Lee Counties and the end of the easterly limits. Southerly limits: Begin at the point of ending of the easterly limits, above described, said point being in the line dividing Charlotte and Lee Counties, thence southwesterly along a straight line to the most southerly point of Devil Fish Key, thence continue along said line to the easterly right-of-way of the Intracoastal Waterway and the end of the southerly limits. Westerly limits: Begin at the point of ending of the southerly limits as described above, thence northerly along the easterly right-of-way line of the Intracoastal Waterway to its intersection with a southerly extension of the west line of Section 18, Township 42 South, Range 21 East, thence north along said line to point of beginning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wekiva River Aquatic Preserve, the boundaries of which are generally: All the state-owned sovereignty lands lying waterward of the ordinary high-water mark of the Wekiva River and the Little Wekiva River and their tributaries lying and being in Lake, Seminole, and Orange counties and more particularly described as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In Sections 15, 16, 17, 20, 21, 22, 27, 28, 29, and 30, Township 20 South, Range 29 East. These sections are also depicted on the Forest City Quadrangle (U.S.G.S. 7.5 minute series-topographic) 1959 (70PR); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In Sections 3, 4, 8, 9, and 10, Township 20 South, Range 29 East and in Sections 21, 28, and 33, Township 19 South, Range 29 East lying north of the right-of-way for the Atlantic Coast Line Railroad and that part of Section 33, Township 19 South, Range 29 East lying between the Lake and Orange County lines and the right-of-way of the Atlantic Coast Line Railroad. These sections are also depicted on the Sanford SW Quadrangle (U.S.G.S. 7.5 minute series-topographic) 1965 (70-1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state-owned sovereignty lands, public lands, and lands whether public or private below the ordinary high-water mark of the Wekiva River and the Little Wekiva and their tributaries within the Peter Miranda Grant in Lake County lying below the 10 foot m.s.l. contour line nearest the meander line of the Wekiva River and all state-owned sovereignty lands, public lands, and lands whether public or private below the ordinary high-water mark of the Wekiva River and the Little Wekiva and their tributaries within the Moses E. Levy Grant in Lake County below the 10 foot m.s.l. contour line nearest the meander lines of the Wekiva River and Black Water Creek as depicted on the PINE LAKES 1962 (70-1), ORANGE CITY 1964 (70PR), SANFORD 1965 (70-1), and SANFORD S.W. 1965 (70-1) QUADRANGLES (U.S.G.S. 7.5 minute topographic); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state-owned sovereignty lands, public lands, and lands whether public or private below the ordinary high-water mark of the Wekiva River and the Little Wekiva River and their tributaries lying below the 10 foot m.s.l. contour line nearest the meander line of the Wekiva and St. Johns Rivers as shown on the ORANGE CITY 1964 (70PR), SANFORD 1965 (70-1), and SANFORD S.W. 1965 (70-1) QUADRANGLES (U.S.G.S. 7.5 minute topographic) within the following described property: Beginning at a point on the south boundary of the Moses E. Levy Grant, Township 19 South, Range 29 East, at its intersection with the meander line of the Wekiva River; thence south 60<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> degrees east along said boundary line 4,915.68 feet; thence north 29<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> degrees east 15,516.5 feet to the meander line of the St. Johns River; thence northerly along the meander line of the St. Johns River to the mouth of the Wekiva River; thence southerly along the meander line of the Wekiva River to the beginning; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state-owned sovereignty lands, public lands, and lands whether public or private below the ordinary high-water mark of the Wekiva River and the Little Wekiva River and their tributaries within the Peter Miranda Grant lying east of the Wekiva River, less the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State Road 46 and all land lying south of said State Road No. 46.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning 15.56 chains West of the Southeast corner of the SW <Fraction>1/4</Fraction> of the NE <Fraction>1/4</Fraction> of Section 21, Township 19 South, Range 29 East, run east 600 feet; thence north 960 feet; thence west 340 feet to the Wekiva River; thence southwesterly along said Wekiva River to point of beginning.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That part of the east <Fraction>1/4</Fraction> of the SW <Fraction>1/4</Fraction> of Section 22, Township 19 South, Range 29 East, lying within the Peter Miranda Grant east of the Wekiva River.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries: Begin at the intersection of State Road 44 and the westerly ordinary high water line of the St. Johns River, Section 22, Township 17 South, Range 29 East, Lake County: Thence proceed southerly along the westerly ordinary high water line of said river and its tributaries to the intersection of the northerly right-of-way of State Road 400; thence proceed northeasterly along said right-of-way to the easterly ordinary high water line of the St. Johns River; thence proceed northerly along said ordinary high water line of the St. Johns River and its tributaries to its intersection with the easterly ordinary high water line of Lake Beresford; thence proceed northerly along the ordinary high water line of said lake to its intersection with the westerly line of Section 24, Township 17 South, Range 29 East; thence proceed northerly to the southerly right-of-way of West New York Avenue; thence proceed westerly along the southerly right-of-way of said avenue to its intersection with the southerly right-of-way line of State Road 44; thence proceed southwesterly along said right-of-way to the point of beginning.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="31"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rookery Bay Aquatic Preserve, the boundaries of which are generally: All of the state-owned sovereignty lands lying waterward of the mean high-water line in Rookery Bay and in Henderson Creek and the tributaries thereto in Collier County, Florida. Said lands are more particularly described as lying and being in Sections 27, 34, 35, and 36, Township 50 South, Range 25 East; in Section 31, Township 50 South, Range 26 East; in Sections 1, 2, 3, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 23, 24, and 25, Township 51 South, Range 25 East; and in Sections 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 30, and 31, Township 51 South, Range 26 East, Collier County, Florida, and all the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries: Begin at the southwest corner of Section 30, Township 52 South, Range 27 East, Collier County: Thence proceed easterly along the southerly line of said Section 30 to the southwest corner of Section 29, Township 52 South, Range 27 East; proceed thence northerly along the westerly lines of Sections 29, 20 and 17 to the northwest corner of said Section 17; thence proceed westerly along the northerly line of Section 18 to the southeast corner of Section 12, Township 52 South, Range 26 East; thence proceed northerly along the easterly lines of Sections 12, 1, 36 and 25 to the northeast corner of said Section 25, Township 51 South, Range 26 East; thence proceed westerly along the northerly lines of Sections 25 and 26 to the northwest corner of said Section 26; thence proceed northerly to northeast corner of said Section 22; thence proceed westerly along the northerly lines of Sections 22 and 21 to the northwest corner of said Section 21; thence proceed southerly to the southwest corner of said Section 21; thence proceed westerly along the northerly line of Section 29 to the northwest corner thereof; thence proceed southerly along the westerly lines of Sections 29 and 32 to the southwest corner of said Section 32; thence proceed westerly to the northwest corner of Section 6, Township 52 South, Range 26 East; thence proceed southerly along a projection of Range line 25 East to its intersection with a line which runs westerly from the southwest corner of Cape Romano - Ten Thousand Islands Aquatic Preserve; thence proceed easterly to the southwest corner of Cape Romano - Ten Thousand Islands Aquatic Preserve; thence proceed northerly to the point of beginning. Less and except: Begin at the southeast corner of Section 21, Township 52 South, Range 26 East; thence proceed northerly along the easterly lines of Sections 21 and 16 to the northeast corner of said Section 16, thence proceed northerly to the thread of John Stevens Creek; thence proceed northwesterly along the thread of said creek to its intersection with the thread of Marco River; thence proceed northwesterly and westerly along the thread of said river to its intersection with the thread of Big Marco Pass; thence proceed southwesterly along the thread of Big Marco Pass to its intersection with Range line 25 East; thence proceed southerly along Range line 25 East to a point which is west from the point of beginning: Thence proceed easterly to the point of beginning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="32"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rainbow Springs Aquatic Preserve, the boundaries of which are generally: Commencing at the intersection of Blue Run with the Withlacoochee River in Section 35, Township 16 South, Range 18 East; thence run southeasterly and easterly along said Blue Run to the east boundary of said Section 35; thence continue easterly and northerly along said Blue Run through Section 36, Township 16 South, Range 18 East, to the north boundary of said Section 36; thence continue northerly and northeasterly along said Blue Run in Section 25, Township 16 South, Range 18 East, to the north boundary of the city limits of Dunnellon, Florida; thence from the north boundary of the city limits of Dunnellon, Florida, in Section 25, Township 16 South, Range 18 East; thence run easterly along said Blue Run to its intersection with the east boundary line of said Section 25; thence continue easterly along said Rainbow River (Blue Run) into Section 30, Township 16 South, Range 19 East, thence northerly along said Rainbow River (Blue Run) through Sections 30 and 19, Township 16 South, Range 19 East, to a point on the north boundary of the northwest <Fraction>1/4</Fraction> of Section 18; thence continue to run northwesterly to the head of Rainbow Springs in Section 12, Township 16 South, Range 18 East.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any and all submerged lands theretofore conveyed by the Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and any and all uplands now in private ownership are specifically exempted from this dedication.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 75-172; s. 1, ch. 76-109; s. 1, ch. 76-211; s. 84, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 83-62; s. 2, ch. 84-312; s. 1, ch. 85-345; s. 6, ch. 86-186; s. 3, ch. 89-25; s. 1, ch. 91-35; s. 7, ch. 91-221; s. 51, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>