<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.392" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gasparilla Sound-Charlotte Harbor Aquatic Preserve.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following described area in Lee and Charlotte Counties is designated by the Legislature for inclusion in the aquatic preserve system under the Florida Aquatic Preserve Act of 1975. Such area, to be known as the Gasparilla Sound-Charlotte Harbor Aquatic Preserve, shall be included in the aquatic preserve system and shall include the following described real property: Commence at the northwest corner of Section 18, Township 42 South, Range 21 East; thence northerly along the line of mean high water to the intersection of State Road 775 with said mean high-water line; thence south-southwesterly along said road to the intersection of said road with the mean high-water line of Gasparilla Island; thence southerly along said mean high-water line to the most southerly point of Gasparilla Island; thence southeasterly to the northernmost point at the mean high-water line on Lacosta Island; thence southeasterly along said mean high-water line to the northwest corner of Section 6, Township 44 South, Range 21 East; thence east to a northerly extension of the east line of Section 25, Township 44 South, Range 21 East; thence southeasterly along the mean high-water line of Pine Island to the intersection of the east line of Section 28, Township 43 South, Range 22 East, with said mean high-water line; thence northeasterly to the intersection of the north line of Section 23, Township 43 South, Range 22 East with the mean high-water line; thence northerly along said mean high-water line to the intersection of State Road 45 (U.S. Highway 41, Gilchrist Bridge) with said mean high-water line; thence northwesterly along said road to the intersection of said road with the mean high-water line at Live Oak Point; thence westerly along the mean high-water line to the intersection of State Road 771 with said mean high-water line; thence south-southwesterly along said road to the intersection of said road with the mean high-water line, on the southern shore of the Myakka River; thence southerly along the mean high-water line of the westerly shore of Charlotte Harbor to the northwest corner of Section 6, Township 42 South, Range 22 East; thence east along the north line and extension thereof of said Section 6 to a point 2,640 feet east of the westerly shoreline of Charlotte Harbor; thence southerly along a line 2,640 feet easterly of and parallel with the westerly shoreline of Charlotte Harbor and along a southerly extension of said line to the line dividing Charlotte and Lee Counties; thence southwesterly along a straight line to the most southerly point of Devil Fish Key; thence along said line to the easterly right-of-way of the Intracoastal Waterway; thence northerly along the easterly right-of-way of the Intracoastal Waterway to its intersection with a southerly extension of the west line of Section 18, Township 42 South, Range 21 East; thence north along said line to the point of beginning. Said boundary extends across the mouths of all artificial waterways, but includes all tidally connected natural waterways.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-115; s. 4, ch. 89-25.</History></Section>