<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.391" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cockroach Bay Aquatic Preserve.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following described area in Hillsborough County is hereby designated by the Legislature for inclusion in the aquatic preserve system under the Florida Aquatic Preserve Act of 1975. Such area shall be known as the Cockroach Bay Aquatic Preserve. Those portions of the Cockroach Bay Aquatic Preserve owned by the Tampa Port Authority shall be included in the aquatic preserve system for the period of a lease and future lease extensions of such area from the Tampa Port Authority. The area designated for inclusion in the Cockroach Bay Aquatic Preserve shall include the following described real property: Begin at the northeast corner of Section 1, Township 33 South, Range 17 East, Manatee County, thence west along the north line of said Section 1 to its intersection with the mean high-water line of Tampa Bay, said point being the point of beginning; from said point of beginning continue west 2,000 feet into the waters of Tampa Bay, thence northeasterly along a line 2,000 feet westerly of the mean high-water line of Tampa Bay, said line also being 2,000 feet westerly of the mean high-water line on Beacon Key, Snake Key, Camp Key, Big Pass Key, Little Cockroach Island, and Sand Key, to a point due west from the southwesterly point of Bird Key, thence east to the most southwesterly point of Bird Key, thence southeasterly, southerly, and easterly along the southerly edge of a channel along the northerly side of Tropical Island to the easterly point of Tropical Island, thence in an easterly direction to the westerly point of Negro Island, thence in an easterly direction along the southerly edge of a channel along the northerly side of Negro Island and Chicken Island, to a point due south of the southeast corner of Collura Subdivision as shown in Plat Book 34, page 2 of the Public Records of Hillsborough County, Florida, said corner being located along the east boundary of government lot 2, thence due north to the northerly shore of the Little Manatee River, thence easterly and southeasterly along the mean high-water line of the northerly shore of the Little Manatee River, including all of the channels, tributaries, bayous, and sloughs of the river, with the exception of Ruskin Inlet, to the intersection of the Little Manatee River and U.S. 301, thence westerly and northwesterly along the mean high-water line of the southerly shore of the Little Manatee River, including all of the channels, tributaries, bayous, and sloughs of the river, to the mouth of the Little Manatee River, thence in a westerly and southwesterly direction along the mean high-water line of Tampa Bay, Little Cockroach Bay, and Cockroach Bay to the point of beginning. Less any islands, submerged lands, or uplands not owned by the Tampa Port Authority or the State of Florida.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-197; s. 1, ch. 88-258.</History></Section>