<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citizen support organizations; use of property; audit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For the purpose of this section, a “citizen support organization” means an organization which is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida corporation not for profit incorporated under the provisions of chapter 617 and approved by the Department of State;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized and operated to conduct programs and activities; raise funds; request and receive grants, gifts, and bequests of money; acquire, receive, hold, invest, and administer, in its own name, securities, funds, objects of value, or other property, real or personal; and make expenditures to or for the direct or indirect benefit of the state park system or individual units of the state park system;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determined by the Division of Recreation and Parks of the Department of Environmental Protection to be consistent with the goals of the state park system and in the best interests of the state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approved in writing by the division to operate for the direct or indirect benefit of the state park system or individual units of the state park system. Such approval shall be given in a letter of agreement from the division.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF PROPERTY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may permit, without charge, appropriate use of fixed property and facilities of the state park system by a citizen support organization, subject to the provisions of this section. Such use must be directly in keeping with the approved purposes of the citizen support organization, and may not be made at times or places that would unreasonably interfere with opportunities for the general public to use the park or parks for established recreational purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may prescribe by rule any condition with which a citizen support organization shall comply in order to use fixed property or facilities of the state park system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall not permit the use of any fixed property or facilities of the state park system by a citizen support organization which does not provide equal membership and employment opportunities to all persons regardless of race, color, religion, sex, age, or national origin.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTNERSHIPS IN PARKS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that many of the parks in the state park system need a variety of facilities to enhance their use and potential. Such facilities include, but are not limited to, improved access, camping areas, picnicking shelters, park management offices and facilities, and environmental education facilities. The need for such facilities has exceeded the ability of the state to provide such facilities in a timely manner with moneys available. The Legislature finds it to be in the public interest to provide incentives for partnerships with private organizations with the intent of producing additional revenue to help enhance the use and potential of the state park system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature may annually appropriate funds from the Land Acquisition Trust Fund for use only as state matching funds, in conjunction with private donations in aggregates of at least $60,000 matched by $40,000 of state funds for a total minimum project amount of $100,000 for capital improvement facility development at state parks, at either individually designated parks or for priority projects within the overall state park system. Not more than 30 percent of the Land Acquisition Trust Fund unencumbered fund balance or $3 million, whichever is less, shall be reserved, available annually for matching private donations. The amount held in reserve for the state match will be no greater than $6 million for any fiscal year. State funds from the Land Acquisition Trust Fund or other appropriate funding sources shall be used for matching private donations for 40 percent of the projects’ costs. Funds held in reserve for the purposes of this subsection shall be available only after the requirements of s. 375.041(3) are met. Citizen support organizations organized and operating for the benefit of state parks may acquire private donations pursuant to this section, and matching state funds for approved projects may be provided in accordance with this subsection. The department is authorized to properly recognize and honor a private donor by placing a plaque or other appropriate designation noting the contribution on project facilities or by naming project facilities after the person or organization that provided matching funds. The department is authorized to adopt necessary administrative rules to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-47; s. 2, ch. 89-117; s. 87, ch. 90-360; s. 92, ch. 94-356; s. 1, ch. 96-389; s. 2, ch. 96-395; s. 114, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>