<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Park regions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of administering this chapter, regulating the public parks, monuments and memorials of this state, the state is divided into five park regions which are defined as:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FIRST REGION.<EmDash />The Counties of Escambia, Santa Rosa, Okaloosa, Walton, Bay, Washington, Holmes, Jackson, Calhoun, Gulf, Gadsden, Liberty, Franklin, Wakulla, Leon, and Jefferson shall constitute the First Park Region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SECOND REGION.<EmDash />The Counties of Madison, Taylor, Hamilton, Suwannee, Lafayette, Dixie, Levy, Gilchrist, Columbia, Baker, Union, Bradford, Alachua, Marion, Putnam, Clay, Duval, Nassau, and St. Johns shall constitute the Second Park Region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIRD REGION.<EmDash />The Counties of Citrus, Sumter, Lake, Hernando, Pasco, Hillsborough, Pinellas, Polk, Manatee, Hardee, Highlands, Sarasota, DeSoto, Charlotte, and Glades shall constitute the Third Park Region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOURTH REGION.<EmDash />The Counties of Flagler, Volusia, Seminole, Orange, Osceola, Brevard, Indian River, Okeechobee, St. Lucie, and Martin shall constitute the Fourth Park Region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FIFTH REGION.<EmDash />The Counties of Lee, Hendry, Palm Beach, Collier, Broward, Miami-Dade, and Monroe shall constitute the Fifth Park Region.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 25353, 1949; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 48, ch. 2008-4.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 592.02.</Text></Note></Section>