<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment of aquatic preserves.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may establish additional areas to be included in the aquatic preserve system, subject to confirmation by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, after public notice and public hearing in the county or counties in which the proposed preserve is to be located, adopt a resolution formally setting aside such areas to be included in the aquatic preserve system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resolution setting aside an aquatic preserve area shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legal description of the area to be included.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designation of the type of aquatic preserve being set aside.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general statement of what is sought to be preserved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear statement of the management responsibilities for the area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands and water bottoms owned by other governmental agencies may be included in an aquatic preserve upon specific authorization for inclusion by an appropriate instrument in writing from the governmental agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands and water bottoms in private ownership may be included in an aquatic preserve upon specific authorization for inclusion by an appropriate instrument in writing from the owner. The appropriate instrument shall be either a dedication in perpetuity or a lease. Such lease shall contain the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Term of the lease shall be for a minimum period of 10 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the power and duty to enforce the provisions of each lease agreement and shall additionally have the power to terminate any lease if the termination is in the best interest of the aquatic preserve system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall pay no more than $1 per year for any such lease.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (5), no aquatic preserve or any part thereof shall be withdrawn from the state aquatic preserve system except by an act of the Legislature. Notice of such proposed legislation shall be published in each county in which the affected area is located, in the manner prescribed by law relating to local legislation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days of the designation and establishment of an aquatic preserve, the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund shall record in the public records of the county or counties in which the aquatic preserve is located a legal description of the aquatic preserve.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 75-172.</History></Section>