<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0258.395" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Big Bend Seagrasses Aquatic Preserve.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following described area in Wakulla, Jefferson, Taylor, Dixie, and Levy Counties is hereby designated by the Legislature for inclusion in the aquatic preserve system under the Florida Aquatic Preserve Act of 1975. Such area, to be known as the Big Bend Seagrasses Aquatic Preserve, shall be included in the aquatic preserve system and shall include all the sovereignty submerged lands lying within the following described boundaries: Begin where the northerly mean high water line of Withlacoochee River meets the mean high water line of the Gulf of Mexico, Township 17 South, Range 15 East, Levy County: Thence from the said point of beginning proceed northwesterly along the mean high water line of the coast and its navigable tributaries to the intersection of the westerly mean high water line of St. Marks River with the mean high water line of the Gulf of Mexico, in Township 4 South, Range 1 East, Wakulla County; thence proceed south three marine leagues into the Gulf of Mexico; thence proceed southeasterly along a line three marine leagues from and parallel to the line of mean high water previously described to an intersection with a line projected west from the point of beginning; thence proceed east to the point of beginning. Less and except all those sovereignty submerged lands within 500 feet of any incorporated or unincorporated municipality within the above described lands. Less and except: Begin at the intersection of the southerly projection of the east line of Range line 4 East with the mean high water line of the Gulf of Mexico; thence proceed southwest to a point on the three marine league line; thence proceed southeasterly three marine leagues from and parallel to the mean high water line to a point which is southwest of the intersection of the southerly line of Section 22, Township 6 South, Range 6 East, Taylor County, with the mean high water line of the Gulf of Mexico; thence proceed Northeast to the foresaid point of intersection; thence proceed northwesterly along the mean high water line of the Gulf of Mexico and its tributaries to the point of beginning. Less and except all those local access channels adjacent to Keaton Beach and a proposed navigational channel more particularly described as follows: Begin at State Plane Coordinate; X=2,288,032; Y=298,365: Thence proceed West 11,608 feet; thence proceed south 1,440 feet; thence proceed east 11,608 feet; thence proceed north 1,440 feet to the point of beginning; less and except all those sovereign submerged lands lying northerly and easterly of U.S. Highway 19.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 85-345.</History></Section>