<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0554.109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurance company insuring a boiler located in a public assembly location in this state shall inspect such boiler so insured, and any county, city, town, or other governmental subdivision which has adopted into law the Boiler and Pressure Vessel Code of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers and the National Board Inspection Code for the construction, installation, inspection, maintenance, and repair of boilers, regulating such boilers in public assembly locations, shall inspect such boilers so regulated; provided that such inspection shall be conducted by a special inspector licensed pursuant to ss. 554.1011-554.115. Upon filing of a report of satisfactory inspection with the department, such boiler is exempt from inspection by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to hot water supply boilers or lined storage water heaters which are directly fired with oil, gas, electricity, or solar energy, provided that none of the following limitations are exceeded:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heat input of 400,000 Btu per hour.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water temperature of 210 degrees Fahrenheit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nominal water-containing capacity of 120 gallons.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">These exempt hot water supply boilers and lined storage water heaters shall be equipped with safety relief valves conforming to the requirements of the Boiler and Pressure Vessel Code of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers and of the National Board Inspection Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-361; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 10, ch. 89-233; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>