<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0554.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The only boilers required to be inspected under the provisions of ss. 554.1011-554.115 are boilers located in public assembly locations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each inspection of a boiler conducted pursuant to ss. 554.1011-554.115 shall be made by the chief inspector, a deputy inspector, or a special inspector.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction, installation, and condition of each boiler used in a public assembly location shall be inspected as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Power boilers and high pressure, high temperature water boilers shall receive a certificate inspection annually. Such inspection shall include, but not be limited to, an external inspection while the boiler is under pressure and an internal inspection if the construction of the boiler so permits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Low pressure steam or vapor heating boilers shall receive a certificate inspection biennially. Such inspection shall include, but not be limited to, an internal inspection if the construction of the boiler so permits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hot water heating boilers and hot water supply boilers shall receive a certificate inspection biennially. Such boilers shall receive an internal inspection every 4 years if the construction of the boiler so permits.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deputy inspectors and special inspectors shall file a written report on each certificate inspection with the chief inspector within 15 days following such inspection. The filing of reports of inspections other than certificate inspections are not required unless such inspections disclose that a boiler is in an unsafe condition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determining that a boiler is in an unsafe condition and poses an imminent danger to the public health, safety, and welfare, the chief inspector, a deputy inspector, or a special inspector may immediately order the boiler to be shut down. The boiler shall remain shut down until a reinspection by a certified inspector determines that all violations have been corrected, that the boiler may be operated safely, and that a certificate of compliance has been issued.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-361; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>