<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0554.113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification of inspectors; renewals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief inspector shall issue a certificate of competency, upon receipt of the certificate fee, to each person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has passed the certification examination; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who holds a commission from the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors and who has at least 3 years’ experience in the construction, installation, inspection, operation, maintenance, or repair of high pressure, high temperature water boilers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate is valid for a period of 1 year. The department shall mail each certificateholder an application for renewal. The certificateholder shall complete, sign, and forward the renewal application to the department, together with the appropriate fee, and the department shall, upon receipt of the application and fee, renew the certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, by rule, may establish a penalty fee for late renewal not to exceed $10.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate which is inoperative because of failure to renew shall be restored upon payment of the renewal fee, if the application for restoration is made to the department within 60 days after the renewal date. If the application for restoration is not made within the 60-day period, the fee for restoration shall be equal to the original application fee, plus the renewal fee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 87-361; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>