<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0554.115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may suspend or revoke a certificate of compliance upon proof that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate has been obtained by fraud or misrepresentation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boiler for which the certificate was issued cannot be operated safely; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person who received the certificate willfully or deliberately violated the State Boiler Code or ss. 554.1011-554.115 or any rule adopted pursuant to ss. 554.1011-554.115.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may suspend or revoke a certificate of competency upon proof that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate was obtained by fraud or misrepresentation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspector to whom the certificate was issued is no longer qualified under ss. 554.1011-554.115 to inspect boilers; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspector:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operated a boiler at a public assembly location without a valid certificate of compliance for that boiler;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gave false or forged information to the department or to another boiler inspector for the purpose of obtaining a certificate of compliance;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Used a certificate of compliance for any boiler other than the boiler for which it was issued;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operated a boiler for which the certificate of compliance has been suspended or revoked or has expired;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspected any boiler regulated under ss. 554.1011-554.115 without having obtained a valid certificate of competency;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operated a boiler that is in an unsafe condition; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operated a boiler in a manner that is contrary to the requirements of this chapter or any rule adopted under this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each suspension of a certificate of compliance or certificate of competency shall continue in effect until all violations have been corrected and, for boiler safety violations, until the boiler has been inspected and shown to be in a safe condition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person in violation of this section who does not have a valid certificate of competency shall be reported by the chief inspector to the appropriate state attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person in violation of this section who has a valid certificate of competency is subject to administrative action by the chief inspector.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A revocation of a certificate of competency is permanent, and a revoked certificate of competency may not be reinstated or a new certificate of competency issued to the same person. A suspension of a certificate of competency continues in effect until all violations have been corrected. A suspension of a certificate of compliance for any boiler safety violation continues in effect until the boiler has been inspected by an authorized inspector and shown to be in safe working condition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 87-361; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 2000-370.</History></Section>