<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0243.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of Higher Educational Facilities Financing Authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a public body corporate and politic to be known as the Higher Educational Facilities Financing Authority. The authority is constituted as a public instrumentality and the exercise by the authority of the powers conferred by ss. 243.50-243.77 is considered to be the performance of an essential public function. Chapters 119 and 286 apply to the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall consist of five members to be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. One member shall be a trustee, director, officer, or employee of an institution of higher education. Of the members first appointed, one shall serve for 1 year, one for 2 years, one for 3 years, one for 4 years, and one for 5 years, and in each case until his or her successor is appointed and has qualified. Thereafter, the Governor shall appoint for terms of 5 years each a member or members to succeed those whose terms expire. The Governor shall fill any vacancy for an unexpired term. A member of the authority is eligible for reappointment. Any member of the authority may be removed by the Governor for misfeasance, malfeasance, or willful neglect of duty. Each member of the authority before entering upon his or her duties shall take and subscribe to the oath or affirmation required by the State Constitution. A record of each oath must be filed in the office of the Department of State and with the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall annually elect one of its members as chair and one as vice chair, and shall also appoint an executive director who is not a member of the authority and who serves at the pleasure of the authority and receives compensation as fixed by the authority. The authority may contract for the services of an executive director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director shall keep a record of the proceedings of the authority and shall be custodian of all books, documents, and papers filed with the authority and of the minute book or journal of the authority and of its official seal. He or she may cause copies to be made of all minutes and other records and documents of the authority and may give certificates under the official seal of the authority to the effect that the copies are true copies, and all persons dealing with the authority may rely upon those certificates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the members of the authority constitutes a quorum, and the affirmative vote of a majority of the members present at a meeting of the authority is necessary for any action taken by the authority. A vacancy in the membership of the authority does not impair the right of a quorum to exercise all the rights and perform all the duties of the authority. Any action taken by the authority under ss. 243.50-243.77 may be authorized by resolution at any regular or special meeting, and each resolution shall take effect immediately and need not be published or posted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for the performance of their duties, but each member is entitled to reimbursement as provided in s. 112.061 for necessary expenses incurred while engaged in the performance of his or her duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority is assigned to the Department of Education for administrative purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2001-79.</History></Section>