<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0243.65" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security of bondholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the discretion of the authority, any revenue bonds issued under ss. 243.50-243.77 may be secured by a trust agreement by and between the authority and a corporate trustee or trustees, which may be any trust company or bank having the powers of a trust company within or without the state. The trust agreement or the resolution providing for the issuance of revenue bonds may pledge or assign the revenues to be received or the proceeds of any contract or contracts pledged and may convey or mortgage the project or any portion thereof. The trust agreement or resolution providing for the issuance of revenue bonds may contain provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of the bondholders as may be reasonable and proper and not in violation of law, including particularly those provisions specifically authorized by ss. 243.50-243.77 to be included in any resolution of the authority authorizing revenue bonds. Any bank or trust company incorporated under the laws of this state or of any other state or the United States which may legally act as depository of the proceeds of bonds or of revenues or other moneys or security may furnish indemnifying bonds or pledge securities required by the authority, if any. Any trust agreement may set forth the rights and remedies of the bondholders and of the trustee or trustees, and may restrict the individual right of action by bondholders. In addition, any trust agreement or resolution may contain any other provisions the authority considers reasonable and proper for the security of the bondholders. All expenses incurred in carrying out the trust agreement or resolution may be treated as a part of the cost of the operation of a project.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2001-79.</History></Section>