<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0243.54" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of the authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the authority is to assist institutions of higher education in constructing, financing, and refinancing projects throughout the state and, for this purpose, the authority may:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise all powers granted to corporations under the Florida Business Corporation Act, chapter 607.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have perpetual succession as a body politic and corporate and adopt bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt an official seal and alter the same at its pleasure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain an office at any place in the state that it may designate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued in its own name, and plead and be impleaded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and execute financing agreements, leases, as lessee or as lessor, contracts, deeds, and other instruments necessary or convenient in the exercise of the powers and functions of the authority, including contracts with persons, firms, corporations, federal and state agencies, and other authorities, which state agencies and other authorities are authorized to enter into contracts and otherwise cooperate with the authority to facilitate the financing, construction, leasing, or sale of any project or the institution of any program; engage in sale-leaseback, lease-purchase, lease-leaseback, or other undertakings and provide for the sale of certificates of participation incident thereto; and enter into interlocal agreements in the manner provided in s. 163.01.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the location and character of any project to be financed under ss. 243.50-243.77 and may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construct, reconstruct, maintain, repair, and lease the project as lessee or lessor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts for any of those purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate a participating institution as its agent to determine the location and character of a project undertaken by a participating institution under ss. 243.50-243.77 and, as the agent of the authority, construct, reconstruct, maintain, repair, own, and lease the project as lessee or lessor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue bonds, bond anticipation notes, and other obligations of the authority for any of its corporate purposes, including the provision of funds to pay all or any part of the cost of any project and to fund or refund the cost of any project as provided in ss. 243.50-243.77.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish rules for the use of a project or any portion thereof and designate a participating institution as its agent to establish rules for the use of a project undertaken by the participating institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ consulting engineers, architects, attorneys, accountants, construction and financial experts, superintendents, managers, and other employees and agents as necessary, and fix their compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive and accept from any public agency loans or grants for or in aid of the construction of a project or any portion thereof, and receive and accept loans, grants, aid, or contributions from any source of money, property, labor, or other things of value, to be held, used, and applied only for the purposes for which the loans, grants, aid, and contributions are made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mortgage any project and the site thereof for the benefit of the holders of revenue bonds issued to finance projects or those providing credit for that purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make loans to any participating institution for the cost of a project, including a loan in anticipation of tuition revenues, in accordance with an agreement between the authority and the participating institution. However, a loan may not exceed the total cost of the project as determined by the participating institution and approved by the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make loans to a participating institution to refund outstanding obligations, mortgages, or advances issued, made, or given by the participating institution for the cost of a project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charge to and equitably apportion among participating institutions its administrative costs and expenses incurred in the exercise of the powers and duties conferred by ss. 243.50-243.77.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with an entity as its agent to assist the authority in screening applications of institutions of higher education for loans under ss. 243.50-243.77 and receive any recommendations the entity may make.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of ss. 243.50-243.77.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2001-79.</History></Section>