<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0838.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Benefit” means gain or advantage, or anything regarded by the person to be benefited as a gain or advantage, including the doing of an act beneficial to any person in whose welfare he or she is interested, including any commission, gift, gratuity, property, commercial interest, or any other thing of economic value not authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bid” includes a response to an “invitation to bid,” “invitation to negotiate,” “request for a quote,” or “request for proposals” as those terms are defined in s. 287.012.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commodity” means any goods, merchandise, wares, produce, chose in action, land, article of commerce, or other tangible or intangible property, real, personal, or mixed, for use, consumption, production, enjoyment, or resale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corruptly” or “with corrupt intent” means acting knowingly and dishonestly for a wrongful purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Harm” means pecuniary or other loss, disadvantage, or injury to the person affected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public servant” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee of a state, county, municipal, or special district agency or entity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any legislative or judicial officer or employee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, except a witness, who acts as a general or special magistrate, receiver, auditor, arbitrator, umpire, referee, consultant, or hearing officer while performing a governmental function; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A candidate for election or appointment to any of the positions listed in this subsection, or an individual who has been elected to, but has yet to officially assume the responsibilities of, public office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service” means any kind of activity performed in whole or in part for economic benefit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 59, ch. 74-383; s. 317, ch. 96-410; s. 1824, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 2003-158; s. 99, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>