<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0015.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">International and cultural relations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Divisions of Cultural Affairs, Historical Resources, and Library and Information Services of the Department of State promote programs having substantial cultural, artistic, and indirect economic significance that emphasize American creativity. The Secretary of State, as the head administrator of these divisions, shall hereafter be known as “Florida’s Chief Cultural Officer.” As this officer, the Secretary of State is encouraged to initiate and develop relationships between the state and foreign cultural officers, their representatives, and other foreign governmental officials in order to promote Florida as the center of American creativity. The Secretary of State shall coordinate international activities pursuant to this section with Enterprise Florida, Inc., and any other organization the secretary deems appropriate. For the accomplishment of this purpose, the Secretary of State shall have the power and authority to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate any information pertaining to the State of Florida which promotes the state’s cultural assets.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan and carry out activities designed to cause improved cultural and governmental programs and exchanges with foreign countries.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan and implement cultural and social activities for visiting foreign heads of state, diplomats, dignitaries, and exchange groups.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage and cooperate with other public and private organizations or groups in their efforts to promote the cultural advantages of Florida.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as the liaison with all foreign consular and ambassadorial corps, as well as international organizations, that are consistent with the purposes of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, arrange, and make expenditures for the achievement of any or all of the purposes specified in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-159; s. 1, ch. 83-64; s. 1, ch. 86-163; s. 87, ch. 90-201; s. 30, ch. 91-5; s. 76, ch. 99-251; s. 5, ch. 2002-1; s. 12, ch. 2012-116.</History>
</Section>