<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0467.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Approved program” means a midwifery school or a midwifery training program which is approved by the department pursuant to s. 467.205.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified nurse midwife” means a person who is licensed as an advanced registered nurse practitioner under part I of chapter 464 and who is certified to practice midwifery by the American College of Nurse Midwives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Council of Licensed Midwifery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intrapartal” means occurring during the process of giving birth.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensure” means authorization and license granted by the department for a person to engage in the practice of midwifery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Midwife” means any person not less than 21 years of age, other than a licensed physician or certified nurse midwife, who is licensed under this chapter to supervise the birth of a child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Midwifery” means the practice of supervising the conduct of a normal labor and childbirth, with the informed consent of the parent; the practice of advising the parents as to the progress of the childbirth; and the practice of rendering prenatal and postpartal care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Normal labor and childbirth” means the physiological process of a healthy woman giving birth to a healthy infant and expelling an intact placenta, without injury, complications, or undue strain to the mother.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a person licensed to practice medicine as authorized in chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Postpartal” or “postpartum” means existing or occurring subsequent to birth.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preceptor” means a physician, a licensed midwife, or a certified nurse midwife, who has a minimum of 3 years’ professional experience, and who directs, teaches, supervises, and evaluates the learning experiences of the student midwife.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prenatal” or “antepartal” means occurring during pregnancy up to the point of onset of labor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stillbirth” means the death of a fetus of more than 20 weeks’ gestation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 82-99; ss. 2, 8, ch. 84-268; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-429; ss. 2, 19, ch. 92-179; s. 128, ch. 94-218; s. 74, ch. 98-166; s. 131, ch. 2000-318; s. 87, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>