<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0467.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary actions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, attempting to procure, or renewing a license to practice midwifery by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice midwifery revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including being denied licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, in any jurisdiction of a crime which directly relates to the practice of midwifery or to the ability to practice midwifery. A plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for purposes of this provision.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a false report or record, which the licensee knows to be false; intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law; or willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another to do so. Such reports or records shall include only those which are signed in the midwife’s capacity as a licensed midwife.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising falsely, misleadingly, or deceptively.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in unprofessional conduct, which includes, but is not limited to, any departure from, or the failure to conform to, the standards of practice of midwifery as established by the department, in which case actual injury need not be established.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice midwifery with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness; drunkenness; or use of drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or other materials or as a result of any mental or physical condition. A midwife affected under this paragraph shall, at reasonable intervals, be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of midwifery with reasonable skill and safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this chapter or of the rules of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any lawful order of the department previously entered in a disciplinary proceeding or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not reinstate the license of a midwife, or cause a license to be issued to a person it has deemed unqualified, until such time as it is satisfied that such person has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and that such person is capable of safely engaging in the practice of midwifery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall by rule establish guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. Such guidelines may include minimum and maximum fines, periods of suspension or probation, or conditions of probation or reissuance of a license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 82-99; s. 90, ch. 83-218; s. 8, ch. 84-268; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-429; s. 19, ch. 92-179; s. 266, ch. 97-103; s. 133, ch. 2000-318; s. 79, ch. 2001-62; s. 36, ch. 2001-277; s. 12, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>