<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0701.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cancellation of mortgages, liens, and judgments.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 14 days after receipt of the written request of a mortgagor, a record title owner of the property, a fiduciary or trustee lawfully acting on behalf of a record title owner, or any other person lawfully authorized to act on behalf of a mortgagor or record title owner of the property, the holder of a mortgage shall deliver or cause the servicer of the mortgage to deliver to the person making the request at a place designated in the written request an estoppel letter setting forth the unpaid balance of the loan secured by the mortgage.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the mortgagor, or any person lawfully authorized to act on behalf of the mortgagor, makes the request, the estoppel letter must include an itemization of the principal, interest, and any other charges properly due under or secured by the mortgage and interest on a per-day basis for the unpaid balance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a record title owner of the property, or any person lawfully authorized to act on behalf of a mortgagor or record title owner of the property, makes the request:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The request must include a copy of the instrument showing title in the property or lawful authorization.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estoppel letter may include the itemization of information required under paragraph (a), but must at a minimum include the total unpaid balance due under or secured by the mortgage on a per-day basis.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgagee or servicer of the mortgagee acting in accordance with a request in substantial compliance with this paragraph is expressly discharged from any obligation or liability to any person on account of the release of the requested information, other than the obligation to comply with the terms of the estoppel letter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mortgage holder may provide the financial information required under this subsection to a person authorized under this subsection to request the financial information notwithstanding s. 655.059.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the amount of money due on any mortgage, lien, or judgment has been fully paid to the person or party entitled to the payment thereof, the mortgagee, creditor, or assignee, or the attorney of record in the case of a judgment, to whom the payment was made, shall execute in writing an instrument acknowledging satisfaction of the mortgage, lien, or judgment and have the instrument acknowledged, or proven, and duly entered in the official records of the proper county. Within 60 days after the date of receipt of the full payment of the mortgage, lien, or judgment, the person required to acknowledge satisfaction of the mortgage, lien, or judgment shall send or cause to be sent the recorded satisfaction to the person who has made the full payment. In the case of a civil action arising out of this section, the prevailing party is entitled to attorney fees and costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a writ of execution has been issued, docketed, and indexed with a sheriff and the judgment upon which it was issued has been fully paid, it is the responsibility of the party receiving payment to request, in writing, addressed to the sheriff, return of the writ of execution as fully satisfied.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 4138, 1893; s. 1, ch. 4918, 1901; GS 2500; RGS 3843; CGL 5746; s. 1, ch. 80-17; s. 15, ch. 93-250; s. 12, ch. 94-170; s. 8, ch. 2007-44; s. 1, ch. 2012-49.</History>
</Section>