<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1002.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public school parental choice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “controlled open enrollment” means a public education delivery system that allows school districts to make student school assignments using parents’ indicated preferential school choice as a significant factor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board may offer controlled open enrollment within the public schools. The controlled open enrollment program shall be offered in addition to the existing choice programs such as virtual instruction programs, magnet schools, alternative schools, special programs, advanced placement, and dual enrollment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall develop a controlled open enrollment plan which describes the implementation of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School districts shall adhere to federal desegregation requirements. No controlled open enrollment plan that conflicts with federal desegregation orders shall be implemented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each school district shall develop a system of priorities for its plan that includes consideration of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application process required to participate in the controlled open enrollment program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A process that allows parents to declare school preferences.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A process that encourages placement of siblings within the same school.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lottery procedure used by the school district to determine student assignment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appeals process for hardship cases.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedures to maintain socioeconomic, demographic, and racial balance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability of transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A process that promotes strong parental involvement, including the designation of a parent liaison.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A strategy that establishes a clearinghouse of information designed to assist parents in making informed choices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans shall be submitted to the Commissioner of Education. The Commissioner of Education shall develop an annual report on the status of school choice and deliver the report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives at least 90 days prior to the convening of the regular session of the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this section, a school district with schools operating on both multiple session schedules and single session schedules shall afford parents of students in multiple session schools preferred access to the controlled open enrollment program of the school district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall annually report the number of students applying for and attending the various types of public schools of choice in the district, including schools such as virtual instruction programs, magnet schools, and public charter schools, according to rules adopted by the State Board of Education.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 96, ch. 2002-387; s. 3, ch. 2008-147.</History></Section>