<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1002.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Office of Early Learning; powers and duties; operational requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall administer the operational requirements of the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program at the state level.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall adopt procedures governing the administration of the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program by the early learning coalitions and school districts for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrolling children in and determining the eligibility of children for the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program under s. 1002.53.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing parents with profiles of private prekindergarten providers and public schools under s. 1002.53.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registering private prekindergarten providers and public schools to deliver the program under ss. 1002.55, 1002.61, and 1002.63.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining the eligibility of private prekindergarten providers to deliver the program under ss. 1002.55 and 1002.61.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Verifying the compliance of private prekindergarten providers and public schools and removing providers or schools from eligibility to deliver the program due to noncompliance or misconduct as provided in s. 1002.67.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying private prekindergarten providers and public schools under s. 1002.71.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documenting and certifying student enrollment and student attendance under s. 1002.71.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reconciling advance payments in accordance with the uniform attendance policy under s. 1002.71.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reenrolling students dismissed by a private prekindergarten provider or public school for noncompliance with the provider’s or school district’s attendance policy under s. 1002.71.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall adopt, in consultation with and subject to approval by the department, procedures governing the administration of the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program by the early learning coalitions and school districts for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approving improvement plans of private prekindergarten providers and public schools under s. 1002.67.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing private prekindergarten providers and public schools on probation and requiring corrective actions under s. 1002.67.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removing a private prekindergarten provider or public school from eligibility to deliver the program due to the provider’s or school’s remaining on probation beyond the time permitted under s. 1002.67.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrolling children in and determining the eligibility of children for the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program under s. 1002.66.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying specialized instructional services providers under s. 1002.66.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall also adopt procedures for the distribution of funds to early learning coalitions under s. 1002.71.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided by law, the Office of Early Learning may not impose requirements on a private prekindergarten provider or public school that does not deliver the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program or receive state funds under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-484; s. 7, ch. 2010-227; s. 459, ch. 2011-142; s. 78, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>