<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1002.3105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Academically Challenging Curriculum to Enhance Learning (ACCEL) options.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCEL OPTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Academically Challenging Curriculum to Enhance Learning (ACCEL) options are educational options that provide academically challenging curriculum or accelerated instruction to eligible public school students in kindergarten through grade 12.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a minimum, each school must offer the following ACCEL options: whole-grade and midyear promotion; subject-matter acceleration; virtual instruction in higher grade level subjects; and the Credit Acceleration Program under s. 1003.4295. Additional ACCEL options may include, but are not limited to, enriched science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) coursework; enrichment programs; flexible grouping; advanced academic courses; combined classes; self-paced instruction; curriculum compacting; advanced-content instruction; and telescoping curriculum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY AND PROCEDURAL REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Principal determined eligibility requirements.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each principal must establish student eligibility requirements for virtual instruction in higher grade level subjects. Each principal must also establish student eligibility requirements for whole-grade promotion, midyear promotion, and subject-matter acceleration when the promotion or acceleration occurs within the principal’s school.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a school offers enriched STEM coursework, enrichment programs, flexible grouping, advanced academic courses, combined classes, self-paced instruction, curriculum compacting, advanced-content instruction, telescoping curriculum, or an alternative ACCEL option established by the principal, the principal must establish student eligibility requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">School district determined eligibility and procedural requirements.</Font><EmDash />A school district must establish student eligibility requirements and procedural requirements for any whole-grade promotion, midyear promotion, or subject-matter acceleration that would result in a student attending a different school. Student eligibility requirements and procedural requirements established by the school district must be included in the school district’s comprehensive student progression plan under s. 1008.25.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STUDENT ELIGIBILITY CONSIDERATIONS.<EmDash />When establishing student eligibility requirements, principals and school districts must consider, at a minimum:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student’s performance on a locally determined assessment, a statewide assessment, or a statewide, standardized assessment administered pursuant to s. 1008.22.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student’s grade point average.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student’s attendance and conduct record.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations from one or more of the student’s teachers in core-curricula courses as defined in s. 1003.01(14)(a)-(e).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recommendation from a guidance counselor if one is assigned to the school in which the student is enrolled.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCEL REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each principal must inform parents and students of the ACCEL options available at the school and the student eligibility requirements for the ACCEL options established pursuant to paragraph (2)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each principal must establish a process by which a parent may request student participation in whole-grade promotion, midyear promotion, and subject-matter acceleration when the promotion or acceleration occurs within the principal’s school; virtual instruction in higher grade level subjects; or an alternative ACCEL option established by the principal. If the parent selects one of these ACCEL options and the student meets the eligibility requirements established by the principal pursuant to paragraph (2)(a), the student must be provided the opportunity to participate in the ACCEL option.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each school district must establish a process by which a parent may request student participation in whole-grade promotion, midyear promotion, or subject-matter acceleration that would result in a student attending a different school. If the parent selects one of these ACCEL options and the student meets the eligibility and procedural requirements set forth in the district’s comprehensive student progression plan, as required under paragraph (2)(b), the student must be provided the opportunity to participate in the ACCEL option.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a student participates in an ACCEL option pursuant to the parental request under subparagraph (b)1., a performance contract must be executed by the student, the parent, and the principal. At a minimum, the performance contract must require compliance with:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimum student attendance requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimum student conduct requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCEL option requirements established by the principal, which may include participation in extracurricular activities, educational outings, field trips, interscholastic competitions, and other activities related to the ACCEL option selected.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a principal initiates a student’s participation in an ACCEL option, the student’s parent must be notified. A performance contract, pursuant to paragraph (c), is not required when a principal initiates participation but may be used at the discretion of the principal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>