<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1002.455" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Student eligibility for K-12 virtual instruction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student may participate in virtual instruction in the school district in which he or she resides if the student meets the eligibility criteria in subsection (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student is eligible to participate in virtual instruction if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student spent the prior school year in attendance at a public school in the state and was enrolled and reported by the school district for funding during October and February for purposes of the Florida Education Finance Program surveys;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student is a dependent child of a member of the United States Armed Forces who was transferred within the last 12 months to this state from another state or from a foreign country pursuant to a permanent change of station order;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student was enrolled during the prior school year in a virtual instruction program under s. 1002.45, the K-8 Virtual School Program under s. 1002.415, or a full-time Florida Virtual School program under s. 1002.37(8)(a);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student has a sibling who is currently enrolled in a virtual instruction program and the sibling was enrolled in that program at the end of the prior school year; </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student is eligible to enter kindergarten or first grade; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student is eligible to enter grades 2 through 5 and is enrolled full-time in a school district virtual instruction program, virtual charter school, or the Florida Virtual School.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The virtual instruction options for which this eligibility section applies include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School district operated part-time or full-time kindergarten through grade 12 virtual instruction programs under s. 1002.45(1)(b) for students enrolled in the school district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time virtual charter school instruction authorized under s. 1002.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Virtual courses offered in the course code directory to students within the school district or to students in other school districts throughout the state pursuant to s. 1003.498.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2011-137; s. 5, ch. 2012-192.</History>
</Section>