<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1002.57" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prekindergarten director credential.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By July 1, 2006, the department shall adopt minimum standards for a credential for prekindergarten directors of private prekindergarten providers delivering the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program. The credential must encompass requirements for education and onsite experience.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The educational requirements must include training in the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professionally accepted standards for prekindergarten programs, early learning, and strategies and techniques to address the age-appropriate progress of prekindergarten students in attaining the performance standards adopted by the department under s. 1002.67;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strategies that allow students with disabilities and other special needs to derive maximum benefit from the Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program administration and operations, including management, organizational leadership, and financial and legal issues.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prekindergarten director credential must meet or exceed the requirements of the Department of Children and Family Services for the child care facility director credential under s. 402.305(2)(f), and successful completion of the prekindergarten director credential satisfies these requirements for the child care facility director credential.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, to the maximum extent practicable, award credit to a person who successfully completes the child care facility director credential under s. 402.305(2)(f) for those requirements of the prekindergarten director credential which are duplicative of requirements for the child care facility director credential.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-484.</History></Section>