<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1002.321" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Digital learning.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DIGITAL LEARNING NOW ACT.<EmDash />There is created the Digital Learning Now Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELEMENTS OF HIGH-QUALITY DIGITAL LEARNING.<EmDash />The Legislature finds that each student should have access to a high-quality digital learning environment that provides:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Access to digital learning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Access to high-quality digital content and online courses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education that is customized to the needs of the student using digital content.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A means for the student to demonstrate competency in completed coursework.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">High-quality digital content, instructional materials, and online and blended learning courses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">High-quality digital instruction and teachers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Content and instruction that are evaluated on the metric of student learning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of funding as an incentive for performance, options, and innovation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Infrastructure that supports digital learning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Online administration of state assessments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DIGITAL PREPARATION.<EmDash />Each student must graduate from high school having taken at least one online course, as provided in s. 1003.428.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CUSTOMIZED AND ACCELERATED LEARNING.<EmDash />A school district must establish multiple opportunities for student participation in part-time and full-time kindergarten through grade 12 virtual instruction. Options include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School district operated part-time or full-time virtual instruction programs under s. 1002.45(1)(b) for kindergarten through grade 12 students enrolled in the school district. A full-time program shall operate under its own Master School Identification Number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Virtual School instructional services authorized under s. 1002.37.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blended learning instruction provided by charter schools authorized under s. 1002.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time virtual charter school instruction authorized under s. 1002.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses delivered in the traditional school setting by personnel providing direct instruction through virtual instruction or through blended learning courses consisting of both traditional classroom and online instructional techniques pursuant to s. 1003.498.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Virtual courses offered in the course code directory to students within the school district or to students in other school districts throughout the state pursuant to s. 1003.498.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTEGRITY OF ONLINE COURSES.<EmDash />It is unlawful for any person to knowingly and willfully take an online course or examination on behalf of another person for compensation. Any person who violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-137; s. 2, ch. 2012-192.</History>
</Section>