<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1002.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Family and School Partnership for Student Achievement Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the Family and School Partnership for Student Achievement Act is to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide parents with specific information about their child’s educational progress;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide parents with comprehensive information about their choices and opportunities for involvement in their child’s education; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a framework for building and strengthening partnerships among parents, teachers, principals, district school superintendents, and other personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Each district school board, school district superintendent, and teacher shall fully support and cooperate in implementing a well-planned, inclusive, and comprehensive program to assist parents and families in effectively participating in their child’s education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate meaningful parent and family involvement, the Department of Education shall develop guidelines for a parent guide to successful student achievement which describes what parents need to know about their child’s educational progress and how they can help their child to succeed in school. The guidelines shall include, but need not be limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parental information regarding:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for their child to be promoted to the next grade, as provided for in s. 1008.25;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Progress of their child toward achieving state and district expectations for academic proficiency;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessment results, including report cards and progress reports;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifications of their child’s teachers; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School entry requirements, including required immunizations and the recommended immunization schedule;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services available for parents and their children, such as family literacy services; mentoring, tutorial, and other academic reinforcement programs; college planning, academic advisement, and student counseling services; and after-school programs;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Opportunities for parental participation, such as parenting classes, adult education, school advisory councils, and school volunteer programs;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Opportunities for parents to learn about rigorous academic programs that may be available for their child, such as honors programs, dual enrollment, advanced placement, International Baccalaureate, International General Certificate of Secondary Education (pre-AICE), Advanced International Certificate of Education, Florida Virtual High School courses, and accelerated access to postsecondary education;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational choices, as provided for in s. 1002.20(6), and Florida tax credit scholarships, as provided for in s. 1002.395;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Classroom and test accommodations available for students with disabilities;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School board rules, policies, and procedures for student promotion and retention, academic standards, student assessment, courses of study, instructional materials, and contact information for school and district offices; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resources for information on student health and other available resources for parents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall develop and disseminate a checklist for school districts to provide to parents to assist with the parent’s involvement in their child’s educational progress. The checklist shall address parental actions that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strengthen the child’s academic progress, especially in the area of reading;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strengthen the child’s citizenship, especially social skills and respect for others;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strengthen the child’s realization of high expectations and setting lifelong learning goals; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place a strong emphasis on the communication between the school and the home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall establish a parent-response center to provide assistance to parents and families in answering questions and resolving issues related to the child’s education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall adopt rules that strengthen family involvement and family empowerment. The rules shall be developed in collaboration with parents, school administrators, teachers, and community partners, and shall address:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parental choices and responsibilities;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Links with community services;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Opportunities for parental involvement in the development, implementation, and evaluation of family involvement programs; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Opportunities for parents to participate on school advisory councils and in school volunteer programs and other activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the 2003-2004 school year, each school district shall submit a copy of the rules developed under subsection (5) to the Department of Education by October 1.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each school district shall develop and disseminate a parent guide to successful student achievement, consistent with the guidelines of the Department of Education, which addresses what parents need to know about their child’s educational progress and how parents can help their child to succeed in school. The guide must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be understandable to students and parents;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be distributed to all parents, students, and school personnel at the beginning of each school year;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be discussed at the beginning of each school year in meetings of students, parents, and teachers;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include information concerning services, opportunities, choices, academic standards, and student assessment; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information on the importance of student health and available immunizations and vaccinations, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recommended immunization schedule in accordance with United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommendations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Detailed information regarding the causes, symptoms, and transmission of meningococcal disease and the availability, effectiveness, known contraindications, and appropriate age for the administration of any required or recommended vaccine against meningococcal disease, in accordance with the recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The parent guide may be included as a part of the code of student conduct that is required in s. 1006.07(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each school district shall develop and disseminate a checklist of parental actions that can strengthen parental involvement in their child’s educational progress, consistent with the requirements in subsection (3). The checklist shall be provided each school year to all parents of students in kindergarten through grade 12 and shall focus on academics, especially reading, high expectations for students, citizenship, and communication.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall annually review each school district’s compliance with this section and the district’s success in achieving improved services for families. The State Board of Education shall use all appropriate enforcement actions, as provided for in s. 1008.32, until the school district fully complies with the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2003-118; s. 2, ch. 2005-196; s. 1, ch. 2006-246; s. 5, ch. 2009-108; s. 14, ch. 2010-24; s. 3, ch. 2011-103.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 20, ch. 2010-24, provides that “[t]he Department of Revenue is authorized and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54, Florida Statutes, to administer the provisions of this act. The emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the rules are adopted and the rules may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>