<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1002.35" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">New World School of the Arts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The New World School of the Arts is created as a center of excellence for the performing and visual arts, to serve all of the State of Florida. The school shall offer a program of academic and artistic studies in the visual and performing arts which shall be available to talented high school and college students.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of governance, the New World School of the Arts is assigned to Miami Dade College, the Miami-Dade County Public Schools, and one or more universities designated by the State Board of Education. The State Board of Education, in conjunction with the Board of Governors, shall assign to the New World School of the Arts a university partner or partners. In this selection, the State Board of Education and the Board of Governors shall consider the accreditation status of the core programs. Florida International University, in its capacity as the provider of university services to Miami-Dade County, shall be a partner to serve the New World School of the Arts, upon meeting the accreditation criteria. The respective boards shall appoint members to an executive board for administration of the school. The executive board may include community members and shall reflect proportionately the participating institutions. Miami Dade College shall serve as fiscal agent for the school.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The New World School of the Arts Foundation is created for the purpose of providing auxiliary financial support for the school’s programs, including, but not limited to, the promotion and sponsorship of special events and scholarships. Foundation membership shall be determined by the executive board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school may affiliate with other public or private educational or arts institutions. The school shall serve as a professional school for all qualified students within appropriations and limitations established by the Legislature and the respective educational institutions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school shall submit annually a formula-driven budget request to the commissioner and the Legislature. This formula shall be developed in consultation with the Department of Education and staff of the Legislature. However, the actual funding for the school shall be determined by the Legislature in the General Appropriations Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education and the Board of Governors shall utilize resources, programs, and faculty from the various state universities in planning and providing the curriculum and courses at the New World School of the Arts, drawing on program strengths at each state university.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 100, ch. 2002-387; s. 81, ch. 2007-217; s. 176, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>