<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of suspension, revocation upon associated licenses and licensees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the suspension, revocation, or refusal to renew or continue any license or appointment or the eligibility to hold a license or appointment of a bail bond agent or temporary bail bond agent, the department shall at the same time likewise suspend or revoke all other licenses or appointments and the eligibility to hold any other such licenses or appointments which may be held by the licensee under the Florida Insurance Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of the suspension or revocation of the license or appointment, or the eligibility to hold a license or appointment, of any bail bond agent, the license, appointment, or eligibility of any and all bail bond agents who are members of a bail bond agency, whether incorporated or unincorporated, and any and all temporary bail bond agents employed by such bail bond agency, who knowingly are parties to the act which formed the ground for the suspension or revocation may likewise be suspended or revoked.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person whose license as a bail bond agent or temporary bail bond agent has been revoked or suspended shall be employed by any bail bond agent, have any ownership interest in any business involving bail bonds, or have any financial interest of any type in any bail bond business during the period of revocation or suspension.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 61-406; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 177, ch. 70-339; s. 28, ch. 71-86; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 29, 71, 72, ch. 82-175; ss. 50, 51, ch. 84-103; s. 5, ch. 87-321; ss. 37, 46, 47, ch. 90-131; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 38, ch. 96-372; s. 80, ch. 2003-267; s. 71, ch. 2003-281; s. 126, ch. 2005-2; s. 31, ch. 2005-257.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 903.544.</Text></Note></Section>