<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.365" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statistical reporting requirements; penalty for failure to comply.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer and each bail bond agent who writes bail bonds in this state, shall maintain and transmit the following information, based on their Florida bail bond business, to the department or office when requested and shall report the information separately for each company represented but only insurers shall report the information specified in paragraphs (a), (l), and (m):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissions paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, bonds executed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, bonds declared forfeited.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, forfeitures discharged, remitted, or otherwise recovered prior to payment for any reason.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, forfeitures discharged, remitted, or otherwise recovered prior to payment due to the apprehension of the defendant by the bail bond agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, judgments entered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, forfeitures paid and subsequently recovered from the court by discharge or remission or otherwise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of every outstanding or unpaid forfeiture, estreature, and judgment, with the case number and the name of the court in which such forfeiture, estreature, or judgment is recorded and the name of each agency or firm that employs the bail bond agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of, and the total dollar amount of, bonds for which collateral was accepted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actual realized value of collateral converted, excluding the cost of converting the collateral.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of converting collateral.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The underwriting gain or loss.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net investment gain or loss allocated to the flow of funds associated with Florida business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such additional information as the department or office may require in order to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate the reasonableness of rates or assure that such rates are not excessive or unfairly discriminatory.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate the financial condition or trade practices of bail bond agents and sureties executing bail bonds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate the performance of the commercial bail bond industry in accordance with appropriate criminal justice system goals and standards.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Each bail bond agent shall submit a copy of such information to each insurer he or she represents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who intentionally fails to provide the information in this section when requested by the department or office, intentionally provides incorrect or misleading information, or intentionally omits any required information commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 72, ch. 82-175; ss. 14, 50, 51, ch. 84-103; s. 5, ch. 87-321; s. 84, ch. 89-360; ss. 15, 46, 47, ch. 90-131; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 15, ch. 96-372; s. 1656, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>