<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bail bond agents; qualifications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for licensure as a bail bond agent must be submitted on forms prescribed by the department. The application must include the applicant’s full name; date of birth; social security number; residence, business, and mailing addresses; contact telephone numbers, including a business telephone number; and e-mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To qualify as a bail bond agent, it must affirmatively appear at the time of application and throughout the period of licensure that the applicant has complied with the provisions of s. 648.355 and has obtained a temporary license pursuant to such section and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is a natural person who has reached the age of 18 years and holds a high school diploma or its equivalent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is a United States citizen or legal alien who possesses work authorization from the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services and is a resident of this state. An individual who is a resident of this state shall be deemed to meet the residence requirement of this paragraph, notwithstanding the existence, at the time of application for license, of a license in the applicant’s name on the records of another state as a resident licensee of such other state, if the applicant furnishes a letter of clearance satisfactory to the department that his or her resident licenses have been canceled or changed to a nonresident basis and that he or she is in good standing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The place of business of the applicant will be located in this state and in the county where the applicant will maintain his or her records and be actively engaged in the bail bond business and maintain an agency accessible to the public which is open for reasonable business hours.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is vouched for and recommended upon sworn statements filed with the department by at least three reputable citizens who are residents of the same counties in which the applicant proposes to engage in the bail bond business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is a person of high character and approved integrity and has not been convicted of or pleaded guilty or no contest to a felony, a crime involving moral turpitude, or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of any state, territory, or country, whether or not a judgment or conviction has been entered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has passed any required examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may collect a fee necessary to cover the cost of a character and credit report made by an established and reputable independent reporting service. The fee shall be deposited to the credit of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. Any information so furnished is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall furnish, with his or her application, a complete set of his or her fingerprints and a recent credential-sized, fullface photograph of the applicant. The applicant’s fingerprints shall be certified by an authorized law enforcement officer. The department shall not authorize an applicant to take the required examination until the department has received a report from the Department of Law Enforcement and the Federal Bureau of Investigation relative to the existence or nonexistence of a criminal history report based on the applicant’s fingerprints.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct a comprehensive investigation of each applicant, including a background check. The investigation of the applicant’s qualifications, character, experience, background, and fitness shall include submission of the applicant’s fingerprints to the Department of Law Enforcement and the Federal Bureau of Investigation and consideration of any state criminal records, federal criminal records, or local criminal records obtained from these agencies or from local law enforcement agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 112.011 do not apply to bail bond agents or to applicants for licensure as bail bond agents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 29621, 1955; s. 5, ch. 59-326; s. 9, ch. 61-406; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 24, ch. 65-269; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 177, ch. 70-339; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-96; s. 1, ch. 77-116; s. 61, ch. 77-121, s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 71, 72, ch. 82-175; ss. 11, 50, 51, ch. 84-103; s. 5, ch. 87-321; s. 58, ch. 88-166; s. 82, ch. 89-360; ss. 12, 46, 47, ch. 90-131; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-119; s. 11, ch. 96-372; s. 403, ch. 96-406; s. 8, ch. 2002-260; s. 1653, ch. 2003-261; s. 76, ch. 2003-267; s. 67, ch. 2003-281; s. 137, ch. 2004-5; s. 54, ch. 2012-209.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 903.43.</Text></Note></Section>