<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.387" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Primary bail bond agents; duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or operator of a bail bond agency shall designate a primary bail bond agent for each location, and shall file with the department the name and license number of the person and the address of the location on a form approved by the department. The designation of the primary bail bond agent may be changed if the department is notified immediately. Failure to notify the department within 10 working days after such change is grounds for disciplinary action pursuant to s. 648.45.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary bail bond agent is responsible for the overall operation and management of a bail bond agency location, whose responsibilities may include, without limitations, hiring and supervising of all individuals within the location, whether they deal with the public in the solicitation or negotiation of bail bond contracts or in the collection or accounting of moneys. A person may be designated as primary bail bond agent for only one location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may suspend or revoke the license of the owner, operator, and primary bail bond agent if a bail bond agency employs, contracts with, or uses the services of a person who has had a license denied or whose license is currently suspended or revoked. However, a person who has been denied a license for failure to pass a required examination may be employed to perform clerical or administrative functions for which licensure is not required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner, operator, or primary agent may not employ, contract with, or use the services of any person in a bail bond agency who has been charged with, found guilty of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of any jurisdiction, without regard to whether judgment was entered or withheld by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bail bond agency location may not conduct surety business unless a primary bail bond agent is designated at all times. The failure to designate a primary agent on a form prescribed by the department, within 10 working days after an agency’s inception or a change of primary agent, is a violation of this chapter, punishable as provided in s. 648.45.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2002-260.</History></Section>