<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.386" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for prelicensing and continuing education schools and instructors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOOLS AND CURRICULUM FOR PRELICENSING SCHOOLS.<EmDash />In order to be considered for approval and certification as an approved limited surety agent and professional bail bond agent prelicensing school, such entity must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer a minimum of two 120-hour classroom-instruction basic certification courses in the criminal justice system per calendar year unless a reduced number of course offerings per calendar year is warranted in accordance with rules promulgated by the department; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer a department-approved correspondence course pursuant to department rules.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a prelicensing course curriculum to the department for approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, offer prelicensing classes which are taught by instructors approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOOLS AND CURRICULUM FOR CONTINUING EDUCATION SCHOOLS.<EmDash />In order to be considered for approval and certification as an approved limited surety agent and professional bail bond agent continuing education school, such entity must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a minimum of three continuing education classes per calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a course curriculum to the department for approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer continuing education classes which are comprised of a minimum of 2 hours of approved coursework and are taught by an approved supervising instructor or guest lecturer approved by the entity or the supervising instructor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GEOGRAPHIC REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />Any provider approved under this section by the department to offer prelicensing courses or continuing education courses shall be required to offer such courses in at least two geographic areas of the state until such time that the department determines that there are adequate providers statewide to provide these courses to applicants and licensees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INSTRUCTOR’S DUTIES AND QUALIFICATIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each course must have a supervising instructor who is approved by the department. The supervising instructor shall be present at all classes. The supervising instructor is responsible for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All course instructors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All guest lecturers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The course outlines and curriculum.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification of each attending limited surety agent or professional bail bond agent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of all required forms.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assuring that the course is approved.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Either the entity or the supervising instructor may approve guest lecturers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to obtain department approval as a supervising instructor, the following qualifications must be met:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the past 15 years, the person must have had at least 10 years’ experience as a manager or officer of a managing general agent in this state as prescribed in s. 648.388;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the past 15 years, the person must have had at least 10 years’ experience as a manager or officer of an insurance company authorized to and actively engaged in underwriting bail in this state, provided there is a showing that the manager’s or officer’s experience is directly related to the bail bond industry; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has been a licensed bail bond agent in this state for at least 10 years.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to obtain department approval as an instructor or guest lecturer, the person must be qualified by education or experience in the specific area of instruction as prescribed by department rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person teaching any approved course of instruction or lecturing at any approved seminar and attending the entire course or seminar shall qualify for the same number of classroom hours as would be granted to a person taking and successfully completing such course, seminar, or program. Credit shall be limited to the number of hours actually taught unless a person attends the entire course or seminar.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules necessary to carry out the duties conferred upon it under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 96-372; s. 1, ch. 99-303; s. 16, ch. 2002-260; s. 1657, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>