<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0648.382" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of bail bond agents and temporary bail bond agents; effective date of appointment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer appointing a bail bond agent and each insurer, managing general agent, or bail bond agent appointing a temporary bail bond agent in this state must file the appointment with the department and, at the same time, pay the applicable appointment fees and taxes. A person appointed under this section must hold a valid bail bond agent’s or temporary bail bond agent’s license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to any appointment, an appropriate officer or official of the appointing insurer in the case of a bail bond agent or an insurer, managing general agent, or bail bond agent in the case of a temporary bail bond agent must submit:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified statement or affidavit to the department stating what investigation has been made concerning the proposed appointee and the proposed appointee’s background and the appointing person’s opinion to the best of his or her knowledge and belief as to the moral character and reputation of the proposed appointee. In lieu of such certified statement or affidavit, by authorizing the effectuation of an appointment for a licensee, the appointing entity certifies to the department that such investigation has been made and that the results of the investigation and the appointing person’s opinion is that the proposed appointee is a person of good moral character and reputation and is fit to engage in the bail bond business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit under oath on a form prescribed by the department, signed by the proposed appointee, stating that premiums are not owed to any insurer and that the appointee will discharge all outstanding forfeitures and judgments on bonds previously written. If the appointee does not satisfy or discharge such forfeitures or judgments, the former insurer shall file a notice, with supporting documents, with the appointing insurer, the former agent, and the department, stating under oath that the licensee has failed to timely satisfy forfeitures and judgments on bonds written and that the insurer has satisfied the forfeiture or judgment from its own funds. Upon receipt of such notification and supporting documents, the appointing insurer shall immediately cancel the licensee’s appointment. The licensee may be reappointed only upon certification by the former insurer that all forfeitures and judgments on bonds written by the licensee have been discharged. The appointing insurer or former agent may, within 10 days, file a petition with the department seeking relief from this paragraph. Filing of the petition stays the duty of the appointing insurer to cancel the appointment until the department grants or denies the petition; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information that the department reasonably requires concerning the proposed appointee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By authorizing the effectuation of an appointment for a licensee, the appointing insurer certifies to the department that the insurer will be bound by the acts of the bail bond agent acting within the scope of his or her appointment, and, in the case of a temporary bail bond agent, the appointing insurer, managing general agent, or bail bond agent, as the case may be, must certify to the department that he or she will supervise the temporary bail bond agent’s activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointing insurer, managing general agent, or bail bond agent must advise the department in writing within 5 days after receiving notice or learning that an appointee has been arrested for, pled guilty or nolo contendere to, or been found guilty of, a felony or other offense punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of any jurisdiction, whether judgment was entered or withheld by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of current appointments must be submitted to the department each month but in no case later than 45 days after the date of appointment. All appointments are effective as of the date indicated on the appointment form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to notify the department within the required time period shall result in the appointing entity being assessed a delinquent fee of $250. Delinquent fees shall be paid by the appointing entity and shall not be charged to the appointee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 19, 47, ch. 90-131; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 19, ch. 96-372; s. 12, ch. 2002-260; s. 78, ch. 2003-267; s. 69, ch. 2003-281.</History></Section>