<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0129.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budget of supervisor of elections; matters related to allocation, expenditure, etc., of amounts in budget.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall requisition and the board of county commissioners shall pay that officer, at the first meeting in October of each year, 25 percent of the total amount budgeted for the office and, thereafter on the first of each month, 6.82 percent of the total amount budgeted for the office. However, if there are unusual or unanticipated expenses in any one month, upon notification by the supervisor of elections, the board shall transfer the necessary amount, except that the total amount paid during the year shall not, without appropriate amendments, exceed the total budgeted for the year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriation shall be transferred into a special account set up in the name of the supervisor of elections, and the clerk of the court acting as the clerk of the board of county commissioners shall draw checks or warrants thereon for payment of all expenses requisitioned by the supervisor of elections. All salaries shall be supported by payrolls, and all expenses paid shall be supported with bills approved by the supervisor of elections. Should the supervisor of elections desire, he or she may have the monthly allocation for the office of the supervisor of elections deposited directly into an official bank or depository trust account for the supervisor of elections and draw his or her own checks thereon for payment of budgeted expenditures authorized by law. All fees, commissions, and other funds collected by the supervisor of elections shall be deposited directly into the supervisor of elections’ special account established under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regardless of whether the supervisor of elections draws checks or warrants for the office of the supervisor of elections or allows the clerk to handle that function, the supervisor of elections may have a revolving petty cash fund established for payment of small cash outlay items by cash, check, or warrant. The revolving petty cash fund shall be reimbursed from time to time upon the presentation of vouchers and receipts substantiating disbursements from the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the supervisor of elections draws the checks or warrants for the office of the supervisor of elections, he or she shall keep the necessary budget accounts and records and shall charge all paid bills and payrolls to the proper budget accounts. If the clerk draws the checks for the office of the supervisor of elections, this responsibility shall remain with the clerk. A reserve for contingencies, or any part thereof, may be transferred to any of the budget accounts in the discretion of the supervisor of elections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All expenses incurred in the fiscal year for which the budget is made shall be vouchered and charged to the budget for that year. To carry out the purpose of this budgeting provision, the books may be held open for 30 days after the end of the year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All unexpended balances at the end of each fiscal year shall be refunded to the board of county commissioners and deposited to the county fund or funds from which payment was originally made.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The independence of the supervisor of elections shall be preserved concerning the purchase of supplies and equipment; the selection of personnel; and the hiring, firing, and setting of salaries of such personnel; however, nothing herein contained shall restrict the operation of any lawfully established county civil service system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 82-202; s. 39, ch. 83-217; s. 830, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>