<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0324.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice to department; notice to insurer.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each owner and operator involved in a crash or conviction case within the purview of this chapter shall furnish evidence of automobile liability insurance, motor vehicle liability insurance, or a surety bond within 14 days after the date of the mailing of notice of crash by the department in the form and manner as it may designate. Upon receipt of evidence that an automobile liability policy, motor vehicle liability policy, or surety bond was in effect at the time of the crash or conviction case, the department shall forward by United States mail, postage prepaid, to the insurer or surety insurer a copy of such information and shall assume that the policy or bond was in effect, unless the insurer or surety insurer notifies the department otherwise within 20 days after the mailing of the notice to the insurer or surety insurer. However, if the department later determines that an automobile liability policy, motor vehicle liability policy, or surety bond was not in effect and did not provide coverage for both the owner and the operator, it shall take action as it is otherwise authorized to do under this chapter. Proof of mailing to the insurer or surety insurer may be made by the department by naming the insurer or surety insurer to whom the mailing was made and by specifying the time, place, and manner of mailing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer doing business in this state shall immediately give notice to the department of each motor vehicle liability policy when issued to effect the return of a license which has been suspended under s. 324.051(2); and said notice shall be upon such form and in such manner as the department may designate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29963, 1955; s. 3, ch. 65-122; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 306, ch. 99-248; s. 66, ch. 2012-181.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 324.08.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>