<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Treasurer; depositories; fiscal agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall designate an individual who is a resident of the state, or a qualified public depository as defined in s. 280.02, as treasurer of Space Florida, who shall have charge of the funds of Space Florida. Such funds shall be disbursed only upon the order of or pursuant to the resolution of the board by warrant, check, authorization, or direct deposit pursuant to s. 215.85, signed or authorized by the treasurer or his or her representative or by such other persons as may be authorized by the board. The board may give the treasurer such other or additional powers and duties as the board may deem appropriate and shall establish the treasurer’s compensation. The board may require the treasurer to give a bond in such amount, on such terms, and with such sureties as may be deemed satisfactory to the board to secure the performance by the treasurer of his or her powers and duties. The board shall audit or have audited the books of the treasurer at least once a year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to select as depositories in which the funds of the board and of Space Florida shall be deposited any qualified public depository as defined in s. 280.02, upon such terms and conditions as to the payment of interest by such depository upon the funds so deposited as the board may deem just and reasonable. The funds of Space Florida may be kept in or removed from the State Treasury upon written notification from the chair of the board to the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may employ a fiscal agent, who shall be either a resident of the state or a corporation organized under the laws of this or any other state and authorized by such laws to act as such fiscal agent in the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 7, 8, ch. 90-192; s. 4, ch. 91-265; s. 478, ch. 95-148; s. 20, ch. 98-409; s. 17, ch. 99-256; s. 368, ch. 2003-261; s. 9, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>