<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0331.3051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of Space Florida.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create a business plan to foster the growth and development of the aerospace industry. The business plan must address business development, finance, spaceport operations, research and development, workforce development, and education. The business plan must be completed by March 1, 2007, and be revised when determined as necessary by the board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreement with the Department of Education, the Department of Transportation, Enterprise Florida, Inc., and Workforce Florida, Inc., for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with Enterprise Florida, Inc., develop a plan to retain, expand, attract, and create aerospace industry entities, public or private, which results in the creation of high-value-added businesses and jobs in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create a marketing campaign to help attract, develop, and retain aerospace businesses, aerospace research and technology, and other related activities in this state. Space Florida shall attempt to coordinate the campaign with existing economic development promotion efforts in this state and may use private resources. Marketing strategies may include developing promotional materials, Internet and print advertising, public relations and media placement, trade show attendance, and other activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consult with Enterprise Florida, Inc., in developing a space tourism marketing plan. Space Florida and Enterprise Florida, Inc., may enter into a mutually beneficial agreement that provides funding to Enterprise Florida, Inc., for its services to implement this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, in cooperation with Enterprise Florida, Inc., a plan to provide financing assistance to aerospace businesses. The plan may include the following activities:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assembling, publishing, and disseminating information concerning financing opportunities and techniques for aerospace projects, programs, and activities; sources of public and private aerospace financing assistance; and sources of aerospace-related financing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizing, hosting, and participating in seminars and other forums designed to disseminate information and technical assistance regarding aerospace-related financing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinating with programs and goals of the Department of Defense, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the International Trade Administration of the United States Department of Commerce, the Foreign Credit Insurance Association, and other private and public programs and organizations, domestic and foreign.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a network of contacts among those domestic and foreign public and private organizations that provide information, technical assistance, and financial support to the aerospace industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financing aerospace business development projects or initiatives using funds provided by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out its responsibilities for spaceport operations by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seeking federal support and developing partnerships to renew and upgrade the infrastructure and technologies at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, the John F. Kennedy Space Center, and the Eastern Range that will enhance space and military programs of the Federal Government, and improve access for commercial launch activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supporting federal efforts to clarify roles and responsibilities of federal agencies and eliminate duplicative federal rules and policies, in an effort to streamline access for commercial launch users.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuing the development of commercial spaceports in the state, in addition to those defined in s. 331.304, through a competitive request for proposals in partnership with counties or municipalities, the Federal Government, or private entities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting and facilitating launch activity within the state by supporting and assisting commercial launch operators in completing and submitting required documentation and gaining approvals and authorization from the required federal agencies for launching from Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consulting, as necessary, with the appropriate federal, state, and local authorities, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Department of Defense, the Department of Transportation, the Florida National Guard, and industry on all aspects of establishing and operating spaceport infrastructure and related facilities within the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out its responsibility for research and development by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracting for the operations of the state’s Space Life Sciences Laboratory.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Working in collaboration with one or more public or private universities and other public or private entities to develop a proposal for a Center of Excellence for Aerospace that will foster and promote the research necessary to develop commercially promising, advanced, and innovative science and technology and will transfer those discoveries to the commercial sector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out its responsibility for workforce development by coordinating with Workforce Florida, Inc., community colleges, colleges, public and private universities, and other public and private partners to develop a plan to retain, train, and retrain workers, from entry-level skills training through to technician-level, and 4-year degrees and higher, with the skills most relevant to aerospace employers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out its responsibility for creating innovative education programs by funding programs developed in conjunction with the Department of Education that target grades K-20 in an effort to promote mathematics and science education programs, which may include the Florida-NASA Matching Grant Program, aerospace-focused education programs for teachers, education-oriented microgravity flight programs for teachers and students, and Internet-based aerospace education. Funds appropriated and any in-kind or private sector contributions may be used to carry out innovative education programs. Funding levels shall be determined by the Space Florida board of directors. In its annual report, Space Florida shall include, at a minimum, a description of programs funded, the number of students served, and private sector support.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually report on its performance with respect to its business plan, to include finance, spaceport operations, research and development, workforce development, and education. The report shall be submitted to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives no later than September 1 for the prior fiscal year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2006-60; s. 235, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>