<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.329" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Changing boundary lines; annexation and exclusion of lands; creation of municipalities within the geographical limits of any spaceport territory; limitations on the furnishing of services within annexed areas.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may at any time strike out or correct the description of any land within or claimed to be within the boundary lines of any spaceport territory upon the written consent of the owners of all the land that would be included or excluded from the boundary lines of any spaceport territory or otherwise affected by the taking of such action, and of the owners of not less than the majority in acreage of all lands within any spaceport territory.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enlarge the geographical limits of any spaceport territory to include any lands not then within any spaceport territory:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the written consent of the owners of all the land to be included in any spaceport territory and of the owners of not less than a majority in acreage of all the land then within any spaceport territory; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By resolution of the board approved at a special election called for such purpose, by vote of a majority of freeholders residing within the area to be annexed and a majority of freeholders residing within any spaceport territory.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may contract the geographical limits of any spaceport territory so as to exclude from any spaceport territory any land then within any spaceport territory:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the written consent of the owners of all the land to be so excluded and of the owners of not less than a majority in acreage of all the land then within any spaceport territory; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By resolution of the board approved at a special election called for such purpose, by vote of a majority of freeholders residing within the area to be excluded and a majority of the freeholders residing within any spaceport territory.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land, including property situated thereon, added to any spaceport territory in the manner provided in subsection (1) shall from the time of its inclusion within such spaceport territory be subject to all assessments thereafter levied and assessed on all other land or property of any spaceport territory similarly situated. Land, including property situated thereon, excluded from any spaceport territory in the manner provided in subsection (1) shall from the date of such exclusion be exempt from assessments thereafter imposed by Space Florida but shall not be exempt from assessments theretofore levied or due with respect to such land or property, or from subsequent installments of assessments theretofore levied or assessed with respect thereto, and such assessments may be enforced and collected by or on behalf of Space Florida in the same manner as if such land or property continued to be within the geographical limits of any spaceport territory.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the geographical limits of any spaceport territory as set forth in s. 331.304 are revised so as to include within any spaceport territory any areas not presently contained within any spaceport territory, Space Florida may not engage in the business of furnishing electric power for sale in such annexed area, unless Space Florida shall offer to purchase from any person who is at the time engaged in the business of making, generating, or distributing electricity for sale within such annexed area, such portion of its electric plant and property suitable and used for such business in connection therewith as lies within the limits of such annexed area, in a manner consistent with law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall designate new launch pads outside the present designated spaceport territories by statutory amendment of s. 331.304.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 33, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 7, 8, ch. 90-192; s. 28, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>