<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.3101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Space Florida; travel and entertainment expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 112.061, Space Florida shall adopt rules by which it may make expenditures by advancement or reimbursement, or a combination thereof, to Space Florida officers and employees; reimburse business clients, guests, and authorized persons as defined in s. 112.061(2)(e); and make direct payments to third-party vendors:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For travel expenses of such business clients, guests, and authorized persons incurred by Space Florida in connection with the performance of its statutory duties, and for travel expenses incurred by state officials and state employees while accompanying such business clients, guests, or authorized persons or when authorized by the board or its designee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For entertainment expenses of such guests, business clients, and authorized persons incurred by Space Florida in connection with the performance of its statutory duties, and for entertainment expenses incurred for Space Florida officials and employees when such expenses are incurred while in the physical presence of such business clients, guests, or authorized persons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules shall be subject to approval by the Chief Financial Officer before adoption. The rules shall require the submission of paid receipts, or other proof prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer, with any claim for reimbursement, and shall require, as a condition for any advancement, an agreement to submit paid receipts or other proof and to refund any unused portion of the advancement within 15 days after the expense is incurred or, if the advancement is made in connection with travel, within 15 days after completion of the travel. However, with respect to an advancement made solely for travel expenses, the rules may allow paid receipts or other proof to be submitted, and any unused portion of the advancement to be refunded, within 30 days after completion of the travel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual report shall be made to the Legislature not later than November 30 of each year for the previous fiscal year, which shall consist of a synopsis concisely summarizing all travel, entertainment, and incidental expenses incurred within the United States and, separately, all travel, entertainment, and incidental expenses incurred outside the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim submitted under this section is not required to be sworn to before a notary public or other officer authorized to administer oaths, but any claim authorized or required to be made under any provision of this section must contain a statement that the expenses were actually incurred as necessary travel or entertainment expenses in the performance of official duties of Space Florida and shall be verified by written declaration that it is true and correct as to every material matter. Any person who willfully makes and subscribes to any such claim which the person does not believe to be true and correct as to every material matter or who willfully aids or assists in, or procures, counsels, or advises, the preparation or presentation of a claim pursuant to this section, which claim is fraudulent or false as to any material matter, whether or not such falsity or fraud is with the knowledge or consent of the person authorized or required to present such claim, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Whoever receives an advancement or reimbursement by means of a false claim is civilly liable, in the amount of the overpayment, for the reimbursement of the public fund from which the claim was paid.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-361; s. 37, ch. 91-201; s. 247, ch. 91-224; s. 479, ch. 95-148; s. 15, ch. 2002-183; s. 369, ch. 2003-261; s. 11, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>