<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.360" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joint participation agreement or assistance; spaceport master plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty, function, and responsibility of the Department of Transportation to promote the further development and improvement of aerospace transportation facilities; to address intermodal requirements and impacts of the launch ranges, spaceports, and other space transportation facilities; to assist in the development of joint-use facilities and technology that support aviation and aerospace operations; to coordinate and cooperate in the development of spaceport infrastructure and related transportation facilities contained in the Strategic Intermodal System Plan; to encourage, where appropriate, the cooperation and integration of airports and spaceports in order to meet transportation-related needs; and to facilitate and promote cooperative efforts between federal and state government entities to improve space transportation capacity and efficiency. In carrying out this duty and responsibility, the department may assist and advise, cooperate with, and coordinate with federal, state, local, or private organizations and individuals. The department may administratively house its space transportation responsibilities within an existing division or office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department of Transportation may enter into a joint participation agreement with, or otherwise assist, Space Florida as necessary to effectuate the provisions of this chapter and may allocate funds for such purposes in its 5-year work program. However, the department may not fund the administrative or operational costs of Space Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall develop a spaceport master plan for expansion and modernization of space transportation facilities within spaceport territories as defined in s. 331.303. The plan shall contain recommended projects to meet current and future commercial, national, and state space transportation requirements. Space Florida shall submit the plan to any appropriate metropolitan planning organization for review of intermodal impacts. Space Florida shall submit the spaceport master plan to the Department of Transportation, and such plan may be included within the department’s 5-year work program of qualifying aerospace discretionary capacity improvement under subsection (4). The plan shall identify appropriate funding levels and include recommendations on appropriate sources of revenue that may be developed to contribute to the State Transportation Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, the department may participate in the capital cost of eligible spaceport discretionary capacity improvement projects. The annual legislative budget request shall be based on the proposed funding requested for approved spaceport discretionary capacity improvement projects.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 65, ch. 93-164; s. 4, ch. 99-256; s. 17, ch. 2002-183; s. 48, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>