<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0331.369" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Space Industry Workforce Initiative.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the aerospace industry is critical to the economic future of the state and that the competitiveness of the industry in the state depends upon the development and maintenance of a qualified workforce. The Legislature further finds that the aerospace industry in this state has diverse and complex workforce needs, including, but not limited to, the need for qualified entry-level workers, the need to upgrade the skills of technician-level incumbent workers, and the need to ensure continuing education opportunities for workers with advanced educational degrees. It is the intent of the Legislature to support programs designed to address the workforce development needs of the aerospace industry in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall coordinate development of a Space Industry Workforce Initiative in partnership with Space Florida, public and private universities, community colleges, and other training providers approved by the board. The purpose of the initiative is to use or revise existing programs and to develop innovative new programs to address the workforce needs of the aerospace industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initiative shall emphasize:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Curricula content and timeframes developed with industry participation and endorsed by the industry;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Programs that certify persons completing training as meeting industry-approved standards or competencies;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of distance-learning and computer-based training modules as appropriate and feasible;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industry solicitation of public and private universities to develop continuing education programs at the master’s and doctoral levels;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agreements with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to replicate on a national level successful training programs developed through the initiative; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leveraging of state and federal workforce funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., with the assistance of Space Florida, shall convene representatives from the aerospace industry to identify the priority training and education needs of the industry and to appoint a team to design programs to meet the priority needs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., as part of its statutorily prescribed annual report to the Legislature, shall provide recommendations for policies, programs, and funding to enhance the workforce needs of the aerospace industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2000-290; s. 49, ch. 2006-60; s. 18, ch. 2011-213.</History>
</Section>