<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.340" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorization and form of bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be authorized by resolution or resolutions of the board which shall be adopted by a majority of all of the members thereof then in office and present at the meeting at which the resolution or resolutions are adopted and shall be approved as provided in s. 331.305. The resolution or resolutions of the board may be adopted at the same meeting at which they are introduced, and shall be published and noticed. The board may by resolution authorize the issuance of bonds, fix the aggregate amount of bonds to be issued, the purpose or purposes for which the moneys derived therefrom shall be expanded, the rate or rates of interest, the denomination of the bonds, whether or not the bonds are to be issued in one or more series, the date or dates thereof, the date or dates of maturity, which shall not exceed 40 years from their respective dates of issuance, the medium of payment, the place or places within or without the state where payment shall be made, registration privileges, redemption terms and privileges (whether with or without premium), the manner of execution, the form of the bonds including any interest coupons to be attached thereto, the manner of execution of bonds and coupons, and any and all other terms, covenants, and conditions thereof, and the establishment of reserve or other funds. Such authorizing resolution may further provide that such bonds may be executed manually or by engraved, lithographed, or facsimile signature, provided that where signatures are engraved, lithographed, or facsimile no bond shall be valid unless countersigned by a registrar or other officer designated by appropriate resolution of the board. The seal of Space Florida may be affixed, lithographed, engraved, or otherwise reproduced in facsimile on such bonds. In case any officer whose signature or a facsimile of whose signature shall appear on any bonds or coupons shall cease to be such officer before the delivery of such bonds, such signature or facsimile shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if the officer had remained in office until such delivery.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 44, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 7, 8, ch. 90-192; s. 480, ch. 95-148; s. 37, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>