<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.350" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance coverage of Space Florida; safety program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the State Risk Management Trust Fund established under s. 284.30 may not insure buildings and property owned or leased by Space Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the State Risk Management Trust Fund established under s. 284.30 may not insure against any liability of Space Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall establish a safety program. The safety program shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development and implementation of a loss prevention program which shall consist of a comprehensive safety program for all of Space Florida, including a statement, established by the board of directors, of safety policy and responsibility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision for regular and periodic facility and equipment inspections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigation of job-related employee accidents and other accidents occurring on the premises of Space Florida or within areas of its jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a program to promote increased safety awareness among employees, agents, and subcontractors of Space Florida.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall, if available, secure insurance coverage within reasonable limits for liability which may arise as a consequence of its responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida shall, if available, and if cost-effective, secure insurance coverage on its buildings, facilities, and property at reasonable levels.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Space Florida, with respect to the purchase of insurance, shall be subject to the applicable provisions of chapter 287 and other applicable law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 54, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 7, 8, ch. 90-192; s. 64, ch. 96-418; s. 20, ch. 2000-122; s. 44, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>