<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0331.323" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperative agreements with the state, counties, and municipalities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state and the counties, municipalities, and other political subdivisions, public bodies, and agencies thereof, or any of them, whether now existing or hereafter created, are authorized to aid and cooperate with Space Florida in carrying out any of the purposes and projects of Space Florida, to enter into cooperative agreements with Space Florida, to provide in any such cooperative agreement for the making of loans, gifts, grants, or contributions to Space Florida and the granting and conveyance to Space Florida of real or personal property of any kind or nature, or any interest therein, for the carrying out of the purpose and projects of Space Florida; to covenant in any such cooperative agreement to pay all or any part of the costs of acquisition, planning, development, construction, reconstruction, extension, improvement, operation, and maintenance of any projects of Space Florida; and to pay all or any part of the principal and interest on any bonds of Space Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state and the counties, municipalities, and other political subdivisions, public bodies, and agencies thereof, or any of them, whether now existing or hereafter created, and Space Florida, are further authorized to enter into cooperative agreements to provide for the furnishing by Space Florida to the state or any county, municipality, or other political subdivision, public body, or agency thereof of any of the facilities and services of Space Florida, or by the state or any county, municipality, or other political subdivision, public body, or agency thereof to Space Florida and to persons within the spaceport territory of facilities and services of the type that Space Florida is authorized to furnish or undertake, or such other facilities and services as may be determined necessary or desirable by the board for the carrying out of the purposes of this act. Without limitation of the foregoing, such cooperative agreements may provide for the furnishing by any county, municipality, or other political subdivision of fire and police protection for Space Florida and persons and property within Space Florida, and for the providing to Space Florida of any services deemed necessary or desirable by the board for the proper functioning of Space Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without limitation of the foregoing, the board may undertake and finance any of the projects of Space Florida, in whole or in part, jointly with any municipality or municipalities, now existing or hereafter created, or in any other manner combine the projects of Space Florida with the projects of such municipality or municipalities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agreement of the type authorized by this section may be made and entered into under this act for such time or times, not exceeding 40 years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 23, 61, ch. 89-300; ss. 7, 8, ch. 90-192; s. 22, ch. 2006-60.</History></Section>