<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for discretionary refusal, suspension, or revocation of certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny, suspend, or revoke the provisional certificate of authority or the certificate of authority of any applicant or provider if it finds that any one or more of the following grounds applicable to the applicant or provider exist:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by the provider to continue to meet the requirements for the authority originally granted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by the provider to meet one or more of the qualifications for the authority specified by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material misstatement, misrepresentation, or fraud in obtaining the authority, or in attempting to obtain the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of fitness or trustworthiness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practices of management in the conduct of business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation, conversion, or withholding of moneys.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with, or violation of, any proper order or rule of the office or commission or violation of any provision of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insolvent condition of the provider or the provider’s being in such condition or using such methods and practices in the conduct of its business as to render its further transactions in this state hazardous or injurious to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal by the provider to be examined or to produce its accounts, records, and files for examination, or refusal by any of its officers to give information with respect to its affairs or to perform any other legal obligation under this chapter when required by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by the provider to comply with the requirements of s. 651.026 or s. 651.033.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by the provider to maintain escrow accounts or funds as required by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by the provider to meet the requirements of this chapter for disclosure of information to residents concerning the facility, its ownership, its management, its development, or its financial condition or failure to honor its continuing care or continuing care at-home contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any cause for which issuance of the license could have been refused had it then existed and been known to the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been found guilty of, or having pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to, a felony in this state or any other state, without regard to whether a judgment or conviction has been entered by the court having jurisdiction of such cases.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the conduct of business under the license, engaging in unfair methods of competition or in unfair or deceptive acts or practices prohibited under part IX of chapter 626.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pattern of bankrupt enterprises.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Revocation of a certificate of authority under this section does not relieve a provider from the provider’s obligation to residents under the terms and conditions of any continuing care or continuing care at-home contract between the provider and residents or the provisions of this chapter. The provider shall continue to file its annual statement and pay license fees to the office as required under this chapter as if the certificate of authority had continued in full force, but the provider shall not issue any new contracts. The office may seek an action in the circuit court of Leon County to enforce the office’s order and the provisions of this section.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 18, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 37, ch. 85-62; s. 7, ch. 86-209; s. 11, ch. 91-98; s. 12, ch. 93-22; s. 18, ch. 97-229; s. 12, ch. 2001-64; s. 1685, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2011-193.</History></Section>