<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0651.0235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Validity of provisional certificates of authority and certificates of authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisional certificate of authority and certificate of authority shall be valid for as long as the office determines that the provider continues to meet the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the provider fails to meet the requirements of this chapter for a provisional certificate of authority or a certificate of authority, the office may notify the provider of any deficiencies and require the provider to correct such deficiencies within a period to be determined by the office. If such deficiencies are not corrected within 20 days after the notice to the provider, or within less time at the discretion of the office, the office shall notify the Continuing Care Advisory Council, which may assist the facility in formulating a remedial plan to be submitted to the office within 60 days after the date of notification. The time period for correcting the deficiencies may be extended upon submission of a plan for corrective action approved by the office. If such deficiencies have not been cleared by the expiration of such time period, as extended, the office shall petition for a delinquency proceeding or pursue such other relief as provided under this chapter, as the circumstances may require.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall notify the Agency for Health Care Administration of any facility for which a provisional certificate of authority or certificate of authority is no longer valid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 9, ch. 87-136; s. 12, ch. 93-22; s. 6, ch. 97-229; s. 1672, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2010-202.</History>
</Section>