<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advertising” means the dissemination of written, visual, or electronic information by a provider, or any person affiliated with or controlled by a provider, to potential residents or their representatives for the purpose of inducing such persons to subscribe to or enter into a contract for continuing care or continuing care at-home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Continuing care” or “care” means, pursuant to a contract, furnishing shelter and nursing care or personal services to a resident who resides in a facility, whether such nursing care or personal services are provided in the facility or in another setting designated in the contract for continuing care, by an individual not related by consanguinity or affinity to the resident, upon payment of an entrance fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Continuing Care Advisory Council” or “advisory council” means the council established in s. 651.121.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Continuing care at-home” means, pursuant to a contract other than a contract described in subsection (2), furnishing to a resident who resides outside the facility the right to future access to shelter and nursing care or personal services, whether such services are provided in the facility or in another setting designated in the contract, by an individual not related by consanguinity or affinity to the resident, upon payment of an entrance fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Entrance fee” means an initial or deferred payment of a sum of money or property made as full or partial payment for continuing care or continuing care at-home. An accommodation fee, admission fee, member fee, or other fee of similar form and application are considered to be an entrance fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facility” means a place where continuing care is furnished and may include one or more physical plants on a primary or contiguous site or an immediately accessible site. As used in this subsection, the term “immediately accessible site” means a parcel of real property separated by a reasonable distance from the facility as measured along public thoroughfares, and the term “primary or contiguous site” means the real property contemplated in the feasibility study required by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Generally accepted accounting principles” means those accounting principles and practices adopted by the Financial Accounting Standards Board and the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants, including Statement of Position 90-8 with respect to any full year to which the statement applies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insolvency” means the condition in which the provider is unable to pay its obligations as they come due in the normal course of business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed” means that the provider has obtained a certificate of authority from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nursing care” means those services or acts rendered to a resident by an individual licensed or certified pursuant to chapter 464.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal services” has the same meaning as in s. 429.02.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Provider” means the owner or operator, whether a natural person, partnership or other unincorporated association, however organized, trust, or corporation, of an institution, building, residence, or other place, whether operated for profit or not, which owner or operator provides continuing care or continuing care at-home for a fixed or variable fee, or for any other remuneration of any type, whether fixed or variable, for the period of care, payable in a lump sum or lump sum and monthly maintenance charges or in installments. The term does not apply to an entity that has existed and continuously operated a facility located on at least 63 acres in this state providing residential lodging to members and their spouses for at least 66 years on or before July 1, 1989, and has the residential capacity of 500 persons, is directly or indirectly owned or operated by a nationally recognized fraternal organization, is not open to the public, and accepts only its members and their spouses as residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Records” means the permanent financial, directory, and personnel information and data maintained by a provider pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a purchaser of, a nominee of, or a subscriber to a continuing care or continuing care at-home contract. Such contract does not give the resident a part ownership of the facility in which the resident is to reside, unless expressly provided in the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Shelter” means an independent living unit, room, apartment, cottage, villa, personal care unit, nursing bed, or other living area within a facility set aside for the exclusive use of one or more identified residents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; s. 170, ch. 79-164; ss. 1, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 1, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 1, ch. 91-98; s. 33, ch. 91-263; s. 12, ch. 93-22; s. 36, ch. 93-216; s. 2, ch. 96-363; s. 12, ch. 97-82; s. 1, ch. 97-229; s. 1662, ch. 2003-261; s. 99, ch. 2006-197; s. 1, ch. 2010-202; s. 1, ch. 2011-193.</History></Section>