<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum liquid reserve requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider shall maintain in escrow a minimum liquid reserve consisting of the following reserves, as applicable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each provider shall maintain in escrow as a debt service reserve the aggregate amount of all principal and interest payments due during the fiscal year on any mortgage loan or other long-term financing of the facility, including property taxes as recorded in the audited financial statements required under s. 651.026. The amount must include any leasehold payments and all costs related to such payments. If principal payments are not due during the fiscal year, the provider shall maintain in escrow as a minimum liquid reserve an amount equal to interest payments due during the next 12 months on any mortgage loan or other long-term financing of the facility, including property taxes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider that has outstanding indebtedness that requires a debt service reserve to be held in escrow pursuant to a trust indenture or mortgage lien on the facility and for which the debt service reserve may only be used to pay principal and interest payments on the debt that the debtor is obligated to pay, and which may include property taxes and insurance, may include such debt service reserve in computing the minimum liquid reserve needed to satisfy this subsection if the provider furnishes to the office a copy of the agreement under which such debt service is held, together with a statement of the amount being held in escrow for the debt service reserve, certified by the lender or trustee and the provider to be correct. The trustee shall provide the office with any information concerning the debt service reserve account upon request of the provider or the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each provider shall maintain in escrow an operating reserve equal to 30 percent of the total operating expenses projected in the feasibility study required by s. 651.023 for the first 12 months of operation. Thereafter, each provider shall maintain in escrow an operating reserve equal to 15 percent of the total operating expenses in the annual report filed pursuant to s. 651.026. If a provider has been in operation for more than 12 months, the total annual operating expenses shall be determined by averaging the total annual operating expenses reported to the office by the number of annual reports filed with the office within the preceding 3-year period subject to adjustment if there is a change in the number of facilities owned. For purposes of this subsection, total annual operating expenses include all expenses of the facility except: depreciation and amortization; interest and property taxes included in paragraph (a); extraordinary expenses that are adequately explained and documented in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles; liability insurance premiums in excess of those paid in calendar year 1999; and changes in the obligation to provide future services to current residents. For providers initially licensed during or after calendar year 1999, liability insurance shall be included in the total operating expenses in an amount not to exceed the premium paid during the first 12 months of facility operation. Beginning January 1, 1993, the operating reserves required under this subsection shall be in an unencumbered account held in escrow for the benefit of the residents. Such funds may not be encumbered or subject to any liens or charges by the escrow agent or judgments, garnishments, or creditors’ claims against the provider or facility. However, if a facility had a lien, mortgage, trust indenture, or similar debt instrument in place before January 1, 1993, which encumbered all or any part of the reserves required by this subsection and such funds were used to meet the requirements of this subsection, then such arrangement may be continued, unless a refinancing or acquisition has occurred, and the provider shall be in compliance with this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each provider shall maintain in escrow a renewal and replacement reserve equal to 15 percent of the total accumulated depreciation based on the audited financial statement required to be filed pursuant to s. 651.026, not to exceed 15 percent of the facility’s average operating expenses for the past 3 fiscal years based on the audited financial statements for each of those years. For a provider who is an operator of a facility but is not the owner and depreciation is not included as part of the provider’s financial statement, the renewal and replacement reserve required by this paragraph must equal 15 percent of the total operating expenses of the provider, as described in this section. Each provider licensed before October 1, 1983, shall fully fund the renewal and replacement reserve by October 1, 2003, by multiplying the difference between the former escrow requirement and the present escrow requirement by the number of years the facility has been in operation after October 1, 1983.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In facilities where not all residents are under continuing care or continuing care at-home contracts, the reserve requirements of subsection (1) shall be computed only with respect to the proportional share of operating expenses that are applicable to residents. For purposes of this calculation, the proportional share shall be based upon the ratio of residents under continuing care or continuing care at-home contracts to those residents who do not hold such contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In facilities that have voluntarily and permanently discontinued marketing continuing care and continuing care at-home contracts, the office may allow a reduced debt service reserve as required in subsection (1) based upon the ratio of residents under continuing care or continuing care at-home contracts to those residents who do not hold such contracts if the office finds that such reduction is not inconsistent with the security protections intended by this chapter. In making this determination, the office may consider such factors as the financial condition of the facility, the provisions of outstanding continuing care and continuing care at-home contracts, the ratio of residents under continuing care or continuing care at-home contracts to those residents who do not hold such contracts, the current occupancy rates, the previous sales and marketing efforts, the life expectancy of the remaining residents, and the written policies of the board of directors of the provider or a similar board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If principal and interest payments are paid to a trust that is beneficially held by the residents as described in s. 651.023(7), the office may waive all or any portion of the escrow requirements for mortgage principal and interest contained in subsection (1) if the office finds that such waiver is not inconsistent with the security protections intended by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office, upon approval of a plan for fulfilling the requirements of this section and upon demonstration by the facility of an annual increase in liquid reserves, may extend the time for compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider may satisfy the minimum liquid reserve requirements of this section by acquiring from a financial institution, as specified in paragraph (b), a clean, unconditional irrevocable letter of credit equal to the requirements of this section.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The letter of credit must be issued by a financial institution participating in the State of Florida Treasury Certificate of Deposit Program, and must be approved by the office before issuance and before any renewal or modification thereof. At a minimum, the letter of credit must provide for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ninety days’ prior written notice to both the provider and the office of the financial institution’s determination not to renew or extend the term of the letter of credit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise arranged by the provider to the satisfaction of the office, deposit by the financial institution of letter of credit funds in an account designated by the office no later than 30 days before the expiration of the letter of credit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deposit by the financial institution of letter of credit funds in an account designated by the office within 4 business days following written instructions from the office that, in the sole judgment of the office, funding of the minimum liquid reserve is required.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms of the letter of credit must be approved by the office and the long-term debt of the financial institution providing such letter of credit must be rated in one of their top three long-term debt rating categories by either Moody’s Investors Service, Standard &amp; Poor’s Corporation, or a recognized securities rating agency acceptable to the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The letter of credit must name the office as beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a provider using a letter of credit pursuant to this subsection shall, at all times, have and maintain in escrow an operating cash reserve equal to 2 months’ operating expenses as determined pursuant to s. 651.026.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the issuing financial institution no longer participates in the State of Florida Treasury Certificate of Deposit Program, such financial institution shall deposit as collateral with the department eligible securities, as prescribed by s. 625.52, having a market value equal to or greater than 100 percent of the stated amount of the letter of credit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each fiscal year, a provider may withdraw up to 33 percent of the total renewal and replacement reserve available. The reserve available is equal to the market value of the invested reserves at the end of the provider’s prior fiscal year. The withdrawal must be used for capital items or major repairs.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any funds are eligible for withdrawal, the provider must obtain written permission from the office by submitting the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the withdrawal and the intended use of the proceeds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board resolution and sworn affidavit signed by two officers or general partners of the provider which indicates approval of the withdrawal and use of the funds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that the provider has met all funding requirements for the operating, debt service, and renewal and replacement reserves computed for the previous fiscal year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anticipated payment schedule for refunding the renewal and replacement reserve fund.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the withdrawal of funds, the provider must begin refunding the reserve account in equal monthly payments that allow for a complete funding of the withdrawal within 36 months. If the payment schedule required under subparagraph (a)4. has changed, the provider must update the office with the new payment schedule. If the provider fails to make a required monthly payment or the payment is late, the provider must notify the office within 5 days after the due date of the payment. No additional withdrawals from the renewal and replacement reserve will be allowed until all scheduled payments are current.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; ss. 7, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 8, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 53, ch. 85-321; s. 4, ch. 86-209; s. 7, ch. 87-136; s. 5, ch. 89-363; s. 7, ch. 91-98; s. 184, ch. 91-108; ss. 5, 12, ch. 93-22; s. 9, ch. 97-229; s. 3, ch. 2002-222; s. 1677, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2006-202; s. 7, ch. 2010-202; s. 8, ch. 2011-193.</History></Section>