<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requests for inspections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interested party may request an inspection of the records and related financial affairs of a provider providing care in accordance with the provisions of this chapter by transmitting to the office notice of an alleged violation of applicable requirements prescribed by statute or by rule, specifying to a reasonable extent the details of the alleged violation, which notice shall be signed by the complainant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The substance of the complaint shall be given to the provider no earlier than the time of the inspection. Unless the complainant specifically requests otherwise, neither the substance of the complaint which is provided to the provider nor any copy of the complaint or any record which is published, released, or otherwise made available to the provider shall disclose the name of any person mentioned in the complaint except the name of any duly authorized officer, employee, or agent of the office conducting the investigation or inspection pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a complaint, the office shall make a preliminary review; and, unless the office determines that the complaint is without any reasonable basis, the office shall make an inspection. The complainant shall be advised, within 30 days after the receipt of the complaint by the office, of the proposed course of action of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provider operating under a certificate of authority under this chapter may discriminate or retaliate in any manner against a resident or an employee of a facility providing care because such resident or employee or any other person has initiated a complaint pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; ss. 18, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 19, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 12, ch. 93-22; s. 21, ch. 97-229; s. 1689, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>