<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0651.085" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Quarterly meetings between residents and the governing body of the provider; resident representation before the governing body of the provider.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a provider, or the designated representative of the provider, shall hold quarterly meetings with the residents of the continuing care facility for the purpose of free discussion of subjects including, but not limited to, income, expenditures, and financial trends and problems as they apply to the facility, as well as a discussion on proposed changes in policies, programs, and services. At quarterly meetings where monthly maintenance fee increases are discussed, a summary of the reasons for raising the fee as specified in subsection (4) must be provided in writing to the president or chair of the residents’ council. Upon request of the residents’ council, a member of the governing body of the provider, such as a board member, general partner, principal owner, or designated representative shall attend such meetings. Residents are entitled to at least 7 days’ advance notice of each quarterly meeting. An agenda and any materials that will be distributed by the governing body or representative of the provider shall be posted in a conspicuous place at the facility and shall be available upon request to residents of the facility. The office shall request verification from a facility that quarterly meetings are held and open to all residents if it receives a complaint from the residents’ council that a facility is not in compliance with this subsection. In addition, a facility shall report to the office in the annual report required under s. 651.026 the dates on which quarterly meetings were held during the reporting period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A residents’ council formed pursuant to s. 651.081, members of which are elected by the residents, may designate a resident to represent them before the governing body of the provider or organize a meeting or ballot election of the residents to determine whether to elect a resident to represent them before the governing body of the provider. If a residents’ council does not exist, any resident may organize a meeting or ballot election of the residents of the facility to determine whether to elect a resident to represent them before the governing body and, if applicable, elect the representative. The residents’ council, or the resident that organizes a meeting or ballot election to elect a representative, shall give all residents notice at least 10 business days before the meeting or election. Notice may be given through internal mailboxes, communitywide newsletters, bulletin boards, in-house television stations, and other similar means of communication. An election of the representative is valid if at least 40 percent of the total resident population participates in the election and a majority of the participants vote affirmatively for the representative. The initial designated representative elected under this section shall be elected to serve at least 12 months.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designated representative shall be notified at least 14 days in advance of any meeting of the full governing body at which proposed changes in resident fees or services will be discussed. The representative shall be invited to attend and participate in that portion of the meeting designated for the discussion of such changes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a quarterly meeting prior to the implementation of any increase in the monthly maintenance fee, the designated representative of the provider must provide the reasons, by department cost centers, for any increase in the fee that exceeds the most recently published Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, all items, Class A Areas of the Southern Region. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as placing a cap or limitation on the amount of any increase in the monthly maintenance fee, establishing a presumption of the appropriateness of the Consumer Price Index as the basis for any increase in the monthly maintenance fee, or limiting or restricting the right of a provider to establish or set monthly maintenance fee increases.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; s. 252, ch. 79-400; ss. 11, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 14, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 1, ch. 92-56; ss. 7, 12, ch. 93-22; s. 4, ch. 2003-120; s. 1681, ch. 2003-261; s. 11, ch. 2010-202.</History>
</Section>