<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Availability, distribution, and posting of reports and records; requirement of full disclosure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each continuing care facility shall maintain as public information, available upon request, records of all cost and inspection reports pertaining to that facility which have been filed with or issued by any governmental agency. A copy of each report shall be retained for at least 5 years after the date the report is filed or issued. Each facility shall also maintain as public information, available upon request, all annual statements that have been filed with the office. For purposes of this section, a management company or operator is considered an agent of the provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every continuing care facility shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display the certificate of authority in a conspicuous place inside the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Post in a prominent position in the facility which is accessible to all residents and the general public a concise summary of the last examination report issued by the office, with references to the page numbers of the full report noting any deficiencies found by the office, and the actions taken by the provider to rectify such deficiencies, indicating in such summary where the full report may be inspected in the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Post in a prominent position in the facility which is accessible to all residents and the general public a summary of the latest annual statement, indicating in the summary where the full annual statement may be inspected in the facility. A listing of any proposed changes in policies, programs, and services must also be posted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribute a copy of the full annual statement to the president or chair of the residents’ council within 30 days after filing the annual report with the office, and designate a staff person to provide explanation thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the residents’ council of any plans filed with the office to obtain new financing, additional financing, or refinancing for the facility and of any applications to the office for any expansion of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver to the president or chair of the residents’ council a summary of entrance fees collected and refunds made during the time period covered in the annual report and the refund balances due at the end of the report period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver to the president or chair of the residents’ council a copy of each quarterly statement within 30 days after the quarterly statement is filed with the office if the facility is required to file quarterly.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, deliver to the president or chair of the residents’ council a copy of any newly approved continuing care or continuing care at-home contract within 30 days after approval by the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before entering into a contract to furnish continuing care or continuing care at-home, the provider undertaking to furnish the care, or the agent of the provider, shall make full disclosure, and provide copies of the disclosure documents to the prospective resident or his or her legal representative, of the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract to furnish continuing care or continuing care at-home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summary listed in paragraph (2)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All ownership interests and lease agreements, including information specified in s. 651.022(2)(b)8.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In keeping with the intent of this subsection relating to disclosure, the provider shall make available for review master plans approved by the provider’s governing board and any plans for expansion or phased development, to the extent that the availability of such plans does not put at risk real estate, financing, acquisition, negotiations, or other implementation of operational plans and thus jeopardize the success of negotiations, operations, and development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the rules and regulations of the facility and an explanation of the responsibilities of the resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy of the facility with respect to admission to and discharge from the various levels of health care offered by the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and location of any reserve funds required by this chapter, and the name of the person or entity having a claim to such funds in the event of a bankruptcy, foreclosure, or rehabilitation proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of s. 651.071.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the resident’s rights as described in s. 651.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A true and complete copy of the full disclosure document to be used must be filed with the office before use. A resident or prospective resident or his or her legal representative may inspect the full reports referred to in paragraph (2)(b); the charter or other agreement or instrument required to be filed with the office pursuant to s. 651.022(2), together with all amendments thereto; and the bylaws of the corporation or association, if any. Upon request, copies of the reports and information shall be provided to the individual requesting them if the individual agrees to pay a reasonable charge to cover copying costs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; ss. 12, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 15, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 10, ch. 91-98; s. 34, ch. 91-263; ss. 8, 12, ch. 93-22; s. 2, ch. 93-79; s. 513, ch. 97-102; s. 15, ch. 97-229; s. 1682, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2010-202; s. 12, ch. 2011-193.</History></Section>