<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of authority required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may engage in the business of providing continuing care, issuing contracts for continuing care or continuing care at-home, or constructing a facility for the purpose of providing continuing care in this state without a certificate of authority obtained from the office as provided in this chapter. This subsection does not prohibit the preparation of a construction site or construction of a model residence unit for marketing purposes, or both. The office may allow the purchase of an existing building for the purpose of providing continuing care if the office determines that the purchase is not being made to circumvent the prohibitions in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written approval must be obtained from the office before commencing construction or marketing for an expansion of a certificated facility equivalent to the addition of at least 20 percent of existing units or 20 percent or more in the number of continuing care at-home contracts. This provision does not apply to construction for which a certificate of need from the Agency for Health Care Administration is required.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For providers that offer both continuing care and continuing care at-home, the 20 percent is based on the total of both existing units and existing contracts for continuing care at-home. For purposes of this subsection, an expansion includes increases in the number of constructed units or continuing care at-home contracts or a combination of both.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for such approval shall be on forms adopted by the commission and provided by the office. The application must include the feasibility study required by s. 651.022(3) or s. 651.023(1)(b) and such other information as required by s. 651.023. If the expansion is only for continuing care at-home contracts, an actuarial study prepared by an independent actuary in accordance with standards adopted by the American Academy of Actuaries which presents the financial impact of the expansion may be substituted for the feasibility study.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether an expansion should be approved, the office shall use the criteria provided in ss. 651.022(6) and 651.023(4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-323; ss. 3, 25, ch. 81-292; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 3, 31, 33, 35, ch. 83-328; s. 1, ch. 86-209; s. 1, ch. 89-363; ss. 1, 12, ch. 93-22; s. 275, ch. 99-8; s. 1669, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2011-193.</History></Section>