<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0651.119" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistance to persons affected by closure due to liquidation or pending liquidation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a facility closes and ceases to operate as a result of liquidation or pending liquidation and residents are forced to relocate, the department shall become a creditor of the facility for the purpose of providing moving expenses for displaced residents and such other care or services as is made possible by the unencumbered assets of the facility. To the extent that another provider provides, as approved by the office, direct assistance to such residents, the cost of such direct assistance shall be offset against reserves pursuant to subsection (4). The department shall provide proportional reimbursements of such costs to the respective providers from such unencumbered assets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the moneys and direct assistance made available under subsection (1) are not sufficient to cover moving costs, the office may seek voluntary contributions from the reserves maintained by providers under s. 651.035 in amounts approved by the office to provide for the moving expenses of the residents in moving to another residence within the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the moneys and direct assistance provided under subsections (1) and (2) are not sufficient to provide for the moving expenses of displaced residents in moving to other residences within the state, the office may levy pro rata assessments on the reserves of providers maintained under s. 651.035 for such moving expenses of any displaced resident who lacks sufficient assets to pay for such moving expenses. The assessments for such moving expenses on any particular provider may not exceed for any 12-month period an aggregate of 1 percent of the unencumbered portion of the reserves maintained by the provider under s. 651.035. If the office determines that payment of an assessment under this subsection would impair the financial standing of a facility or its residents, the office may waive or temporarily defer all or part of the assessment with respect to that provider. The office shall apply any moneys voluntarily paid by a provider under subsection (1) or subsection (2) to satisfaction of assessments under this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall permanently reduce the reserves required of a provider under s. 651.035 to the extent of the provider’s costs under subsection (1), voluntary contributions under subsection (2), and assessments under subsection (3). However, the office shall thereafter raise the reserve requirements of a provider to the extent of reimbursements paid to the provider under subsection (1) unless such increase would raise the reserve requirement above the amount required under s. 651.035.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No payment, contribution, or assessment may be paid by a provider under this section if the release of funds from the reserves of the provider would violate a bond or lending commitment or covenant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys received under this section for the support of residents shall be kept in a separate fund maintained and administered by the department. The Continuing Care Advisory Council shall monitor the collection and use of such funds and shall advise the office or department on plans for resident relocation. The council shall seek the assistance of providers licensed under this chapter and other service providers in locating alternative housing and care arrangements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “moving expenses” means transportation expenses and the cost of packing and relocating personal belongings.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 14, 16, ch. 91-98; ss. 6, 9, ch. 92-56; s. 12, ch. 93-22; s. 1694, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>