<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0272.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Historic Capitol Curator.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The position of Capitol Curator is created within the Legislature, which shall establish the qualifications for the position. The curator shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Capitol Curator shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and encourage throughout the state knowledge and appreciation of the Florida Historic Capitol.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect, research, exhibit, interpret, preserve, and protect the history, artifacts, objects, furnishings, and other materials related to the Florida Historic Capitol, except for archaeological research and resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, direct, supervise, and maintain the interior design and furnishings of all space within the Florida Historic Capitol in a manner consistent with the restoration of the Florida Historic Capitol in its 1902 form.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with the Legislative Research Center and Museum at the Historic Capitol, the Capitol Curator may assist the Florida Historic Capitol in the performance of its mission by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Raising money;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting requests for and receiving grants;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receiving, holding, investing, and administering in the name of the Historic Capitol and the Legislative Research Center and Museum securities, funds, objects of value, or other real and personal property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receiving gifts and donations for the direct or indirect benefit of the Historic Capitol; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making expenditures to or for the direct or indirect benefit of the Historic Capitol.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 81-232; s. 6, ch. 2006-111; s. 2, ch. 2009-179.</History></Section>