<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0272.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Parking areas within Capitol Center area.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services may assign parking areas within the Capitol Center area to a state agency for its own use or for reassignment to state officers and employees employed in Tallahassee; however, parking areas must be provided for members of the Legislature during sessions of the Legislature, regular and extraordinary. Not more than 15 percent of said parking areas may be set aside for the use of persons temporarily visiting or attending to business in the Capitol Center area who reside beyond the territorial limits of the City of Tallahassee. Any remaining portion of the parking areas not assigned as aforesaid may be limited in period of time for use. However, the Department of Management Services shall have no power to assign parking spaces in the legislative office buildings, nor shall those spaces and spaces in the parking facility within the Capitol Building which are allocated to the Legislature be included under the provisions of this section and s. 272.161(1), except as provided in subsection (2) of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The presiding officer of each house of the Legislature shall be responsible for the assignment of parking spaces in its respective office building.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parking areas so assigned, or so limited in use, shall be clearly marked, and any violation of the same shall constitute a violation of this chapter and may be punished as if it constituted a violation of a municipal ordinance of the City of Tallahassee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall adopt such rules as are necessary to carry out the purposes of subsections (1) and (3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 29840, 1955; ss. 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-34; s. 2, ch. 75-70; s. 1, ch. 80-225; s. 54, ch. 85-349; s. 211, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 55, ch. 98-279.</History></Section>