<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0272.185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maintenance of Governor’s Mansion by Department of Management Services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall maintain all structures, furnishings, equipment, and grounds of the Governor’s Mansion, except that the exterior facades; the landscaping of the grounds; the antique furnishings in the private quarters; the interiors of the state rooms; and the articles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects used or displayed in the state rooms shall be maintained pursuant to the directives of the Governor’s Mansion Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall insure the Governor’s Mansion, its contents, and all structures and appurtenances thereto with the State Risk Management Trust Fund as provided in s. 284.01. The department may purchase any necessary insurance either by a primary insurance contract, excess coverage insurance, or reinsurance to cover the contents of the mansion, whether title of the contents is in the state or in any other person or entity not a resident of the mansion, notwithstanding the provision of s. 287.025.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have authority to contract and be contracted with for work and materials required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall keep a continuing and accurate inventory of all equipment and furnishings.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 57-61; s. 1, ch. 61-30; ss. 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 78, ch. 71-377; s. 2, ch. 75-70; s. 2, ch. 81-13; s. 1, ch. 81-316; s. 56, ch. 85-349; s. 214, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 59, ch. 96-418; s. 56, ch. 98-279; s. 26, ch. 99-399; s. 8, ch. 2000-122.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 272.18(2), (3).</Text></Note></Section>