<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0272.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Capitol Center Planning District.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created the Florida Capitol Center Planning District, which may be referred to in this chapter as “Capitol Center” or “district.” The district shall extend to and include all lands within the following boundaries of the City of Tallahassee: Commence at the northwest corner of Lot 293 of the Old Plan of the City of Tallahassee as recorded in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court, Leon County, Florida; thence east along the south right-of-way line of West College Avenue and East College Avenue to its intersection with the west right-of-way line of Franklin Boulevard; thence south along said right-of-way line of Franklin Boulevard to its intersection with the south right-of-way line of East Jefferson Street; thence east along said right-of-way line of East Jefferson Street and the east prolongation of East Jefferson Street to its intersection with the west right-of-way line of the Seaboard Coastline Railroad; thence southerly and westerly along said Seaboard Coastline Railroad right-of-way line to a point of intersection with the south prolongation of the east right-of-way line of South Martin Luther King, Jr. Boulevard; thence north along said south prolongation of the east right-of-way line of South Martin Luther King, Jr. Boulevard and along the east right-of-way line of South Martin Luther King, Jr. Boulevard to the point of beginning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services is hereby authorized to purchase at fair market value any lands or buildings owned by the Department of Transportation within the Capitol Center. The Department of Management Services may use for this purpose any funds which are available to it at the time of the purchase.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29840, 1955; s. 1, ch. 63-28; ss. 22, 23, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 2, 4, 5, ch. 72-13; s. 2, ch. 75-70; s. 17, ch. 78-95; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-214; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 81-12; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 50, ch. 85-349; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 88-13; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 206, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 184, ch. 95-148; s. 51, ch. 98-279; s. 19, ch. 2001-89.</History></Section>