<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0272.136" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Direct-support organization.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislative Research Center and Museum at the Historic Capitol and the Capitol Curator may establish a direct-support organization to provide assistance and promotional support through fundraising for the Florida Historic Capitol and the Legislative Research Center and Museum, including, but not limited to, their educational programs and initiatives.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization shall be governed by a board of directors who have demonstrated a capacity for supporting the mission of the Historic Capitol.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial appointments to the board shall be made by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives at the recommendation of the center and the curator. Appointments to the board shall thereafter be made by the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial board shall consist of nine members who shall be appointed to 3-year terms, except that the terms of the initial appointees shall be accomplished so that three members are appointed for 1 year, three members are appointed for 2 years, and three members are appointed for 3 years, in order to achieve staggered terms, as determined by the presiding officers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may add up to two additional members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board members shall serve without compensation, except that they are entitled to receive reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses in accordance with s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may use the fixed property and facilities of the Historic Capitol, subject to the provisions of this subsection. Such use must be directly in keeping with the approved purposes of the direct-support organization and may not be made at times or places that would unreasonably interfere with the normal operations of the Historic Capitol.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization must be a Florida corporation, not for profit, incorporated under chapter 617, and approved by the Department of State.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The curator and center may prescribe any condition with which the direct-support organization must comply.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The curator and the center may not permit the use of any fixed property or facilities by the direct-support organization if the organization does not provide equal membership and employment opportunities to all persons regardless of race, color, religion, gender, age, or national origin.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization shall provide for an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the direct-support organization is no longer authorized by this section, fails to comply with the requirements of this section, fails to maintain its tax-exempt status pursuant to s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, or ceases to exist, all funds obtained through grants, gifts, and donations in the direct-support organization account shall revert to the state and be deposited into an account designated by the Legislature for the support of the Historic Capitol, provided that donations made for specific purposes in an original donor agreement shall be applied only to those purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of a donor or prospective donor to the direct-support organization who desires to remain anonymous and all information identifying such donor or prospective donor is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. Such anonymity shall be maintained in any auditor’s report created pursuant to the annual financial audit required under subsection (5).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2017, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2009-179; s. 1, ch. 2012-11.</History>
</Section>