<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0806.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal mischief; penalties; penalty for minor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits the offense of criminal mischief if he or she willfully and maliciously injures or damages by any means any real or personal property belonging to another, including, but not limited to, the placement of graffiti thereon or other acts of vandalism thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the damage to such property is $200 or less, it is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the damage to such property is greater than $200 but less than $1,000, it is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the damage is $1,000 or greater, or if there is interruption or impairment of a business operation or public communication, transportation, supply of water, gas or power, or other public service which costs $1,000 or more in labor and supplies to restore, it is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person has one or more previous convictions for violating this subsection, the offense under subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2. for which the person is charged shall be reclassified as a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and maliciously defaces, injures, or damages by any means any church, synagogue, mosque, or other place of worship, or any religious article contained therein, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the damage to the property is greater than $200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever, without the consent of the owner thereof, willfully destroys or substantially damages any public telephone, or telephone cables, wires, fixtures, antennas, amplifiers, or any other apparatus, equipment, or appliances, which destruction or damage renders a public telephone inoperative or which opens the body of a public telephone, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084; provided, however, that a conspicuous notice of the provisions of this subsection and the penalties provided is posted on or near the destroyed or damaged instrument and visible to the public at the time of the commission of the offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and maliciously defaces, injures, or damages by any means a sexually violent predator detention or commitment facility, as defined in part V of chapter 394, or any property contained therein, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the damage to property is greater than $200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amounts of value of damage to property owned by separate persons, if the property was damaged during one scheme or course of conduct, may be aggregated in determining the grade of the offense under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section may, in addition to any other criminal penalty, be required to pay for the damages caused by such offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section when the violation is related to the placement of graffiti shall, in addition to any other criminal penalty, be required to pay a fine of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than $250 for a first conviction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than $500 for a second conviction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than $1,000 for a third or subsequent conviction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person convicted under this section when the offense is related to the placement of graffiti shall, in addition to any other criminal penalty, be required to perform at least 40 hours of community service and, if possible, perform at least 100 hours of community service that involves the removal of graffiti.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a minor commits a delinquent act prohibited under paragraph (a), the parent or legal guardian of the minor is liable along with the minor for payment of the fine. The court may decline to order a person to pay a fine under paragraph (a) if the court finds that the person is indigent and does not have the ability to pay the fine or if the court finds that the person does not have the ability to pay the fine whether or not the person is indigent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided by law, if a minor is found to have committed a delinquent act under this section for placing graffiti on any public property or private property, and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor is eligible by reason of age for a driver’s license or driving privilege, the court shall direct the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to revoke or withhold issuance of the minor’s driver’s license or driving privilege for not more than 1 year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor’s driver’s license or driving privilege is under suspension or revocation for any reason, the court shall direct the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to extend the period of suspension or revocation by an additional period of not more than 1 year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor is ineligible by reason of age for a driver’s license or driving privilege, the court shall direct the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to withhold issuance of the minor’s driver’s license or driving privilege for not more than 1 year after the date on which he or she would otherwise have become eligible.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor whose driver’s license or driving privilege is revoked, suspended, or withheld under subsection (7) may elect to reduce the period of revocation, suspension, or withholding by performing community service at the rate of 1 day for each hour of community service performed. In addition, if the court determines that due to a family hardship, the minor’s driver’s license or driving privilege is necessary for employment or medical purposes of the minor or a member of the minor’s family, the court shall order the minor to perform community service and reduce the period of revocation, suspension, or withholding at the rate of 1 day for each hour of community service performed. As used in this subsection, the term “community service” means cleaning graffiti from public property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because of the difficulty of confronting the blight of graffiti, it is the intent of the Legislature that municipalities and counties not be preempted by state law from establishing ordinances that prohibit the marking of graffiti or other graffiti-related offenses. Furthermore, as related to graffiti, such municipalities and counties are not preempted by state law from establishing higher penalties than those provided by state law and mandatory penalties when state law provides discretionary penalties. Such higher and mandatory penalties include fines that do not exceed the amount specified in ss. 125.69 and 162.21, community service, restitution, and forfeiture. Upon a finding that a juvenile has violated a graffiti-related ordinance, a court acting under chapter 985 may not provide a disposition of the case which is less severe than any mandatory penalty prescribed by municipal or county ordinance for such violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 74-383; s. 20, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 82-21; s. 1, ch. 86-281; s. 1, ch. 88-273; s. 183, ch. 91-224; s. 1, ch. 95-164; s. 1231, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 98-93; s. 1, ch. 98-415; s. 5, ch. 2001-244; s. 117, ch. 2002-1; s. 1, ch. 2002-163.</History></Section>