<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0806.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Arson.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and unlawfully, or while in the commission of any felony, by fire or explosion, damages or causes to be damaged:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dwelling, whether occupied or not, or its contents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any structure, or contents thereof, where persons are normally present, such as: jails, prisons, or detention centers; hospitals, nursing homes, or other health care facilities; department stores, office buildings, business establishments, churches, or educational institutions during normal hours of occupancy; or other similar structures; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other structure that he or she knew or had reasonable grounds to believe was occupied by a human being,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of arson in the first degree, which constitutes a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and unlawfully, or while in the commission of any felony, by fire or explosion, damages or causes to be damaged any structure, whether the property of himself or herself or another, under any circumstances not referred to in subsection (1), is guilty of arson in the second degree, which constitutes a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, “structure” means any building of any kind, any enclosed area with a roof over it, any real property and appurtenances thereto, any tent or other portable building, and any vehicle, vessel, watercraft, or aircraft.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 15603, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 7208(8), (9); ss. 786, 787, ch. 71-136; s. 26, ch. 74-383; s. 18, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 79-108; s. 1, ch. 90-225; s. 1228, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>