<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.017" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Children of servicemembers who died or became disabled in the Lebanon and Grenada military arenas; educational opportunity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is hereby declared to be the policy of the state to provide educational opportunity at state expense for the dependent children of any servicemember who died or suffered a service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation as determined by the Veterans Administration, or who has been determined to have a service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent and is in receipt of disability retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services, while participating in a Multinational Peace Keeping Force in Lebanon during the period from September 17, 1982, through February 3, 1984, inclusive, or as a participant in Operation Urgent Fury in Grenada during the period from October 23, 1983, through November 2, 1983, inclusive, which servicemember was residing in the state during those periods of military action. A certified copy of a death certificate, a valid identification card issued in accordance with the provisions of s. 295.17, a letter certifying the service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation from the Veterans Administration, or a letter certifying the service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent for retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services shall be prima facie evidence of the fact that the dependent children of the servicemember are eligible for such benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 295.03, 295.04, 295.05, and 1009.40 shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-177; s. 13, ch. 87-356; s. 28, ch. 89-207; s. 245, ch. 95-148; s. 951, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>