<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigation; administrative hearing for not employing preferred applicant.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Veterans’ Affairs or its designee shall, upon the written request of any person specified in s. 295.07, investigate any complaint filed with the department by such person when the person has applied to any state agency or any agency of a political subdivision in the state for a position of employment which was awarded to a nonveteran and the person feels aggrieved under this chapter. The Department of Veterans’ Affairs shall review each case and may issue an opinion to the Public Employees Relations Commission as to the merit or lack of merit in each case. The investigation must be accomplished within existing amounts appropriated to the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon completion of the investigation, the department shall furnish a copy of the investigative findings to the complainant and to the agency involved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a satisfactory resolution to the complaint is not forthcoming, any department of the state or political subdivision in the state may testify telephonically or in person at the discretion of the Public Employees Relations Commission. The complainant, however, may be represented at the hearing by counsel of his or her choice at his or her expense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jurisdiction to effectuate the purposes of ss. 295.07-295.09 shall vest with the Public Employees Relations Commission for appropriate administrative determination. If, upon preliminary review of the Public Employees Relations Commission, the commission agrees with the department’s determination that a case lacks merit and finds, in its discretion, that there was a complete absence of justiciable issues of either law or fact raised by the veterans’ preference complaint, the Public Employees Relations Commission shall dismiss the complaint without the necessity of holding a hearing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 24201, 1947; ss. 18, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 77-422; s. 4, ch. 78-372; s. 33, ch. 79-190; s. 4, ch. 80-370; s. 79, ch. 86-163; s. 8, ch. 87-356; s. 23, ch. 88-290; s. 113, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 251, ch. 95-148; s. 6, ch. 98-33; s. 82, ch. 99-13.</History></Section>