<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identification cards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Veterans’ Affairs may issue an identification card to any veteran who is a permanent resident of the state and who has been adjudged by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor to have a 100-percent, service-connected permanent and total disability rating for compensation, or who has been determined to have a service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent and is in receipt of disability retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services, upon the written request of such veteran. Such card may be used by the veteran as proof of eligibility for any benefit provided by state law for 100-percent, service-connected permanently and totally disabled veterans except those benefits provided by ss. 196.081, 196.091, and 196.24. The identification card shall bear a statement that it is unlawful for any person other than the veteran to whom it was issued to use the card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is responsible for design and content of the identification card and shall adopt rules and procedures relating to the eligibility and application for and issuance and control of identification cards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display, cause or permit to be displayed, or have in his or her possession any fictitious, fraudulently altered, or fraudulently obtained identification card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lend his or her identification card to any person or knowingly permit the use thereof by another.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display or represent any identification card which has not been issued to the person as being his or her card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit any unlawful use of an identification card issued to him or her.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photograph, photostat, duplicate, or in any way reproduce any identification card or facsimile thereof in such a manner that the photograph, photostat, duplicate, reproduction, or facsimile could be mistaken for a valid identification card or display or have in his or her possession any such photograph, photostat, duplicate, reproduction, or facsimile.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display or cause or permit to be displayed his or her identification card after such card has expired.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of subsection (2) is guilty of a noncriminal violation and shall be punished by a fine of $200.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-61; s. 31, ch. 81-167; s. 31, ch. 83-55; s. 14, ch. 87-356; s. 26, ch. 88-290; s. 10, ch. 93-268; s. 254, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 97-14.</History></Section>