<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.0185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Children of deceased or disabled military personnel who die or become disabled in Operation Enduring Freedom or Operation Iraqi Freedom; educational opportunity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared to be the policy of the state to provide educational opportunity at state expense for the dependent children of those military personnel who die or suffer a service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation as determined by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, or who are determined to have a service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent and are in receipt of disability retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services, while participating in Operation Enduring Freedom, which began on October 7, 2001, or while participating in Operation Iraqi Freedom, which began on March 19, 2003, if such military personnel have been residents of the state during the period of military action. A certified copy of a death certificate, a valid identification card issued in accordance with the provisions of s. 295.17, a letter certifying the service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation from the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, or a letter certifying the service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent for retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services is prima facie evidence that the dependent children of such military personnel are eligible for educational benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 295.03, 295.04, 295.05, and 1009.40 apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-279; s. 25, ch. 2003-1; s. 2, ch. 2005-127.</History></Section>