<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reinstatement or reemployment; promotion preference.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an employee of the state or any of its political subdivisions employed in a position subject or not subject to a career service system or other merit-type system, with the exception of those positions which are exempt pursuant to s. 295.07(4), has served in the Armed Forces of the United States and is discharged or separated therefrom with an honorable discharge, the state or its political subdivision shall reemploy or reinstate such person to the same position that he or she held prior to such service in the armed forces, or to an equivalent position, provided such person returns to the position within 1 year of his or her date of separation or, in cases of extended active duty, within 1 year of the date of discharge or separation subsequent to the extension. Such person shall also be awarded preference in promotion and shall be promoted ahead of all others who are as well qualified or less qualified for the position. When an examination for promotion is utilized, such person shall be awarded preference points, as provided in s. 295.08, and shall be promoted ahead of all those who appear in an equal or lesser position on the promotional register, provided he or she first successfully passes the examination for the promotional position.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraph (a) shall also apply to a person who was a veteran when employed by the state or its political subdivision and who was recalled to extended active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States and was discharged or separated therefrom with an honorable discharge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraphs (a) and (b) shall apply only to a veteran’s first promotion after reinstatement or reemployment, without exception.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “extended active duty” means active duty, other than for training, beyond the date of honorable discharge or separation, due to military requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 24201, 1947; s. 1, ch. 77-422; s. 2, ch. 78-372; s. 2, ch. 80-370; s. 3, ch. 89-323; s. 250, ch. 95-148; s. 81, ch. 99-13.</History></Section>