<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0295.0195" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Children of deceased or disabled military personnel who died or became disabled in the Mideast Persian Gulf military arena during hostilities with Iraq or in the military action in Panama known as Operation Just Cause.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is hereby declared to be the policy of the state to provide educational opportunity at state expense for the dependent children of those military personnel who died or suffered a service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation as determined by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, or who have been determined to have a service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent and are in receipt of disability retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Forces, while participating in the Mideast Persian Gulf arena during hostilities with Iraq, which began as Operation Desert Shield on August 5, 1990, through cessation of those hostilities, inclusive, or while participating in the military action in Panama known as Operation Just Cause during December 1989, if such military personnel were residents of the state during the period of military action. A certified copy of a death certificate, a valid identification card issued in accordance with the provisions of s. 295.17, a letter certifying the service-connected 100-percent total and permanent disability rating for compensation from the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, or a letter certifying the service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent for retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Forces shall be prima facie evidence of the fact that the dependent children of such military personnel are eligible for educational benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 295.03, 295.04, 295.05, and 1009.40 shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 91-166; s. 7, ch. 93-268; s. 954, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>