<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Length of detention.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may not be placed into or held in secure, nonsecure, or home detention care for longer than 24 hours unless the court orders such detention care, and the order includes specific instructions that direct the release of the child from such detention care, in accordance with s. 985.255. The order shall be a final order, reviewable by appeal under s. 985.534 and the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. Appeals of such orders shall take precedence over other appeals and other pending matters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may not be held in secure, nonsecure, or home detention care under a special detention order for more than 21 days unless an adjudicatory hearing for the case has been commenced in good faith by the court. However, upon good cause being shown that the nature of the charge requires additional time for the prosecution or defense of the case, the court may extend the length of detention for an additional 9 days if the child is charged with an offense that would be, if committed by an adult, a capital felony, a life felony, a felony of the first degree, or a felony of the second degree involving violence against any individual.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), a child may not be held in secure, nonsecure, or home detention care for more than 15 days following the entry of an order of adjudication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limits in subsections (2) and (3) do not include periods of delay resulting from a continuance granted by the court for cause on motion of the child or his or her counsel or of the state. Upon the issuance of an order granting a continuance for cause on a motion by either the child, the child’s counsel, or the state, the court shall conduct a hearing at the end of each 72-hour period, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, to determine the need for continued detention of the child and the need for further continuance of proceedings for the child or the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who was not in secure detention at the time of the adjudicatory hearing, but for whom residential commitment is anticipated or recommended, may be placed under a special detention order for a period not to exceed 72 hours, excluding weekends and legal holidays, for the purpose of conducting a comprehensive evaluation as provided in s. 985.185. Motions for the issuance of such special detention order may be made subsequent to a finding of delinquency. Upon said motion, the court shall conduct a hearing to determine the appropriateness of such special detention order and shall order the least restrictive level of detention necessary to complete the comprehensive evaluation process that is consistent with public safety. Such special detention order may be extended for an additional 72 hours upon further order of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is detained and a petition for delinquency is filed, the child shall be arraigned in accordance with the Florida Rules of Juvenile Procedure within 48 hours after the filing of the petition for delinquency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 31, ch. 94-209; s. 1343, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 96-398; s. 23, ch. 97-238; s. 13, ch. 98-207; s. 9, ch. 2000-134; s. 24, ch. 2000-135; s. 4, ch. 2005-263; s. 35, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) former s. 39.044(5)(a); s. 985.215(5)(a). Subsection (2) former s. 39.044(5)(b); s. 985.215(5)(c), (g). Subsection (3) former s. 39.044(5)(c); s. 985.215(5)(d). Subsection (4) former s. 39.044(5)(d); s. 985.215(5)(f). Subsection (5) former s. 985.215(5)(e). Subsection (6) former s. 39.044(7); s. 985.215(7).</Text></Note></Section>