<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.682" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Siting of facilities; study; criteria.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to conduct or contract for a statewide comprehensive study to determine current and future needs for all types of facilities for children committed to the custody, care, or supervision of the department under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The study shall assess, rank, and designate appropriate sites, and shall be reflective of the different purposes and uses for all facilities, based upon the following criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current and future estimates of children originating from each county;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current and future estimates of types of delinquent acts committed in each county;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Geographic location of existing facilities;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Availability of personnel within the local labor market;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current capacity of facilities in the area;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total usable and developable acreage of various sites based upon the use and purpose of the facility;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accessibility of each site to existing utility, transportation, law enforcement, health care, fire protection, refuse collection, water, and sewage disposal services;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Susceptibility of each site to flooding hazards or other adverse natural environmental consequences;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Site location in relation to desirable and undesirable proximity to other public facilities, including schools;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patterns of residential growth and projected population growth; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other criteria as the department, in conjunction with local governments, deems appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall recommend certification of the study by the Governor and Cabinet within 2 months after its receipt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon certification of the study by the Governor and Cabinet, the department shall notify those counties designated as being in need of a facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department or a contracted provider proposes a site for a juvenile justice facility, the department or provider shall request that the local government having jurisdiction over such proposed site determine whether or not the proposed site is appropriate for public use under local government comprehensive plans, local land use ordinances, local zoning ordinances or regulations, and other local ordinances in effect at the time of such request. If no such determination is made within 90 days after the request, it shall be presumed that the proposed site is in compliance with such plans, ordinances, or regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government determines within 90 days after the request that construction of a facility on the proposed site does not comply with any such plan, ordinance, or regulation, the department may request a modification of such plan, ordinance, or regulation without having an ownership interest in such property. For the purposes of this section, modification includes, but is not limited to, a variance, rezoning, special exception, or any other action of the local government having jurisdiction over the proposed site which would authorize siting of a facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a request for modification from the department, the local government may recommend and hold a public hearing on the request for modification in the same manner as for a rezoning as provided under the appropriate special or local law or ordinance, except that such proceeding shall be recorded by tape or by a certified court reporter and made available for transcription at the expense of any interested party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department requests such a modification and it is denied by the local government, the local government or the department shall initiate the dispute resolution process established under s. 186.509 to reconcile differences on the siting of correctional facilities between the department, local governments, and private citizens. If the regional planning council has not established a dispute resolution process pursuant to s. 186.509, the department shall establish, by rule, procedures for dispute resolution. The dispute resolution process shall require the parties to commence meetings to reconcile their differences. If the parties fail to resolve their differences within 30 days after the denial, the parties shall engage in voluntary mediation or similar process. If the parties fail to resolve their differences by mediation within 60 days after the denial, or if no action is taken on the department’s request within 90 days after the request, the department must appeal the decision of the local government on the requested modification of local plans, ordinances, or regulations to the Governor and Cabinet. Any dispute resolution process initiated under this section must conform to the time limitations set forth herein. However, upon agreement of all parties, the time limits may be extended, but in no event may the dispute resolution process extend over 180 days.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet shall consider the following when determining whether to grant the appeal from the decision of the local government on the requested modification:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The record of the proceedings before the local government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports and studies by any other agency relating to matters within the jurisdiction of such agency which may be potentially affected by the proposed site.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statewide study, as established in subsection (1); other existing studies; reports and information maintained by the department as the Governor and Cabinet may request addressing the feasibility and availability of alternative sites in the general area; and the need for a facility in the area based on the average number of petitions, commitments, and transfers into the criminal court from the county to state facilities for the most recent 3 calendar years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet, upon determining that the local government has recommended no feasible alternative site and that the interests of the state in providing facilities outweigh the concerns of the local government, shall authorize construction and operation of a facility on the proposed site notwithstanding any local plan, ordinance, or regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet may adopt rules of procedure to govern these proceedings in accordance with the provisions of s. 120.54.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the department or the Governor and Cabinet pursuant to this section shall not be subject to the provisions of ss. 120.56, 120.569, and 120.57. The decision by the Governor and Cabinet shall be subject to judicial review pursuant to s. 120.68 in the District Court of Appeal, First District.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other departments and agencies of the state shall cooperate fully with the department to accomplish the siting of facilities for juvenile offenders.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to expedite the siting of, acquisition of land for, and construction by the Department of Juvenile Justice of state juvenile justice facilities operated by the department or a private vendor under contract with the department. Other agencies shall cooperate with the department and expeditiously fulfill their responsibilities to avoid unnecessary delay in the siting of, acquisition of land for, and construction of state juvenile justice facilities. This section and all other laws of the state shall be construed to accomplish this intent. This section shall take precedence over any other law to the contrary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall acquire land and erect juvenile justice facilities necessary to accommodate children committed to the custody, care, or supervision of the department, and shall make additional alterations to facilities to accommodate any increase in the number of children. The department shall establish adequate accommodations for staff of the department who are required to reside continuously within the facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 255.25(1)(b), the department may enter into lease-purchase agreements to provide juvenile justice facilities for the housing of committed youths contingent upon available funds. The facilities provided through such agreements shall meet the program plan and specifications of the department. The department may enter into such lease agreements with private corporations and other governmental entities. However, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 255.25(3)(a), no such lease agreement may be entered into except upon advertisement for the receipt of competitive bids and award to the lowest and best bidder except when contracting with other governmental entities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lease-purchase agreement that is for a term extending beyond the end of a fiscal year is subject to the provisions of s. 216.311.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025 or s. 287.057, when the department finds it necessary for timely site acquisition, it may contract, without using the competitive selection procedure, with an appraiser whose name is on the list of approved appraisers maintained by the Division of State Lands of the Department of Environmental Protection under s. 253.025(6)(b). When the department directly contracts for appraisal services, it must contract with an approved appraiser who is not employed by the same appraisal firm for review services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025(6), the department may negotiate and enter into an option contract before an appraisal is obtained. The option contract must state that the final purchase price may not exceed the maximum value allowed by law. The consideration for such an option contract may not exceed 10 percent of the estimate obtained by the department or 10 percent of the value of the parcel, whichever amount is greater.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection applies only to a purchase or acquisition of land for juvenile justice facilities. This subsection does not modify the authority of the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund or the Division of State Lands of the Department of Environmental Protection to approve any contract for purchase of state lands as provided by law or to require policies and procedures to obtain clear legal title to parcels purchased for state purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may sell, to the best possible advantage, any detached parcels of land belonging to the bodies of land purchased for the state juvenile justice facilities. The department may purchase any parcel of land contiguous with the lands purchased for state juvenile justice facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may begin preliminary site preparation and obtain the appropriate permits for the construction of a juvenile justice facility after approval by the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of the lease purchase agreement or option contract if, in the department’s discretion, commencing construction is in the best interests of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insofar as the provisions of this section are inconsistent with the provisions of any other law, general, special, or local, the provisions of this section are controlling. Additionally, the criteria and procedures set forth in this section supersede and are in lieu of any review and approval required by s. 380.06.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 20, ch. 93-230; s. 56, ch. 94-209; s. 13, ch. 96-398; s. 5, ch. 96-410; s. 70, ch. 97-238; s. 27, ch. 98-207; s. 140, ch. 99-3; s. 94, ch. 2006-120; s. 57, ch. 2012-116.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.074; s. 985.41.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>