<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.481" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexual offenders adjudicated delinquent; notification upon release.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Convicted” has the same meaning as provided in s. 943.0435.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual offender” means a person who has been adjudicated delinquent as provided in s. 943.0435(1)(a)1.d.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that certain juvenile sexual offenders pose a high risk of engaging in sexual offenses even after being released from commitment and that protection of the public from sexual offenders is a paramount governmental interest. Sexual offenders have a reduced expectation of privacy because of the public’s interest in public safety and in the effective operation of government. Releasing sexual offender information to law enforcement agencies, to persons who request such information, and to the public by a law enforcement agency or public agency will further the governmental interests of public safety.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must provide information regarding any sexual offender who is being released after serving a period of residential commitment under the department for any offense, as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must provide the sexual offender’s name, any change in the offender’s name by reason of marriage or other legal process, and any alias, if known; the correctional facility from which the sexual offender is released; the sexual offender’s social security number, race, sex, date of birth, height, weight, and hair and eye color; address of any planned permanent residence or temporary residence, within the state or out of state, including a rural route address and a post office box; if no permanent or temporary address, any transient residence within the state; address, location or description, and dates of any known future temporary residence within the state or out of state; date and county of disposition and each crime for which there was a disposition; a copy of the offender’s fingerprints and a digitized photograph taken within 60 days before release; the date of release of the sexual offender; and home telephone number and any cellular telephone number. The department shall notify the Department of Law Enforcement if the sexual offender escapes, absconds, or dies. If the sexual offender is in the custody of a private correctional facility, the facility shall take the digitized photograph of the sexual offender within 60 days before the sexual offender’s release and also place it in the sexual offender’s file. If the sexual offender is in the custody of a local jail, the custodian of the local jail shall register the offender within 3 business days after intake of the offender for any reason and upon release, and shall notify the Department of Law Enforcement of the sexual offender’s release and provide to the Department of Law Enforcement the information specified in this subparagraph and any information specified in subparagraph 2. which the Department of Law Enforcement requests.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide any other information considered necessary, including criminal and delinquency records, when available.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than November 1, 2007, the department must make the information described in subparagraph (a)1. available electronically to the Department of Law Enforcement in its database and in a format that is compatible with the requirements of the Florida Crime Information Center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving information regarding a sexual offender from the department, the Department of Law Enforcement, the sheriff, or the chief of police shall provide the information described in subparagraph (a)1. to any individual who requests such information and may release the information to the public in any manner considered appropriate, unless the information so received is confidential or exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section authorizes the department or any law enforcement agency to notify the community and the public of a sexual offender’s presence in the community. However, with respect to a sexual offender who has been found to be a sexual predator under chapter 775, the Department of Law Enforcement or any other law enforcement agency must inform the community and the public of the sexual predator’s presence in the community as provided in chapter 775.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An elected or appointed official, public employee, school administrator or employee, or agency, or any individual or entity acting at the request or upon the direction of any law enforcement agency, is immune from civil liability for damages resulting from the release of information under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2007-209; s. 6, ch. 2009-194; s. 14, ch. 2010-92.</History>
</Section>