<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.461" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transition to adulthood.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that older youth are faced with the need to learn how to support themselves within legal means and overcome the stigma of being delinquent. In most cases, parents expedite this transition. It is the intent of the Legislature that the department provide older youth in its custody or under its supervision with opportunities for participating in transition-to-adulthood services while in the department’s commitment programs or in probation or conditional release programs in the community. These services should be reasonable and appropriate for the youths’ respective ages or special needs and provide activities that build life skills and increase the ability to live independently and become self-sufficient.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Youth served by the department who are in the custody of the Department of Children and Family Services and who entered juvenile justice placement from a foster care placement, if otherwise eligible, may receive independent living transition services pursuant to s. 409.1451. Court-ordered commitment or probation with the department is not a barrier to eligibility for the array of services available to a youth who is in the dependency foster care system only.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a dependent child in the foster care system, adjudication for delinquency does not, by itself, disqualify such child for eligibility in the Department of Children and Family Services’ independent living program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To support participation in transition-to-adulthood services and subject to appropriation, the department may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assess the child’s skills and abilities to live independently and become self-sufficient. The specific services to be provided shall be determined using an assessment of his or her readiness for adult life.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a list of age-appropriate activities and responsibilities to be incorporated in the child’s written case plan for any youth 17 years of age or older who is under the custody or supervision of the department. Activities may include, but are not limited to, life skills training, including training to develop banking and budgeting skills, interviewing and career planning skills, parenting skills, personal health management, and time management or organizational skills; educational support; employment training; and counseling.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information related to social security insurance benefits and public assistance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request parental or guardian permission for the youth to participate in transition-to-adulthood services. Upon such consent, age-appropriate activities shall be incorporated into the youth’s written case plan. This plan may include specific goals and objectives and shall be reviewed and updated at least quarterly. If the parent or guardian is cooperative, the plan may not interfere with the parent’s or guardian’s rights to nurture and train his or her child in ways that are otherwise in compliance with the law and court order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract for transition-to-adulthood services that include residential services and assistance and allow the child to live independently of the daily care and supervision of an adult in a setting that is not licensed under s. 409.175. A child under the care or supervision of the department who has reached 17 years of age but is not yet 19 years of age is eligible for such services if he or she does not pose a danger to the public and is able to demonstrate minimally sufficient skills and aptitude for living under decreased adult supervision, as determined by the department, using established procedures and assessments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a child who is 17 years of age or older, under the department’s care or supervision, and without benefit of parents or legal guardians capable of assisting the child in the transition to adult life, the department may provide an assessment to determine the child’s skills and abilities to live independently and become self-sufficient. Based on the assessment and within existing resources, services and training may be provided in order to develop the necessary skills and abilities before the child’s 18th birthday.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of transition-to-adulthood services must be part of an overall plan leading to the total independence of the child from department supervision. The plan must include, but need not be limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the child’s skills and a plan for learning additional identified skills;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The behavior that the child has exhibited which indicates an ability to be responsible and a plan for developing additional responsibilities, as appropriate;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan for the provision of future educational, vocational, and training skills;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present financial and budgeting capabilities and a plan for improving resources and abilities;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed residence;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation that the child understands the specific consequences of his or her conduct in such a program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of proposed services to be provided by the department and other agencies, including the type of services and the nature and frequency of contact; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan for maintaining or developing relationships with family, other adults, friends, and the community, as appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2011-236.</History>
</Section>