<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Postcommitment detention while awaiting placement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court must place all children who are adjudicated and awaiting placement in a commitment program in detention care. Children who are in home detention care or nonsecure detention care may be placed on electronic monitoring.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is awaiting placement in a low-risk residential program must be removed from detention within 5 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays. Any child held in secure detention during the 5 days must meet detention admission criteria under this part. A child who is placed in home detention care, nonsecure detention care, or home or nonsecure detention care with electronic monitoring, while awaiting placement in a minimum-risk or low-risk program, may be held in secure detention care for 5 days, if the child violates the conditions of the home detention care, the nonsecure detention care, or the electronic monitoring agreement. For any subsequent violation, the court may impose an additional 5 days in secure detention care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is awaiting placement in a moderate-risk residential program must be removed from detention within 5 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays. Any child held in secure detention during the 5 days must meet detention admission criteria under this part. The department may seek an order from the court authorizing continued detention for a specific period of time necessary for the appropriate residential placement of the child. However, such continued detention in secure detention care may not exceed 15 days after entry of the commitment order, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, and except as otherwise provided in this section. A child who is placed in home detention care, nonsecure detention care, or home or nonsecure detention care with electronic monitoring, while awaiting placement in a moderate-risk program, may be held in secure detention care for 5 days, if the child violates the conditions of the home detention care, the nonsecure detention care, or the electronic monitoring agreement. For any subsequent violation, the court may impose an additional 5 days in secure detention care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is committed to a high-risk residential program, the child must be held in detention care until placement or commitment is accomplished.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is committed to a maximum-risk residential program, the child must be held in detention care until placement or commitment is accomplished.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regardless of detention status, a child being transported by the department to a residential commitment facility of the department may be placed in secure detention overnight, not to exceed a 24-hour period, for the specific purpose of ensuring the safe delivery of the child to his or her residential commitment program, court, appointment, transfer, or release.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 31, ch. 94-209; s. 42, ch. 95-267; s. 5, ch. 96-398; s. 23, ch. 97-238; s. 13, ch. 98-207; s. 9, ch. 2000-134; s. 5, ch. 2000-327; s. 19, ch. 2001-125; s. 4, ch. 2005-263; s. 37, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.044(10)(a)-(d); s. 985.215(10)(a)-(d), (f).</Text></Note></Section>