<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.319" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Process and service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal appearance of any person in a hearing before the court obviates the necessity of serving process on that person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a petition containing allegations of facts which, if true, would establish that the child committed a delinquent act or violation of law, and upon the request of the petitioner, the clerk or deputy clerk shall issue a summons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summons shall have a copy of the petition attached and shall require the person on whom it is served to appear for a hearing at a time and place specified. Except in cases of medical emergency, the time may not be less than 24 hours after service of the summons. If the child is not detained by an order of the court, the summons shall require the custodian of the child to produce the child at the said time and place.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Law enforcement agencies shall act upon subpoenas received and serve process within 7 days after arraignment or as soon thereafter as is possible, except that no service shall be made on Sundays.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summons shall be directed to, and shall be served upon, the following persons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child, in the same manner as an adult;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents of the child; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any legal custodians, actual custodians, guardians, and guardians ad litem of the child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the petition alleges that the child has committed a delinquent act or violation of law and the judge deems it advisable to do so, under the criteria of s. 985.255, the judge may, by endorsement upon the summons and after the entry of an order in which valid reasons are specified, order the child to be taken into custody immediately, and in such case the person serving the summons shall immediately take the child into custody.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the identity or residence of the parents, custodians, or guardians of the child is unknown after a diligent search and inquiry, if the parents, custodians, or guardians are residents of a state other than Florida, or if the parents, custodians, or guardians evade service, the person who made the search and inquiry shall file in the case a certificate of those facts, and the court shall appoint a guardian ad litem for the child, if appropriate. If the parent, custodian, or guardian of the child fails to obey a summons, the court may, by endorsement upon the summons and after the entry of an order in which valid reasons are specified, order the parent, custodian, or guardian to be taken into custody immediately to show cause why the parent, guardian, or custodian should not be held in contempt for failing to obey the summons. The court may appoint a guardian ad litem for the child, if appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the application of the child or the state attorney, the clerk or deputy clerk shall issue, and the court on its own motion may issue, subpoenas requiring attendance and testimony of witnesses and production of records, documents, or other tangible objects at any hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All process and orders issued by the court shall be served or executed as other process and orders of the circuit court and, in addition, may be served or executed by authorized agents of the Department of Juvenile Justice at the department’s discretion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subpoenas may be served within the state by any person over 18 years of age who is not a party to the proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No fee shall be paid for service of any process or other papers by an agent of the department. If any process, orders, or other papers are served or executed by any sheriff, the sheriff’s fees shall be paid by the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 7, ch. 92-287; s. 39, ch. 94-209; s. 1347, ch. 95-147; s. 27, ch. 97-238; s. 11, ch. 2000-134; s. 40, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.049(1)-(6), (8)-(11); s. 985.219(1)-(7), (9)-(12).</Text></Note></Section>