<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.8025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Council for Interstate Juvenile Offender Supervision.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to Article IX of the Interstate Compact for Juveniles in s. 985.802, the State Council for Interstate Juvenile Offender Supervision is created. The purpose of the council is to oversee state participation in the activities of the Interstate Commission for Juveniles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall consist of seven members and the secretary of the Department of Juvenile Justice or his or her designee, who shall serve as the chair of the council and may vote only to break a tie. The compact administrator or his or her designee and the executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement or his or her designee shall serve as members of the council. The remaining members shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of 4 years; however, the Governor may, in writing and on an individual basis for each appointee, delegate the power of appointment to the Secretary of Juvenile Justice. Of the initial appointees, one shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, one shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, one shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, and two shall be appointed for terms of 4 years each.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appointees shall be selected from individuals with personal or professional experience in the juvenile justice system and may include a victim’s advocate, employees of the Department of Children and Family Services, employees of the Department of Law Enforcement who work with missing and exploited children, and a parent who, at the time of appointment, does not have a child involved in the juvenile justice system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Council members shall serve without compensation, but they are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution and of chapter 119 and s. 286.011 apply to proceedings and records of the council. Minutes, including a record of all votes cast, must be maintained for all meetings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the council is abolished, its records must be appropriately stored, within 30 days after the effective date of its abolition, by the Department of Juvenile Justice or its successor agency. Any property assigned to the council must be reclaimed by the department or its successor agency. The council may not perform any activities after the effective date of its abolition.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 2005-80; s. 102, ch. 2006-120; s. 2, ch. 2011-89.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 985.5025.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>