<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.0301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court has exclusive original jurisdiction of proceedings in which a child is alleged to have committed a delinquent act or violation of law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of the court shall attach to the child and the case when the summons is served upon the child and a parent or legal or actual custodian or guardian of the child, or when the child is taken into custody with or without service of summons and before or after the filing of a petition, whichever first occurs, and thereafter the court may control the child and the case in accordance with this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the prosecution of any violation of law against any person who has been presumed to be an adult, if it is shown that the person was a child at the time the offense was committed and that the person does not meet the criteria for prosecution and sentencing as an adult, the court shall immediately transfer the case, together with the physical custody of the person and all physical evidence, papers, documents, and testimony, original and duplicate, connected therewith, to the appropriate court for proceedings under this chapter. The circuit court is exclusively authorized to assume jurisdiction over any juvenile offender who is arrested and charged with violating a federal law or a law of the District of Columbia, who is found or is living or domiciled in a county in which the circuit court is established, and who is surrendered to the circuit court as provided in 18 U.S.C. s. 5001.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petitions alleging delinquency shall be filed in the county where the delinquent act or violation of law occurred, but the circuit court for that county may transfer the case to the circuit court of the circuit in which the child resides or will reside at the time of detention or placement for dispositional purposes. A child who has been detained shall be transferred to the appropriate detention center or facility or other placement directed by the receiving court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction to be exercised by the court when a child is taken into custody before the filing of a petition under subsection (2) shall be exercised by the circuit court for the county in which the child is taken into custody, which court shall have personal jurisdiction of the child and the child’s parent or legal guardian. Upon the filing of a petition in the appropriate circuit court, the court that is exercising initial jurisdiction of the person of the child shall, if the child has been detained, immediately order the child to be transferred to the detention center or facility or other placement as ordered by the court having subject matter jurisdiction of the case.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 743.07, 985.43, 985.433, 985.435, 985.439, and 985.441, and except as provided in ss. 985.461 and 985.465 and paragraph (f), when the jurisdiction of any child who is alleged to have committed a delinquent act or violation of law is obtained, the court shall retain jurisdiction, unless relinquished by its order, until the child reaches 19 years of age, with the same power over the child which the court had before the child became an adult. For the purposes of s. 985.461, the court may retain jurisdiction for an additional 365 days following the child’s 19th birthday if the child is participating in transition-to-adulthood services. The additional services do not extend involuntary court-sanctioned residential commitment and therefore require voluntary participation by the affected youth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 743.07 and 985.455(3), the term of any order placing a child in a probation program must be until the child’s 19th birthday unless he or she is released by the court on the motion of an interested party or on his or her own motion.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 743.07 and 985.455(3), the term of the commitment must be until the child is discharged by the department or until he or she reaches the age of 21 years. Notwithstanding ss. 743.07, 985.435, 985.437, 985.439, 985.441, 985.455, and 985.513, and except as provided in this section, a child may not be held under a commitment from a court under s. 985.439, s. 985.441(1)(a) or (b), or s. 985.455 after becoming 21 years of age.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a child committed to the department for placement in a juvenile prison or in a high-risk or maximum-risk residential commitment program to allow the child to participate in a juvenile conditional release program pursuant to s. 985.46. The jurisdiction of the court may not be retained after the child’s 22nd birthday. However, if the child is not successful in the conditional release program, the department may use the transfer procedure under s. 985.441(4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a child committed to the department for placement in an intensive residential treatment program for 10-year-old to 13-year-old offenders, in the residential commitment program in a juvenile prison or in a residential sex offender program until the child reaches the age of 21. If the court exercises this jurisdiction retention, it shall do so solely for the purpose of the child completing the intensive residential treatment program for 10-year-old to 13-year-old offenders, in the residential commitment program in a juvenile prison, or in a residential sex offender program. Such jurisdiction retention does not apply for other programs, other purposes, or new offenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a child committed to a juvenile correctional facility or a juvenile prison until the child reaches the age of 21 years, specifically for the purpose of allowing the child to complete such program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a juvenile sexual offender who has been placed in a program or facility for juvenile sexual offenders until the juvenile sexual offender reaches the age of 21, specifically for the purpose of completing the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a child and the child’s parent or legal guardian whom the court has ordered to pay restitution until the restitution order is satisfied. To retain jurisdiction, the court shall enter a restitution order, which is separate from any disposition or order of commitment, on or prior to the date that the court’s jurisdiction would cease under this section. The contents of the restitution order shall be limited to the child’s name and address, the name and address of the parent or legal guardian, the name and address of the payee, the case number, the date and amount of restitution ordered, any amount of restitution paid, the amount of restitution due and owing, and a notation that costs, interest, penalties, and attorney fees may also be due and owing. The terms of the restitution order are subject to s. 775.089(5).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prevent the exercise of jurisdiction by any court having jurisdiction of the child if the child, after becoming an adult, commits a violation of law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may at any time enter an order ending its jurisdiction over any child.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 12, ch. 92-287; s. 2, ch. 93-37; ss. 19, 39, ch. 94-209; s. 21, ch. 94-342; s. 2, ch. 95-160; ss. 9, 27, ch. 97-238; s. 33, ch. 99-284; ss. 5, 11, ch. 2000-134; s. 36, ch. 2001-64; s. 65, ch. 2005-236; s. 19, ch. 2005-263; s. 5, ch. 2006-120; s. 2, ch. 2011-54; s. 10, ch. 2011-70; s. 3, ch. 2011-236; s. 90, ch. 2012-5; s. 6, ch. 2012-56.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1), (3)-(5) former s. 39.022; s. 985.201. Subsection (2) former s. 39.049(7); s. 985.219(8).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>