<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.475" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Juvenile sexual offenders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CRITERIA.<EmDash />A “juvenile sexual offender” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A juvenile who has been found by the court under s. 985.35 to have committed a violation of chapter 794, chapter 796, chapter 800, s. 827.071, or s. 847.0133;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A juvenile found to have committed any felony violation of law or delinquent act involving juvenile sexual abuse. “Juvenile sexual abuse” means any sexual behavior that occurs without consent, without equality, or as a result of coercion. For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions apply:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Coercion” means the exploitation of authority, use of bribes, threats of force, or intimidation to gain cooperation or compliance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Equality” means two participants operating with the same level of power in a relationship, neither being controlled nor coerced by the other.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consent” means an agreement including all of the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Understanding what is proposed based on age, maturity, developmental level, functioning, and experience.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowledge of societal standards for what is being proposed.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Awareness of potential consequences and alternatives.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assumption that agreement or disagreement will be accepted equally.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Voluntary decision.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mental competence.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Juvenile sexual offender behavior ranges from noncontact sexual behavior such as making obscene phone calls, exhibitionism, voyeurism, and the showing or taking of lewd photographs to varying degrees of direct sexual contact, such as frottage, fondling, digital penetration, rape, fellatio, sodomy, and various other sexually aggressive acts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following a delinquency adjudicatory hearing under s. 985.35, the court may on its own or upon request by the state or the department and subject to specific appropriation, determine whether a juvenile sexual offender placement is required for the protection of the public and what would be the best approach to address the treatment needs of the juvenile sexual offender. When the court determines that a juvenile has no history of a recent comprehensive assessment focused on sexually deviant behavior, the court may, subject to specific appropriation, order the department to conduct or arrange for an examination to determine whether the juvenile sexual offender is amenable to community-based treatment.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report of the examination shall include, at a minimum, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juvenile sexual offender’s account of the incident and the official report of the investigation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juvenile sexual offender’s offense history.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A multidisciplinary assessment of the sexually deviant behaviors, including an assessment by a certified psychologist, therapist, or psychiatrist.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the juvenile sexual offender’s family, social, educational, and employment situation. The report shall set forth the sources of the evaluator’s information.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report shall assess the juvenile sexual offender’s amenability to treatment and relative risk to the victim and the community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide a proposed plan to the court that shall include, at a minimum:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The frequency and type of contact between the offender and therapist.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific issues and behaviors to be addressed in the treatment and description of planned treatment methods.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitoring plans, including any requirements regarding living conditions, school attendance and participation, lifestyle, and monitoring by family members, legal guardians, or others.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anticipated length of treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommended crime-related prohibitions and curfew.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable restrictions on the contact between the juvenile sexual offender and either the victim or alleged victim.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receipt of the report on the proposed plan of treatment, the court shall consider whether the community and the offender will benefit from use of juvenile sexual offender community-based treatment alternative disposition and consider the opinion of the victim or the victim’s family as to whether the offender should receive a community-based treatment alternative disposition under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court determines that this juvenile sexual offender community-based treatment alternative is appropriate, the court may place the offender on community supervision for up to 3 years. As a condition of community treatment and supervision, the court may order the offender to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undergo available outpatient juvenile sexual offender treatment for up to 3 years. A program or provider may not be used for such treatment unless it has an appropriate program designed for sexual offender treatment. The department shall not change the treatment provider without first notifying the state attorney’s office.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remain within described geographical boundaries and notify the court or the department counselor prior to any change in the offender’s address, educational program, or employment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with all requirements of the treatment plan.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juvenile sexual offender treatment provider shall submit quarterly reports on the respondent’s progress in treatment to the court and the parties to the proceedings. The juvenile sexual offender reports shall reference the treatment plan and include, at a minimum, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dates of attendance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juvenile sexual offender’s compliance with the requirements of treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the treatment activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sexual offender’s relative progress in treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offender’s family support of the treatment objectives.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other material specified by the court at the time of the disposition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the disposition hearing, the court may set case review hearings as the court considers appropriate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the juvenile sexual offender violates any condition of the disposition or the court finds that the juvenile sexual offender is failing to make satisfactory progress in treatment, the court may revoke the community-based treatment alternative and order commitment to the department under s. 985.441.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court determines that the juvenile sexual offender is not amenable to community-based treatment, the court shall proceed with a juvenile sexual offender disposition hearing under s. 985.441.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 39, ch. 97-238; s. 9, ch. 99-284; s. 18, ch. 2000-135; s. 14, ch. 2001-125; s. 1, ch. 2005-263; s. 57, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) former s. 985.03(32). Subsection (2) former s. 985.231(3).</Text></Note></Section>