<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.61" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Early delinquency intervention program; criteria.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Juvenile Justice shall, contingent upon specific appropriation and with the cooperation of local law enforcement agencies, the judiciary, district school board personnel, the office of the state attorney, the office of the public defender, the Department of Children and Family Services, and community service agencies that work with children, establish an early delinquency intervention program, the components of which shall include, but not be limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Case management services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Treatment modalities, including substance abuse treatment services, mental health services, and retardation services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevocational education and career education services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diagnostic evaluation services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Self-sufficiency planning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Independent living skills.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parenting skills.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recreational and leisure time activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program evaluation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical screening.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The early delinquency intervention program shall consist of intensive residential treatment in a secure facility for 7 days to 6 weeks, followed by 6 to 9 months of additional services. An early delinquency intervention program facility shall be designed to accommodate the placement of a maximum of 10 children, except that the facility may accommodate up to 2 children in excess of that maximum if the additional children have previously been released from the residential portion of the program and are later found to need additional residential treatment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the arrest report of any child 15 years of age or younger who is taken into custody for committing a delinquent act or any violation of law shall be forwarded to the local operating circuit office of the Department of Juvenile Justice. Upon receiving the second arrest report of any such child from the judicial circuit in which the program is located, the Department of Juvenile Justice shall initiate an intensive review of the child’s social and educational history to determine the likelihood of further significant delinquent behavior. In making this determination, the Department of Juvenile Justice shall consider, without limitation, the following factors:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any prior allegation that the child is dependent or a child in need of services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physical, emotional, and intellectual status and developmental level of the child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s academic history, including school attendance, school achievements, grade level, and involvement in school-sponsored activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and quality of the child’s peer group relationships.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s history of substance abuse or behavioral problems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s family status, including the capability of the child’s family members to participate in a family-centered intervention program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s family history of substance abuse or criminal activity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervision that is available in the child’s home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the relationship between the parents and the child and any siblings and the child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determination that a child is likely to continue to exhibit significant delinquent behavior, the department may recommend to the court that the child be placed in an early delinquency intervention program, and the court may order the program as the dispositional placement for the child. At the discretion of the department or its designee, or upon order of the court, a child who is 11 years of age or younger may be excused from the residential portion of treatment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 21, ch. 93-200; s. 44, ch. 94-209; s. 4, ch. 97-101; s. 49, ch. 97-238; s. 35, ch. 2000-135; s. 28, ch. 2001-125; s. 78, ch. 2006-120; s. 171, ch. 2010-102.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.055; s. 985.305.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>