<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right to counsel.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child is entitled to representation by legal counsel at all stages of any delinquency court proceedings under this chapter. If the child and the parents or other legal guardian are indigent and unable to employ counsel for the child, the court shall appoint counsel under s. 27.52. Determination of indigence and costs of representation shall be as provided by ss. 27.52 and 938.29. Legal counsel representing a child who exercises the right to counsel shall be allowed to provide advice and counsel to the child at any time subsequent to the child’s arrest, including prior to a detention hearing while in secure detention care. A child shall be represented by legal counsel at all stages of all court proceedings unless the right to counsel is freely, knowingly, and intelligently waived by the child. If the child appears without counsel, the court shall advise the child of his or her rights with respect to representation of court-appointed counsel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to transfer proceedings under s. 985.441(4), unless the court sets a hearing to review the transfer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the parents or legal guardian of an indigent child are not indigent but refuse to employ counsel, the court shall appoint counsel pursuant to s. 27.52 to represent the child at the detention hearing and until counsel is provided. Costs of representation are hereby imposed as provided by ss. 27.52 and 938.29. Thereafter, the court shall not appoint counsel for an indigent child with nonindigent parents or legal guardian but shall order the parents or legal guardian to obtain private counsel. A parent or legal guardian of an indigent child who has been ordered to obtain private counsel for the child and who willfully fails to follow the court order shall be punished by the court in civil contempt proceedings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An indigent child with nonindigent parents or legal guardian may have counsel appointed pursuant to s. 27.52 if the parents or legal guardian have willfully refused to obey the court order to obtain counsel for the child and have been punished by civil contempt and then still have willfully refused to obey the court order. Costs of representation are hereby imposed as provided by ss. 27.52 and 938.29.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this section or any other law to the contrary, if a child is transferred for criminal prosecution pursuant to this chapter, a nonindigent or indigent-but-able-to-contribute parent or legal guardian of the child pursuant to s. 27.52 is liable for necessary legal fees and costs incident to the criminal prosecution of the child as an adult.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 220, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 96-232; s. 11, ch. 97-238; s. 30, ch. 97-271; s. 129, ch. 99-3; s. 139, ch. 2003-402; s. 165, ch. 2004-5; s. 90, ch. 2004-265; s. 7, ch. 2006-120; s. 3, ch. 2011-54.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.041; s. 985.203.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>