<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.66" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Juvenile justice training academies; staff development and training; Juvenile Justice Training Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE PURPOSE.<EmDash />In order to enable the state to provide a systematic approach to staff development and training for judges, state attorneys, public defenders, law enforcement officers, school district personnel, and juvenile justice program staff that will meet the needs of such persons in their discharge of duties while at the same time meeting the requirements for the American Correction Association accreditation by the Commission on Accreditation for Corrections, it is the purpose of the Legislature to require the department to establish, maintain, and oversee the operation of juvenile justice training academies in the state. The purpose of the Legislature in establishing staff development and training programs is to foster better staff morale and reduce mistreatment and aggressive and abusive behavior in delinquency programs; to positively impact the recidivism of children in the juvenile justice system; and to afford greater protection of the public through an improved level of services delivered by a professionally trained juvenile justice program staff to children who are alleged to be or who have been found to be delinquent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STAFF DEVELOPMENT AND TRAINING.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate the location of the training academies; develop, implement, maintain, and update the curriculum to be used in the training of juvenile justice program staff; establish timeframes for participation in and completion of training by juvenile justice program staff; develop, implement, maintain, and update job-related examinations; develop, implement, and update the types and frequencies of evaluations of the training academies; approve, modify, or disapprove the budget for the training academies, and the contractor to be selected to organize and operate the training academies and to provide the training curriculum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish uniform minimum job-related training courses and examinations for juvenile justice program staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consult and cooperate with the state or any political subdivision; any private entity or contractor; and with private and public universities, colleges, community colleges, and other educational institutions concerning the development of juvenile justice training and programs or courses of instruction, including, but not limited to, education and training in the areas of juvenile justice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts and agreements with other agencies, organizations, associations, corporations, individuals, or federal agencies as necessary in the execution of the powers of the department or the performance of its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">JUVENILE JUSTICE TRAINING PROGRAM.<EmDash />The department shall establish a certifiable program for juvenile justice training pursuant to this section, and all department program staff and providers who deliver direct care services pursuant to contract with the department shall be required to participate in and successfully complete the department-approved program of training pertinent to their areas of responsibility. Judges, state attorneys, and public defenders, law enforcement officers, and school district personnel may participate in such training program. For the juvenile justice program staff, the department shall, based on a job-task analysis:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Design, implement, maintain, evaluate, and revise a basic training program, including a competency-based examination, for the purpose of providing minimum employment training qualifications for all juvenile justice personnel. All program staff of the department and providers who deliver direct-care services who are hired after October 1, 1999, must meet the following minimum requirements:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 19 years of age.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a high school graduate or its equivalent as determined by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not have been convicted of any felony or a misdemeanor involving perjury or a false statement, or have received a dishonorable discharge from any of the Armed Forces of the United States. Any person who, after September 30, 1999, pleads guilty or nolo contendere to or is found guilty of any felony or a misdemeanor involving perjury or false statement is not eligible for employment, notwithstanding suspension of sentence or withholding of adjudication. Notwithstanding this subparagraph, any person who pled nolo contendere to a misdemeanor involving a false statement before October 1, 1999, and who has had such record of that plea sealed or expunged is not ineligible for employment for that reason.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abide by all the provisions of s. 985.644(1) regarding fingerprinting and background investigations and other screening requirements for personnel.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute and submit to the department an affidavit-of-application form, adopted by the department, attesting to his or her compliance with subparagraphs 1.-4. The affidavit must be executed under oath and constitutes an official statement under s. 837.06. The affidavit must include conspicuous language that the intentional false execution of the affidavit constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree. The employing agency shall retain the affidavit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Design, implement, maintain, evaluate, and revise an advanced training program, including a competency-based examination for each training course, which is intended to enhance knowledge, skills, and abilities related to job performance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Design, implement, maintain, evaluate, and revise a career development training program, including a competency-based examination for each training course. Career development courses are intended to prepare personnel for promotion.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is encouraged to design, implement, maintain, evaluate, and revise juvenile justice training courses, or to enter into contracts for such training courses, that are intended to provide for the safety and well-being of both citizens and juvenile offenders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">JUVENILE JUSTICE TRAINING TRUST FUND.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the State Treasury a Juvenile Justice Training Trust Fund to be used by the department for the purpose of funding the development and updating of a job-task analysis of juvenile justice personnel; the development, implementation, and updating of job-related training courses and examinations; and the cost of juvenile justice training courses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One dollar from every noncriminal traffic infraction collected pursuant to ss. 318.14(10)(b) and 318.18 shall be deposited into the Juvenile Justice Training Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the funds generated by paragraph (b), the trust fund may receive funds from any other public or private source.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds that are not expended by the end of the budget cycle or through a supplemental budget approved by the department shall revert to the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ESTABLISHMENT OF JUVENILE JUSTICE TRAINING ACADEMIES.<EmDash />The number, location, and establishment of juvenile justice training academies shall be determined by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOLARSHIPS AND STIPENDS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By rule, the department shall establish criteria to award scholarships or stipends to qualified juvenile justice personnel who are residents of the state who want to pursue a bachelor’s or associate in arts degree in juvenile justice or a related field. The department shall handle the administration of the scholarship or stipend. The Department of Education shall handle the notes issued for the payment of the scholarships or stipends. All scholarship and stipend awards shall be paid from the Juvenile Justice Training Trust Fund upon vouchers approved by the Department of Education and properly certified by the Chief Financial Officer. Prior to the award of a scholarship or stipend, the juvenile justice employee must agree in writing to practice her or his profession in juvenile justice or a related field for 1 month for each month of grant or to repay the full amount of the scholarship or stipend together with interest at the rate of 5 percent per annum over a period not to exceed 10 years. Repayment shall be made payable to the state for deposit into the Juvenile Justice Training Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish the scholarship program by rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADOPTION OF RULES.<EmDash />The department shall adopt rules as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTICIPATION OF CERTAIN PROGRAMS IN THE STATE RISK MANAGEMENT TRUST FUND.<EmDash />Pursuant to s. 284.30, the Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services is authorized to insure a private agency, individual, or corporation operating a state-owned training school under a contract to carry out the purposes and responsibilities of any program of the department. The coverage authorized herein shall be under the same general terms and conditions as the department is insured for its responsibilities under chapter 284.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 3, ch. 91-74; s. 21, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 21, ch. 94-209; s. 1336, ch. 95-147; s. 53, ch. 95-280; s. 1, ch. 97-215; s. 66, ch. 97-238; s. 26, ch. 98-207; s. 19, ch. 99-284; s. 25, ch. 2000-122; s. 48, ch. 2000-135; s. 1940, ch. 2003-261; s. 90, ch. 2006-120; s. 9, ch. 2006-296; s. 13, ch. 2011-70.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.024; s. 985.406.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>