<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fingerprinting and photographing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is charged with or found to have committed an offense that would be a felony if committed by an adult shall be fingerprinted and the fingerprints must be submitted to the Department of Law Enforcement as provided in s. 943.051(3)(a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is charged with or found to have committed one of the following offenses shall be fingerprinted, and the fingerprints shall be submitted to the Department of Law Enforcement as provided in s. 943.051(3)(b):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assault, as defined in s. 784.011.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Battery, as defined in s. 784.03.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carrying a concealed weapon, as defined in s. 790.01(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawful use of destructive devices or bombs, as defined in s. 790.1615(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Negligent treatment of children, as defined in former s. 827.05.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assault on a law enforcement officer, a firefighter, or other specified officers, as defined in s. 784.07(2)(a).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Open carrying of a weapon, as defined in s. 790.053.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exposure of sexual organs, as defined in s. 800.03.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawful possession of a firearm, as defined in s. 790.22(5).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petit theft, as defined in s. 812.014.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cruelty to animals, as defined in s. 828.12(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arson, resulting in bodily harm to a firefighter, as defined in s. 806.031(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawful possession or discharge of a weapon or firearm at a school-sponsored event or on school property as defined in s. 790.115.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A law enforcement agency may fingerprint and photograph a child taken into custody upon probable cause that such child has committed any other violation of law, as the agency deems appropriate. Such fingerprint records and photographs shall be retained by the law enforcement agency in a separate file, and these records and all copies thereof must be marked “Juvenile Confidential.” These records are not available for public disclosure and inspection under s. 119.07(1) except as provided in ss. 943.053 and 985.04(2), but shall be available to other law enforcement agencies, criminal justice agencies, state attorneys, the courts, the child, the parents or legal custodians of the child, their attorneys, and any other person authorized by the court to have access to such records. In addition, such records may be submitted to the Department of Law Enforcement for inclusion in the state criminal history records and used by criminal justice agencies for criminal justice purposes. These records may, in the discretion of the court, be open to inspection by anyone upon a showing of cause. The fingerprint and photograph records shall be produced in the court whenever directed by the court. Any photograph taken pursuant to this section may be shown by a law enforcement officer to any victim or witness of a crime for the purpose of identifying the person who committed such crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall be responsible for the fingerprinting of any child at the disposition hearing if the child has been adjudicated or had adjudication withheld for any felony in the case currently before the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is not referred to the court, or if the child is found not to have committed a violation of law, the court may, after notice to the law enforcement agency involved, order the originals and copies of the fingerprints and photographs destroyed. Unless otherwise ordered by the court, if the child is found to have committed an offense which would be a felony if it had been committed by an adult, then the law enforcement agency having custody of the fingerprint and photograph records shall retain the originals and immediately thereafter forward adequate duplicate copies to the court along with the written offense report relating to the matter for which the child was taken into custody. Except as otherwise provided by this subsection, the clerk of the court, after the disposition hearing on the case, shall forward duplicate copies of the fingerprints and photographs, together with the child’s name, address, date of birth, age, and sex, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff of the county in which the child was taken into custody, in order to maintain a central child identification file in that county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement agency of each municipality having a population in excess of 50,000 persons and located in the county of arrest, if so requested specifically or by a general request by that agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the fingerprinting or photographing of child traffic violators. All records of such traffic violations shall be kept in the full name of the violator and shall be open to inspection and publication in the same manner as adult traffic violations. This section does not apply to the photographing of children by the Department of Juvenile Justice or the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 6, ch. 93-204; s. 28, ch. 94-209; s. 8, ch. 95-267; s. 2, ch. 96-293; s. 20, ch. 96-322; s. 17, ch. 96-388; s. 13, ch. 96-406; s. 162, ch. 97-101; s. 20, ch. 97-238; s. 14, ch. 99-284; s. 2, ch. 2002-51; s. 17, ch. 2006-120; s. 7, ch. 2007-112.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.039; s. 985.212.</Text></Note></Section>