<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.711" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Introduction, removal, or possession of certain articles unlawful; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as authorized through program policy or operating procedure or as authorized by the facility superintendent, program director, or manager, a person may not introduce into or upon the grounds of a juvenile detention facility or commitment program, or take or send, or attempt to take or send, from a juvenile detention facility or commitment program, any of the following articles, which are declared to be contraband under this section:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unauthorized article of food or clothing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any intoxicating beverage or any beverage that causes or may cause an intoxicating effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any controlled substance, as defined in s. 893.02(4), or any prescription or nonprescription drug that has a hypnotic, stimulating, or depressing effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firearm or weapon of any kind or any explosive substance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not transmit contraband to, cause contraband to be transmitted to or received by, attempt to transmit contraband to, or attempt to cause contraband to be transmitted to or received by, a juvenile offender into or upon the grounds of a juvenile detention facility or commitment program, except as authorized through program policy or operating procedures or as authorized by the facility superintendent, program director, or manager.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A juvenile offender or any person, while upon the grounds of a juvenile detention facility or commitment program, may not be in actual or constructive possession of any article or thing declared to be contraband under this section, except as authorized through program policy or operating procedures or as authorized by the facility superintendent, program director, or manager.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section as it pertains to an article of contraband described in subparagraph (1)(a)1. commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. In all other cases, a person who violates this section commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 97-215; s. 98, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 985.4046.</Text></Note></Section>