<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.437" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restitution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court that has jurisdiction over an adjudicated delinquent child may, by an order stating the facts upon which a determination of a sanction and rehabilitative program was made at the disposition hearing, order the child to make restitution in the manner provided in this section. This order shall be part of the probation program to be implemented by the department or, in the case of a committed child, as part of the community-based sanctions ordered by the court at the disposition hearing or before the child’s release from commitment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order the child to make restitution in money, through a promissory note cosigned by the child’s parent or guardian, or in kind for any damage or loss caused by the child’s offense in a reasonable amount or manner to be determined by the court. When restitution is ordered by the court, the amount of restitution may not exceed an amount the child and the parent or guardian could reasonably be expected to pay or make.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the circuit court shall be the receiving and dispensing agent. In such case, the court shall order the child or the child’s parent or guardian to pay to the office of the clerk of the circuit court an amount not to exceed the actual cost incurred by the clerk as a result of receiving and dispensing restitution payments. The clerk shall notify the court if restitution is not made, and the court shall take any further action that is necessary against the child or the child’s parent or guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A finding by the court, after a hearing, that the parent or guardian has made diligent and good faith efforts to prevent the child from engaging in delinquent acts absolves the parent or guardian of liability for restitution under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may retain jurisdiction over a child and the child’s parent or legal guardian whom the court has ordered to pay restitution until the restitution order is satisfied or until the court orders otherwise, as provided in s. 985.0301.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 47, ch. 2006-120.</History></Section>