<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.265" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Detention transfer and release; education; adult jails.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is detained under this part, the department may transfer the child from nonsecure or home detention care to secure detention care only if significantly changed circumstances warrant such transfer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is on release status and not detained under this part, the child may be placed into secure, nonsecure, or home detention care only pursuant to a court hearing in which the original risk assessment instrument, rescored based on newly discovered evidence or changed circumstances with the results recommending detention, is introduced into evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a juvenile sexual offender is placed in detention, detention staff shall provide appropriate monitoring and supervision to ensure the safety of other children in the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a juvenile sexual offender, under this subsection, is released from detention or transferred to home detention or nonsecure detention, detention staff shall immediately notify the appropriate law enforcement agency and school personnel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While a child who is currently enrolled in school is in nonsecure or home detention care, the child shall continue to attend school unless otherwise ordered by the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While a child is in secure detention care, the child shall receive education commensurate with his or her grade level and educational ability.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall order the delivery of a child to a jail or other facility intended or used for the detention of adults:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the child has been transferred or indicted for criminal prosecution as an adult under part X, except that the court may not order or allow a child alleged to have committed a misdemeanor who is being transferred for criminal prosecution pursuant to either s. 985.556 or s. 985.557 to be detained or held in a jail or other facility intended or used for the detention of adults; however, such child may be held temporarily in a detention facility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a child taken into custody in this state is wanted by another jurisdiction for prosecution as an adult.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The child shall be housed separately from adult inmates to prohibit a child from having regular contact with incarcerated adults, including trustees. “Regular contact” means sight and sound contact. Separation of children from adults shall permit no more than haphazard or accidental contact. The receiving jail or other facility shall contain a separate section for children and shall have an adequate staff to supervise and monitor the child’s activities at all times. Supervision and monitoring of children includes physical observation and documented checks by jail or receiving facility supervisory personnel at intervals not to exceed 15 minutes. This subsection does not prohibit placing two or more children in the same cell. Under no circumstances shall a child be placed in the same cell with an adult.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 3, ch. 93-408; ss. 29, 31, ch. 94-209; s. 1342, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 95-266; s. 44, ch. 95-267; s. 5, ch. 96-398; ss. 21, 23, ch. 97-238; s. 13, ch. 98-207; s. 36, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1), (2), (3) former s. 39.044(8), (9), (11); s. 985.215(8), (9), (11). Subsection (4) former s. 39.042(3); s. 985.213(3). Subsection (5) former s. 39.044(4); s. 985.215(4).</Text></Note></Section>