<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.039" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cost of supervision; cost of care.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (3) or subsection (4):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any child is placed into home detention, probation, or other supervision status with the department, or is committed to the minimum-risk nonresidential restrictiveness level, the court shall order the parent of such child to pay to the department a fee for the cost of the supervision of such child in the amount of $1 per day for each day that the child is in such status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any child is placed into secure detention or placed on committed status and the temporary legal custody of such child is placed with the department, the court shall order the parent of such child to pay to the department a fee for the cost of the care of such child in the amount of $5 per day for each day that the child is in the temporary legal custody of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent of any child who has been placed under the supervision or care of the department shall provide to the department his or her name, address, social security number, date of birth, driver’s license number or identification card number, and sufficient financial information so as to assist the court in determining the parent’s ability to pay any fee associated with the cost of the child’s supervision or care. If the parent refuses to provide the department with the information required by this subsection, the court shall order the parent to provide such information. The failure of the parent to comply with such order of the court constitutes contempt of court, and the court may punish the parent accordingly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of any detention or disposition hearing, the court shall receive the information described in subsection (2), as well as any other verbal or written information offered as to the ability of the parent of a child who is being placed under the supervision or care of the department to pay any fee imposed pursuant to this section and whether the payment of such fee will create a significant financial hardship. The court may apportion the obligation for the fee to each parent in a manner it deems appropriate; however, the total amount of the daily fee may not exceed the amounts specified in this section. Any finding made by the court as to the ability of the parent to pay such fee, including any finding of indigency or significant financial hardship, shall be in writing and shall contain a detailed description of the facts supporting such finding. If the court makes a finding of indigency and significant financial hardship, the court shall waive the fee or reduce it to an amount deemed appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (3), the court may reduce or waive the fee as to each parent if the court makes a finding on the record that the parent was the victim of the delinquent act or violation of law for which the child has been placed under the supervision or care of the department and that the parent is cooperating or has cooperated with the investigation of the offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall order the payment of any fees required in this section as part of the detention or disposition order. Such order must include specific written findings as to what fees are ordered, reduced, or waived. If the court fails to enter an order as required by this section, the parent is deemed to have an obligation to pay to the department a fee in the amount of $1 per day for each day that the child is under the supervision of the department and $5 per day for each day that the child remains in the care of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), with respect to a child who reaches the age of 18 prior to the detention or disposition hearing, the court may elect to direct an order required by this section to such child, rather than to the child’s parent. With regard to a child who reaches 18 while under the supervision or care of the department, the court may, upon proper motion of any party, hold a hearing as to whether any party should be further obligated to pay any fee associated with cost of the supervision or care of such child. If the court does not enter an order under this subsection, it shall be presumed that the court intended for the parent to pay or to continue to pay the fees specified in this section. Any order entered pursuant to this subsection must include specific findings as to what fees are ordered, reduced, or waived as to the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a child who has been placed under the supervision or care of the department and whose parent receives public assistance for any portion of such child’s care, the department must seek a federal waiver to garnish or otherwise order the payment of a portion of the public assistance relating to such child, in an amount not to exceed the amount of the parent’s obligation, in order to offset the costs to the department associated with providing supervision or care of such child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any order entered pursuant to this section affects the guardianship of an estate, a certified copy of such order shall be delivered to the judge having jurisdiction over the guardianship of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may employ a collection agency for the purpose of receiving, collecting, and managing the payment of any fees ordered pursuant to this section that have gone delinquent or unpaid for 90 days or more. The collection agency must be registered and in good standing under chapter 559. The department may pay for the services of the collection agency from available authorized funds or from funds generated by any collections under this subsection. Alternatively, the department may authorize the collection agency to withhold a specified amount of any fee collected as payment for its services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or the collection agency shall provide to the payor documentation of the payment of any fee paid pursuant to this section. Except as provided in subsection (9), all payments received by the department or the collection agency pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the department’s Grants and Donations Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under no circumstance shall the court or the department extend the child’s length of stay in the department’s supervision or care solely for the purpose of collecting the fees specified in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No parent or child shall be liable for any fee provided in this section unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child is adjudicated delinquent, or has adjudication of delinquency withheld, for the offense that gave rise to the supervision or care; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child is found to have violated an order of the court, including any order of supervision or care, and the costs are associated with the violation of such order.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If any funds are paid for the supervision or care of a child who is determined not to meet the criteria specified in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), such funds shall be refunded to the payor forthwith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, “parent” means any person who meets the definition of “parent” or “legal custody or guardian” in s. 985.03.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-241; s. 7, ch. 2005-263; s. 11, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 985.2311.</Text></Note></Section>