<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community arbitration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The purpose of community arbitration is to provide a system by which children who commit delinquent acts may be dealt with in a speedy and informal manner at the community or neighborhood level, in an attempt to reduce the ever-increasing instances of delinquent acts and permit the judicial system to deal effectively with cases which are more serious in nature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAMS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county may establish community arbitration programs designed to complement the department’s intake process provided in this chapter. Community arbitration programs shall provide one or more community arbitrators or community arbitration panels to hear informally cases which involve alleged commissions of certain delinquent acts by children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cases which may be referred to a community arbitrator or community arbitration panel are limited to those which involve violations of local ordinances, those which involve misdemeanors, and those which involve third degree felonies, exclusive of third degree felonies involving personal violence, grand theft auto, or the use of a weapon.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who has been the subject of at least one prior adjudication or adjudication withheld for any first or second degree felony offense, any third degree felony offense involving personal violence, grand theft auto, or the use of a weapon, or any other offense not eligible for arbitration, shall not be eligible for resolution of any current offense through community arbitration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cases resolved through community arbitration shall be limited pursuant to this subsection.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each child referred to community arbitration, the primary offense shall be assigned a point value.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misdemeanor offenses shall be assigned two points for a misdemeanor of the second degree, four points for a nonviolent misdemeanor of the first degree, and six points for a misdemeanor of the first degree involving violence.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible third degree felony offenses shall be assigned eight points.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is not a restriction on the limit of separate incidents for which a law enforcement officer may refer a child to community arbitration, but a child who has accrued a point value of 12 or more points through community arbitration prior to the current offense shall no longer be eligible for community arbitration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The point values provided in this paragraph shall also be assigned to a child’s prior adjudications or adjudications withheld on eligible offenses for cases not referred to community arbitration.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMMUNITY ARBITRATORS.<EmDash />The chief judge of each judicial circuit shall maintain a list of qualified persons who have agreed to serve as community arbitrators for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter. Community arbitrators shall meet the qualification and training requirements adopted in rule by the Supreme Court. Whenever possible, qualified volunteers shall be used as community arbitrators.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each community arbitrator or member of a community arbitration panel shall be selected by the chief judge of the circuit, the senior circuit court judge assigned to juvenile cases in the circuit, and the state attorney. A community arbitrator or, in the case of a panel, the chief arbitrator shall have such powers as are necessary to conduct the proceedings in a fair and expeditious manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community arbitrator or member of a community arbitration panel shall be trained or experienced in juvenile causes and shall be:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Either a graduate of an accredited law school or of an accredited school with a degree in behavioral social work or trained in conflict resolution techniques; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person of the temperament necessary to deal properly with cases involving children and with the family crises likely to be presented to him or her.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROCEDURE FOR INITIATING CASES FOR COMMUNITY ARBITRATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer may issue a complaint, along with a recommendation for community arbitration, against any child who such officer has reason to believe has committed any offense that is eligible for community arbitration. The complaint shall specify the offense and the reasons why the law enforcement officer feels that the offense should be handled by community arbitration. Any juvenile probation officer or, at the request of the child’s parent or legal custodian or guardian, the state attorney or the court having jurisdiction, with the concurrence of the state attorney, may refer a complaint to be handled by community arbitration when appropriate. A copy of the complaint shall be forwarded to the appropriate juvenile probation officer and the parent or legal custodian or guardian of the child within 48 hours after issuance of the complaint. In addition to the complaint, the child and the parent or legal custodian or guardian shall be informed of the objectives of the community arbitration process; the conditions, procedures, and timeframes under which it will be conducted; and the fact that it is not obligatory. The juvenile probation officer shall contact the child and the parent or legal custodian or guardian within 2 days after the date on which the complaint was received. At this time, the child or the parent or legal custodian or guardian shall inform the juvenile probation officer of the decision to approve or reject the handling of the complaint through community arbitration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juvenile probation officer shall verify accurate identification of the child and determine whether or not the child has any prior adjudications or adjudications withheld for an offense eligible for community arbitration for consideration in the point value structure. If the child has at least one prior adjudication or adjudication withheld for an offense which is not eligible for community arbitration, or if the child has already surpassed the accepted level of points on prior community arbitration resolutions, the juvenile probation officer shall consult with the state attorney regarding the filing of formal juvenile proceedings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child or the parent or legal custodian or guardian rejects the handling of the complaint through community arbitration, the juvenile probation officer shall consult with the state attorney for the filing of formal juvenile proceedings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child or the parent or legal custodian or guardian accepts the handling of the complaint through community arbitration, the juvenile probation officer shall provide copies of the complaint to the arbitrator or panel within 24 hours.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The community arbitrator or community arbitration panel shall, upon receipt of the complaint, set a time and date for a hearing within 7 days and shall inform the child’s parent or legal custodian or guardian, the complaining witness, and any victims of the time, date, and place of the hearing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEARINGS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement officer who issued the complaint need not appear at the scheduled hearing. However, prior to the hearing, the officer shall file with the community arbitrator or the community arbitration panel a comprehensive report setting forth the facts and circumstances surrounding the allegation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records and reports submitted by interested agencies and parties, including, but not limited to, complaining witnesses and victims, may be received in evidence before the community arbitrator or the community arbitration panel without the necessity of formal proof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The testimony of the complaining witness and any alleged victim may be received when available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statement or admission made by the child appearing before the community arbitrator or the community arbitration panel relating to the offense for which he or she was cited is privileged and may not be used as evidence against the child either in a subsequent juvenile proceeding or in any subsequent civil or criminal action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child fails to appear on the original hearing date, the matter shall be referred back to the juvenile probation officer who shall consult with the state attorney regarding the filing of formal juvenile proceedings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISPOSITION OF CASES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent to any hearing held as provided in subsection (5), the community arbitrator or community arbitration panel may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend that the state attorney decline to prosecute the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a warning to the child or the child’s family and recommend that the state attorney decline to prosecute the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the child for placement in a community-based nonresidential program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the child or the family to community counseling.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the child to a safety and education program related to delinquent children.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the child to a work program related to delinquent children and require up to 100 hours of work by the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the child to a nonprofit organization for volunteer work in the community and require up to 100 hours of work by the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order restitution in money or in kind in a case involving property damage; however, the amount of restitution shall not exceed the amount of actual damage to property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continue the case for further investigation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the child to undergo urinalysis monitoring.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose any other restrictions or sanctions that are designed to encourage responsible and acceptable behavior and are agreed upon by the participants of the community arbitration proceedings.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The community arbitrator or community arbitration panel shall determine an appropriate timeframe in which the disposition must be completed. The community arbitrator or community arbitration panel shall report the disposition of the case to the juvenile probation officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or agency to whom a child is referred pursuant to this section shall periodically report the progress of the child to the referring community arbitrator or community arbitration panel in the manner prescribed by such arbitrator or panel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any child who is referred by the community arbitrator or community arbitration panel to a work program related to delinquent children or to a nonprofit organization for volunteer work in the community, and who is also ordered to pay restitution to the victim, may be paid a reasonable hourly wage for work, to the extent that funds are specifically appropriated or authorized for this purpose; provided, however, that such payments shall not, in total, exceed the amount of restitution ordered and that such payments shall be turned over by the child to the victim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child consents to an informal resolution and, in the presence of the parent or legal custodian or guardian and the community arbitrator or community arbitration panel, agrees to comply with any disposition suggested or ordered by such arbitrator or panel and subsequently fails to abide by the terms of such agreement, the community arbitrator or community arbitration panel may, after a careful review of the circumstances, forward the case back to the juvenile probation officer, who shall consult with the state attorney regarding the filing of formal juvenile proceedings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVIEW.<EmDash />Any child or his or her parent or legal custodian or guardian who is dissatisfied with the disposition provided by the community arbitrator or the community arbitration panel may request a review of the disposition to the appropriate juvenile probation officer within 15 days after the community arbitration hearing. Upon receipt of the request for review, the juvenile probation officer shall consult with the state attorney who shall consider the request for review and may file formal juvenile proceedings or take such other action as may be warranted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING.<EmDash />Funding for the provisions of community arbitration may be provided through appropriations from the state or from local governments, through federal or other public or private grants, through any appropriations as authorized by the county participating in the community arbitration program, and through donations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-208; s. 48, ch. 97-238; s. 20, ch. 98-207; s. 133, ch. 99-3; s. 27, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.026; s. 985.304.</Text></Note></Section>