<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.676" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community juvenile justice partnership grants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GRANTS; CRITERIA.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to encourage the development of county and circuit juvenile justice plans and the development and implementation of county and circuit interagency agreements under s. 985.664, the community juvenile justice partnership grant program is established and shall be administered by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In awarding these grants, the department shall consider applications that at a minimum provide for the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The participation of the agencies and programs needed to implement the project or program for which the applicant is applying;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reduction of truancy and in-school and out-of-school suspensions and expulsions, the enhancement of school safety, and other delinquency early-intervention and diversion services;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of youths from 10 through 17 years of age within the geographic area to be served by the program, giving those geographic areas having the highest number of youths from 10 to 17 years of age priority for selection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the program targets high-juvenile-crime neighborhoods and those public schools serving juveniles from high-crime neighborhoods;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The validity and cost-effectiveness of the program; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree to which the program is located in and managed by local leaders of the target neighborhoods and public schools serving the target neighborhoods.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, the department may consider the following criteria in awarding grants:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit juvenile justice plan and any county juvenile justice plans that are referred to or incorporated into the circuit plan, including a list of individuals, groups, and public and private entities that participated in the development of the plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The diversity of community entities participating in the development of the circuit juvenile justice plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of community partners who will be actively involved in the operation of the grant program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of students or youths to be served by the grant and the criteria by which they will be selected.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The criteria by which the grant program will be evaluated and, if deemed successful, the feasibility of implementation in other communities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GRANT APPLICATION PROCEDURES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each entity wishing to apply for an annual community juvenile justice partnership grant, which may be renewed for a maximum of 2 additional years for the same provision of services, shall submit a grant proposal for funding or continued funding to the department. The department shall establish the grant application procedures. In order to be considered for funding, the grant proposal shall include the following assurances and information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A letter from the chair of the juvenile justice circuit board confirming that the grant application has been reviewed and found to support one or more purposes or goals of the juvenile justice plan as developed by the board.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rationale and description of the program and the services to be provided, including goals and objectives.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method for identification of the juveniles most likely to be involved in the juvenile justice system who will be the focus of the program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for the participation of parents and guardians in the program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination with other community-based and social service prevention efforts, including, but not limited to, drug and alcohol abuse prevention and dropout prevention programs, that serve the target population or neighborhood.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An evaluation component to measure the effectiveness of the program in accordance with s. 985.632.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A program budget, including the amount and sources of local cash and in-kind resources committed to the budget. The proposal must establish to the satisfaction of the department that the entity will make a cash or in-kind contribution to the program of a value that is at least equal to 20 percent of the amount of the grant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The necessary program staff.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall consider the following in awarding such grants:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recommendations of the juvenile justice county council as to the priority that should be given to proposals submitted by entities within a county.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recommendations of the juvenile justice circuit board as to the priority that should be given to proposals submitted by entities within a circuit.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall make available, to anyone wishing to apply for such a grant, information on all of the criteria to be used in the selection of the proposals for funding pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review all program proposals submitted. Entities submitting proposals shall be notified of approval not later than June 30 of each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each entity that is awarded a grant as provided for in this section shall submit an annual evaluation report to the department, the circuit juvenile justice manager, the juvenile justice circuit board, and the juvenile justice county council, by a date subsequent to the end of the contract period established by the department, documenting the extent to which the program objectives have been met, the effect of the program on the juvenile arrest rate, and any other information required by the department. The department shall coordinate and incorporate all such annual evaluation reports with s. 985.632. Each entity is also subject to a financial audit and a performance audit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish rules and policy provisions necessary to implement this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESTRICTIONS.<EmDash />This section does not prevent a program initiated under a community juvenile justice partnership grant established pursuant to this section from continuing to operate beyond the 3-year maximum funding period if it can find other funding sources. Likewise, this section does not restrict the number of programs an entity may apply for or operate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 75, ch. 97-238; s. 32, ch. 98-207; s. 21, ch. 99-284; s. 52, ch. 2000-135; s. 93, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 985.415.</Text></Note></Section>