<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0985.037" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Punishment for contempt of court; alternative sanctions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTEMPT OF COURT; LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />The court may punish any child for contempt for interfering with the court or with court administration, or for violating any provision of this chapter or order of the court relative thereto. It is the intent of the Legislature that the court restrict and limit the use of contempt powers with respect to commitment of a child to a secure facility. A child who commits direct contempt of court or indirect contempt of a valid court order may be taken into custody and ordered to serve an alternative sanction or placed in a secure facility, as authorized in this section, by order of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PLACEMENT IN A SECURE FACILITY.<EmDash />A child may be placed in a secure facility for purposes of punishment for contempt of court if alternative sanctions are unavailable or inappropriate, or if the child has already been ordered to serve an alternative sanction but failed to comply with the sanction. A delinquent child who has been held in direct or indirect contempt may be placed in a secure detention facility not to exceed 5 days for a first offense and not to exceed 15 days for a second or subsequent offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ALTERNATIVE SANCTIONS.<EmDash />Each judicial circuit shall have an alternative sanctions coordinator who shall serve under the chief administrative judge of the juvenile division of the circuit court, and who shall coordinate and maintain a spectrum of contempt sanction alternatives in conjunction with the circuit plan implemented in accordance with s. 790.22(4)(c). Upon determining that a child has committed direct contempt of court or indirect contempt of a valid court order, the court may immediately request the alternative sanctions coordinator to recommend the most appropriate available alternative sanction and shall order the child to perform up to 50 hours of community-service manual labor or a similar alternative sanction, unless an alternative sanction is unavailable or inappropriate, or unless the child has failed to comply with a prior alternative sanction. Alternative contempt sanctions may be provided by local industry or by any nonprofit organization or any public or private business or service entity that has entered into a contract with the Department of Juvenile Justice to act as an agent of the state to provide voluntary supervision of children on behalf of the state in exchange for the manual labor of children and limited immunity in accordance with s. 768.28(11).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTEMPT OF COURT SANCTIONS; PROCEDURE AND DUE PROCESS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is charged with direct contempt of court, including traffic court, the court may impose an authorized sanction immediately.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is charged with indirect contempt of court, the court must hold a hearing within 24 hours to determine whether the child committed indirect contempt of a valid court order. At the hearing, the following due process rights must be provided to the child:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to a copy of the order to show cause alleging facts supporting the contempt charge.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to an explanation of the nature and the consequences of the proceedings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to legal counsel and the right to have legal counsel appointed by the court if the juvenile is indigent, under s. 985.033.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to confront witnesses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to present witnesses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to have a transcript or record of the proceeding.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Right to appeal to an appropriate court.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The child’s parent or guardian may address the court regarding the due process rights of the child. The court shall review the placement of the child every 72 hours to determine whether it is appropriate for the child to remain in the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may not order that a child be placed in a secure facility for punishment for contempt unless the court determines that an alternative sanction is inappropriate or unavailable or that the child was initially ordered to an alternative sanction and did not comply with the alternative sanction. The court is encouraged to order a child to perform community service, up to the maximum number of hours, where appropriate before ordering that the child be placed in a secure facility as punishment for contempt of court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other sanction imposed under this section, the court may direct the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to withhold issuance of, or suspend, a child’s driver’s license or driving privilege. The court may order that a child’s driver’s license or driving privilege be withheld or suspended for up to 1 year for a first offense of contempt and up to 2 years for a second or subsequent offense. If the child’s driver’s license or driving privilege is suspended or revoked for any reason at the time the sanction for contempt is imposed, the court shall extend the period of suspension or revocation by the additional period ordered under this paragraph. If the child’s driver’s license is being withheld at the time the sanction for contempt is imposed, the period of suspension or revocation ordered under this paragraph shall begin on the date on which the child is otherwise eligible to drive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ALTERNATIVE SANCTIONS COORDINATOR.<EmDash />There is created the position of alternative sanctions coordinator within each judicial circuit, pursuant to subsection (3). Each alternative sanctions coordinator shall serve under the direction of the chief administrative judge of the juvenile division as directed by the chief judge of the circuit. The alternative sanctions coordinator shall act as the liaison between the judiciary, local department officials, district school board employees, and local law enforcement agencies. The alternative sanctions coordinator shall coordinate within the circuit community-based alternative sanctions, including nonsecure detention programs, community service projects, and other juvenile sanctions, in conjunction with the circuit plan implemented in accordance with s. 790.22(4)(c).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 94-209; s. 4, ch. 95-267; s. 24, ch. 97-238; s. 1, ch. 97-281; s. 15, ch. 98-207; s. 10, ch. 2000-134; s. 25, ch. 2000-135; s. 10, ch. 2006-120.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.0145; s. 985.216.</Text></Note></Section>