<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0985.645" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Protective action response.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct care” means direct contact with youth for the purpose of providing care, supervision, custody, or control of youth in a detention facility, delinquency program, or commitment program within any restrictiveness level, which is operated by the department or by a provider under contract with the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” means any person who exercises direct care. The term “employee” does not include a licensed medical professional, mental health counselor, substance abuse counselor, or social services counselor whose primary responsibilities are to provide treatment to youth in a detention facility, delinquency program, or commitment program within any restrictiveness level, which is operated by the department or by a provider under contract with the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Protective Action Response policy” means the policy governing the use of verbal and physical intervention techniques, mechanical restraints, aerosol and chemical agents, and Tasers by employees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Taser” means any mechanism that is designed to emit or project an electronic, magnetic, or other type of charge or shock for the purpose of temporarily incapacitating a person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a Protective Action Response policy that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defines the authorized level of response by an employee to each level of verbal or physical resistance by a youth.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requires the use of verbal intervention techniques as the initial response by an employee to verbal or physical resistance by a youth, except where physical intervention techniques are necessary to prevent:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical harm to the youth, employee, or another person;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property damage; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The youth from escaping or absconding from lawful supervision.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defines authorized physical intervention techniques and the situations under which employees may use these techniques for youth. Pain compliance techniques and use of less than lethal force shall be prohibited, except where necessary to prevent:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical harm to the youth, employee, or another person;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property damage; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The youth from escaping or absconding from lawful supervision.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Lethal force shall be prohibited, except where necessary to protect the employee or another person from an imminent threat of great bodily harm or death. Prior authorization by an employee’s supervisor for the use of physical intervention techniques shall be obtained when practical.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defines authorized use of mechanical restraints and the situations under which employees may use such restraints on youth. Prohibited uses of mechanical restraints shall include the use of neck restraints and the securing of a youth to a fixed object. Supervision requirements for youth who are secured in mechanical restraints shall include constant and direct visual monitoring by an employee for purposes of ensuring youth safety and ascertaining indications by the youth that restraints are no longer necessary. Prior authorization by an employee’s supervisor for the use of mechanical restraints shall be obtained when practical.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prohibits the use of aerosol or chemical agents, including, but not limited to, oleoresin capsicum spray and ammonia capsules, on a youth unless required for medical treatment of the youth by a licensed medical professional.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prohibits the use of a Taser on a youth.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish training curricula for protective action response certification of employees and instructors. The training curriculum for employee certification shall, at a minimum, require the employee to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete instruction on the Protective Action Response policy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain a passing score:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a written examination that tests the employee’s knowledge and understanding of the Protective Action Response policy.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During an evaluation by an instructor of the employee’s physically demonstrated ability to implement the Protective Action Response policy.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require training curricula for protective action response certification of employees to be taught by instructors who have been certified under the training curriculum for protective action response certification of instructors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require each employee who was not certified by the department in protective action response prior to July 1, 2006, to receive his or her protective action response certification by September 30, 2006, or within 90 calendar days following his or her date of hire, whichever date is later.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require any employee who exercises direct care prior to receiving his or her protective action response certification to be directly supervised by an employee who has received his or her protective action response certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2006-62; s. 22, ch. 2010-113.</History>
</Section>