<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0065.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax titles; quieting title.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIES.<EmDash />Any grantee under any tax deed issued by the state, or any municipality or other political subdivision thereof, or any purchaser from the state, or any municipality or other political subdivision thereof, of any land the title to which has been acquired by this state or such municipality or political subdivision through any proceeding or foreclosure for the nonpayment of taxes or special assessments, or the successor in title to the grantee or purchaser, may maintain an action in chancery to quiet title to the land included in the tax deed, or so purchased against the holder of the record title to the land, and against any other person or corporation claiming any interest in the land or any lien or encumbrance thereon, before issuance of the tax deed or before the loss of title to the land in the tax proceeding or foreclosure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DERAIGNING TITLE.<EmDash />Actions may be maintained hereunder whether or not plaintiff is in possession of the land involved but when defendant is in actual possession of the land a jury trial may be had as provided in other actions to quiet title. When the action is based on a tax deed, the complaint need not deraign title beyond the issuance of the tax deed. When the action is based on a conveyance by this state, or any municipality or other political subdivision thereof, of land the title to which it has acquired through a foreclosure or other proceeding for the nonpayment of taxes, the complaint need not deraign title beyond the deed or other instrument or act vesting title in the state or municipality or other political subdivision of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WHEN TAXES HAVE BEEN PAID.<EmDash />No defense to the action or attack upon the tax deed shall be made except the defense that the taxes assessed against the property had been paid by the former owner before issuance of the tax deed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WHEN TAX DEED HAS BEEN ISSUED BEFORE CONVEYANCE BY SOVEREIGN.<EmDash />No defense shall be made to the action because of assessment of the property or issuance of the tax deed before the United States or the state has parted with title to the property, and no other attack shall be made on it, except the defense that the taxes assessed against the property had been paid by the person, or a claimant under him or her, to whom the United States patent or conveyance from the state was issued before the issuance of the tax deed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 21822, 1943; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 20, ch. 67-254; s. 29, ch. 74-382; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 347, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 66.26, 66.27.</Text></Note></Section>