<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0753.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards for supervised visitation and supervised exchange programs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within existing funds from the department, the clearinghouse shall develop standards for supervised visitation programs in order to ensure the safety and quality of each program. Standards must be uniform for all the programs and must address the purposes, policies, standards of practice, program content, security measures, qualifications of providers, training standards, credentials and background screening requirements of staff, information to be provided to the court, and data collection for supervised visitation programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clearinghouse shall use an advisory board to assist in developing the standards. The advisory board must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members of the executive board of the state chapter of the Supervised Visitation Network, appointed by the president of the state chapter of the Supervised Visitation Network.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Office of the State Courts Administrator, appointed by the State Courts Administrator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the department, appointed by the secretary of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Florida Coalition Against Domestic Violence, appointed by the executive director of the Florida Coalition Against Domestic Violence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of a local law enforcement agency, appointed by the executive director of the Florida Sheriffs Association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A circuit court judge who presides over domestic violence proceedings, appointed by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A circuit court judge who presides over dependency proceedings, appointed by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two representatives of a supervised visitation program, appointed by the director of the clearinghouse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Statewide Guardian Ad Litem Office, appointed by the executive director of the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clearinghouse, in consultation with the advisory board, shall develop criteria and procedures for approving and rejecting certification applications for and monitoring compliance with the certification of a supervised visitation program. The clearinghouse shall recommend the process for phasing in the implementation of the standards and certification procedures and the criteria for distributing funds to eligible programs and designating the state entity that should certify and monitor the supervised visitation programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2007-109; s. 50, ch. 2011-213; s. 82, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>