<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0753.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Referrals involving child sexual abuse.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any supervised visitation program that wishes to accept referrals involving child sexual abuse must have an agreement with the court and a current affidavit of compliance on file with the chief judge of the circuit in which the program is located affirming that the program has agreed to comply with the minimum standards contained in an administrative order issued by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court on November 17, 1999, and provided the program has a written agreement with the court and with the department that contains policies and guidelines specifically related to child sexual abuse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement must include provisions for the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program staff who supervise visits or other contact must have specific training in child sexual abuse provided through the Clearinghouse on Supervised Visitation documented in personnel files.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must have protocols for obtaining background material on the family prior to the initiation of services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must accept only those child sexual abuse referrals for which staff have the requisite background material, training, and security in place to safely monitor contact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must decline referrals of child sexual abuse cases when staff lack necessary training or education, when background material has not been received, or when lack of security may allow revictimization of the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must suspend visits in cases when the child appears to be traumatized by the visits or when the individual visiting or having other contact engages in inappropriate behavior or violates program rules.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2007-109.</History></Section>