<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0923.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Indictment and information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following forms of indictment and information, in all cases to which they are applicable, shall be deemed sufficient, as a charge of the offense to which they relate as defined by the laws of this state, and analogous forms may be used in all other cases:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to first degree murder:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">In the name and by the authority of the State of Florida: The Grand Jurors of the County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> charge that A. B. unlawfully and from a premeditated design to effect the death of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> (or while robbing the house of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> as the case may be) did murder <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> in said county, by shooting her or him with a gun or pistol (or by striking her or him with a club—or by giving her or him poison to drink—or by pushing her or him into the water whereby she or he was drowned).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to second degree murder:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Unlawfully by an act imminently dangerous to another, and evincing a depraved mind, regardless of human life; that is to say, by firing her or his shotgun into the store of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> (or by striking <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> with an adz, as the case may be) but without a premeditated design to effect the death of any particular person, did kill <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> in said county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to third degree murder:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Unlawfully, and while feloniously stealing cattle (or timber, or while feloniously assaulting <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> as the case may be), but without any design to effect death, did kill <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> in said county, by sinking her or his boat (or by running over her or him with an automobile—or by shooting her or him with a gun or pistol, as the case may be).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to manslaughter:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Unlawfully and by culpable negligence, in driving an automobile (or firing a boiler—or by performing a surgical operation) or (in the heat of passion—omitting in this latter case the allegation of culpable negligence), but without intent to murder, did kill <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> in said county, by running over her or him with said automobile (or by causing said boiler to explode—or by infecting her or him with a deadly infection—or by striking her or him with a hammer).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to perjury:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">In the hearing of a cause in the <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> court of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida, in which <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> and others were plaintiffs and <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> others were defendants, after being duly sworn to speak the truth, falsely swore, etc. (stating the substance of the false testimony), such matter being material in said cause, and the said <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> then and there knowing that she or he swore falsely.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An information shall be in the same form and signed by the state attorney who shall also append thereto the oath of the state attorney to the effect following:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally appeared before me <Directions xml:space="preserve">(official title of state attorney)</Directions> who, being first duly sworn, says that the allegations as set forth in the foregoing information are based upon facts that have been sworn to as true and which, if true, would constitute the offense therein charged.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The affidavit shall be made by the state attorney before some person qualified to administer an oath.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 279(1-2), ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(289); s. 38, ch. 73-334; s. 1553, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>