<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0923.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each committing trial court judge at the time commitment papers are sent by her or him to the proper trial court, and the sheriff when an arrest is made, other than on a capias, shall transmit to the prosecuting attorney of the trial court having jurisdiction, a report in the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">CRIMINAL REPORT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Date: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name and address of defendant: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Age: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. If under 18, give name and address of parent, next friend, or guardian: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name of offense, such as murder, assault, robbery, etc.: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Date and place where committed: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Value of property stolen: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Kind of property stolen: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Kind of building robbed: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name and address of owner of property stolen or building robbed: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name and address of occupant of building robbed: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name of party assaulted or murdered: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Weapon used in assault or murder: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Exhibits taken at scene of crime or from defendant: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name of custodian of such exhibits: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Location of building or place where offense committed: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Previous prison record of defendant: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Has defendant been arrested: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Does defendant desire to plead guilty: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Names and addresses of state witnesses: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name of defendant’s lawyer: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> If defendant is released on bond, names and addresses of sureties: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Brief statement of facts: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Name of committing trial court judge: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> If additional space required, use reverse side of this sheet.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of party making this report.)</Directions></Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 277, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(287); s. 70, ch. 77-121; s. 1551, ch. 97-102; s. 34, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>