<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment Security Administration Trust Fund; appropriation; reimbursement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EMPLOYMENT SECURITY ADMINISTRATION TRUST FUND.<EmDash />There is created in the State Treasury the “Employment Security Administration Trust Fund.” All moneys deposited into this fund remain continuously available to the Department of Economic Opportunity for expenditure in accordance with this chapter and do not revert at any time and may not be transferred to any other fund. All moneys in this fund which are received from the Federal Government or any federal agency or which are appropriated by this state under ss. 443.171 and 443.181, except money received under s. 443.191(5)(c), must be expended solely for the purposes and in the amounts found necessary by the authorized cooperating federal agencies for the proper and efficient administration of this chapter. The fund consists of: all moneys appropriated by this state; all moneys received from the United States or any federal agency; all moneys received from any other source for the administration of this chapter; any funds collected for enhanced, specialized, or value-added labor market information services; any moneys received from any agency of the United States or any other state as compensation for services or facilities supplied to that agency; any amounts received from any surety bond or insurance policy or from other sources for losses sustained by the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund or by reason of damage to equipment or supplies purchased from moneys in the fund; and any proceeds from the sale or disposition of such equipment or supplies. All money requisitioned and deposited in this fund under s. 443.191(5)(c) remains part of the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund and must be used only in accordance with s. 443.191(5). All moneys in this fund must be deposited, administered, and disbursed in the same manner and under the same conditions and requirements as provided by law for other trust funds in the State Treasury. These moneys must be secured by the depositary in which they are held to the same extent and in the same manner as required by the general depositary law of the state, and collateral pledged must be maintained in a separate custody account. All payments from the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund must be approved by the Department of Economic Opportunity or by an authorized agent and must be made by the Chief Financial Officer. Any balances in this fund do not revert at any time and must remain continuously available to the Department of Economic Opportunity for expenditure consistent with this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPECIAL EMPLOYMENT SECURITY ADMINISTRATION TRUST FUND.<EmDash />There is created in the State Treasury the “Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund,” into which shall be deposited or transferred all interest on contributions and reimbursements, penalties, and fines or fees collected under this chapter. Interest on contributions and reimbursements, penalties, and fines or fees deposited during any calendar quarter in the clearing account in the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund shall, as soon as practicable after the close of that calendar quarter and upon certification of the Department of Economic Opportunity, be transferred to the Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund. The amount certified by the Department of Economic Opportunity as required under this chapter to pay refunds of interest on contributions and reimbursements, penalties, and fines or fees collected and erroneously deposited into the clearing account in the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund shall, however, be withheld from this transfer. The interest and penalties certified for transfer are deemed as being erroneously deposited in the clearing account, and their transfer to the Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund is deemed to be a refund of the erroneous deposits. All moneys in this fund shall be deposited, administered, and disbursed in the same manner and under the same requirements as provided by law for other trust funds in the State Treasury. These moneys may not be expended or be available for expenditure in any manner that would permit their substitution for, or permit a corresponding reduction in, federal funds that would, in the absence of these moneys, be available to finance expenditures for the administration of this chapter. This section does not prevent these moneys from being used as a revolving fund to cover lawful expenditures for which federal funds are requested but not yet received, subject to the charging of the expenditures against the funds when received. The moneys in this fund, with the approval of the Executive Office of the Governor, shall be used by the Department of Economic Opportunity for paying administrative costs that are not chargeable against funds obtained from federal sources. All moneys in the Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund shall be continuously available to the Department of Economic Opportunity for expenditure in accordance with this chapter and do not revert at any time. All payments from the Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund must be approved by the Department of Economic Opportunity or by an authorized agent and shall be made by the Chief Financial Officer. The moneys in this fund are available to replace, as contemplated by subsection (3), expenditures from the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund which the United States Secretary of Labor, or other authorized federal agency or authority, finds are lost or improperly expended because of any action or contingency. The Chief Financial Officer is liable on her or his official bond for the faithful performance of her or his duties in connection with the Special Employment Security Administration Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REIMBURSEMENT OF FUND.<EmDash />If any moneys received from the United States Secretary of Labor under 42 U.S.C. ss. 501-504, any unencumbered balances in the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund, any moneys granted to this state under the Wagner-Peyser Act, or any moneys made available by this state or its political subdivisions and matched by the moneys granted to this state under the Wagner-Peyser Act, are after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing, found by the United States Secretary of Labor, because of any action or contingency, to be lost or expended for purposes other than, or in amounts in excess of, those allowed by the United States Secretary of Labor for the administration of this chapter, these moneys shall be replaced by moneys appropriated for that purpose from the General Revenue Fund to the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund for expenditure as provided in subsection (1). Upon receipt of notice of such a finding by the United States Secretary of Labor, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall promptly report the amount required for replacement to the Governor. The Governor shall, at the earliest opportunity, submit to the Legislature a request for the appropriation of the replacement funds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESPONSIBILITY FOR TRUST FUNDS.<EmDash />In connection with its duties under s. 443.181, the Department of Economic Opportunity is responsible for the deposit, requisition, expenditure, approval of payment, reimbursement, and reporting in regard to the trust funds established by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 18402, 1937; s. 9, ch. 19637, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(501); s. 13, ch. 20685, 1941; s. 4, ch. 24084, 1947; s. 1, ch. 25206, 1949; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; ss. 10, 11, ch. 29771, 1955; s. 4, ch. 59-99; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 17, 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-215; s. 139, ch. 79-190; ss. 6, 8, 9, ch. 80-95; s. 16, ch. 83-174; s. 13, ch. 85-61; s. 5, ch. 95-345; s. 144, ch. 97-103; s. 38, ch. 98-34; s. 108, ch. 2000-165; s. 45, ch. 2003-36; s. 498, ch. 2003-261; s. 6, ch. 2004-235; s. 378, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 443.14.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>