<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reciprocal arrangements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity or its tax collection service provider may enter into reciprocal arrangements with other states or with the Federal Government, or both, for considering services performed by an individual for a single employing unit for which services are performed by the individual in more than one state as services performed entirely within any one of the states:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which any part of the individual’s service is performed;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which the individual has her or his residence; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which the employing unit maintains a place of business.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For services to be considered as performed within a state under a reciprocal agreement, the employing unit must have an election in effect for those services, which is approved by the agency charged with the administration of such state’s reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law, under which all the services performed by the individual for the employing unit are deemed to be performed entirely within that state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall participate in any arrangements for the payment of compensation on the basis of combining an individual’s wages and employment covered under this chapter with her or his wages and employment covered under the reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation laws of other states, which are approved by the United States Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the state reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation agencies, as reasonably calculated to assure the prompt and full payment of compensation in those situations and which include provisions for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applying the base period of a single state law to a claim involving the combining of an individual’s wages and employment covered under two or more state reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation laws; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Avoiding the duplicate use of wages and employment because of the combination.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributions or reimbursements due under this chapter with respect to wages for insured work are, for the purposes of ss. 443.131, 443.1312, 443.1313, and 443.141, deemed to be paid to the fund as of the date payment was made as contributions or reimbursements therefor under another state or federal reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law, but an arrangement may not be entered into unless it contains provisions for reimbursement to the fund of the contributions or reimbursements and the actual earnings thereon as the department or its tax collection service provider finds are fair and reasonable as to all affected interests.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity or its tax collection service provider may make to other state or federal agencies and receive from these other state or federal agencies reimbursements from or to the fund, in accordance with arrangements entered into under subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity or its tax collection service provider may enter into reciprocal arrangements with other states or the Federal Government, or both, for exchanging services, determining and enforcing payment obligations, and making available facilities and information. The department or its tax collection service provider may conduct investigations, secure and transmit information, make available services and facilities, and exercise other powers provided under this chapter to facilitate the administration of any reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation or public employment service law and, in a similar manner, accept and use information, services, and facilities made available to this state by the agency charged with the administration of any other unemployment compensation or public employment service law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent permissible under federal law, the Department of Economic Opportunity may enter into or cooperate in arrangements whereby facilities and services provided under this chapter and facilities and services provided under the reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law of any foreign government may be used for the taking of claims and the payment of benefits under the employment security law of the state or under a similar law of that government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 18402, 1937; s. 12, ch. 19637, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(505); s. 17, ch. 20685, 1941; s. 6, ch. 24084, 1947; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 1, ch. 29768, 1955; ss. 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 13, ch. 71-225; s. 119, ch. 73-333; ss. 6, 8, 9, ch. 80-95; s. 17, ch. 83-174; s. 6, ch. 95-345; s. 8, ch. 96-378; s. 1068, ch. 97-103; s. 109, ch. 2000-165; s. 46, ch. 2003-36; s. 379, ch. 2011-142; s. 29, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 443.18.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>