<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.1216" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment, as defined in s. 443.036, is subject to this chapter under the following conditions:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes a service performed, including a service performed in interstate commerce, by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer of a corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who, under the usual common-law rules applicable in determining the employer-employee relationship, is an employee. However, whenever a client, as defined in s. 443.036(18), which would otherwise be designated as an employing unit has contracted with an employee leasing company to supply it with workers, those workers are considered employees of the employee leasing company. An employee leasing company may lease corporate officers of the client to the client and other workers to the client, except as prohibited by regulations of the Internal Revenue Service. Employees of an employee leasing company must be reported under the employee leasing company’s tax identification number and contribution rate for work performed for the employee leasing company.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, except for the internal employees of an employee leasing company, each employee leasing company may make a separate one-time election to report and pay contributions under the tax identification number and contribution rate for each client of the employee leasing company. Under the client method, an employee leasing company choosing this option must assign leased employees to the client company that is leasing the employees. The client method is solely a method to report and pay unemployment contributions, and, whichever method is chosen, such election may not impact any other aspect of state law. An employee leasing company that elects the client method must pay contributions at the rates assigned to each client company.</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election applies to all of the employee leasing company’s current and future clients.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee leasing company must notify the Department of Revenue of its election by July 1, 2012, and such election applies to reports and contributions for the first quarter of the following calendar year. The notification must include:</Text>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of each client company and the unemployment account number or, if one has not yet been issued, the federal employment identification number, as established by the employee leasing company upon the election to file by client method;</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of each client company’s current and previous employees and their respective social security numbers for the prior 3 state fiscal years or, if the client company has not been a client for the prior 3 state fiscal years, such portion of the prior 3 state fiscal years that the client company has been a client must be supplied;</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="C">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The wage data and benefit charges associated with each client company for the prior 3 state fiscal years or, if the client company has not been a client for the prior 3 state fiscal years, such portion of the prior 3 state fiscal years that the client company has been a client must be supplied. If the client company’s employment record is chargeable with benefits for less than 8 calendar quarters while being a client of the employee leasing company, the client company must pay contributions at the initial rate of 2.7 percent; and</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="D">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The wage data and benefit charges for the prior 3 state fiscal years that cannot be associated with a client company must be reported and charged to the employee leasing company.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent to choosing the client method, the employee leasing company may not change its reporting method.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee leasing company shall file a Florida Department of Revenue Employer’s Quarterly Report for each client company by approved electronic means, and pay all contributions by approved electronic means.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="V">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of calculating experience rates when the client method is chosen, each client’s own benefit charges and wage data experience while with the employee leasing company determines each client’s tax rate where the client has been a client of the employee leasing company for at least 8 calendar quarters before the election. The client company shall continue to report the nonleased employees under its tax rate.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election is binding on each client of the employee leasing company for as long as a written agreement is in effect between the client and the employee leasing company pursuant to s. 468.525(3)(a). If the relationship between the employee leasing company and the client terminates, the client retains the wage and benefit history experienced under the employee leasing company.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding which election method the employee leasing company chooses, the applicable client company is an employing unit for purposes of s. 443.071. The employee leasing company or any of its officers or agents are liable for any violation of s. 443.071 engaged in by such persons or entities. The applicable client company or any of its officers or agents are liable for any violation of s. 443.071 engaged in by such persons or entities. The employee leasing company or its applicable client company is not liable for any violation of s. 443.071 engaged in by the other party or by the other party’s officers or agents.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VIII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employee leasing company fails to select the client method of reporting not later than July 1, 2012, the entity is required to report under the employee leasing company’s tax identification number and contribution rate.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IX">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After an employee leasing company is licensed pursuant to part XI of chapter 468, each newly licensed entity has 30 days after the date the license is granted to notify the tax collection service provider in writing of their selection of the client method. A newly licensed employee leasing company that fails to timely select reporting pursuant to the client method of reporting must report under the employee leasing company’s tax identification number and contribution rate.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="X">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Irrespective of the election, each transfer of trade or business, including workforce, or a portion thereof, between employee leasing companies is subject to the provisions of s. 443.131(3)(g) if, at the time of the transfer, there is common ownership, management, or control between the entities.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other report required to be filed by law, an employee leasing company shall submit a report to the Labor Market Statistics Center within the Department of Economic Opportunity which includes each client establishment and each establishment of the leasing company, or as otherwise directed by the department. The report must include the following information for each establishment:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trade or establishment name;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The former reemployment assistance account number, if available;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The former federal employer’s identification number, if available;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The industry code recognized and published by the United States Office of Management and Budget, if available;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="V">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the client’s primary business activity in order to verify or assign an industry code;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address of the physical location;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of full-time and part-time employees who worked during, or received pay that was subject to reemployment assistance taxes for, the pay period including the 12th of the month for each month of the quarter;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VIII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total wages subject to reemployment assistance taxes paid during the calendar quarter;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IX">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An internal identification code to uniquely identify each establishment of each client;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="X">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The month and year that the client entered into the contract for services; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The month and year that the client terminated the contract for services.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must be submitted electronically or in a manner otherwise prescribed by the Department of Economic Opportunity in the format specified by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor for its Multiple Worksite Report for Professional Employer Organizations. The report must be provided quarterly to the Labor Market Statistics Center within the department, or as otherwise directed by the department, and must be filed by the last day of the month immediately after the end of the calendar quarter. The information required in sub-sub-subparagraphs b.(X) and (XI) need be provided only in the quarter in which the contract to which it relates was entered into or terminated. The sum of the employment data and the sum of the wage data in this report must match the employment and wages reported in the reemployment assistance quarterly tax and wage report. A report is not required for any calendar quarter preceding the third calendar quarter of 2010.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules as necessary to administer this subparagraph, and may administer, collect, enforce, and waive the penalty imposed by s. 443.141(1)(b) for the report required by this subparagraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “establishment” means any location where business is conducted or where services or industrial operations are performed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual other than an individual who is an employee under subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2., who performs services for remuneration for any person:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an agent-driver or commission-driver engaged in distributing meat products, vegetable products, fruit products, bakery products, beverages other than milk, or laundry or drycleaning services for his or her principal.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a traveling or city salesperson engaged on a full-time basis in the solicitation on behalf of, and the transmission to, his or her principal of orders from wholesalers, retailers, contractors, or operators of hotels, restaurants, or other similar establishments for merchandise for resale or supplies for use in the business operations. This sub-subparagraph does not apply to an agent-driver or a commission-driver and does not apply to sideline sales activities performed on behalf of a person other than the salesperson’s principal.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services described in subparagraph 3. are employment subject to this chapter only if:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract of service contemplates that substantially all of the services are to be performed personally by the individual;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual does not have a substantial investment in facilities used in connection with the services, other than facilities used for transportation; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services are not in the nature of a single transaction that is not part of a continuing relationship with the person for whom the services are performed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, service for which a tax is required to be paid under any federal law imposing a tax against which credit may be taken for contributions required to be paid into a state unemployment fund or which as a condition for full tax credit against the tax imposed by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act is required to be covered under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the services performed during at least one-half of a pay period by an employee for the person employing him or her constitute employment, all of the services performed by the employee during the period are deemed to be employment. If the services performed during more than one-half of the pay period by an employee for the person employing him or her do not constitute employment, all of the services performed by the employee during the period are not deemed to be employment. This paragraph does not apply to services performed in a pay period by an employee for the person employing him or her if any of those services are exempted under paragraph (13)(g).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If two or more related corporations concurrently employ the same individual and compensate the individual through a common paymaster, each related corporation is considered to have paid wages to the individual only in the amounts actually disbursed by that corporation to the individual and is not considered to have paid the wages actually disbursed to the individual by another of the related corporations. The department and the state agency providing reemployment assistance tax collection services may adopt rules necessary to administer this paragraph.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “common paymaster” means a member of a group of related corporations that disburses wages to concurrent employees on behalf of the related corporations and that is responsible for keeping payroll records for those concurrent employees. A common paymaster is not required to disburse wages to all the employees of the related corporations; however, this subparagraph does not apply to wages of concurrent employees which are not disbursed through a common paymaster. A common paymaster must pay concurrently employed individuals under this subparagraph by one combined paycheck.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “concurrent employment” means the existence of simultaneous employment relationships between an individual and related corporations. Those relationships require the performance of services by the employee for the benefit of the related corporations, including the common paymaster, in exchange for wages that, if deductible for the purposes of federal income tax, are deductible by the related corporations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporations are considered related corporations for an entire calendar quarter if they satisfy any one of the following tests at any time during the calendar quarter:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporations are members of a “controlled group of corporations” as defined in s. 1563 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or would be members if s. 1563(a)(4) and (b) did not apply.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a corporation that does not issue stock, at least 50 percent of the members of the board of directors or other governing body of one corporation are members of the board of directors or other governing body of the other corporation or the holders of at least 50 percent of the voting power to select those members are concurrently the holders of at least 50 percent of the voting power to select those members of the other corporation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 50 percent of the officers of one corporation are concurrently officers of the other corporation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 30 percent of the employees of one corporation are concurrently employees of the other corporation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common paymaster must report to the tax collection service provider, as part of the reemployment assistance quarterly tax and wage report, the state reemployment assistance account number and name of each related corporation for which concurrent employees are being reported. Failure to timely report this information shall result in the related corporations being denied common paymaster status for that calendar quarter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common paymaster shall remit contributions due under this chapter for the wages it disburses as the common paymaster. The common paymaster must compute these contributions as though it were the sole employer of the concurrently employed individuals. If a common paymaster fails to timely remit these contributions or reports, in whole or in part, the common paymaster is liable for the full amount of the unpaid portion of these contributions. In addition, each of the other related corporations using the common paymaster is jointly and severally liable for its appropriate share of these contributions. Each related corporation’s share equals the greater of:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The liability of the common paymaster under this chapter, after taking into account any contributions made.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The liability under this chapter which, notwithstanding this section, would have existed for the wages from the other related corporations, reduced by an allocable portion of any contributions previously paid by the common paymaster for those wages.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes service performed in the employ of a public employer as defined in s. 443.036, if the service is excluded from the definition of “employment” in s. 3306(c)(7) of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act and is not excluded from the employment subject to this chapter under subsection (4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes service performed by an individual in the employ of a religious, charitable, educational, or other organization, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is excluded from the definition of “employment” in the Federal Unemployment Tax Act solely by reason of s. 3306(c)(8) of that act; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization had at least four individuals in employment for some portion of a day in each of 20 different weeks during the current or preceding calendar year, regardless of whether the weeks were consecutive and whether the individuals were employed at the same time.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of subsections (2) and (3), the employment subject to this chapter does not apply to service performed:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the employ of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A church or a convention or association of churches.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An organization that is operated primarily for religious purposes and that is operated, supervised, controlled, or principally supported by a church or a convention or association of churches.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a duly ordained, commissioned, or licensed minister of a church in the exercise of his or her ministry or by a member of a religious order in the exercise of duties required by the order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the employ of a public employer if the service is performed by an individual in the exercise of duties:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an elected official.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a member of a legislative body, or a member of the judiciary, of a state or a political subdivision of a state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an employee serving on a temporary basis in case of fire, storm, snow, earthquake, flood, or similar emergency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a position that, under state law, is designated as a major nontenured policymaking or advisory position, including any major nontenured policymaking or advisory position in the Senior Management Service created under s. 110.402, or a policymaking or advisory position for which the duties do not ordinarily require more than 8 hours per week.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an election official or election worker if the amount of remuneration received by the individual during the calendar year for those services is less than $1,000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a facility operating a program of rehabilitation for individuals whose earning capacity is impaired by age, physical or mental deficiency, or injury, or a program providing remunerative work for individuals who cannot be readily absorbed in the competitive labor market because of their impaired physical or mental capacity, by an individual receiving such rehabilitation or remunerative work.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of an unemployment work-relief or work-training program assisted or financed in whole or in part by any federal agency or an agency of a state or political subdivision of a state, by an individual receiving the work relief or work training. This paragraph does not apply to unemployment work-relief or work-training programs for which unemployment compensation coverage is required by the Federal Government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By an inmate of a custodial or penal institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes service performed by an individual in agricultural labor if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is performed for a person who:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paid remuneration in cash of at least $10,000 to individuals employed in agricultural labor in a calendar quarter during the current or preceding calendar year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employed in agricultural labor at least five individuals for some portion of a day in each of 20 different calendar weeks during the current or preceding calendar year, regardless of whether the weeks were consecutive or whether the individuals were employed at the same time.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is performed by a member of a crew furnished by a crew leader to perform agricultural labor for another person.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this paragraph, a crew member is treated as an employee of the crew leader if:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The crew leader holds a valid certificate of registration under the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act of 1983 or substantially all of the crew members operate or maintain tractors, mechanized harvesting or crop-dusting equipment, or any other mechanized equipment provided by the crew leader; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual does not perform that agricultural labor as an employee of an employer other than the crew leader.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this paragraph, in the case of an individual who is furnished by a crew leader to perform agricultural labor for another person and who is not treated as an employee of the crew leader under subparagraph 1.:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The other person and not the crew leader is treated as the employer of the individual; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The other person is treated as having paid cash remuneration to the individual equal to the cash remuneration paid to the individual by the crew leader, either on his or her own behalf or on behalf of the other person, for the agricultural labor performed for the other person.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes domestic service performed by maids, cooks, maintenance workers, chauffeurs, social secretaries, caretakers, private yacht crews, butlers, and houseparents, in a private home, local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority performed for a person who paid cash remuneration of at least $1,000 during a calendar quarter in the current calendar year or the preceding calendar year to individuals employed in the domestic service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes an individual’s entire service, performed inside or both inside and outside this state if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is localized within this state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is not localized within any state, but some of the service is performed in this state, and:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The base of operations, or, if there is no base of operations, the place from which the service is directed or controlled, is located within this state; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The base of operations or place from which the service is directed or controlled is not located within any state in which some part of the service is performed, but the individual’s residence is located within this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services not covered under paragraph (7)(b) which are performed entirely outside of this state, and for which contributions are not required or paid under a reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law of any other state or of the Federal Government, are deemed to be employment subject to this chapter if the individual performing the services is a resident of this state and the tax collection service provider approves the election of the employing unit for whom the services are performed, electing that the entire service of the individual is deemed to be employment subject to this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service is deemed to be localized within a state if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is performed entirely inside the state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is performed both inside and outside the state, but the service performed outside the state is incidental to the individual’s service inside the state. Incidental service includes, but is not limited to, service that is temporary or transitory in nature or consists of isolated transactions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes service performed outside the United States, except in Canada, by a citizen of the United States who is in the employ of an American employer, other than service deemed employment subject to this chapter under subsection (2), subsection (3), or similar provisions of another state’s law, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer’s principal place of business in the United States is located within this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer does not have a place of business located in the United States, but:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer is a natural person who is a resident of this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer is a corporation organized under the laws of this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer is a partnership or a trust and the number of the partners or trustees who are residents of this state is greater than the number who are residents of any one other state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer is not an American employer, or neither paragraph (a) nor paragraph (b) apply, but the employer elects coverage in this state or the employer fails to elect coverage in any state and the individual files a claim for benefits based on that service under the laws of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes all service performed by an officer or member of a crew of an American vessel or American aircraft on, or in connection with, the vessel or aircraft, if the operating office from which the operations of the vessel or aircraft operating inside or both inside and outside the United States is ordinarily and regularly supervised, managed, directed, and controlled within this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment subject to this chapter includes services covered by a reciprocal arrangement under s. 443.221 between the Department of Economic Opportunity or its tax collection service provider and the agency charged with the administration of another state reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law or a federal reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law, under which all services performed by an individual for an employing unit are deemed to be performed entirely within this state, if the department or its tax collection service provider approved an election of the employing unit in which all of the services performed by the individual during the period covered by the election are deemed to be insured work.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from coverage under this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Domestic service in a private home, local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority, except as provided in subsection (6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed on or in connection with a vessel or aircraft that is not an American vessel or American aircraft, if the employee is employed on and in connection with the vessel or aircraft while the vessel or aircraft is outside the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual engaged in, or as an officer or member of the crew of a vessel engaged in, the catching, taking, harvesting, cultivating, or farming of any kind of fish, shellfish, crustacea, sponges, seaweeds, or other aquatic forms of animal and vegetable life, including service performed by an individual as an ordinary incident to engaging in those activities, except:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in connection with the catching or taking of salmon or halibut for commercial purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed on, or in connection with, a vessel of more than 10 net tons, determined in the manner provided for determining the registered tonnage of merchant vessels under the laws of the United States.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual in the employ of his or her son, daughter, or spouse, including step relationships, and service performed by a child, or stepchild, under the age of 21 in the employ of his or her father, mother, stepfather, or stepmother.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of the Federal Government or of an instrumentality of the Federal Government which is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wholly or partially owned by the United States.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exempt from the tax imposed by s. 3301 of the Internal Revenue Code under a federal law that specifically cites s. 3301, or the corresponding section of prior law, in granting the exemption. However, to the extent that the United States Congress permits the state to require an instrumentality of the Federal Government to make payments into the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund under this chapter, this chapter applies to that instrumentality, and to services performed for that instrumentality, in the same manner, to the same extent, and on the same terms as other employers, employing units, individuals, and services. If this state is not certified for any year by the Secretary of Labor under s. 3304 of the federal Internal Revenue Code, the tax collection service provider shall refund the payments required of each instrumentality of the Federal Government for that year from the fund in the same manner and within the same period as provided in s. 443.141(6) for contributions erroneously collected.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of a public employer as defined in s. 443.036, except as provided in subsection (2), and service performed in the employ of an instrumentality of a public employer as described in s. 443.036(36)(b) or (c), to the extent that the instrumentality is immune under the United States Constitution from the tax imposed by s. 3301 of the Internal Revenue Code for that service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of a corporation, community chest, fund, or foundation that is organized and operated exclusively for religious, charitable, scientific, testing for public safety, literary, or educational purposes or for the prevention of cruelty to children or animals. This exemption does not apply to an employer if part of the employer’s net earnings inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual or if a substantial part of the employer’s activities involve carrying on propaganda, otherwise attempting to influence legislation, or participating or intervening in, including the publishing or distributing of statements, a political campaign on behalf of a candidate for public office, except as provided in subsection (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service for which reemployment assistance is payable under a reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation system established by the United States Congress, of which this chapter is not a part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed during a calendar quarter in the employ of an organization exempt from the federal income tax under s. 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, other than an organization described in s. 401(a), or under s. 521, if the remuneration for the service is less than $50.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of a school, college, or university, if the service is performed by a student who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes at the school, college, or university.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of a foreign government, including service as a consular or other officer or employee of a nondiplomatic representative.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in the employ of an instrumentality wholly owned by a foreign government if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service is of a character similar to that performed in foreign countries by employees of the Federal Government or of an instrumentality of the Federal Government; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States Secretary of State certifies to the United States Secretary of the Treasury that the foreign government for whose instrumentality the exemption is claimed grants an equivalent exemption for similar service performed in the foreign country by employees of the Federal Government and of instrumentalities of the Federal Government.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed as a student nurse in the employ of a hospital or a nurses’ training school by an individual who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes in a nurses’ training school chartered or approved under state law, service performed as an intern in the employ of a hospital by an individual who has completed a 4-year course in a medical school chartered or approved under state law, and service performed by a patient of a hospital for the hospital.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual for a person as an insurance agent or as an insurance solicitor, if all of the service performed by the individual for that person is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission, except for services performed in accordance with 26 U.S.C. s. 3306(c)(7) and (8). For purposes of this section, those benefits excluded from the wages subject to this chapter under s. 443.1217(2)(b)-(f), inclusive, are not considered remuneration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual for a person as a real estate salesperson or agent, if all of the service performed by the individual for that person is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual under the age of 18 in the delivery or distribution of newspapers or shopping news, excluding delivery or distribution to any point for subsequent delivery or distribution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service covered by an arrangement between the Department of Economic Opportunity, or its tax collection service provider, and the agency charged with the administration of another state or federal reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law under which all services performed by an individual for an employing unit during the period covered by the employing unit’s duly approved election is deemed to be performed entirely within the other agency’s state or under the federal law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual enrolled at a nonprofit or public educational institution that normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly organized body of students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are carried on, if the institution certifies to the employer that the individual is a student in a full-time program, taken for credit at the institution that combines academic instruction with work experience, and that the service is an integral part of the program. This paragraph does not apply to service performed in a program established for or on behalf of an employer or group of employers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual for a person as a barber, if all of the service performed by the individual for that person is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Casual labor not in the course of the employer’s trade or business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by a speech therapist, occupational therapist, or physical therapist who is nonsalaried and working under a written contract with a home health agency as defined in s. 400.462.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by a direct seller. As used in this paragraph, the term “direct seller” means a person:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is engaged in the trade or business of selling or soliciting the sale of consumer products to buyers on a buy-sell basis, on a deposit-commission basis, or on a similar basis, for resale in the home or in another place that is not a permanent retail establishment; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is engaged in the trade or business of selling or soliciting the sale of consumer products in the home or in another place that is not a permanent retail establishment;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substantially all of whose remuneration for services described in subparagraph 1., regardless of whether paid in cash, is directly related to sales or other output, rather than to the number of hours worked; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who performs the services under a written contract with the person for whom the services are performed, if the contract provides that the person will not be treated as an employee for those services for federal tax purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by a nonresident alien for the period he or she is temporarily present in the United States as a nonimmigrant under subparagraph (F) or subparagraph (J) of s. 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, and which is performed to carry out the purpose specified in subparagraph (F) or subparagraph (J), as applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by an individual for remuneration for a private, for-profit delivery or messenger service, if the individual:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is free to accept or reject jobs from the delivery or messenger service and the delivery or messenger service does not have control over when the individual works;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is remunerated for each delivery, or the remuneration is based on factors that relate to the work performed, including receipt of a percentage of any rate schedule;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays all expenses, and the opportunity for profit or loss rests solely with the individual;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is responsible for operating costs, including fuel, repairs, supplies, and motor vehicle insurance;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determines the method of performing the service, including selection of routes and order of deliveries;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is responsible for the completion of a specific job and is liable for any failure to complete that job;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enters into a contract with the delivery or messenger service which specifies that the individual is an independent contractor and not an employee of the delivery or messenger service; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides the vehicle used to perform the service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed in agricultural labor by an individual who is an alien admitted to the United States to perform service in agricultural labor under ss. 101(a)(15)(H) and 214(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service performed by a person who is an inmate of a penal institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 2003-36; s. 4, ch. 2005-209; s. 33, ch. 2007-106; s. 3, ch. 2009-101; s. 363, ch. 2011-142; s. 62, ch. 2012-5; s. 12, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>