<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.1217" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wages.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The wages subject to this chapter include all remuneration for employment, including commissions, bonuses, back pay awards, and the cash value of all remuneration paid in any medium other than cash. The reasonable cash value of remuneration in any medium other than cash must be estimated and determined in accordance with rules adopted by the Department of Economic Opportunity or the state agency providing tax collection services. The wages subject to this chapter include tips or gratuities received while performing services that constitute employment and are included in a written statement furnished to the employer under s. 6053(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954. As used in this section only, the term “employment” includes services constituting employment under any employment security law of another state or of the Federal Government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of determining an employer’s contributions, the following wages are exempt from this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 2012, that part of remuneration paid to an individual by an employer for employment during a calendar year in excess of the first $8,000 of remuneration paid to the individual by the employer or his or her predecessor during that calendar year, unless that part of the remuneration is subject to a tax, under a federal law imposing the tax, against which credit may be taken for contributions required to be paid into a state unemployment fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 2015, the part of remuneration paid to an individual by an employer for employment during a calendar year in excess of the first $7,000 of remuneration paid to the individual by an employer or his or her predecessor during that calendar year, unless that part of the remuneration is subject to a tax, under a federal law imposing the tax, against which credit may be taken for contributions required to be paid into a state unemployment fund. The wage base exemption adjustment authorized by this subparagraph shall be suspended in any calendar year in which repayment of the principal amount of an advance received from the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund under 42 U.S.C. s. 1321 is due to the Federal Government.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment by an employing unit with respect to services performed for, or on behalf of, an individual employed by the employing unit under a plan or system established by the employing unit which provides for payment to its employees generally or to a class of its employees, including any amount paid by the employing unit for insurance or annuities or paid into a fund on account of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sickness or accident disability. When payment is made to an employee or any of his or her dependents, this subparagraph exempts from the wages subject to this chapter only those payments received under a workers’ compensation law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical and hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident disability.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death, if the employee:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have the option to receive, in lieu of the death benefit, part of the payment or, if the death benefit is insured, part of the premiums or contributions to premiums paid by his or her employing unit; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have the right under the plan, system, or policy providing the death benefit to assign the benefit or to receive cash consideration in lieu of the benefit upon his or her withdrawal from the plan or system; upon termination of the plan, system, or policy; or upon termination of his or her services with the employing unit.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment on account of sickness or accident disability, or payment of medical or hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident disability, by an employing unit to, or on behalf of, an individual performing services for the employing unit more than 6 calendar months after the last calendar month the individual performed services for the employing unit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment by an employing unit, without deduction from the remuneration of an individual employed by the employing unit, of the tax imposed upon the individual under s. 3101 of the federal Internal Revenue Code for services performed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meals furnished to an employee or the employee’s spouse or dependents by the employer on the business premises of the employer for the convenience of the employer; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lodging furnished to an employee or the employee’s spouse or dependents by the employer on the business premises of the employer for the convenience of the employer when lodging is included as a condition of employment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment made by an employing unit to, or on behalf of, an individual performing services for the employing unit or a beneficiary of the individual:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From or to a trust described in s. 401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 which is exempt from tax under s. 501(a) at the time of payment, unless payment is made to an employee of the trust as remuneration for services rendered as an employee of the trust and not as a beneficiary of the trust;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under or to an annuity plan that, at the time of payment, is a plan described in s. 403(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under a simplified employee pension if, at the time of payment, it is reasonable to believe that the employee is entitled to a deduction under s. 219(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 for the payment;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under or to an annuity contract described in s. 403(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, other than a payment for the purchase of an annuity contract as part of a salary reduction agreement, regardless of whether the agreement is evidenced by a written instrument or otherwise;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under or to an exempt governmental deferred compensation plan described in s. 3121(v)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To supplement pension benefits under a plan or trust described in subparagraphs 1.-5. to account for some portion or all of the increase in the cost of living, as determined by the United States Secretary of Labor, since retirement, but only if the supplemental payments are under a plan that is treated as a welfare plan under s. 3(2)(B)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under a cafeteria plan, as defined in s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, if the payment would not be treated as wages without regard to such plan and it is reasonable to believe that, if s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, applied for purposes of this section, s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, would not treat any wages as constructively received.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment made, or benefit provided, by an employing unit to or for the benefit of an individual performing services for the employing unit or a beneficiary of the individual if, at the time of such payment or provision of the benefit, it is reasonable to believe that the individual may exclude the payment or benefit from income under s. 127 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 2003-36; s. 5, ch. 2005-209; s. 1, ch. 2009-99; s. 3, ch. 2010-1; s. 364, ch. 2011-142; s. 13, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 13, ch. 2012-30, amends paragraph (2)(a) “[e]ffective upon this act becoming a law and operating retroactively to June 29, 2011.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>