<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public employment service.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The one-stop delivery system established under s. 445.009 is this state’s public employment service as part of the national system of public employment offices under 29 U.S.C. s. 49. The Department of Economic Opportunity, under policy direction from Workforce Florida, Inc., shall cooperate with any official or agency of the United States having power or duties under 29 U.S.C. ss. 49-49l-1 and shall perform those duties necessary to secure to this state the funds provided under federal law for the promotion and maintenance of the state’s public employment service. In accordance with 29 U.S.C. s. 49c, this state accepts 29 U.S.C. ss. 49-49l-1. The department is designated the state agency responsible for cooperating with the United States Secretary of Labor under 29 U.S.C. s. 49c. The department shall appoint sufficient employees to administer this section. The department may cooperate with or enter into agreements with the Railroad Retirement Board for the establishment, maintenance, and use of one-stop career centers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds received by this state under 29 U.S.C. ss. 49-49l-1 must be paid into the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund, and these funds are available to the Department of Economic Opportunity for expenditure as provided by this chapter or by federal law. For the purpose of establishing and maintaining one-stop career centers, the department may enter into agreements with the Railroad Retirement Board or any other agency of the United States charged with the administration of a reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation law, with any political subdivision of this state, or with any private, nonprofit organization. As a part of any such agreement, the department may accept moneys, services, or quarters as a contribution to the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 18402, 1937; s. 8, ch. 19637, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(500); s. 12, ch. 20685, 1941; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-283; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 26, ch. 79-7; ss. 6, 8, 9, ch. 80-95; s. 15, ch. 83-174; s. 4, ch. 95-345; s. 107, ch. 2000-165; s. 43, ch. 2003-36; s. 376, ch. 2011-142; s. 27, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 443.13.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>