<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reemployment Assistance Appeals Commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Division of Workforce Services of the Department of Economic Opportunity a Reemployment Assistance Appeals Commission. The commission is composed of a chair and two other members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. Only one appointee may be a representative of employers, as demonstrated by his or her previous vocation, employment, or affiliation; and only one appointee may be a representative of employees, as demonstrated by his or her previous vocation, employment, or affiliation.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair shall devote his or her entire time to commission duties and is responsible for the administrative functions of the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair has authority to appoint a general counsel and other personnel to carry out the duties and responsibilities of the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair must have the qualifications required by law for a judge of the circuit court and may not engage in any other business vocation or employment. Notwithstanding any other law, the chair shall be paid a salary equal to that paid under state law to a judge of the circuit court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining members shall be paid a stipend of $100 for each day they are engaged in the work of the commission. The chair and other members are entitled to be reimbursed for travel expenses, as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total salary and travel expenses of each member of the commission shall be paid from the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the commission shall be appointed to staggered terms of 4 years each. A vacancy for the unexpired term of a member shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. The presence of two members constitutes a quorum for any called meeting of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission has all authority, powers, duties, and responsibilities relating to reemployment assistance appeal proceedings under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property, personnel, and appropriations relating to the specified authority, powers, duties, and responsibilities of the commission shall be provided to the commission by the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is not subject to control, supervision, or direction by the Department of Economic Opportunity in performing its powers or duties under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may make expenditures, including expenditures for personal services and rent, for law books, books of reference, periodicals, furniture, equipment, and supplies, and for printing and binding as necessary in exercising its authority and powers and carrying out its duties and responsibilities. All such expenditures of the commission shall be allowed and paid as provided in s. 443.211 upon the presentation of itemized vouchers approved by the chair.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may charge fees for publications, subscriptions, and copies of records and documents. These fees must be deposited in the Employment Security Administration Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall maintain and keep open during reasonable business hours an office in Tallahassee for the purpose of transacting its business, at which office the commission shall keep its official records and papers. The offices shall be furnished and equipped by the commission. The commission may hold sessions and conduct hearings at any place within the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall prepare and submit a budget covering the necessary administrative cost of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall have a seal for authenticating its orders, awards, and proceedings, upon which shall be inscribed the words “State of Florida–Reemployment Assistance Appeals Commission–Seal,” and it shall be judicially noticed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission has authority to adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer the provisions of law conferring duties upon it.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Orders of the commission relating to reemployment assistance under this chapter are subject to review only by notice of appeal to the district courts of appeal in the manner provided in s. 443.151(4)(e).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 99-240; s. 57, ch. 2002-194; s. 14, ch. 2003-36; s. 351, ch. 2011-142; s. 2, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>