<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0443.1113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that funds are appropriated for each phase of the Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System by the Legislature, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall replace and enhance the functionality provided in the following systems with an integrated Internet-based system that is known as the “Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System”:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims and benefit mainframe system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida unemployment Internet direct.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida continued claim Internet directory.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Call center interactive voice response system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Benefit overpayment screening system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internet and Intranet appeals system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits System shall accomplish the following main business objectives:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wherever cost-effective and operationally feasible, eliminate or automate existing paper processes and enhance any existing automated workflows in order to expedite customer transactions and eliminate redundancy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enable online, self-service access to claimant and employer information and federal and state reporting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrate benefit payment control with the adjudication program and collection system in order to improve the detection of fraud.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with all requirements established in federal and state law for reemployment assistance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrate with the Department of Revenue’s statewide unified tax system that collects reemployment assistance taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope of the Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System does not include any of the following functionalities:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection of reemployment assistance taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General ledger, financial management, or budgeting capabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Human resource planning or management capabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project to implement the Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System shall be comprised of the following phases and corresponding implementation timeframes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than the end of fiscal year 2009-2010 completion of the business re-engineering analysis and documentation of both the detailed system requirements and the overall system architecture.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Internet portal that replaces the Florida Unemployment Internet Direct and the Florida Continued Claims Internet Directory systems, the Call Center Interactive Voice Response System, the Benefit Overpayment Screening System, the Internet and Intranet Appeals System, and the Claims and Benefits Mainframe System shall be deployed to full operational status no later than the end of fiscal year 2012-2013.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall implement the following project governance structure until such time as the project is completed, suspended, or terminated:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project sponsor for the Reemployment Assistance Claims and Benefits Information System project is the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project shall be governed by an executive steering committee composed of the following voting members or their designees:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Revenue.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Division of Workforce Services within the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program director of the General Tax Administration Program Office within the Department of Revenue.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief information officer of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive steering committee has the overall responsibility for ensuring that the project meets its primary objectives and is specifically responsible for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing management direction and support to the project management team.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessing the project’s alignment with the strategic goals of the department for administering the reemployment assistance program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing and approving or disapproving any changes to the project’s scope, schedule, and costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing, approving or disapproving, and determining whether to proceed with any major project deliverables.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommending suspension or termination of the project to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives if it determines that the primary objectives cannot be achieved.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project management team shall work under the direction of the executive steering committee and shall be minimally comprised of senior managers and stakeholders from the department and the Department of Revenue. The project management team is responsible for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing daily planning, management, and oversight of the project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting an operational work plan and providing quarterly updates to that plan to the executive steering committee. The plan must specify project milestones, deliverables, and expenditures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting written monthly project status reports to the executive steering committee which include:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Planned versus actual project costs;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the status of major milestones and deliverables;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of any issues requiring resolution, the proposed resolution for these issues, and information regarding the status of the resolution;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of risks that must be managed; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of and recommendations regarding necessary changes in the project’s scope, schedule, or costs. All recommendations must be reviewed by project stakeholders before submission to the executive steering committee in order to ensure that the recommendations meet required acceptance criteria.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2009-73; s. 359, ch. 2011-142; s. 9, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>