<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0292.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County and city veteran service officer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of county commissioners may employ a county veteran service officer; provide office space, clerical assistance, and the necessary supplies incidental to providing and maintaining a county service office; and pay said expenses and salaries from the moneys hereinafter provided for. The governing body of any city may employ a city veteran service officer; provide such office space, clerical assistance, and supplies; and pay expenses and salaries. A county or city veteran service officer must be a veteran who served as a member of the Armed Forces of the United States during a period of war, as defined in Title 38, U.S.C.; who served at least 18 months’ active duty in the Armed Forces; and who was separated from such service under honorable conditions, or the surviving spouse of any such veteran. Any honorably discharged wartime veteran who was so discharged for service-connected or aggravated medical reasons before serving 18 months of active duty; who completed a tour of duty other than active duty for training, regardless of the length of the tour; or who satisfied his or her military obligation in a manner other than active duty for training or reserve duty shall be eligible for employment as a county or city veteran service officer. Every county or city veteran service officer, in order to be eligible for employment as a county or city veteran service officer, shall have a 2-year degree from an accredited university, college, or community college or a high school degree or equivalency diploma and 4 years of administrative experience.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or city desiring to employ a county or city veteran service officer under the provisions of this section may notify the Department of Veterans’ Affairs of its intention to do so and may furnish the department with the name or names of any person or persons applying to fill such position, along with documentation supporting the qualifications thereof. The department shall thereupon certify to such county or city the name or names of candidates for such position who meet the requirements and qualifications prescribed by the department. The county or city may thereupon employ any person or persons so certified by the department. Duties, compensation, and terms of employment shall be prescribed by the board of county commissioners or, where applicable, by the governing body of the city.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person employed by any county or city under the provisions of this section shall, from the time of his or her employment, be subject to such rules as the Department of Veterans’ Affairs may from time to time prescribe. Appropriations made by any county or city, or both, for the purposes set forth in this section are hereby declared to be appropriations for a county or municipal purpose, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Veterans’ Affairs is directed to establish a training program for county and city veteran service officers. Every county or city veteran service officer employed under this chapter shall attend the training program established by the department and successfully complete a test administered by the department prior to assuming any responsibilities as a county or city veteran service officer. The department shall further establish periodic training refresher courses which each county or city veteran service officer must attend and complete as a condition of remaining in employment as a county or city veteran service officer. County and city veteran service officers shall be reimbursed for travel expenses, as provided in s. 112.061, in fulfilling the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) shall not apply to, or in any way affect, the employment of any county or city service officer who was so employed prior to July 1, 1974.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 23017, 1945; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 74-288; s. 5, ch. 77-330; s. 121, ch. 79-400; s. 30, ch. 81-167; s. 3, ch. 81-288; s. 30, ch. 83-55; s. 20, ch. 88-290; s. 242, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>