<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0825.1025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lewd or lascivious offenses committed upon or in the presence of an elderly person or disabled person.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “sexual activity” means the oral, anal, or vaginal penetration by, or union with, the sexual organ of another or the anal or vaginal penetration of another by any other object; however, sexual activity does not include an act done for a bona fide medical purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lewd or lascivious battery upon an elderly person or disabled person” occurs when a person encourages, forces, or entices an elderly person or disabled person to engage in sadomasochistic abuse, sexual bestiality, prostitution, or any other act involving sexual activity, when the person knows or reasonably should know that the elderly person or disabled person either lacks the capacity to consent or fails to give consent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits lewd or lascivious battery upon an elderly person or disabled person commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lewd or lascivious molestation of an elderly person or disabled person” occurs when a person intentionally touches in a lewd or lascivious manner the breasts, genitals, genital area, or buttocks, or the clothing covering them, of an elderly person or disabled person when the person knows or reasonably should know that the elderly person or disabled person either lacks the capacity to consent or fails to give consent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits lewd or lascivious molestation of an elderly person or disabled person commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lewd or lascivious exhibition in the presence of an elderly person or disabled person” occurs when a person, in the presence of an elderly person or disabled person:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally masturbates;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally exposes his or her genitals in a lewd or lascivious manner; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally commits any other lewd or lascivious act that does not involve actual physical or sexual contact with the elderly person or disabled person, including but not limited to, sadomasochistic abuse, sexual bestiality, or the simulation of any act involving sexual activity,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion" SpaceAbove="true">when the person knows or reasonably should know that the elderly person or disabled person either lacks the capacity to consent or fails to give consent to having such act committed in his or her presence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits a lewd or lascivious exhibition in the presence of an elderly person or disabled person commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 96-322; s. 1, ch. 2002-159.</History></Section>