<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0825.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business relationship” means a relationship between two or more individuals or entities where there exists an oral or written contract or agreement for goods or services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Caregiver” means a person who has been entrusted with or has assumed responsibility for the care or the property of an elderly person or disabled adult. “Caregiver” includes, but is not limited to, relatives, court-appointed or voluntary guardians, adult household members, neighbors, health care providers, and employees and volunteers of facilities as defined in subsection (7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deception” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresenting or concealing a material fact relating to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services rendered, disposition of property, or use of property, when such services or property are intended to benefit an elderly person or disabled adult;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terms of a contract or agreement entered into with an elderly person or disabled adult; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An existing or preexisting condition of any property involved in a contract or agreement entered into with an elderly person or disabled adult; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using any misrepresentation, false pretense, or false promise in order to induce, encourage, or solicit an elderly person or disabled adult to enter into a contract or agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disabled adult” means a person 18 years of age or older who suffers from a condition of physical or mental incapacitation due to a developmental disability, organic brain damage, or mental illness, or who has one or more physical or mental limitations that restrict the person’s ability to perform the normal activities of daily living.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Elderly person” means a person 60 years of age or older who is suffering from the infirmities of aging as manifested by advanced age or organic brain damage, or other physical, mental, or emotional dysfunctioning, to the extent that the ability of the person to provide adequately for the person’s own care or protection is impaired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Endeavor” means to attempt or try.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facility” means any location providing day or residential care or treatment for elderly persons or disabled adults. The term “facility” may include, but is not limited to, any hospital, training center, state institution, nursing home, assisted living facility, adult family-care home, adult day care center, group home, mental health treatment center, or continuing care community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intimidation” means the communication by word or act to an elderly person or disabled adult that the elderly person or disabled adult will be deprived of food, nutrition, clothing, shelter, supervision, medicine, medical services, money, or financial support or will suffer physical violence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lacks capacity to consent” means an impairment by reason of mental illness, developmental disability, organic brain disorder, physical illness or disability, chronic use of drugs, chronic intoxication, short-term memory loss, or other cause, that causes an elderly person or disabled adult to lack sufficient understanding or capacity to make or communicate reasonable decisions concerning the elderly person’s or disabled adult’s person or property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Obtains or uses” means any manner of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking or exercising control over property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any use, disposition, or transfer of property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Position of trust and confidence” with respect to an elderly person or a disabled adult means the position of a person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a parent, spouse, adult child, or other relative by blood or marriage of the elderly person or disabled adult;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a joint tenant or tenant in common with the elderly person or disabled adult;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a legal or fiduciary relationship with the elderly person or disabled adult, including, but not limited to, a court-appointed or voluntary guardian, trustee, attorney, or conservator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a caregiver of the elderly person or disabled adult; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is any other person who has been entrusted with or has assumed responsibility for the use or management of the elderly person’s or disabled adult’s funds, assets, or property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” means anything of value and includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property, including things growing on, affixed to, and found in land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tangible or intangible personal property, including rights, privileges, interests, and claims.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Services” means anything of value resulting from a person’s physical or mental labor or skill, or from the use, possession, or presence of property, and includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repairs or improvements to property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private, public, or governmental communication, transportation, power, water, or sanitation services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lodging accommodations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Admissions to places of exhibition or entertainment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Value” means value determined according to any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The market value of the property at the time and place of the offense or, if the market value cannot be satisfactorily ascertained, the cost of replacing the property within a reasonable time after the offense.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a written instrument such as a check, draft, or promissory note, which does not have a readily ascertainable market value, the value is the amount due or collectible. The value of any other instrument that creates, releases, discharges, or otherwise affects any valuable legal right, privilege, or obligation is the greatest amount of economic loss that the owner of the instrument might reasonably suffer by the loss of the instrument.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of a trade secret that does not have a readily ascertainable market value is any reasonable value representing the damage to the owner suffered by reason of losing advantage over those who do not know of or use the trade secret.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property cannot be ascertained, the trier of fact may find the value to be not less than a certain amount; if no such minimum value can be ascertained, the value is an amount less than $100.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts of value of separate properties involved in exploitation committed pursuant to one scheme or course of conduct, whether the exploitation involves the same person or several persons, may be aggregated in determining the degree of the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 95-158; s. 1, ch. 96-322; s. 1, ch. 2002-195.</History></Section>