<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0285.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tribal Secured Transactions Filing Offices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the governing body of the Seminole Tribe of Florida or the governing body of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians adopts or enacts a law or ordinance governing secured transactions arising within or relating to the reservation of such tribe in this state, and if such tribal law or ordinance authorizes financing statements and other records relating to secured transactions to be filed:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the Department of State or such other central filing office as may be established from time to time under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state, then the Department of State or other central filing office, including any private secured transaction registry that may be designated as such in this state, shall accept and process such filings made under the tribal secured transactions law in accordance with this section and the provisions of chapter 679; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the office of the clerk of circuit court in any county of this state in which the tribal secured transactions law requires a local filing, then such county filing office shall accept and process such filings made under such tribal law in accordance with this section and the provisions of chapter 28.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing office shall not be required to accept any financing statements or other records communicated for filing under a tribal secured transactions law unless they satisfy the same filing requirements then applicable to financing statements and other records communicated to that filing office under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state, including the payment of the same filing, processing, or recording charges or fees then charged by that filing office for filing or recording comparable financing statements and other records under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing office shall maintain and index its records of all financing statements or other records filing with that filing office under the tribal secured transactions law together with and in the same manner as its records of financing statements and other records filed under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state. The filing office shall not be required to record or index separately, or otherwise segregate in any manner, any such filings made under the tribal secured transactions law from other filings made under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state. In all respects, the filing office shall have the same duties and responsibilities with respect to filings made under the tribal secured transactions law as with respect to filings made under the Uniform Commercial Code of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>