<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0285.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lands set aside; description.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following described lands in the County of Monroe, are set aside and given to the Seminole Indians of Florida as a reservation, to wit:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the lands now belonging to the state in township fifty-six south of range thirty-two east, being all of sections seven to fifteen, inclusive, and seventeen to thirty-six, inclusive, containing 18,560 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also, all of sections one to four, inclusive; ten to fifteen, inclusive; twenty-two to twenty-four, inclusive, and sections thirty-five and thirty-six, in township fifty-seven south of range thirty-two east, containing 9,600 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also, all of sections one to three, inclusive; ten to fourteen, inclusive; twenty-four, twenty-five, thirty-five and thirty-six, of township fifty-eight south of range thirty-two east, containing 7,680 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also, all of sections seven to fifteen, inclusive, and seventeen to thirty-six, inclusive, of township fifty-six south of range thirty-three east, containing 18,560 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also, all of sections one to fifteen, inclusive, and seventeen to thirty-six, inclusive, of township fifty-seven south of range thirty-three east, containing 22,400 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also, all of sections one to fifteen, inclusive, and seventeen to thirty-six, inclusive, of township fifty-eight south of range thirty-three east, containing 22,400 acres, more or less.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7310, 1917; RGS 1313; CGL 1994; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945.</History></Section>