<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0285.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of land to United States in trust for Seminole and Miccosukee Indian Tribes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of state Indian reservation lands is authorized in its discretion, to transfer to the United States to be held in trust for the use and benefit of the Seminole Tribe of Florida the following described lands:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Beginning in the southwest corner of Section 31, Township 48 South, Range 35 East; thence easterly along the south border of Sections 31, 32, and 33 in Township 48 South, Range 35 East, to the westernmost boundary of the Levee-28 works in Section 33, Township 48 South, Range 35 East; thence continuing north along the westernmost boundary of the Levee-28 works to the point at which the westernmost boundary of the Levee-28 works intersects the southernmost boundary of the Levee-4 works in Section 9, Township 48 South, Range 35 East; thence continuing westerly along the southernmost boundary of the Levee-4 works to the point at which the southernmost boundary of the Levee-4 works intersects the dividing line between Township 48 South, Range 35 East and Township 48 South, Range 34 East at the Broward County and Hendry County line; and thence continuing south along said line to the point of beginning; said lands situate, lying, and being in Broward County, Florida;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">and the said board is further authorized to transfer to the United States to be held in trust for the use and benefit of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida the following described lands:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sections 5, 6, 7, 8, 17, 18, 19, 20, 29, 30, 31, 32, Township 49 South, Range 36 East, and Township 49 South, Range 35 East, Township 50 South, Range 35 East, and Township 51 South, Range 35 East, said lands situate, lying and being in Broward County, Florida.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">All of the aforesaid lands having been set aside as a reservation for the Seminole Indians of Florida by Legislative Acts of 1917 and 1935, and the purpose of this section is to divide the described reservation into two reservations for the use of and benefit of the two tribes named herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this subsection: “Other Florida Indians” means Indian residents of the state who are not members of either the Seminole Tribe of Florida or the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida, who are qualified to meet the enrollment requirements of either the Seminole Tribe of Florida or the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida. Other Florida Indians shall be permitted to use, occupy and enjoy the Seminole Reservation or the Miccosukee Reservation on the same terms and conditions, and subject to the same limitations as are applicable to, or may be imposed upon, tribal members by its constitution, bylaws, or tribal regulations; provided, however, that if either of said tribes shall maintain its membership roll open to all other Florida Indians for a period of 3 years from the effective date of this act, then such Indians who, upon the expiration of said period, have not become enrolled members of either of said tribes, shall have no further right to the use, occupancy or enjoyment of either of said reservations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All the provisions of this chapter, not in conflict with this section, remain in full force and effect. The state reserves both civil and criminal jurisdiction over said reservations in accordance with ss. 285.16 and 285.165 and applicable federal law. The transfer of lands in trust for the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida made pursuant to the authority of this section remains subject to all of the rights, easements, and reservations in favor of the South Florida Water Management District provided in the transfer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 65-249; s. 1, ch. 65-472; ss. 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 71-286; s. 1, ch. 87-292.</History></Section>