<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special identification card for performance of fumigation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs fumigation must be a special identification cardholder, unless such individual is a certified operator who is certified in the category of fumigation. When performing fumigation, a special identification cardholder or certified operator may act only under the direction and supervision of the certified operator in charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe by rule the qualifications, privileges, duties, and limitations of holders of special identification cards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue special identification cards to qualified individuals who pass written examinations that may include practical demonstration. The application forms shall be prescribed by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in its rules, shall provide for such matters as required qualifications for applicants for examination, written or practical phases or categories of examinations, and time of examinations. The fee for an examination shall be set by the department but may not be more than $200 or less than $100 for each category; however, until rules setting these fees are adopted by the department, the fee for each category shall be $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application must be made and the issuance fee paid to the department for an original special identification card within 60 days after the postmark date of written notification of passing the examination. The fee for issuance of an original special identification card shall be set by the department but may not be more than $100 or less than $50; however, until a rule setting this fee is adopted by the department, the fee shall be $50. During a period of 30 days following expiration of the 60-day period, an original special identification card may be issued; however, the department shall assess a late issuance charge of $25, which must be paid in addition to the issuance fee. An original special identification card may not be issued after expiration of the 30-day period, without reexamination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application to the department for renewal of a special identification card must be made on or before an anniversary date set by the department. The fee for renewal of a special identification card shall be set by the department but may not be more than $100 or less than $50; however, until a rule setting this fee is adopted by the department, the renewal fee shall be $50. After a grace period not exceeding 30 calendar days following such renewal date, the department shall assess a late renewal charge of $25, which must be paid in addition to the renewal fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless timely renewed, a special identification card automatically expires 180 calendar days after the anniversary renewal date. Subsequent to such expiration, a special identification card may be issued only upon successful reexamination and upon payment of examination and issuance fees due, as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the expiration date of a special identification card, the cardholder must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete 2 hours of approved continuing education on legislation, safety, and pesticide labeling and 2 hours of approved continuing education in the fumigation category; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pass an examination in fumigation given by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a special identification cardholder becomes a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty, the renewal fee and continuing education requirements are waived while the individual remains on active duty as a member of the Armed Forces.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 381, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 10, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 11, ch. 89-180; s. 6, ch. 91-145; ss. 38, 59, ch. 92-203.</History></Section>