<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.0815" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit to perform preventive termite treatment services for new construction only.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee must have a permit to perform preventive termite treatments for new construction, except for preventive termite treatments on additions to existing structures for which the licensee has a current termite treatment contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit shall be automatically renewed upon renewal of the license held by the licensee, unless the permit has been suspended, revoked, or otherwise denied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit shall be probationary for 120 days after a licensee is found to be in violation of s. 482.051(5) or a rule relating to the application of specific amounts, concentrations, and treatment areas, except for provisions governing recordkeeping. A licensee whose permit is on probationary status must provide advance notice to the department of any preventive treatment planned for new construction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee’s permit shall be suspended for a 30-day to 90-day period if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee whose permit is on probationary status violates s. 482.051(5) or a rule relating to the application of specific amounts, concentrations, or treatment areas, except for provisions governing recordkeeping, at three or more sites on three or more separate dates;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee violates s. 482.051(3) or a rule with respect to three contracts within 2 years and the violation is failure to comply with contractual obligations to re-treat a wood-destroying-organism infestation or to repair damage caused by wood-destroying organisms when required by the contract. If a licensee makes a good faith offer to repair damage covered by a valid contract, the licensee must be considered to be in compliance with the contractual obligation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee violates subsection (9); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee violates the recordkeeping requirements of s. 482.051(5) three or more times within 2 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A suspended permit may be reinstated after the period of the suspension if the licensee’s license is in good standing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permit of a licensee whose permit has been suspended within the previous 3 years shall be revoked if the licensee subsequently meets any of the conditions of subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a permit or renew the permit to perform preventive termite treatments if the applicant or licensee or any of its directors, officers, owners, or general partners are or were directors, officers, owners, or general partners of a pest control business that went out of business or sold the business within 5 years immediately preceding the date of application or renewal and failed to reimburse the prorated renewal fee of any customer’s remaining wood-destroying-organism contract periods or failed to provide for another licensed pest control operator to assume its existing wood-destroying-organism contract responsibility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee must conspicuously display its current permit at all business locations, each of which must have a separate permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee holding a permit must maintain accurate records of all pesticides purchased, obtained, or available for its use; the total amount of the area treated using soil applied termiticides; and the total number of sites treated using this and any other method of treatment. These records must be made available to the department upon request. The amount of pesticides purchased, obtained, or otherwise available must at least equal the amount required by the pesticide label to treat the area or number of sites treated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall suspend the license of any licensee who performs preventive termite treatments for new construction while its permit is suspended or revoked.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2001-280.</History></Section>