<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.242" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preemption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter is intended as comprehensive and exclusive regulation of pest control in this state. The provisions of this chapter preempt to the state all regulation of the activities and operations of pest control services, including the pesticides used pursuant to labeling and registration approved under part I of chapter 487. No local government or political subdivision of the state may enact or enforce an ordinance that regulates pest control, except that the preemption in this section does not prohibit a local government or political subdivision from enacting an ordinance regarding any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local business taxes adopted pursuant to chapter 205.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land development regulations adopted pursuant to chapter 163 which include regulation of any aspect of development, including a subdivision, building construction, sign regulation or any other regulation concerning the development of land, or landscaping or tree protection ordinances which do not include pesticide application restrictions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulations that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require, for multicomplex dwellings in excess of 10 units, annual termite inspections for termite activity or damage, including Formosan termites, which must be performed by a person licensed under this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require pest control treatments of structures that have termite activity or damage which must be performed by a person licensed under this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require property owners or other persons to obtain inspections or pest control treatments performed by a person licensed under this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">An ordinance by a local government or political subdivision which requires an annual inspection or pest control treatment must conform to current law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protection of wellhead protection areas and high recharge areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous materials reporting as set forth in part II of chapter 252, storage, and containment including as relating to stormwater management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous material unlawful discharge and disposal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous materials remediation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hazardous materials” shall be as defined in s. 403.74 and chapter 252.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wellhead protection area” means an area designated by local government to protect the groundwater source for a well intended for human consumption for a community water system and includes the surface and subsurface area surrounding such a potable water wellfield. The maximum boundaries of the wellfield shall be the zone of contribution and the minimum shall be 10 years’ travel time. Differing levels of protection may be established within the protection area zones based upon an evaluation of the risk to human health and the environment. Wellhead protection areas shall be delineated using such methods as reasonable or calculated fixed radii, simplified variable shapes, analytical methods, hydrogeological mapping, numerical flow or transport models, or other professionally accepted methodologies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“High recharge area” means an area contributing a significant volume of water which adds to the storage of an aquifer through vertical flow. The term “significant” will vary geographically depending on the hydrologic characteristics of that aquifer. High recharge areas will receive higher protection than other areas due to their significance as current or future water use areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Zone of contribution” means the area surrounding a well pumping water for human consumption that encompasses all areas or features that supply groundwater recharge to the well as determined by the relevant water management district or the local government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 65-295; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 14, 15, ch. 82-229; ss. 57, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 7, ch. 2001-280; s. 46, ch. 2004-64; s. 115, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>