<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.1562" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited certification for urban landscape commercial fertilizer application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide a means of documenting and ensuring compliance with best management practices for commercial fertilizer application to urban landscapes, the department shall establish a limited certification for urban landscape commercial fertilizer application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 2014, any person applying commercial fertilizer to an urban landscape must be certified under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain a limited certification for urban landscape commercial fertilizer application, an applicant must submit to the department:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the training certificate issued pursuant to s. 403.9338.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification fee set by the department in an amount of at least $25 but not more than $75. Until the fee is set by rule, the fee for certification is $25.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited certification for urban landscape commercial fertilizer application issued under this section expires 4 years after the date of issuance. Before applying for recertification under subsection (5), the applicant must complete 4 classroom hours of acceptable continuing education, of which at least 2 hours address fertilizer best management practices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for recertification must be made at least 90 days before the expiration of the current certificate and be accompanied by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of having completed the 4 classroom hours of acceptable continuing education required under subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recertification fee set by the department in an amount of at least $25 but not more than $75. Until the fee is set by rule, the fee for certification is $25.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A late renewal charge of $50 per month shall be assessed 30 days after the date the application for recertification is due and must be paid in addition to the renewal fee. Unless timely recertified, a certificate automatically expires 90 days after the recertification date. Upon expiration, a certificate may be issued only upon reapplying in accordance with subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification under this section does not authorize:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of pesticides to turf or ornamentals, including pesticide fertilizer mixtures;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation of a pest control business; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of pesticides or fertilizers by unlicensed or uncertified personnel under the supervision of the certified person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide information concerning the certification status of persons certified under this section to other local and state governmental agencies. The department is encouraged to create an online database that lists all persons certified under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Yard workers who apply fertilizer only to individual residential properties using fertilizer and equipment provided by the residential property owner or resident are exempt from the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2009-199.</History></Section>