<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0482.072" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pest control customer contact centers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a license to a qualified business to operate a customer contact center, to solicit pest control business, or to provide services to customers for one or more business locations licensed under s. 482.071. A person may not operate a customer contact center for a pest control business that is not licensed by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before operating a customer contact center, and biennially thereafter, on or before an anniversary date set by the department for a licensed customer contact center location, the pest control business must apply to the department for a license under this chapter, or a renewal thereof, for each customer contact center location. An application must be submitted in the format prescribed by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a fee of at least $600, but not more than $1,000, for the issuance of a customer contact center license and a fee of at least $600, but not more than $1,000, for renewal of a customer contact center license. However, until rules for renewal fees are adopted, the initial licensing fee and renewal fee are each $600. The department shall establish a grace period, not to exceed 30 calendar days after the license’s anniversary renewal date, and shall assess a late fee of $150, in addition to the renewal fee, for a license that is renewed after the grace period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license automatically expires 60 calendar days after the anniversary renewal date unless the license is renewed before that date. When a license expires, it may be reinstated only upon reapplication and payment of the license renewal fee and a late renewal fee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license automatically expires if a licensee changes the business address of its customer contact center location. The department shall issue a new license upon payment of a $250 fee. The new license automatically expires 60 calendar days after the anniversary renewal date of the former license unless the license is renewed before that date.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue or renew a license to operate a customer contact center unless the pest control business licensees for which the customer contact center solicits business are owned in common by a person or business entity recognized by this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny a license or refuse to renew a license if the applicant or licensee, or one or more of the applicant’s or licensee’s directors, officers, owners, or general partners, are or have been directors, officers, owners, or general partners of a pest control business that meets the conditions in s. 482.071(2)(g).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 482.091 and 482.152 do not apply to a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a licensed customer contact center unless the person performs pest control as defined in s. 482.021(22)(a)-(d), executes a pest control contract, or accepts remuneration for such work.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 482.071(2)(e) does not apply to a license issued under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing requirements and procedures for customer contact center recordkeeping and monitoring to ensure compliance with this section and rules adopted in accordance with this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer contact center licensee is subject to disciplinary action under s. 482.161 for a violation of this section or a rule adopted under this section committed by a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a customer contact center.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pest control business licensee may be subject to disciplinary action under s. 482.161 for a violation of this section or a rule adopted under this section committed by a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a customer contact center operated by a licensee if the licensee participates in the violation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2011-192; s. 9, ch. 2011-206.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 9, ch. 2011-206. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Section 482.072 was also created by s. 3, ch. 2011-192, and that version reads:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold"> 482.072 Pest control customer contact centers.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) The department may issue a license to operate a customer contact center from which to solicit pest control business or provide services to customers for one or more business locations licensed under s. 482.071. A person may not operate a customer contact center for a pest control business if the customer contact center is not licensed by the department.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2)(a) Before operating a customer contact center, and biennially thereafter, on or before a renewal date set by the department, a pest control business must apply to the department for a license or license renewal for each customer contact center location it operates. An application must be submitted in the format prescribed by the department.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The department shall establish a licensure fee of at least $600 but not more than $1,000, and a renewal fee of at least $600 but not more than $1,000, for a customer contact center license. However, until renewal fee rules are adopted, the initial license and renewal fees are each $600. The department shall establish a grace period not to exceed 30 days after the renewal date and shall assess a late fee of $150, in addition to the renewal fee, for a license that is renewed after the grace period.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) A license automatically expires if it is not renewed within 60 days after the renewal date and may be reinstated only upon reapplication and payment of the license renewal fee and late fee.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) A license automatically expires if a licensee changes its customer contact center business location. The department shall issue a new license upon payment of a $250 fee, which must be renewed by the renewal date for the former location’s license. A new license that is not renewed within 60 days after the renewal date of the license for the former business location automatically expires.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) The department may not issue or renew a license to operate a customer contact center unless the pest control business licensees for which the customer contact center solicits business are owned in common by a person or business entity recognized by this state.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) The department may deny a license or refuse to renew a license if the applicant or licensee, or one or more of the applicant’s or licensee’s directors, officers, owners, or general partners, are or have been directors, officers, owners, or general partners of a pest control business that meets the conditions in s. 482.071(2)(g).</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(g) Sections 482.091 and 482.152 do not apply to a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a licensed customer contact center unless the person performs the pest control work as defined in s. 482.021(22)(a)-(d), executes a pest control contract, or accepts remuneration for such work.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(h) Section 482.071(2)(e) does not apply to a license issued under this section.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3)(a) The department shall adopt rules establishing requirements and procedures for recordkeeping and monitoring customer contact center operations to ensure compliance with this chapter and rules adopted under this chapter.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. A customer contact center licensee is subject to disciplinary action under s. 482.161 for a violation of this chapter or rules adopted under this chapter committed by a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a customer contact center.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. A pest control business licensee may be subject to disciplinary action under s. 482.161 for a violation of this chapter or rules adopted under this chapter committed by a person who solicits pest control services or provides customer service in a customer contact center operated by the licensee if the licensee participates in the violation.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>