<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.2265" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consumer information; notice of application of pesticide.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, partnership, firm, corporation, or other business entity that is licensed or certified under this chapter to engage in the business of pest control, or any other person who is a limited certificateholder under this chapter, shall, upon request, provide a customer of its pest control services with the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business name of the licensee or certificateholder or the name of the limited certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification card number of the person applying the pesticide or, if a limited certificateholder, the name of that person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common or brand name of the pesticide to be used and the common name of the active ingredient in that pesticide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate safety information pertaining to the pesticide product to be used, as provided on the label for that product.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is licensed or certified under this chapter, including any person who is a limited certificateholder, shall post a notice in a conspicuous location at the time of application of a pesticide to a lawn or to exterior foliage. The department shall provide for the wording and physical makeup of such notice by rule, but the notice must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 4 inches by 5 inches in size;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be constructed of rigid, durable weatherproof material;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a background and lettering of contrasting colors; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clearly set forth the business name of the licensee or name of the limited certificateholder making the pesticide application.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The notice may be made part of a larger sign containing additional information, but the department may not require a sign larger than 4 inches by 5 inches unless the licensee or limited certificateholder seeks to include additional information on the sign.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 17, 18, ch. 89-180; ss. 1, 2, ch. 89-198; ss. 52, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 1, ch. 95-317.</History></Section>