<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.132" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for examination and certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may award a pest control operator’s certificate to an individual who has passed the examinations prescribed by the department and who submits to the department proof that she or he is not under the disability of minority and is qualified to be a certified operator with regard to the safety of persons and property, and is otherwise qualified under the provisions of this chapter and the rules made pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant for examination for a pest control operator’s certificate must possess the minimum qualifications specified in one of the following paragraphs:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years’ employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control in the category or categories in which the applicant seeks certification, 1 year of which employment must have been completed in this state during the year immediately preceding application for examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A degree with advanced training or a major in entomology, botany, agronomy, or horticulture from a recognized college or university, which training or major included the completion of at least 20 semester hours or 30 quarter hours of college credits in those subjects, plus 1 year’s employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control in the category or categories in which the applicant seeks certification or the successful completion of a 1-year entomology program at a public university in this state which specializes in urban pest management and includes practical pest management experience. If such advanced training or major is in entomology, the applicant is qualified for examination in all categories; but if such advanced training or major is in botany, agronomy, or horticulture, the applicant is qualified for examination only in the category of lawn and ornamental pest control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 2-year degree in horticultural technology or the equivalent from a college or university, with advanced training of 20 or more semester hours or 30 or more quarter hours of credit in horticulture, plus 1 year’s employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control only in the category of lawn and ornamental pest control. Such an applicant is qualified for examination only in the category of lawn and ornamental pest control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 2-year degree in general pest control technology or the equivalent from a college or university, with advanced training of 20 or more semester hours or 30 or more quarter hours of credit in entomology, plus 1 year of employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control in any category or categories. Such an applicant is qualified for all examinations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-four semester hours or 36 quarter hours of courses in entomology, pest control technology, and related subjects, plus 1 year of employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control in the category of general household pest, termite, and fumigation. Such an applicant is qualified only for examination in the categories of general household pest control, termite and other wood-destroying organisms pest control, and fumigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-four semester hours or 36 quarter hours of courses in entomology, pest control technology, agronomy, botany, horticulture, and related subjects, plus 1 year of employment as a service employee of a licensee that performs pest control in the category of lawn and ornamental pest control. Such an applicant is qualified only for examination in the category of lawn and ornamental pest control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years’ full-time employment as a service employee of the United States Department of Defense, who has been certified to perform pest control in the category or categories in which the applicant seeks certification, 1 year of which employment must have been completed in this state during the year immediately preceding application for examination. Additionally, the application for certification must be submitted to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services within 12 months after the date of termination of employment from the Department of Defense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, each applicant must have knowledge of practical and scientific facts of pest control and be a graduate of an accredited high school or submit to the department satisfactory evidence of equivalent education.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 63-48; ss. 1, 2, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-116; ss. 378, 379, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 8, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 2, ch. 85-335; s. 9, ch. 89-180; ss. 36, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 4, ch. 94-194; s. 431, ch. 97-103; s. 12, ch. 2000-308; s. 5, ch. 2001-280.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (2) and (3) former s. 482.133.</Text></Note></Section>