<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this chapter, and unless otherwise required by the context, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural area” means an area:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon which a ground crop, trees, or plants are grown for commercial purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a golf course, park, nursery, or cemetery is located; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where farming of any type is performed or livestock is raised.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business location” means an advertised permanent location in or from which pest control business is solicited, accepted, or conducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category” means a distinct branch or phase of pest control for which a pest control operator’s certificate may be issued such as: fumigation, general household pest control, termites and other wood-destroying organisms pest control, lawn and ornamental pest control, and such a combination or division of such branches of pest control as the department may by rule establish.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified operator” means an individual holding a current pest control operator’s certificate issued by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified operator in charge” means a certified operator:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whose primary occupation is the pest control business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is employed full time by a licensee; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whose principal duty is the personal supervision of the licensee’s operation in a category or categories of pest control in which the operator is certified.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial fertilizer application” means the application of fertilizer for payment or other consideration to property not owned by the person or firm applying the fertilizer or the employer of the applicator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” means a person who is employed by a licensee that provides that person with necessary training, supervision, pesticides, equipment, and insurance and who receives compensation from and is under the personal supervision and direct control of the licensee’s certified operator in charge and from whose compensation the licensee regularly deducts and matches federal insurance contributions and federal income and Social Security taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fumigant” means a chemical which, at a required temperature and pressure, can exist in the gaseous state in sufficient concentration to be lethal to a given organism. This definition implies that a fumigant acts as a gas in the strictest sense of the word. This definition excludes aerosols that are particulate suspensions of liquids or solids dispersed in air.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fumigation” means the use, within an enclosed space or in or under a structure or tarpaulins, of a fumigant in concentrations that may be hazardous to human beings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General household pest control” means pest control with respect to any structure, not including fumigation or pest control with respect to termites and other wood-destroying organisms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Identification cardholder” means an owner or employee to whom a current card has been issued by the department identifying the holder to the public or to any law enforcement officer or any agent of the department charged with, or entitled to exercise any function in connection with, the enforcement of this chapter and any rules made pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Independent contractor” means an entity separate from the licensee that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receives moneys from a customer which are deposited in a bank account other than that of the licensee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owns or supplies its own service vehicle, equipment, and pesticides;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintains a business operation, office, or support staff independent of the licensee’s direct control;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays its own operating expenses such as fuel, equipment, pesticides, and materials; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays its own workers’ compensation as an independent contractor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Infestation” means the presence of living pests in, on, or under a structure, lawn, or ornamental.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Integrated pest management” means the selection, integration, and implementation of multiple pest control techniques based on predictable economic, ecological, and sociological consequences, making maximum use of naturally occurring pest controls, such as weather, disease agents, and parasitoids, using various biological, physical, chemical, and habitat modification methods of control, and using artificial controls only as required to keep particular pests from surpassing intolerable population levels predetermined from an accurate assessment of the pest damage potential and the ecological, sociological, and economic cost of other control measures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lawn” means the turf formed from grass or other plants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lawn and ornamental pest control” means pest control with respect to pests of any lawn or ornamental.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means a person, partnership, firm, corporation, or other business entity having a license issued by the department for engaging in the business of pest control at a particular business location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New construction” means the erection of a new building or the construction of an addition to an existing building, which encloses a space and requires a building permit under applicable building codes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ornamental” means any shrub, bush, tree or other plant used or intended for use:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with the occupation or use of any structure; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By human beings for purposes other than in an agricultural area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pest” means an arthropod, wood-destroying organism, rodent, or other obnoxious or undesirable living plant or animal organism.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pest control” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any method or device or the application of any substance to prevent, destroy, repel, mitigate, curb, control, or eradicate any pest in, on, or under a structure, lawn, or ornamental;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification of or inspection for infestations or infections in, on, or under a structure, lawn, or ornamental;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any pesticide, economic poison, or mechanical device for preventing, controlling, eradicating, identifying, inspecting for, mitigating, diminishing, or curtailing insects, vermin, rodents, pest birds, bats, or other pests in, on, or under a structure, lawn, or ornamental;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All phases of fumigation, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment of products by vault fumigation; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fumigation of boxcars, trucks, ships, airplanes, docks, warehouses, and common carriers; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advertisement of, the solicitation of, or the acceptance of remuneration for any work described in this subsection, but does not include the solicitation of a bid from a licensee to be incorporated in an overall bid by an unlicensed primary contractor to supply services to another.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pesticide or economic poison” means any substance or mixture of substances intended for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preventing, destroying, repelling, or mitigating any insects, rodents, nematodes, fungi, weeds, or other forms of plant or animal life or viruses, except viruses or fungi on or in living human beings or other animals; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use as a plant regulator, defoliant, or desiccant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rodent” means a rat, mouse, squirrel, or flying squirrel or other animal of the order Rodentia, including a bat, which may become a pest in, on, or under a structure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rodent control” means application of remedial measures for the purpose of controlling rodents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Special identification cardholder” means a person to whom an identification card has been issued by the department showing that the holder is authorized to perform fumigation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Structure” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any type of edifice or building, together with the land thereunder, the contents thereof, and any patio or terrace thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That portion of land upon which work has commenced for the erection of an edifice or building; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A railway car, motor vehicle, trailer, barge, boat, ship, aircraft, wharf, dock, warehouse, or common carrier.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Termites and other wood-destroying organisms pest control” means pest control with respect to any termite or other wood-destroying organisms, including fungi, by the use of any chemical or mechanical methods, including moisture control for the prevention or control of fungus in existing structures, but not including fumigation or general household pest control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Urban landscape” means pervious areas on residential, commercial, industrial, institutional, highway rights-of-way, or other nonagricultural lands that are planted with turf or horticultural plants. For the purposes of this section, agriculture has the same meaning as in s. 570.02.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wood-destroying organism” means arthropod or plant life which damages and can reinfest seasoned wood in a structure, namely termites, powder-post beetles, oldhouse borers, and wood-decaying fungi.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 176, ch. 71-377; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 180, ch. 77-104; s. 370, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 1, ch. 89-180; ss. 26, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 427, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 2001-280; s. 1, ch. 2006-289; s. 6, ch. 2009-199.</History></Section>