<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each individual seeking certification must satisfactorily pass an examination which must be written but which may include practical demonstration. The department shall hold at least two examinations each year. An applicant may seek certification in one or more categories.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for examination must be made in accordance with the rules of the department. Each application must be accompanied by a fee set by the department, in an amount of not more than $300 or less than $150, for each category in which the applicant desires to be examined; however, until rules setting these fees are adopted by the department, the examination fee for each category shall be $150. Any applicant who fails to pass one or more categories may reapply for examination upon the payment of the applicable fee for each category in which the applicant seeks reexamination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall give an examination in each category for which application is made which tests the applicant’s knowledge of pest control as applicable to that category. The certificate issued must state the categories allowed thereby.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A refund of examination fees may not be made unless the applicant presents written evidence that she or he was under military orders, on jury duty or otherwise subpoenaed, or under medical care which precluded reporting to take the examination, in which case the department shall exercise its discretion as to a refund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 380, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 9, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 7, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 10, ch. 89-180; ss. 37, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 432, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>