<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.152" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of certified operator in charge of pest control activities of licensee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified operator in charge of the pest control activities of a licensee shall have her or his primary occupation with the licensee and shall be a full-time employee of the licensee, and her or his principal duty shall include the responsibility for the personal supervision of and participation in the pest control activities at the business location of the licensee as the same relate to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selection of proper and correct chemicals for the particular pest control work performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safe and proper use of the pesticides used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The correct concentration and formulation of pesticides used in all pest control work performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The training of personnel in the proper and acceptable methods of pest control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The control measures and procedures used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notification of the department of any accidental human poisoning or death connected with pest control work performed on a job she or he is supervising, within 24 hours after she or he has knowledge of the poisoning or death.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 382, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 11, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 9, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 12, ch. 89-180; ss. 39, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 433, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>