<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary grounds and actions; reinstatement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a written warning to or impose a fine against, or deny the application for licensure or licensure renewal of, a licensee, certified operator, limited certificateholder, identification cardholder, or special identification cardholder or any other person, or may suspend, revoke, or deny the issuance or renewal of any license, certificate, limited certificate, identification card, or special identification card that is within the scope of this chapter, in accordance with chapter 120, upon any of the following grounds:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of this chapter or of any rule of the department adopted pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction in any court within this state of a violation of any provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Habitual intemperance or addiction to narcotics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction in any court in any state or in any federal court of a felony, unless civil rights have been restored.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly making false or fraudulent claims with respect to pest control; knowingly misrepresenting the effects of materials or methods used in pest control; or knowingly failing to use materials or methods suitable for the pest control undertaken.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing pest control in a negligent manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to give to the department, or authorized representative thereof, true information upon request regarding methods and materials used, work performed, or other information essential to the administration of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or misleading advertising relative to pest control or advertising in an unauthorized category of pest control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pay an administrative fine imposed pursuant to subsection (7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impersonation of a department employee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A revocation or suspension of a license, certificate, or limited certificate is effective for all categories unless the department, in its sole discretion, suspends or revokes fewer than all categories thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years after a revocation, application may be made to the department for reinstatement; and the department may authorize reinstatement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any charge of a violation of this chapter or of the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter by a licensee affects only the license or permit of the business location from which the violation is alleged to have occurred. Another license or permit may not be issued to the same licensee, or to any person who has an ownership interest in the suspended or revoked business license of the licensee and who knew or should have known of the violation that resulted in the suspension or revocation, for a new business location in the same county or any contiguous county for a period of 3 years after the effective date of the suspension or revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after appropriate hearing in accordance with chapter 120, the department finds that a licensee, certified operator, limited certificateholder, identification cardholder, or special identification cardholder has committed any act described in subsection (1), but further finds that such act is of such nature or occurred under such circumstances that suspension or revocation of the license, certificate, limited certificate, identification card, or special identification card would either be detrimental to the public or be unnecessarily harsh under the circumstances, it may, in lieu of executing the order of suspension or revocation, either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reprimand the party publicly or privately; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place the party on probation for a period of not more than 2 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that the terms of any such probation have been violated, it may revoke the probation order immediately; and its initial order takes effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person is found by the department to have violated any of the other terms of this chapter or of the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter, the department may declare such probation revoked; and, in its proceeding with regard to such additional violation, the department may consider the violation for which probation is in effect in determining the extent of its order with regard to such additional violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, pursuant to chapter 120, in addition to or in lieu of any other remedy provided by state or local law, may impose an administrative fine, in an amount not exceeding $5,000, for the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or of the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter. In determining the amount of fine to be levied for a violation, the following factors shall be considered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the violation, including the probability that the death, or serious harm to the health or safety, of any person will result or has resulted; the severity of the actual or potential harm; and the extent to which the provisions of this chapter or of the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter were violated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any actions taken by the licensee or certified operator in charge, or limited certificateholder, to correct the violation or to remedy complaints;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations of this chapter or of the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost to the department of investigating the violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An administrative law judge may, in lieu of or in addition to imposition of a fine, recommend probation or public or private reprimand. A public reprimand must be made in a newspaper of general circulation in the county of the licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall publish quarterly a list of disciplinary actions taken pursuant to this section and shall provide such list to each licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require any licensee disciplined for a violation of s. 482.226 to submit to the department reports for wood-destroying organism inspections and treatments performed. These reports must be submitted at such times as required by the department but not more frequently than once a week.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 65-295; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 383, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 12, ch. 78-292; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 13, ch. 89-180; ss. 42, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 7, ch. 94-194; s. 225, ch. 96-410; s. 6, ch. 2001-280; s. 5, ch. 2003-35.</History></Section>