<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0482.227" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Guarantees and warranties; contracts executed after October 1, 2003.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the terms “guarantee” and “warranty” are common in contracts for the treatment of wood-destroying organisms. The purpose of this section is to assure that contract language describing a “guarantee” or “warranty” is clear and easily identifiable for the protection of consumers and licensees. Therefore the following provisions shall apply to each new contract for the treatment of wood-destroying organisms issued by the licensee and signed by the customer after October 1, 2003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contract for treatment of wood-destroying organisms must specify on the first page in bold print that it is offered for repair and retreatment or for retreatment only or that no warranty or guarantee is offered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract for treatment of wood-destroying organisms must specify on the first page in bold print whether there are any disclaimers, limitations, conditions, or exclusions on the licensee’s obligation to repair or re-treat the property. Contract sections describing disclaimers, limitations, conditions, or exclusions applicable to the licensee’s obligation to repair or re-treat the property must contain headings in bold print.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a contract for treatment of wood-destroying organisms contains a disclaimer, limitation, condition, or exclusion applicable to the licensee’s obligation to repair or re-treat the property, the term “full” or “unlimited” may not be used together with the term “guarantee” or “warranty.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 15, ch. 82-229; ss. 53, 59, ch. 92-203; ss. 20, 21, ch. 2002-295.</History></Section>