<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0482.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter. Prior to proposing the adoption of a rule, the department shall counsel with members of the pest control industry concerning the proposed rule. The department shall adopt rules for the protection of the health, safety, and welfare of pest control employees and the general public which require:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all pesticides or economic poisons be used only in accordance with the registered labels and labeling or as directed by the United States Environmental Protection Agency or the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That vehicles and trailers used in pest control be permanently marked with the licensee’s name that is registered with the department. However, vehicles that are used to perform only sales and solicitation may have temporary or removable markers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That written contracts be required for providing termites and other wood-destroying organisms pest control, that provisions necessary to assure consumer protection as specified by the department be included in such contracts, and that require licensees to comply with the contracts issued.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a licensee, before performing general fumigation, notify in writing the department inspector having jurisdiction over the location where the fumigation is to be performed, which notice must be received by the department inspector at least 24 hours before the fumigation and must contain such information as the department requires. However, in an authentic and verifiable emergency, when 24 hours’ advance notice is not possible, advance notice may be given by telephone, facsimile, or any other form of acceptable electronic communication, but such notice must be immediately followed by written confirmation providing the required information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That any pesticide used as the primary preventive treatment for subterranean termites in new construction be applied in the amount, concentration, and treatment area in accordance with the label; that a copy of the label of the registered pesticide being applied be carried in a vehicle at the site where the pesticide is being applied; and that the licensee maintain for 3 years the record of each preconstruction treatment, indicating the date of treatment, the location or address of the property treated, the total square footage of the structure treated, the type of pesticide applied, the concentration of each substance in the mixture applied, and the total amount of pesticide applied.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the department may issue an immediate stop-use or stop-work order for fumigation performed in violation of fumigant label requirements or department rules, or in a manner that presents an immediate serious danger to the health, safety, or welfare of the public, including, but not limited to, failure to use required personal protective equipment, failure to use a required warning agent, failure to post required warning signs, failure to secure a structure’s usual entrances as required, or using a fumigant in a manner that will likely result in hazardous exposure to humans, animals, or the environment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-454; s. 1, ch. 65-295; ss. 14, 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 372, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-161; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 14, 15, ch. 82-229; s. 1, ch. 86-78; s. 2, ch. 89-180; ss. 28, 59, ch. 92-203; s. 1, ch. 94-194; s. 154, ch. 98-200; s. 11, ch. 2000-308; s. 2, ch. 2001-280; s. 1, ch. 2003-35; s. 2, ch. 2006-289; s. 1, ch. 2011-192; s. 7, ch. 2011-206.</History>
</Section>