<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0207.023" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority to inspect vehicles, make arrests, seize property, and execute warrants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a part of their responsibility when inspecting commercial vehicles, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, and the Department of Transportation shall ensure that all vehicles are properly qualified under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, the Department of Transportation, and their deputies, agents, and employees may assess the penalty imposed in s. 316.545(4) for violations of s. 207.004(4) and may make arrests without warrants for violations of the other provisions of this chapter. Any person arrested for a violation of any provision of this chapter shall be surrendered without delay to the sheriff of the county in which the arrest was made, and a formal complaint shall be made against the person, in accordance with law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commercial motor vehicles owned or operated by any motor carrier who refuses to comply with this chapter may be seized by authorized agents or employees of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, or the Department of Transportation; or authorized agents and employees of any of these departments also may seize property as set out in ss. 206.205, 206.21, and 206.215. Upon such seizure, the property shall be surrendered without delay to the sheriff of the county where the property was seized for further proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles deems it advisable, it may direct the warrant provided for in s. 207.014 to one of such deputies, agents, or employees of the department, who shall then execute the warrant and proceed thereon in the same manner provided for sheriffs in such cases.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-415; s. 3, ch. 81-151; s. 69, ch. 83-217; s. 56, ch. 85-180; s. 11, ch. 87-198; s. 1094, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 206.992.</Text></Note></Section>