<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0055.204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duration and continuation of judgment lien; destruction of records.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, a judgment lien acquired under s. 55.202 lapses and becomes invalid 5 years after the date of filing the judgment lien certificate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Liens securing the payment of child support or tax obligations under s. 95.091(1)(b) lapse 20 years after the date of the original filing of the warrant or other document required by law to establish a lien. Liens securing the payment of reemployment assistance tax obligations lapse 10 years after the date of the original filing of the notice of lien. A second lien based on the original filing may not be obtained.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time within 6 months before or 6 months after the scheduled lapse of a judgment lien under subsection (1), the judgment creditor may acquire a second judgment lien by filing a new judgment lien certificate. The effective date of the second judgment lien is the date and time on which the judgment lien certificate is filed. The second judgment lien is a new judgment lien and not a continuation of the original judgment lien. The second judgment lien permanently lapses and becomes invalid 5 years after its filing date, and additional liens based on the original judgment or any judgment based on the original judgment may not be acquired.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judgment lien continues only as to itemized property for an additional 90 days after lapse of the lien. Such judgment lien continues only if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property was itemized and its location described with sufficient particularity in the instructions for levy to permit the sheriff to act;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The instructions for the levy had been delivered to the sheriff before the date of lapse of the lien; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property was located in the county in which the sheriff has jurisdiction at the time of delivery of the instruction for levy. Subsequent removal of the property does not defeat the lien. A court may order continuation of the lien beyond the 90-day period on a showing that extraordinary circumstances have prevented levy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of lapse of a judgment lien whose enforceability has been temporarily stayed or enjoined as a result of any legal or equitable proceeding is tolled until 30 days after the stay or injunction is terminated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a second judgment lien is not filed, the Department of State shall maintain each judgment lien file and all information contained therein for a minimum of 1 year after the judgment lien lapses in accordance with this section. If a second judgment lien is filed, the department shall maintain both files and all information contained in such files for a minimum of 1 year after the second judgment lien lapses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> This section does not extend the life of a judgment lien beyond the time that the underlying judgment, order, decree, or warrant otherwise expires or becomes invalid pursuant to law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2000-258; s. 4, ch. 2001-154; s. 3, ch. 2005-241; s. 3, ch. 2010-90; s. 1, ch. 2010-138; s. 34, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>