<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0055.208" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of filed judgment lien on writs of execution previously delivered to a sheriff.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lien created by a writ of execution which has been delivered to the sheriff of any county before October 1, 2001, remains in effect for 2 years thereafter as to any property of the judgment debtor located in that county before October 1, 2001, and remaining within that county after that date. As to any property of the judgment debtor brought into the county on or after October 1, 2001, such writs create no lien, inchoate or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a judgment creditor who has delivered a writ of execution to a sheriff in any county prior to October 1, 2001, properly files a judgment lien certificate with the Department of State by October 1, 2003, the resulting judgment lien is deemed filed on the date the writ was delivered to the sheriff as to all property of the judgment debtor subject to execution in this state under s. 56.061 which is located in that county on October 1, 2001, and that remains continuously in that county thereafter. Priority of such judgment liens is determined as of the effective date they are considered to have been filed. As to all other property of the judgment debtor, the effective date of the judgment lien is as provided in s. 55.202. The duration of all judgment liens is as provided in s. 55.204.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a judgment creditor who has delivered a writ of execution to a sheriff in any county before October 1, 2001, does not properly file a judgment lien certificate with the Department of State by October 1, 2003, such writ is considered to have been abandoned and to be of no effect after October 1, 2003.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2000-258; s. 8, ch. 2001-154.</History></Section>