<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0329.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Aircraft identification numbers; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, firm, association, or corporation to knowingly buy, sell, offer for sale, receive, dispose of, conceal, or have in his or her possession, or to endeavor to buy, sell, offer for sale, receive, dispose of, conceal, or possess, any aircraft or part thereof on which the assigned identification numbers do not meet the requirements of the federal aviation regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the identification numbers required by this subsection have been knowingly omitted, altered, removed, destroyed, covered, or defaced, or the real identity of the aircraft cannot be determined due to an intentional act of the owner or possessor, the aircraft may be seized as contraband property by a law enforcement agency and shall be subject to forfeiture pursuant to ss. 932.701-932.704. Such aircraft may not be knowingly sold or operated from any airport, landing field, or other property or body of water where aircraft may land or take off in this state unless the Federal Aviation Administration has issued the aircraft a replacement identification number which shall thereafter be used for identification purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to knowingly possess, manufacture, sell or exchange, offer to sell or exchange, supply in blank, or give away any counterfeit manufacturer’s aircraft identification number plate or decal used for the purpose of identification of any aircraft; to authorize, direct, aid in exchange, or give away such counterfeit manufacturer’s aircraft identification number plate or decal; or to conspire to do any of the foregoing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure to have aircraft identification numbers clearly displayed on the aircraft and in compliance with federal aviation regulations is probable cause for any law enforcement officer in this state to make further inspection of the aircraft in question to ascertain its true identity. A law enforcement officer is authorized to inspect an aircraft for identification numbers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When it is located on public property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon consent of the owner of the private property on which the aircraft is stored.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 83-272; s. 23, ch. 87-243; s. 33, ch. 91-221; s. 472, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>