<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0341.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transit safety standards; inspections and system safety reviews.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt by rule minimum safety standards for governmentally owned fixed-guideway transportation systems and privately owned or operated fixed-guideway transportation systems operating in this state which are financed wholly or partly by state funds. Standards must be site-specific for fixed-guideway transportation systems and shall be developed jointly by the department and representatives of the affected systems, giving full consideration to nationwide industry safety norms relating to the development and operation of fixed-guideway transportation systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each fixed-guideway transportation system shall develop a safety program plan that complies with established standards and shall certify to the department that the plan complies with the standards. Following certification to the department, the fixed-guideway transportation system shall implement and comply with the plan during the development and operation of the system. Each fixed-guideway transportation system shall verify annually in writing to the department that it has complied with its adopted safety program plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before beginning passenger service operations, a fixed-guideway transportation system must certify in writing to the department that the system is safe for passenger service. Further, before a fixed-guideway transportation system the operations of which have been suspended as a result of noncompliance with established standards returns to service, the system must certify in writing to the department that the system is safe for passenger service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a fixed-guideway transportation system does not comply with paragraph (b) or paragraph (c) or if, upon certification by a fixed-guideway transportation system, the department has good cause to believe that the system is not complying with its adopted safety program plan or is not safe for passenger service, the department may conduct a review of the system for safety compliance. Upon completion of its review, the department shall provide a copy of the review report to the affected system. Any adverse findings and any corrective actions required and the time allowed for such actions must be stated in the report. If at any time continued operation of the system, or a portion thereof, poses an immediate danger to public safety, the system operator shall suspend affected system service until corrective action is taken. If the system operator fails to take corrective action or fails to suspend service when immediate danger to the public exists, the department may require the affected system service to be suspended.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt by rule minimum equipment and operational safety standards for all governmentally owned bus transit systems and privately owned or operated bus transit systems operating in this state that are financed wholly or partly by state funds, all bus transit systems created pursuant to chapter 427, and all privately owned or operated bus transit systems under contract with any of the foregoing systems. Standards for bus transit systems shall be developed jointly by the department and representatives of the transit systems. Each such bus transit system shall develop a transit safety program plan that complies with established standards and shall certify to the department that the plan complies with the standards. Following certification to the department, the bus transit system shall implement and comply with the plan during the operation of the transit system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each bus transit system shall, as part of the safety program plan, require that all transit buses operated by the system be inspected at least annually in accordance with established standards. Qualified personnel of the bus transit system or public or private entities qualified by the bus transit system shall perform safety inspections. Each bus transit system shall certify annually in writing to the department that it has complied with its adopted safety program plan and, as part of that plan, that safety inspections have been performed by a qualified entity at least once that year on all transit buses operated by such system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a bus transit system does not comply with paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) or if, upon certification by a bus transit system, the department has good cause to believe that the system is not complying with its adopted safety program plan or is not safe for passenger service, the department may conduct a review of the system for safety compliance. Upon completion of its review, the department shall provide a copy of the review report to the affected system. Any adverse findings and any corrective actions required and the time allowed for such actions must be stated in the report. If at any time continued operation of the system, or a portion thereof, poses an immediate danger to public safety, the system operator shall suspend affected system service until corrective action is taken. If the system operator fails to take corrective action or fails to suspend service when immediate danger to the public exists, the department may require the affected system service to be suspended.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 84-340; s. 37, ch. 86-243.</History></Section>