<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0341.0532" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide transportation corridors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “statewide transportation corridor” is defined as a system of transportation infrastructure that collectively provides for the efficient movement of significant volumes of intrastate, interstate, and international commerce by seamlessly linking multiple modes of transport.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida’s statewide transportation corridors are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Atlantic Coast Corridor, from Jacksonville to Miami, including Interstate 95.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Gulf Coast Corridor, from Pensacola to St. Petersburg and to Tampa including U.S. Route 98 and U.S. Route 19/State Road 27.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Central Florida/North-South Corridor, from the Florida-Georgia border to Naples and Fort Lauderdale/Miami, including Interstate 75.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Central Florida/East-West Corridor from St. Petersburg to Tampa and to Titusville, including Interstate 4 and the Beeline Expressway.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The North Florida Corridor, from Pensacola to Jacksonville, including Interstate 10, and U.S. Route 231, State Road 77, and State Road 79 from the Florida-Alabama border to Panama City.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Jacksonville to Tampa Corridor, including U.S. Route 301.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Jacksonville to Orlando Corridor, including U.S. 17.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Southeastern Everglades Corridor, linking Wildwood, Winter Garden, Orlando, and West Palm Beach via the Florida Turnpike.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this subsection, the term “corridor” includes railways adjacent to such corridor and the roadways linking to transportation terminals, and intermodal service centers to the major highways listed in this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 2003-286.</History></Section>