<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Governors, or the board’s designee, authorized to secure liability insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors, or the board’s designee, is authorized to secure, or otherwise provide as a self-insurer, or by a combination thereof, comprehensive general liability insurance, including professional liability for health care and veterinary sciences, for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors and its officers and members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A university board of trustees and its officers and members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The faculty and other employees and agents of a university board of trustees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The students of a state university.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state university or any college, school, institute, center, or program thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any not-for-profit corporation organized pursuant to chapter 617, and the directors, officers, employees, and agents thereof, which is affiliated with a state university, if the corporation is operated for the benefit of the state university in a manner consistent with the best interests of the state, and if such participation is approved by a self-insurance program council, the university president, and the board of trustees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the Board of Governors, or the board’s designee, adopts a self-insurance program, a governing council chaired by the vice president for health affairs or his or her academic equivalent shall be established to administer the program and its duties and responsibilities, including the administration of self-insurance program assets and expenditure policies, which shall be defined in rules as authorized by this section. The council shall have an annual actuary review performed to establish funding requirements to maintain the fiscal integrity of the self-insurance program. The assets of a self-insurance program shall be deposited outside the State Treasury and shall be administered in accordance with rules as authorized by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any self-insurance program created under this section shall be funded by the entities and individuals protected by such program. There shall be no funds appropriated to any self-insurance program. The assets of the self-insurance program shall be the property of the board that adopts the self-insurance program and shall be used only to pay the administrative expenses of the self-insurance program and to pay any claim, judgment, or claims bill arising out of activities for which the self-insurance program was created. Investment income that is in excess of that income necessary to ensure the solvency of a self-insurance program as established by a casualty actuary may be used to defray the annual contribution paid into the program by the entities and individuals protected by the program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No self-insurance program adopted by the Board of Governors, or the board’s designee, may sue or be sued. The claims files of any such program are privileged and confidential, exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1), and are only for the use of the program in fulfilling its duties. Any self-insurance trust fund and revenues generated by that fund shall only be used to pay claims and administration expenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each self-insurance program council shall make provision for an annual financial audit pursuant to s. 11.45 of its accounts to be conducted by an independent certified public accountant. The annual audit report must include a management letter and shall be submitted to the Board of Governors and the university board of trustees for review. The Board of Governors shall have the authority to require and receive from the self-insurance program council or from its independent auditor any detail or supplemental data relative to the operation of the self-insurance program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 170, ch. 2002-387; s. 42, ch. 2004-41; s. 88, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>