<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.648" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Energy Systems Consortium.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida Energy Systems Consortium to promote collaboration among experts in the State University System for the purposes of sharing energy-related expertise and assisting in the development and implementation of a comprehensive, long-term, environmentally compatible, sustainable, and efficient energy strategic plan for the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consortium shall focus on the research and development of innovative energy systems that will lead to alternative energy strategies, improved energy efficiencies, and expanded economic development for the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consortium shall consist of the state universities as identified under s. 1000.21(6).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consortium shall be administered at the University of Florida by a director who shall be appointed by the President of the University of Florida.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director, whose office is located at the University of Florida, shall report to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The oversight board shall consist of the Vice President for Research or other appropriate representative appointed by the university president of each member of the consortium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The oversight board shall be responsible for the technical performance and financial management of the consortium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performing its responsibilities, the consortium shall collaborate with the oversight board and may also collaborate with industry and other affected parties.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Through collaborative research and development across the State University System and the industry, the goal of the consortium is to become a world leader in energy research, education, technology, and energy systems analysis. In so doing, the consortium shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate and initiate increased collaborative interdisciplinary energy research among the universities and the energy industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in the creation and development of a Florida-based energy technology industry through efforts that would expedite commercialization of innovative energy technologies by taking advantage of the energy expertise within the State University System, high-technology incubators, industrial parks, and industry-driven research centers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a state resource for objective energy systems analysis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop education and outreach programs to prepare a qualified energy workforce and informed public. Specifically, the faculty associated with the consortium shall coordinate a statewide workforce development initiative focusing on college-level degrees, technician training, and public and commercial sectors awareness. The consortium shall develop specific programs targeted at preparing graduates who have a background in energy, continuing education courses for technical and nontechnical professionals, and modules, laboratories, and courses to be shared among the universities. Additionally, the consortium shall work with the Florida College System using the Florida Advanced Technological Education Center for the coordination and design of industry-specific training programs for technicians.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consortium shall solicit and leverage state, federal, and private funds for the purpose of conducting education, research, and development in the area of sustainable energy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The oversight board, in consultation with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, shall ensure that the consortium:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintains accurate records of any funds received by the consortium.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets financial and technical performance expectations, which may include external technical reviews as required.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The steering committee shall consist of the university representatives included in the Centers of Excellence proposals for the Florida Energy Systems Consortium and the Center of Excellence in Ocean Energy Technology-Phase II which were reviewed during the 2007-2008 fiscal year by the Florida Technology, Research, and Scholarship Board created in s. 1004.226(4), Florida Statutes 2006; a university representative appointed by the President of Florida International University; and a representative of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. The steering committee is responsible for establishing and ensuring the success of the consortium’s mission under subsection (9).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By November 1 of each year, the consortium shall submit an annual report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services regarding its activities, including, but not limited to, education and research related to, and the development and deployment of, alternative energy technologies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 112, ch. 2008-227; s. 49, ch. 2011-5; s. 526, ch. 2011-142; s. 13, ch. 2012-6.</History>
</Section>