<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ringling Center for Cultural Arts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida State University Ringling Center for Cultural Arts is created. The center consists of the following properties located in Sarasota County:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art composed of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The art museum.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Ca’ d’Zan (the Ringling residence).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Ringling Museum of the Circus.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida State University Center for the Fine and Performing Arts, including the Asolo Theater and the Florida State University Center for the Performing Arts, both of which shall provide for academic programs in theatre, dance, art, art history, and museum management.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The center shall be operated by the Florida State University, which shall be charged with encouraging participation by K-12 schools and by other postsecondary educational institutions, public and private, in the educational and cultural enrichment programs of the center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art is designated as the official Art Museum of the State of Florida. The purpose and function of the museum is to maintain and preserve all objects of art and artifacts donated to the state through the will of John Ringling; to acquire and preserve objects of art or artifacts of historical or cultural significance; to exhibit such objects to the public; to undertake scholarly research and publication, including that relating to the collection; to provide educational programs for students at K-12 schools and those in college and graduate school and enrichment programs for children and adults; to assist other museums in the state and nation through education programs and through loaning objects from the collection when such loans do not threaten the safety and security of the objects; to enhance knowledge and appreciation of the collection; and to engage in other activities related to visual arts which benefit the public. The museum shall also engage in programs on the national and international level to enhance further the cultural resources of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida State University shall approve a John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization. Such direct-support organization shall consist of no more than 31 members appointed by the president of the university from a list of nominees provided by the Ringling direct-support organization. No fewer than one-third of the members must be residents of Sarasota and Manatee Counties, and the remaining members may reside elsewhere. The current members of the Board of Trustees of the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art may be members of the direct-support organization. They shall develop a charter and bylaws to govern their operation, and these shall be subject to approval by the Florida State University.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization, operating under the charter and bylaws and such contracts as are approved by the university, shall set policies to maintain and preserve the collections of the Art Museum; the Circus Museum; the furnishings and objects in the Ringling home, referred to as the Ca’ d’Zan; and other objects of art and artifacts in the custody of the museum. Title to all such collections, art objects, and artifacts of the museums and its facilities shall remain with the Florida State University, which shall assign state registration numbers to, and conduct annual inventories of, all such properties. The direct-support organization shall develop policy for the museum, subject to the provisions of the John Ringling will and the overall direction of the president of the university; and it is invested with power and authority to nominate a museum director who is appointed by and serves at the pleasure of the president of the university and shall report to the provost of the university or his or her designee. The museum director, with the approval of the provost or his or her designee, shall appoint other employees in accordance with Florida Statutes and rules; remove the same in accordance with Florida Statutes and rules; provide for the proper keeping of accounts and records and budgeting of funds; enter into contracts for professional programs of the museum and for the support and maintenance of the museum; secure public liability insurance; and do and perform every other matter or thing requisite to the proper management, maintenance, support, and control of the museum at the highest efficiency economically possible, while taking into consideration the purposes of the museum.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provision of s. 287.057, the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization may enter into contracts or agreements with or without competitive bidding, in its discretion, for the restoration of objects of art in the museum collection or for the purchase of objects of art that are to be added to the collection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 273.055, the university may sell any art object in the museum collection, which object has been acquired after 1936, if the director and the direct-support organization recommend such sale to the president of the university and if they first determine that the object is no longer appropriate for the collection. The proceeds of the sale shall be deposited in the Ringling Museum Art Acquisition, Restoration, and Conservation Trust Fund. The university also may exchange any art object in the collection, which object has been acquired after 1936, for an art object or objects that the director and the museum direct-support organization recommend to the university after judging these to be of equivalent or greater value to the museum.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee or member of the museum direct-support organization may not receive a commission, fee, or financial benefit in connection with the sale or exchange of a work of art and may not be a business associate of any individual, firm, or organization involved in the sale or exchange.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university, in consultation with the direct-support organization, shall establish policies and may adopt rules for the sale or exchange of works of art.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization shall provide for an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 1004.28(5). Florida State University is authorized to require and receive from the direct-support organization, or from its independent auditor, any detail or supplemental data relative to the operation of such organization. Information that, if released, would identify donors who desire to remain anonymous, is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). Information that, if released, would identify prospective donors is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) when the direct-support organization has identified the prospective donor itself and has not obtained the name of the prospective donor by copying, purchasing, or borrowing names from another organization or source. Identities of such donors and prospective donors shall not be revealed in the auditor’s report.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization is given authority to make temporary loans of paintings and other objects of art or artifacts belonging to the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art for the purpose of public exhibition in art museums, other museums, or institutions of higher learning wherever located, including such museums or institutions in other states or countries. Temporary loans may also be made to the executive mansion in Tallahassee, chapters and affiliates of the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, and, for education purposes, to schools, public libraries, or other institutions in the state, if such exhibition will benefit the general public as the university deems wise and for the best interest of the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art and under policies established by Florida State University for the protection of the paintings and other objects of art and artifacts. In making temporary loans, the direct-support organization shall give first preference to art museums, other museums, and institutions of higher learning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization is eligible to match state funds in the University Major Gifts Program established pursuant to s. 1011.94 as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first $1,353,750, matching shall be on the basis of 75 cents in state matching for each dollar of private funds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For additional funds, matching shall be provided on the same basis as is authorized in s. 1011.94.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 192, ch. 2002-387; s. 117, ch. 2003-1; s. 5, ch. 2007-18.</History></Section>