<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.726" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trademarks, copyrights, or patents.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution board of trustees may develop and produce work products relating to educational endeavors that are subject to trademark, copyright, or patent statutes. To this end, the board of trustees shall consider the relative contribution by the personnel employed in the development of such work products and shall enter into binding agreements with such personnel, organizations, corporations, or government entities, which agreements shall establish the percentage of ownership of such trademarks, copyrights, or patents. Any other law to the contrary notwithstanding, the board of trustees may in its own name:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform all things necessary to secure letters of patent, copyrights, and trademarks on any such work products and enforce its rights therein.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License, lease, assign, or otherwise give written consent to any person, firm, or corporation for the manufacture or use of its work products on a royalty basis or for such other consideration as the board of trustees deems proper.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take any action necessary, including legal action, to protect its work products against improper or unlawful use of infringement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the collection of any sums due the board of trustees for the manufacture or use of its work products by any other party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell any of its work products and execute all instruments necessary to consummate any such sale.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do all other acts necessary and proper for the execution of powers and duties provided by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 222, ch. 2002-387; s. 57, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>