<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">New College of Florida.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISSION AND GOALS.<EmDash />New College of Florida with a campus in Sarasota County serves a distinctive mission as the 4-year residential liberal arts honors college of the State of Florida. To maintain this mission, New College of Florida has the following goals:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide a quality education to students of high ability who, because of their ability, deserve a program of study that is both demanding and stimulating.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To engage in undergraduate educational reform by combining educational innovation with educational excellence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide programs of study that allow students to design their educational experience as much as possible in accordance with their individual interests, values, and abilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To challenge undergraduates not only to master existing bodies of knowledge but also to extend the frontiers of knowledge through original research.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCREDITATION.<EmDash />As soon as possible, New College of Florida shall apply to the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools for separate accreditation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD OF TRUSTEES.<EmDash />The Governor shall appoint 12 members to the Board of Trustees, to serve 4-year staggered terms, as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three residents of Sarasota County.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two residents of Manatee County.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Until the expiration date of the terms of office of the members who are on the board June 30, 2001, seven members selected from the Board of Trustees of the New College Foundation.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In addition, the student body president of New College of Florida elected pursuant to s. 1004.26 shall serve ex officio as a voting member of the board of trustees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2002-188; s. 176, ch. 2002-387; s. 116, ch. 2003-1.</History></Section>