<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida School of the Arts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the state strives to achieve excellence in all aspects of public education, it is the intent of the Legislature that specific attention be given to the needs of artistically talented high school and college students. It is further intended that such students who are occupationally oriented to the arts be provided with the means for achieving both an academic education and artistic training appropriate to their gifts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida School of the Arts. The school shall offer a program of academic and artistic studies in the visual and performing arts, which program shall be available to talented high school and college students in the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida School of the Arts is assigned to the District Board of Trustees of the St. Johns River State College for purposes of administration and governance; but the Florida School of the Arts, within appropriations and limitations established annually by the Legislature, shall serve as a professional school on a statewide basis for all qualified students.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Council for the Florida School of the Arts shall be established to advise the Florida College System institution district board of trustees on matters pertaining to the operation of the school. The council shall consist of nine members, appointed by the Commissioner of Education for 4-year terms. A member may serve three terms and may serve until replaced.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 225, ch. 2002-387; s. 58, ch. 2011-5; s. 3, ch. 2011-102.</History>
</Section>