<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Training school consolidation pilot projects.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ESTABLISHMENT.<EmDash />To consolidate and more efficiently use state and taxpayer resources by combining training programs, pilot training centers are established to provide public criminal justice training in Leon and St. Johns Counties. The following pilot training centers are established:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Pat Thomas Center at Tallahassee Community College.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Criminal Justice Academy at St. Johns River State College.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXISTING PUBLIC CRIMINAL JUSTICE TRAINING PROGRAMS.<EmDash />Notwithstanding ss. 1001.31, 1001.33, and 1007.25, or any other provision of law to the contrary, criminal justice training programs in the pilot counties will transfer to Florida College System institutions, effective July 1, 1999, at which time responsibility for the provision of basic recruit, advanced, career development, and continuing training courses and programs offered in public criminal justice training programs and for the operation of existing public criminal justice training programs will be shifted from the school district to the Florida College System institution in whose service area the public criminal justice training program is located. Certification of the program granted by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission will be transferred to the respective Florida College System institution and the college must continue to meet the requirements of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FACILITIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal justice training program educational facilities, educational plants, and related equipment as defined in s. 1013.01(6) and (7) which are owned by the state and paid for with only state funds shall be transferred to the Florida College System institution, except that, if such an educational facility or educational plant or part of such facility or plant is used for other purposes in addition to public criminal justice training, the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission shall mediate the transfer or a suitable multiuse arrangement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal justice training program educational facilities, educational plants, and related equipment as defined in s. 1013.01(6) and (7) which are owned by the school district and paid for in whole or in part with local tax funds shall be leased to the Florida College System institution. However, if such an educational facility or educational plant, or part of such facility or plant, is used for other purposes in addition to public criminal justice training, the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission shall mediate a suitable lease agreement. If a school district and a Florida College System institution cannot agree on the terms and conditions of the lease agreement, the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission shall finalize the agreement and report its decision to the Legislature. The Department of Education, Office of Educational Facilities, shall conduct an analysis, by December 31, 1999, to determine the amount of local tax contribution used in the construction of a school-district-owned criminal justice training program, educational facility, or educational plant affected by the transfer. This analysis shall be used to establish a purchase price for the facility or plant. The Florida College System institution board of trustees may make a legislative budget request through the State Board of Education to purchase the facility or plant, or it may continue to lease the facility or plant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />Each pilot training center will be regional in nature, as defined by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission. Each Florida College System institution with responsibility for a public criminal justice training program must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a pilot training center advisory committee made up of professionals from the field of each training program included in the pilot project.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide certificate and noncredit options for students and training components of the pilot training center that so require.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop an articulation agreement with state universities to facilitate the transfer of graduates of a Florida College System institution degree training program to the upper division of a state university with a corresponding program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STAFFING.<EmDash />The Florida College System institution board of trustees may provide for school district public criminal justice training staff employed in full-time budgeted positions to be transferred into the Florida College System institution personnel system at the same rate of salary. Retirement and leave provisions will be transferred according to law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING.<EmDash />The Department of Education shall shift funds generated by students in the pilot training centers established by this section, including workforce development recurring and nonrecurring funds, from the appropriate school district to the respective Florida College System institution. The Florida College System institution shall qualify for future facilities funding upon transfer of the facility.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consistent with s. 1011.62(8), school districts that transfer programs will receive an amount equal to 15 percent of the funding generated for the program under the FEFP in 1996-1997.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reflecting the lower program costs in Florida College System institutions, notwithstanding the funding generated in paragraph (a), Florida College System institutions will receive 90 percent of the funding generated for the program under the FEFP in 1996-1997. The school district will retain the remaining 10 percent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 1009.22(3)(a) and 1011.80(5)(a), or any other provision of law to the contrary, fees for continuing workforce education for public law enforcement officers at these pilot centers shall not exceed 25 percent of the cost of the course, and state funding shall not under any circumstances exceed 50 percent of the cost of the course.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 226, ch. 2002-387; s. 12, ch. 2006-27; s. 59, ch. 2011-5; s. 4, ch. 2011-102.</History>
</Section>