<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult basic education” means courses of instruction designed to improve the employability of the state’s workforce through instruction in mathematics, reading, language, and workforce readiness skills at grade level equivalency 0-8.9.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult ESOL” or “adult ESL” means noncredit English literacy courses designed to improve the employability of the state’s workforce through acquisition of communication skills and cultural competencies that enhance ability to read, write, speak, and listen in English. ESOL means English for Speakers of Other Languages. ESL means English as a Second Language. The two terms are interchangeable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult general education” means comprehensive instructional programs designed to improve the employability of the state’s workforce through adult basic education, adult secondary education, English for Speakers of Other Languages, vocational-preparatory instruction, and instruction for adults with disabilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult high school credit program” means the award of credits upon completion of courses and passing of state mandated assessments necessary to qualify for a high school diploma. Except as provided elsewhere in law, the graduation standards for adults shall be the same as those for secondary students.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult secondary education” means courses through which a person receives high school credit that leads to the award of a high school diploma or courses of instruction through which a student prepares to take the General Educational Development test.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult student” is a student who is beyond the compulsory school age and who has legally left elementary or secondary school.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult with disability” means an individual who has a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more major life activities, has a record of such impairment, or is regarded as having such an impairment, and who requires modifications to the educational program, adaptive equipment, or specialized instructional methods and services in order to participate in workforce development programs that lead to competitive employment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applied technology diploma program” means a course of study that is part of a technical degree program, is less than 60 credit hours, and leads to employment in a specific occupation. An applied technology diploma program may consist of either technical credit or college credit. A public school district may offer an applied technology diploma program only as technical credit, with college credit awarded to a student upon articulation to a Florida College System institution. Statewide articulation among public schools and Florida College System institutions is guaranteed by s. 1007.23, and is subject to guidelines and standards adopted by the State Board of Education pursuant to ss. 1007.24 and 1007.25.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Basic literacy,” means the demonstration of academic competence from 2.0 through 5.9 educational grade levels as measured by means approved for this purpose by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beginning literacy” means the demonstration of academic competence from 0 through 1.9 educational grade levels as measured by means approved for this purpose by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“College-preparatory instruction” means courses through which a high school graduate who applies for any college credit program may attain the communication and computation skills necessary to enroll in college credit instruction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community education” means the use of a school or other public facility as a community center operated in conjunction with other public, private, and governmental organizations for the purpose of providing educational, recreational, social, cultural, health, and community services for persons in the community in accordance with the needs, interests, and concerns of that community, including lifelong learning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Continuing workforce education” means instruction that does not result in a technical certificate, diploma, associate in applied science degree, or associate in science degree. Continuing workforce education is for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals who are required to have training for licensure renewal or certification renewal by a regulatory agency or credentialing body;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">New or expanding businesses as described in chapter 288;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business, industry, and government agencies whose products or services are changing so that retraining of employees is necessary or whose employees need training in specific skills to increase efficiency and productivity; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals who are enhancing occupational skills necessary to maintain current employment, to cross train, or to upgrade employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Technical degree education program” means a course of study that leads to an associate in applied science degree or an associate in science degree. A technical degree program may contain within it one or more program progression points and may lead to certificates or diplomas within the course of study. The term is interchangeable with the term “degree career education program.” For licensure purposes, the term “associate in science degree” is interchangeable with “associate in applied science degree.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Family literacy” means a program for adults with a literacy component for parents and children or other intergenerational literacy components.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Functional literacy,” which is also referred to as “intermediate adult basic education,” means the demonstration of academic competence from 6.0 through 8.9 educational grade levels as measured by means approved for this purpose by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General Educational Development (GED) test preparation” means courses of instruction designed to prepare adults for success on GED subject area tests leading to qualification for a State of Florida high school diploma.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lifelong learning” means a noncredit course or activity offered by a school district or Florida College System institution that seeks to address community social and economic issues related to health and human relations, government, parenting, consumer economics, and senior citizens.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local educational agency” means a Florida College System institution or school district.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local sponsor” means a district school board, Florida College System institution board of trustees, public library, other public entity, or private nonprofit entity, or any combination of these entities, that provides adult literacy instruction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Career certificate program” means a course of study that leads to at least one occupational completion point. The program may also confer credit that may articulate with a diploma or career degree education program, if authorized by rules of the State Board of Education. Any credit instruction designed to articulate to a degree program is subject to guidelines and standards adopted by the Department of Education pursuant to chapter 1007. The term is interchangeable with the term “certificate career education program.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Occupational completion point” means the occupational competencies that qualify a person to enter an occupation that is linked to a career and technical program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Career education planning region” means the geographic area in which career or adult education is provided. Each career region is contiguous with one of the 28 Florida College System institution service areas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vocational-preparatory instruction” means adult general education through which persons attain academic and workforce readiness skills at the level of functional literacy (grade levels 6.0-8.9) or higher so that such persons may pursue technical certificate education or higher-level technical education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Career program” means a group of identified competencies leading to occupations identified by a Classification of Instructional Programs number.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Workforce education” means adult general education or career education and may consist of a continuing workforce education course or a program of study leading to an occupational completion point, a career certificate, an applied technology diploma, or a career degree.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Workforce literacy” means the basic skills necessary to perform in entry-level occupations or the skills necessary to adapt to technological advances in the workplace.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 160, ch. 2002-387; s. 87, ch. 2004-357; s. 39, ch. 2011-5; s. 17, ch. 2011-55.</History>
</Section>