<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multidisciplinary Center for Affordable Housing.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Multidisciplinary Center for Affordable Housing is established within the School of Building Construction of the College of Architecture of the University of Florida with the collaboration of other related disciplines such as agriculture, business administration, engineering, law, and medicine. The center shall work in conjunction with other state universities. The Multidisciplinary Center for Affordable Housing shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct research relating to the problems and solutions associated with the availability of affordable housing in the state for families who are below the median income level and widely disseminate the results of such research to appropriate public and private audiences in the state. Such research shall emphasize methods to improve the planning, design, and production of affordable housing, including, but not limited to, the financial, maintenance, management, and regulatory aspects of residential development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide public services to local, regional, and state agencies, units of government, and authorities by helping them create regulatory climates that are amenable to the introduction of affordable housing within their jurisdictions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct special research relating to firesafety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a focus for the teaching of new technology and skills relating to affordable housing in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a base of informational and financial support from the private sector for the activities of the center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop prototypes for both multifamily and single-family units.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a research agenda and general work plan in cooperation with the Department of Economic Opportunity, which is the state agency responsible for research and planning for affordable housing and for training and technical assistance for providers of affordable housing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1 of each year. The annual report shall include information relating to the activities of the center, including collaborative efforts with public and private entities, affordable housing models, and any other findings and recommendations related to the production of safe, decent, and affordable housing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Director of the Multidisciplinary Center for Affordable Housing shall be appointed by the Dean of the College of Architecture of the University of Florida.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 193, ch. 2002-387; s. 467, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>