<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Leadership Board for Applied Research and Public Service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Leadership Board for Applied Research and Public Service to be staffed by the Institute of Science and Public Affairs at Florida State University. The purpose of the board is to focus, coordinate, and maximize university resources on current issues and events affecting Florida’s residents and elected officials. Emphasis shall be placed on being responsive to and providing accurate, timely, useful, and relevant information to decisionmakers in state and local governments. The board shall set forth a process to provide comprehensive guidance and advice for improving the types and quality of services to be delivered by the state universities. Specifically, the board shall better identify and define the missions and roles of existing institutes and centers at each state university, work to eliminate duplication and confusion over conflicting roles and missions, involve more students in learning with applied research and public service activities, and be organizationally separate from academic departments. The board shall meet at least quarterly. The board may create internal management councils that may include working institute and center directors. The board is responsible for, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing strategic direction, planning, and accompanying decisions that support a coordinated applied public service and research approach in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Addressing state university policy matters and making recommendations to the Board of Governors as they relate to applied public service and research.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serving as a clearinghouse for services requested by public officials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing support for funding and fiscal initiatives involving applied public service and research.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership of the board shall be:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chancellor of the State University System, or the chancellor’s designee, who shall serve as chair.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Office of Planning and Budgeting of the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary of the Department of Management Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of Economic and Demographic Research.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President of the Florida League of Cities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President for the Florida Association of Counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President of the Florida School Board Association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five additional university president members, designated by the chancellor, to rotate annually.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall prepare a report for the Board of Governors to be submitted to the Governor and the Legislature by January 1 of each year which summarizes the work and recommendations of the board in meeting its purpose and mission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 208, ch. 2002-387; s. 101, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>