<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.36" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Atlantic University campuses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Broward County campuses of Florida Atlantic University are hereby established as a partner of the Florida Atlantic University campus in Boca Raton. The Broward County campuses of Florida Atlantic University shall be known as “Florida Atlantic University Broward.” The Boca Raton campuses of Florida Atlantic University shall be known as “Florida Atlantic University Boca Raton.” The office of the president shall be at the campus in Boca Raton.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Atlantic University shall develop and administer a separate budget for Florida Atlantic University Broward. The budget shall include, at a minimum, an allocation of those operating and capital outlay funds appropriated annually by the Legislature in the General Appropriations Act for the Broward campuses; a proportional share, based on student credit hours produced at the Broward campuses, of any allocations received by the university from student tuition and fees, except for athletic fees, specifically authorized by law; all overhead charges from sponsored research conducted on the Broward campuses; and all revenues derived from vending funds, auxiliary enterprises and contracts, and grants and donations, as authorized by s. 1011.91, which result from activities on Broward campuses. Florida Atlantic University Broward and Florida Atlantic University Boca Raton may pay reasonable charges to appropriate levels of administration of Florida Atlantic University for services delivered universitywide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Atlantic University Board of Trustees shall take all actions necessary to ensure that Florida Atlantic University Broward and Florida Atlantic University Boca Raton are partners in the overall policymaking and academic governance structures of the university. Annual legislative budget requests for operations and facilities shall separately identify those funds requested for Florida Atlantic University Broward and Florida Atlantic University Boca Raton. Florida Atlantic University Broward and Florida Atlantic University Boca Raton shall have local management authority over their campus faculty, staff, and programs, but there shall be universitywide standards and processes for evaluating requests for promotion and tenure; there shall be complete transferability of credits and uniform programs across campuses; and colleges operating on multiple campuses shall have only one dean for each college. Florida Atlantic University Broward shall establish a faculty senate and may establish a direct-support organization. Any such direct-support organization shall be subject to s. 1004.28(5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors, as a function of its comprehensive master planning process, pursuant to s. 1001.706, shall continue to evaluate the need for undergraduate programs in Broward County and shall assess the extent to which existing postsecondary programs are addressing those needs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 181, ch. 2002-387; s. 92, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>