<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.346" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Industrial and Phosphate Research Institute.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INSTITUTE CREATION.<EmDash />The Florida Industrial and Phosphate Research Institute is established within the Florida Polytechnic University.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PHOSPHATE RESEARCH AND ACTIVITIES BOARD.<EmDash />The Phosphate Research and Activities Board is created to monitor the expenditure of funds appropriated to the university from the Phosphate Research Trust Fund.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall approve an annual report, prepared by the institute executive director, which outlines the expenditure of the funds appropriated to the university from the Phosphate Research Trust Fund and describes the various phosphate-related projects and institute operations funded by those moneys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall consist of five members. The Governor shall appoint two persons representing the phosphate mining or processing industry and one member representing a major environmental conservation group in the state. The Secretary of Environmental Protection or his or her designee and the president of the Florida Polytechnic University shall also serve as board members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the board appointed by the Governor shall be appointed to 3-year terms. A board member may continue to serve until a successor is appointed, but not more than 180 days after the expiration of his or her term. A board member is eligible for reappointment to subsequent terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members shall annually elect a chair from among the membership.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members shall serve without compensation, but are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INSTITUTE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR.<EmDash />An executive director shall be designated by and serve at the pleasure of the president of the Florida Polytechnic University or his or her designee. The executive director shall be responsible for the daily administration of the institute, including the expenditure of funds from all sources. The executive director shall consult with the Phosphate Research and Activities Board on the projects that the institute expects to undertake using moneys appropriated from the Phosphate Research Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INSTITUTE DUTIES AND AUTHORIZED ACTIVITIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish methods for better and more efficient practices for phosphate mining and processing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct or contract for studies on the environmental and health effects of phosphate mining and reclamation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct or contract for studies of reclamation alternatives and technologies in phosphate mining and processing and wetlands reclamation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct or contract for studies of phosphatic clay and phosphogypsum disposal and utilization as a part of phosphate mining and processing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the public with access to the results of its activities and maintain a public library related to the institute’s activities, which may contain special collections.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute may:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research and develop methods for better and more efficient processes and practices for commercial and industrial activities, including, but not limited to, mitigating the health and environmental effects of such activities as well as developing and evaluating alternatives and technologies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure funding from grants and other available sources for carrying out the activities authorized or required under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts with any firm, institution, or corporation, or federal, state, local, or foreign governmental agency, to carry out the activities authorized or required under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote the application, patenting, and commercialization of the institute’s technologies, knowledge, and intellectual property in accordance with university policies and procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educate the public about the science related to topics and issues that are within the institute’s scope of expertise.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold public hearings.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish public-private partnerships.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide consulting services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 78-136; s. 1, ch. 83-41; s. 16, ch. 83-339; s. 1, ch. 85-23; s. 3, ch. 86-294; s. 12, ch. 89-117; s. 114, ch. 90-360; s. 638, ch. 95-148; s. 181, ch. 96-406; s. 62, ch. 97-100; s. 1, ch. 2010-206; s. 10, ch. 2012-129.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 2, ch. 2012-129, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“The following transfers shall be made:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All real and personal property, licenses and associated revenues, existing contracts, unexpended balances, appropriations, allocations, funds, and mutually agreed-upon obligations, responsibilities, and liabilities of the University of South Florida which relate to the University of South Florida Polytechnic campus, as determined by the Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida and the Board of Trustees of the Florida Polytechnic University, shall be transferred to the Florida Polytechnic University.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) All Florida Industrial and Phosphate Research Institute programs, functions, offices, records, faculty positions, and staff positions of the University of South Florida Polytechnic shall be transferred to the Florida Polytechnic University.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) After the transfers required in subsections (1) and (2) are complete, all programs, functions, offices, records, faculty positions, and staff positions of the University of South Florida Polytechnic shall be transferred to the University of South Florida.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 378.101.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>