<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.635" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State University System Research and Economic Development Investment Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature to create an investment program in state universities that enhances graduate education and enables state universities to become nationally competitive in science and technology-based economic development.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GENERAL PROVISIONS.<EmDash />There is created the State University System Research and Economic Development Investment Program to provide matching funds to eligible institutions to construct and acquire cutting-edge, state-of-the-art science and engineering research facilities and specialized equipment to support research programs, foster economic development, and accelerate Florida’s innovation economy. The program shall be administered by the Board of Governors of the State University System.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INSTITUTIONAL ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to participate in the State University System Research and Economic Development Investment Program at Funding Level 1, a state university must meet each of the following criteria:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of nonprofessional doctoral degrees awarded each year must exceed 250. For purposes of this section, nonprofessional doctoral degrees do not include degrees awarded in law, medicine, dentistry, and veterinary medicine. At least 25 percent of the nonprofessional doctoral degrees must be in a mathematics, science, technology, engineering, or health-related discipline as defined by Classification of Instructional Program codes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of postdoctoral appointees reported in the most recent NSF/NIH Survey of Graduate Students and Postdoctorates in Science and Engineering must exceed 200.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 4-year undergraduate graduation rate must equal 40 percent or higher.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenditures from externally awarded contracts and grants must be a minimum of $100 million per year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university must have a proven track record of securing patents and licenses leading to products in the marketplace over the last 5 years.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 75 percent of the entering freshmen each academic year who are classified as residents for tuition purposes pursuant to s. 1009.21 must be eligible to receive Florida Bright Futures Scholarships.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Basic Classification of the university, according to the 2005 Carnegie Classifications, must be as a research university with very high research activity.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to participate in the State University System Research and Economic Development Investment Program at Funding Level 2, a state university must meet, at a minimum, the requirements of subparagraphs (a)4. and 7.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Board of Governors shall develop uniform guidelines, definitions, and reporting formats for a university to use to demonstrate that it meets each of the criteria described in this subsection. The Board of Governors shall determine the eligibility status of a state university to participate in the program provided that a state university may not participate in both Funding Level 1 and Funding Level 2 simultaneously.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF FUNDS.<EmDash />Funds appropriated for the State University System Research and Economic Development Investment Program shall be used by the Board of Governors to match funds raised by an eligible university from nonuniversity sources on a one-time dollar-for-dollar basis.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2006-58.</History></Section>