<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Louis de la Parte Florida Mental Health Institute.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the Louis de la Parte Florida Mental Health Institute within the University of South Florida.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the institute is to strengthen mental health services throughout the state by providing technical assistance and support services to mental health agencies and mental health professionals. Such assistance and services shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Technical training and specialized education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development, implementation, and evaluation of mental health service programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of availability and effectiveness of existing mental health services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Analysis of factors that influence the incidence and prevalence of mental and emotional disorders.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dissemination of information about innovations in mental health services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consultation on all aspects of program development and implementation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for direct client services, provided for a limited period of time either in the institute facility or in other facilities within the state, and limited to purposes of research or training.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services is authorized to designate the Louis de la Parte Florida Mental Health Institute a treatment facility for the purpose of accepting voluntary and involuntary clients in accordance with institute programs. Clients to be admitted are exempted from prior screening by a community mental health center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute may provide direct services in coordination with other agencies. The institute may also provide support services to state agencies through joint programs, collaborative agreements, contracts, and grants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute shall operate under the authority of the President of the University of South Florida and shall employ a mental health professional as director. The director shall hold a faculty appointment in a university’s college or department related to mental health within the university. The director has primary responsibility for establishing active liaisons with the community of mental health professionals and other related constituencies in the state and may, with approval of the university president, establish appropriate statewide advisory groups to assist in developing these communication links.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 190, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>