<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.445" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Johnnie B. Byrd, Sr., Alzheimer’s Center and Research Institute.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREATION AND MISSION.<EmDash />The Johnnie B. Byrd, Sr., Alzheimer’s Center and Research Institute is established within the University of South Florida. The institute has a statewide mission to advance research, education, treatment, prevention, and the early detection of Alzheimer’s disease and is responsible for distributing peer-reviewed competitive grant funds for Alzheimer’s disease research.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD OF DIRECTORS.<EmDash />The board of directors for the Johnnie B. Byrd, Sr., Alzheimer’s Center and Research Institute is created to oversee the management and operation of the institute. The board of directors shall consist of seven members who shall serve at the pleasure of the entity that appoints them. A board member’s term shall expire after 4 years, but the member may be reappointed to a subsequent 4-year term. The Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall each appoint one person to serve on the board of directors. The Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida shall appoint four persons to serve on the board of directors. Trustees are eligible for appointment to the board of directors. The chair of the board of directors shall be elected by a majority vote from among the membership of the board. Members of the board of directors may not receive a salary. The board of directors may organize and appoint an advisory council of concerned citizens to assist the institute in carrying out its duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER.<EmDash />The institute shall be administered by a chief executive officer who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the president of the University of South Florida or the president’s designee. The chief executive officer shall prepare an annual report for the institute which describes the expenditure of all of the institute’s funds and provides information regarding research that has been conducted or funded by the institute, including the expected and actual results of the research.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BUDGET.<EmDash />The institute’s budget shall include the moneys appropriated in the General Appropriations Act, donated, or otherwise provided to the institute from private, local, state, and federal sources, as well as technical and professional income generated or derived from practice activities at the institute. Any appropriation to the institute shall be expended for the purposes specified in this section, including conducting and supporting research and related clinical services, awarding institutional grants and investigator-initiated research grants to other persons within the state through a peer-reviewed competitive process, developing and operating integrated data projects, providing assistance to the memory disorder clinics established in s. 430.502, and providing for the operation of the institute.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 191, ch. 2002-387; s. 2, ch. 2002-389; s. 1, ch. 2002-396; s. 5, ch. 2004-2; s. 44, ch. 2004-41; s. 12, ch. 2006-182; s. 1, ch. 2006-288; s. 98, ch. 2007-217; s. 1, ch. 2007-332; s. 1, ch. 2008-113; s. 5, ch. 2009-60.</History></Section>