<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1004.345" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Florida Polytechnic University.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By December 31, 2016, the Florida Polytechnic University shall meet the following criteria as established by the Board of Governors:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achieve accreditation from the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate the development of the new programs in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek discipline-specific accreditation for programs;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attain a minimum FTE of 1,244, with a minimum 50 percent of that FTE in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics and 20 percent in programs related to those fields;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete facilities and infrastructure, including the Science and Technology Building, Phase I of the Wellness Center, and a residence hall or halls containing no fewer than 190 beds; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have the ability to provide, either directly or where feasible through a shared services model, administration of financial aid, admissions, student support, information technology, and finance and accounting with an internal audit function.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once the criteria in subsection (1) have been met, the Board of Trustees of the Florida Polytechnic University shall notify the Board of Governors, and the Board of Governors shall conduct a final review to confirm that the criteria have been met.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students enrolled at the University of South Florida Polytechnic shall be afforded the opportunity to complete their degrees at the University of South Florida, subject to university criteria.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-97; s. 1, ch. 2012-129.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 2, ch. 2012-129, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“The following transfers shall be made:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) All real and personal property, licenses and associated revenues, existing contracts, unexpended balances, appropriations, allocations, funds, and mutually agreed-upon obligations, responsibilities, and liabilities of the University of South Florida which relate to the University of South Florida Polytechnic campus, as determined by the Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida and the Board of Trustees of the Florida Polytechnic University, shall be transferred to the Florida Polytechnic University.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) All Florida Industrial and Phosphate Research Institute programs, functions, offices, records, faculty positions, and staff positions of the University of South Florida Polytechnic shall be transferred to the Florida Polytechnic University.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) After the transfers required in subsections (1) and (2) are complete, all programs, functions, offices, records, faculty positions, and staff positions of the University of South Florida Polytechnic shall be transferred to the University of South Florida.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 4, ch. 2012-129, provides that “[a]ll memoranda of understanding between the University of South Florida and the University of South Florida Polytechnic and its successors shall be invalid upon this act becoming a law.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 5, ch. 2012-129, provides that “[t]he University of South Florida shall take appropriate action, in collaboration with the Florida Polytechnic University, to obtain all consents required by the Federal Communications Commission and third parties before assigning the educational broadband service station license that has a Federal Communications Commission-issued reference point in Polk County, Florida, to the Florida Polytechnic University. Upon obtaining such consents, and upon the approval of the Federal Communications Commission, the University of South Florida shall assign the license, along with the excess capacity lease agreement for the license, to the Florida Polytechnic University, which shall assume the benefits, obligations, and liabilities as the successor in interest, including all regulatory and contractual responsibilities. This section is contingent upon the approval of the assignment of the lease by the Federal Communications Commission.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">D. Section 6, ch. 2012-129, provides that “[t]he Florida Polytechnic University shall retain, not subject to lease or other expense, the space occupied by the University of South Florida Polytechnic campus in the Lakeland joint-use facility and the associated facility utilization rights and obligations and shall allow the University of South Florida to use space pursuant to a mutual agreement specifying the space to be used for the purpose of continuing the local education of students who are enrolled at, or already admitted to, the University of South Florida Polytechnic before the effective date of this act and who wish to remain students at the University of South Florida. Such students shall be afforded the opportunity to complete their degrees at the University of South Florida, subject to university criteria. The mutual facility utilization agreement shall be adjusted annually to reflect the space needs of the University of South Florida for the purpose of continuing the local education of eligible students. The Florida Polytechnic University shall transfer space at the Lakeland joint-use facility to Polk State College as new space becomes available on the new campus of the Florida Polytechnic University. Once the Florida Polytechnic University has no further need for the space at the Lakeland joint-use facility, the Florida Polytechnic University shall complete the transfer of all remaining property and buildings of the joint-use facility to Polk State College. This section does not prevent the University of South Florida, the Florida Polytechnic University, or Polk State College from entering into mutual agreements to share or use space in the Lakeland joint-use facility.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">E. Section 7, ch. 2012-129, provides that “[t]he University of Florida, using its expertise in the disciplines of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, shall be available in an advisory or consulting capacity to assist the president and the Board of Trustees of the Florida Polytechnic University in hiring, accreditation, administration, and other areas.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">F. Section 8, ch. 2012-129, provides that “[t]he Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida and the Board of Trustees of the Florida Polytechnic University, and the their respective officers, trustees, employees, attorneys, and agents, are immune from any and all civil liability pertaining to or arising from compliance with this act, including the transfers required in this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>