<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1004.33" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">The University of South Florida St. Petersburg.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The St. Petersburg campus of the University of South Florida is established and shall be known as the “University of South Florida St. Petersburg.”</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature intends that the University of South Florida St. Petersburg be operated and maintained as a separate organizational and budget entity of the University of South Florida, and that all legislative appropriations for the University of South Florida St. Petersburg be set forth as separate line items in the annual General Appropriations Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of South Florida St. Petersburg shall have a Campus Board and a Campus Executive Officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As soon as possible, but no later than the effective date of this act, the President of the University of South Florida shall begin the process of application to the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools for separate accreditation of the University of South Florida St. Petersburg. If the application is not approved or is provisionally approved, the University of South Florida shall correct any identified deficiencies and shall continue to work for accreditation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida shall appoint to the Campus Board, from recommendations of the President of the University of South Florida, five residents of Pinellas County. If a resident of Pinellas County is appointed to the Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida, the board shall appoint that member to serve jointly as a member of the Campus Board. If more than one Pinellas County resident is appointed to the Board of Trustees, the board shall select one joint member. The Board of Trustees may reappoint a member to the Campus Board for one additional term. The Campus Board has the powers and duties provided by law, which include the authority to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and approve an annual legislative budget request to be submitted to the Commissioner of Education. The Campus Executive Officer shall prepare the legislative budget request in accordance with guidelines established by the State Board of Education. This request must include items for campus operations and fixed capital outlay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve and submit an annual operating plan and budget for review and consultation by the Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida. The campus operating budget must reflect the actual funding available to that campus from separate line-item appropriations contained in each annual General Appropriations Act, which line-item appropriations must initially reflect the funds reported to the Legislature for the University of South Florida St. Petersburg campus for fiscal year 2000-2001 and any additional funds provided in the fiscal year 2001-2002 legislative appropriation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into central support services contracts with the Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida for any services that the St. Petersburg campus cannot provide more economically, including payroll processing, accounting, technology, construction administration, and other desired services. However, all legal services for the campus must be provided by a central services contract with the university. The Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida and the Campus Board shall determine in a letter of agreement any allocation or sharing of student fee revenue between the University of South Florida’s main campus and the St. Petersburg campus.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Board of Trustees of the University of South Florida may lawfully delegate other powers and duties to the Campus Board for the efficient operation and improvement of the campus and for the purpose of vesting in the campus the attributes necessary to meet the requirements for separate accreditation by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of South Florida St. Petersburg shall be administered by a Campus Executive Officer who shall be appointed by, report directly to, and serve at the pleasure of the President of the University of South Florida. The President shall consult with the Campus Board before hiring or terminating the Campus Executive Officer. The Campus Executive Officer has authority and responsibility as provided in law, including the authority to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer campus operations within the annual operating budget as approved by the Campus Board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Campus Board an annual legislative budget request that includes funding for campus operations and fixed capital outlay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Campus Board an annual campus operating budget.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Campus Board appropriate services and terms and conditions to be included in annual central support services contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out any additional responsibilities assigned or delegated by the President of the University of South Florida for the efficient operation and improvement of the campus, especially any authority necessary for the purpose of vesting in the campus attributes necessary to meet the requirements for separate accreditation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students enrolled at the University of South Florida, including those enrolled at a branch campus, have the same rights and obligations as provided by law, policy, or rule adopted by the University of South Florida, the Florida Department of Education, or other lawful entity. The University of South Florida shall provide a comprehensive and coordinated system of student registration so that a student enrolled at any campus of the University of South Florida has the ability to register for courses at any other campus of the University of South Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following entities are not affected by this section and remain under the administrative control of the University of South Florida:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of South Florida College of Marine Science, which is a component college of the main campus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Institute of Oceanography, which is a Type One Institute.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of South Florida Pediatric Research Center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of South Florida/USGS joint facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 178, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>