<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0782.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vehicular homicide.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vehicular homicide” is the killing of a human being, or the killing of a viable fetus by any injury to the mother, caused by the operation of a motor vehicle by another in a reckless manner likely to cause the death of, or great bodily harm to, another.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vehicular homicide is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of the accident, the person knew, or should have known, that the accident occurred; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person failed to give information and render aid as required by s. 316.062.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This paragraph does not require that the person knew that the accident resulted in injury or death.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, a fetus is viable when it becomes capable of meaningful life outside the womb through standard medical measures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A right of action for civil damages shall exist under s. 768.19, under all circumstances, for all deaths described in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other punishment, the court may order the person to serve 120 community service hours in a trauma center or hospital that regularly receives victims of vehicle accidents, under the supervision of a registered nurse, an emergency room physician, or an emergency medical technician pursuant to a voluntary community service program operated by the trauma center or hospital.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 74-383; s. 6, ch. 75-298; s. 12, ch. 86-296; s. 14, ch. 96-330; s. 9, ch. 98-417; s. 1, ch. 99-153; s. 2, ch. 2001-147.</History></Section>