<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0782.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Partially born” means the living fetus’s intact body, with the entire head attached, is presented so that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There has been delivered past the mother’s vaginal opening:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fetus’s entire head, in the case of a cephalic presentation, up until the point of complete separation from the mother whether or not the placenta has been delivered or the umbilical cord has been severed; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any portion of the fetus’s torso above the navel, in the case of a breech presentation, up until the point of complete separation from the mother whether or not the placenta has been delivered or the umbilical cord has been severed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There has been delivered outside the mother’s abdominal wall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fetus’s entire head, in the case of a cephalic presentation, up until the point of complete separation from the mother whether or not the placenta has been delivered or the umbilical cord has been severed; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any portion of the child’s torso above the navel, in the case of a breech presentation, up until the point of complete separation from the mother whether or not the placenta has been delivered or the umbilical cord has been severed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Living fetus” means any unborn member of the human species who has a heartbeat or discernible spontaneous movement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Suction or sharp curettage abortion” means an abortion, as defined in chapter 390, in which the developing fetus and the products of conception are evacuated from the uterus through a suction cannula with an attached vacuum apparatus or with a sharp curette.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-142.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 5, ch. 2000-142, provides that “[t]his act shall be liberally construed to effectively carry out its purposes. In the event of conflict between this act and any other provision of law, the provisions of this act shall govern.”</Text></Note></Section>