<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0782.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Killing of unborn quick child by injury to mother.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unlawful killing of an unborn quick child, by any injury to the mother of such child which would be murder if it resulted in the death of such mother, shall be deemed murder in the same degree as that which would have been committed against the mother. Any person, other than the mother, who unlawfully kills an unborn quick child by any injury to the mother:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which would be murder in the first degree constituting a capital felony if it resulted in the mother’s death commits murder in the first degree constituting a capital felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which would be murder in the second degree if it resulted in the mother’s death commits murder in the second degree, a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which would be murder in the third degree if it resulted in the mother’s death commits murder in the third degree, a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unlawful killing of an unborn quick child by any injury to the mother of such child which would be manslaughter if it resulted in the death of such mother shall be deemed manslaughter. A person who unlawfully kills an unborn quick child by any injury to the mother which would be manslaughter if it resulted in the mother’s death commits manslaughter, a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The death of the mother resulting from the same act or criminal episode that caused the death of the unborn quick child does not bar prosecution under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not authorize the prosecution of any person in connection with a termination of pregnancy pursuant to chapter 390.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the definition of the term “unborn quick child” shall be determined in accordance with the definition of viable fetus as set forth in s. 782.071.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 1637, 1868; RS 2386; GS 3211; RGS 5041; CGL 7143; s. 717, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 2005-119.</History></Section>