<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0782.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Attempted felony murder.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who perpetrates or attempts to perpetrate any felony enumerated in s. 782.04(3) and who commits, aids, or abets an intentional act that is not an essential element of the felony and that could, but does not, cause the death of another commits a felony of the first degree, punishable by imprisonment for a term of years not exceeding life, or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, which is an offense ranked in level 9 of the Criminal Punishment Code. Victim injury points shall be scored under this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who perpetrates or attempts to perpetrate any felony other than a felony enumerated in s. 782.04(3) and who commits, aids, or abets an intentional act that is not an essential element of the felony and that could, but does not, cause the death of another commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, which is an offense ranked in level 8 of the Criminal Punishment Code. Victim injury points shall be scored under this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person is injured during the perpetration of or the attempt to perpetrate any felony enumerated in s. 782.04(3) by a person other than the person engaged in the perpetration of or the attempt to perpetrate such felony, the person perpetrating or attempting to perpetrate such felony commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, which is an offense ranked in level 7 of the Criminal Punishment Code. Victim injury points shall be scored under this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 96-359; s. 18, ch. 97-194; s. 12, ch. 98-204; s. 4, ch. 2001-236; s. 6, ch. 2012-21.</History>
</Section>