<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0101.6923" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special absentee ballot instructions for certain first-time voters.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section apply to voters who are subject to the provisions of s. 97.0535 and who have not provided the identification or information required by s. 97.0535 by the time the absentee ballot is mailed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voter covered by this section shall be provided with printed instructions with his or her absentee ballot in substantially the following form:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">READ THESE INSTRUCTIONS CAREFULLY BEFORE MARKING YOUR BALLOT. FAILURE TO FOLLOW THESE INSTRUCTIONS MAY CAUSE YOUR BALLOT NOT TO COUNT.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. In order to ensure that your absentee ballot will be counted, it should be completed and returned as soon as possible so that it can reach the supervisor of elections of the county in which your precinct is located no later than 7 p.m. on the date of the election.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Mark your ballot in secret as instructed on the ballot. You must mark your own ballot unless you are unable to do so because of blindness, disability, or inability to read or write.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. Mark only the number of candidates or issue choices for a race as indicated on the ballot. If you are allowed to “Vote for One” candidate and you vote for more than one, your vote in that race will not be counted.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">4. Place your marked ballot in the enclosed secrecy envelope and seal the envelope.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">5. Insert the secrecy envelope into the enclosed envelope bearing the Voter’s Certificate. Seal the envelope and completely fill out the Voter’s Certificate on the back of the envelope.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. You must sign your name on the line above (Voter’s Signature).</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. If you are an overseas voter, you must include the date you signed the Voter’s Certificate on the line above (Date) or your ballot may not be counted.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">c. An absentee ballot will be considered illegal and will not be counted if the signature on the Voter’s Certificate does not match the signature on record. The signature on file at the start of the canvass of the absentee ballots is the signature that will be used to verify your signature on the Voter’s Certificate. If you need to update your signature for this election, send your signature update on a voter registration application to your supervisor of elections so that it is received no later than the start of canvassing of absentee ballots, which occurs no earlier than the 15th day before election day.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">6. Unless you meet one of the exemptions in Item 7., you must make a copy of one of the following forms of identification:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. Identification which must include your name and photograph: United States passport; debit or credit card; military identification; student identification; retirement center identification; neighborhood association identification; or public assistance identification; or</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. Identification which shows your name and current residence address: current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or government document (excluding voter identification card).</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">7. The identification requirements of Item 6. do not apply if you meet one of the following requirements:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. You are 65 years of age or older.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. You have a temporary or permanent physical disability.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">c. You are a member of a uniformed service on active duty who, by reason of such active duty, will be absent from the county on election day.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">d. You are a member of the Merchant Marine who, by reason of service in the Merchant Marine, will be absent from the county on election day.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">e. You are the spouse or dependent of a member referred to in paragraph c. or paragraph d. who, by reason of the active duty or service of the member, will be absent from the county on election day.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">f. You are currently residing outside the United States.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">8. Place the envelope bearing the Voter’s Certificate into the mailing envelope addressed to the supervisor. Insert a copy of your identification in the mailing envelope. DO NOT PUT YOUR IDENTIFICATION INSIDE THE SECRECY ENVELOPE WITH THE BALLOT OR INSIDE THE ENVELOPE WHICH BEARS THE VOTER’S CERTIFICATE OR YOUR BALLOT WILL NOT COUNT.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">9. Mail, deliver, or have delivered the completed mailing envelope. Be sure there is sufficient postage if mailed.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">10. FELONY NOTICE. It is a felony under Florida law to accept any gift, payment, or gratuity in exchange for your vote for a candidate. It is also a felony under Florida law to vote in an election using a false identity or false address, or under any other circumstances making your ballot false or fraudulent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 2003-415; s. 5, ch. 2004-232; s. 49, ch. 2005-277; s. 42, ch. 2005-278; s. 22, ch. 2008-95; s. 41, ch. 2011-40.</History>
</Section>