<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery of absentee ballots; envelopes; form.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor shall enclose with each absentee ballot two envelopes: a secrecy envelope, into which the absent elector shall enclose his or her marked ballot; and a mailing envelope, into which the absent elector shall then place the secrecy envelope, which shall be addressed to the supervisor and also bear on the back side a certificate in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">Note: Please Read Instructions Carefully Before</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">Marking Ballot and Completing Voter’s Certificate.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">VOTER’S CERTIFICATE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">I, <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, do solemnly swear or affirm that I am a qualified and registered voter of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida, and that I have not and will not vote more than one ballot in this election. I understand that if I commit or attempt to commit any fraud in connection with voting, vote a fraudulent ballot, or vote more than once in an election, I can be convicted of a felony of the third degree and fined up to $5,000 and/or imprisoned for up to 5 years. I also understand that failure to sign this certificate will invalidate my ballot.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Date)</Directions><FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Voter’s Signature)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate shall be arranged on the back of the mailing envelope so that the line for the signature of the absent elector is across the seal of the envelope; however, no statement shall appear on the envelope which indicates that a signature of the voter must cross the seal of the envelope. The absent elector shall execute the certificate on the envelope.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the voter’s certificate provided in this section, the supervisor of elections shall provide each person voting absentee under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act with the standard oath prescribed by the presidential designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor shall mark, code, indicate on, or otherwise track the precinct of the absent elector for each absentee ballot.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 7380, 1917; RGS 371; CGL 432; s. 1, ch. 25385, 1949; s. 5, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 34, ch. 28156, 1953; s. 22, ch. 29934, 1955; s. 1, ch. 61-369; s. 33, ch. 65-380; s. 3, ch. 69-136; s. 5, ch. 69-280; s. 21, ch. 71-355; s. 1, ch. 73-105; s. 6, ch. 73-157; s. 39, ch. 73-333; s. 3, ch. 75-174; s. 23, ch. 77-175; s. 4, ch. 79-365; s. 1, ch. 81-106; s. 9, ch. 81-304; s. 10, ch. 82-143; s. 2, ch. 85-226; s. 1, ch. 86-33; s. 19, ch. 90-315; s. 588, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 96-57; s. 14, ch. 98-129; s. 53, ch. 2001-40; s. 19, ch. 2003-415; s. 1, ch. 2004-232; s. 44, ch. 2005-277; s. 38, ch. 2005-278.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 101.04.</Text></Note></Section>