<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.49" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure of election officers where signatures differ.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any clerk or inspector, upon a just comparison of the signatures, doubts that the signature on the identification presented by the elector is the same as the signature the elector affixed on the precinct register or early voting certificate, the clerk or inspector shall deliver to the person an affidavit which shall be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA,</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that my name is <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />; that I am <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> years old; that I was born in the State of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />; that I am registered to vote; that I am a qualified voter of the county and state aforesaid and have not voted in this election.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of voter)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, A. D. <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Clerk or inspector of election)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true">Precinct No. <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person shall fill out, in his or her own handwriting or with assistance from a member of the election board, the form and make an affidavit to the facts stated in the filled-in form; such affidavit shall then be sworn to and subscribed before one of the inspectors or clerks of the election who is authorized to administer the oath. Whenever the affidavit is made and filed with the clerk or inspector, the person shall then be admitted to cast his or her vote, but if the person fails or refuses to make out or file such affidavit and asserts his or her eligibility, then he or she shall be entitled to vote a provisional ballot.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 18407, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 337(28-d); s. 2, ch. 22018, 1943; s. 5, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 18, ch. 77-175; s. 573, ch. 95-147; s. 11, ch. 99-6; s. 14, ch. 2001-40; s. 33, ch. 2005-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 100.35.</Text></Note></Section>