<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Instructions for electors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State, or in case of municipal elections the governing body of the municipality, shall print, in large type on cards, instructions for the electors to use in voting. It shall provide not less than two cards for each voting precinct for each election and furnish such cards to each supervisor upon requisition. Each supervisor of elections shall send a sufficient number of these cards to the precincts prior to an election. The election inspectors shall display the cards in the polling places as information for electors. The cards shall contain information about how to vote and such other information as the Department of State may deem necessary. The cards must also include the list of rights and responsibilities afforded to Florida voters, as described in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections in each county shall have posted at each polling place in the county the Voter’s Bill of Rights and Responsibilities in the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">VOTER’S BILL OF RIGHTS</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Each registered voter in this state has the right to:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. Vote and have his or her vote accurately counted.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Cast a vote if he or she is in line at the official closing of the polls in that county.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. Ask for and receive assistance in voting.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">4. Receive up to two replacement ballots if he or she makes a mistake prior to the ballot being cast.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">5. An explanation if his or her registration or identity is in question.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">6. If his or her registration or identity is in question, cast a provisional ballot.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">7. Written instructions to use when voting, and, upon request, oral instructions in voting from elections officers.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">8. Vote free from coercion or intimidation by elections officers or any other person.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">9. Vote on a voting system that is in working condition and that will allow votes to be accurately cast.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">VOTER RESPONSIBILITIES</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Each registered voter in this state should:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. Familiarize himself or herself with the candidates and issues.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Maintain with the office of the supervisor of elections a current address.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. Know the location of his or her polling place and its hours of operation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">4. Bring proper identification to the polling station.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">5. Familiarize himself or herself with the operation of the voting equipment in his or her precinct.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">6. Treat precinct workers with courtesy.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">7. Respect the privacy of other voters.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">8. Report any problems or violations of election laws to the supervisor of elections.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">9. Ask questions, if needed.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">10. Make sure that his or her completed ballot is correct before leaving the polling station.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">NOTE TO VOTER: Failure to perform any of these responsibilities does not prohibit a voter from voting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall give rise to a legal cause of action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case any elector, after entering the voting booth, shall ask for further instructions concerning the manner of voting, two election officers who are not both members of the same political party, if present, or, if not, two election officers who are members of the same political party, shall give such instructions to such elector, but no officer or person assisting an elector shall in any manner request, suggest, or seek to persuade or induce any elector to vote for or against any particular ticket, candidate, amendment, question, or proposition. After giving the elector instructions and before the elector has voted, the officers or persons assisting the elector shall retire, and such elector shall vote in secret.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 4328, 1895; s. 12, ch. 4537, 1897; GS 225; RGS 270; CGL 326; s. 1, ch. 25106, 1949; s. 5, ch. 26870, 1951; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 25, ch. 77-104; s. 13, ch. 77-175; s. 31, ch. 79-400; s. 60, ch. 2001-40; s. 5, ch. 2002-17; s. 22, ch. 2005-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 99.24.</Text></Note></Section>