<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.595" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Analysis and reports of voting problems.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than December 15 of each general election year, the supervisor of elections in each county shall report to the Department of State the total number of overvotes and undervotes in the “President and Vice President” or “Governor and Lieutenant Governor” race that appears first on the ballot or, if neither appears, the first race appearing on the ballot pursuant to s. 101.151(2), along with the likely reasons for such overvotes and undervotes and other information as may be useful in evaluating the performance of the voting system and identifying problems with ballot design and instructions which may have contributed to voter confusion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State, upon receipt of such information, shall prepare a public report on the performance of each type of voting system. The report must contain, but is not limited to, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification of problems with the ballot design or instructions which may have contributed to voter confusion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification of voting system design problems; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for correcting any problems identified.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall submit the report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 31 of each year following a general election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 2001-40; s. 16, ch. 2002-17; s. 41, ch. 2005-277.</History></Section>