<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.69" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voting in person; return of absentee ballot.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this code shall not be construed to prohibit any elector from voting in person at the elector’s precinct on the day of an election or at an early voting site, notwithstanding that the elector has requested an absentee ballot for that election. An elector who has returned a voted absentee ballot to the supervisor, however, is deemed to have cast his or her ballot and is not entitled to vote another ballot or to have a provisional ballot counted by the county canvassing board. An elector who has received an absentee ballot and has not returned the voted ballot to the supervisor, but desires to vote in person, shall return the ballot, whether voted or not, to the election board in the elector’s precinct or to an early voting site. The returned ballot shall be marked “canceled” by the board and placed with other canceled ballots. However, if the elector does not return the ballot and the election official:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Confirms that the supervisor has received the elector’s absentee ballot, the elector shall not be allowed to vote in person. If the elector maintains that he or she has not returned the absentee ballot or remains eligible to vote, the elector shall be provided a provisional ballot as provided in s. 101.048.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Confirms that the supervisor has not received the elector’s absentee ballot, the elector shall be allowed to vote in person as provided in this code. The elector’s absentee ballot, if subsequently received, shall not be counted and shall remain in the mailing envelope, and the envelope shall be marked “Rejected as Illegal.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cannot determine whether the supervisor has received the elector’s absentee ballot, the elector may vote a provisional ballot as provided in s. 101.048.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 22014, 1943; s. 1, ch. 25385, 1949; s. 5, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 37, ch. 65-380; s. 23, ch. 77-175; s. 592, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 96-57; s. 38, ch. 2001-40; s. 18, ch. 2002-17; s. 48, ch. 2005-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 101.11.</Text></Note></Section>