<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0101.045">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electors must be registered in precinct; provisions for change of residence or name.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is not permitted to vote in any election precinct or district other than the one in which the person has his or her legal residence and in which the person is registered. However, a person temporarily residing outside the county shall be registered in the precinct in which the main office of the supervisor, as designated by the supervisor, is located when the person has no permanent address in the county and it is the person’s intention to remain a resident of Florida and of the county in which he or she is registered to vote. Such persons who are registered in the precinct in which the main office of the supervisor, as designated by the supervisor, is located and who are residing outside the county with no permanent address in the county shall not be registered electors of a municipality and therefore shall not be permitted to vote in any municipal election.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An elector who moves from the precinct in which the elector is registered may be permitted to vote in the precinct to which he or she has moved his or her legal residence, if the change of residence is within the same county and the elector completes an affirmation in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">Change of Legal Residence of Registered<NewLine />Voter</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Under penalties for false swearing, I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of voter)</Directions>, swear (or affirm) that the former address of my legal residence was <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address of legal residence)</Directions> in the municipality of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule>, in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> County, Florida, and I was registered to vote in the <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> precinct of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> County, Florida; that I have not voted in the precinct of my former registration in this election; that I now reside at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address of legal residence)</Directions> in the Municipality of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule>, in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> County, Florida, and am therefore eligible to vote in the <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> precinct of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> County, Florida; and I further swear (or affirm) that I am otherwise legally registered and entitled to vote.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of voter whose address of legal residence has changed)</Directions></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for an active uniformed services voter or a member of his or her family, an elector whose change of address is from outside the county may not change his or her legal residence at the polling place and vote a regular ballot; however, such elector is entitled to vote a provisional ballot.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An elector whose name changes because of marriage or other legal process may be permitted to vote, provided such elector completes an affirmation in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">Change of Name of Registered<NewLine />Voter</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Under penalties for false swearing, I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(New name of voter)</Directions>, swear (or affirm) that my name has been changed because of marriage or other legal process. My former name and address of legal residence appear on the registration records of precinct <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> as follows:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Municipality<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Florida, Zip<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">My present name and address of legal residence are as follows:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Name<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Address<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Municipality<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Florida, Zip<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">and I further swear (or affirm) that I am otherwise legally registered and entitled to vote.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of voter whose name has changed)</Directions></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instead of the affirmation contained in paragraph (a) or paragraph (c), an elector may complete a voter registration application that indicates the change of name or change of address of legal residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such affirmation or application, when completed and presented at the precinct in which such elector is entitled to vote, and upon verification of the elector’s registration, shall entitle such elector to vote as provided in this subsection. If the elector’s eligibility to vote cannot be determined, he or she shall be entitled to vote a provisional ballot, subject to the requirements and procedures in s. 101.048. Upon receipt of an affirmation or application certifying a change in address of legal residence or name, the supervisor shall as soon as practicable make the necessary changes in the statewide voter registration system to indicate the change in address of legal residence or name of such elector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 3879, 1889; RS 167; s. 15, ch. 4328, 1895; GS 192; RGS 236; CGL 289; s. 4, ch. 24203, 1947; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 1, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 4, ch. 28156, 1953; s. 7, ch. 65-60; s. 1, ch. 71-307; s. 3, ch. 77-175; s. 6, ch. 78-403; s. 4, ch. 80-292; s. 5, ch. 89-338; s. 20, ch. 94-224; s. 1391, ch. 95-147; s. 36, ch. 2001-40; s. 31, ch. 2005-278; s. 16, ch. 2008-95; s. 26, ch. 2011-40.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Former s. 98.32; s. 97.091.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>