<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.5608" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voting by electronic or electromechanical method; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each elector desiring to vote shall be identified to the clerk or inspector of the election as a duly qualified elector of such election and shall sign his or her name on the precinct register or other form or device provided by the supervisor. The inspector shall compare the signature with the signature on the identification provided by the elector. If the inspector is reasonably sure that the person is entitled to vote, the inspector shall provide the person with a ballot.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an electronic or electromechanical voting system utilizes a ballot card or marksense ballot, the following procedures shall be followed:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receiving a ballot from an inspector, the elector shall, without leaving the polling place, retire to a booth or compartment and mark the ballot. After marking his or her ballot, the elector shall place the ballot in a secrecy envelope so that the ballot will be deposited in the tabulator without exposing the voter’s choices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any voter who spoils his or her ballot or makes an error may return the ballot to the election official and secure another ballot, except that in no case shall a voter be furnished more than three ballots. If the vote tabulation device has rejected a ballot, the ballot shall be considered spoiled and a new ballot shall be provided to the voter unless the voter chooses to cast the rejected ballot. The election official, without examining the original ballot, shall state the possible reasons for the rejection and shall provide instruction to the voter pursuant to s. 101.5611. A spoiled ballot shall be preserved, without examination, in an envelope provided for that purpose. The stub shall be removed from the ballot and placed in an envelope.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall prepare for each polling place at least one ballot box to contain the ballots of a particular precinct, and each ballot box shall be plainly marked with the name of the precinct for which it is intended.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall promulgate rules regarding voting procedures to be used when an electronic or electromechanical voting system is of a type which does not utilize a ballot card or marksense ballot.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any election in which a write-in candidate has qualified for office, the supervisor of elections shall provide for write-in voting pursuant to rules adopted by the Division of Elections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 73-156; s. 21, ch. 77-175; s. 13, ch. 81-105; s. 5, ch. 82-143; s. 12, ch. 84-302; s. 579, ch. 95-147; s. 20, ch. 2001-40; s. 11, ch. 2002-17; s. 36, ch. 2005-277; s. 35, ch. 2005-278; s. 20, ch. 2008-95.</History></Section>