<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.6103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mail ballot election procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (7), the supervisor of elections shall mail all official ballots with a secrecy envelope, a return mailing envelope, and instructions sufficient to describe the voting process to each elector entitled to vote in the election not sooner than the 20th day before the election and not later than the 10th day before the date of the election. All such ballots shall be mailed by first-class mail. Ballots shall be addressed to each elector at the address appearing in the registration records and placed in an envelope which is prominently marked “Do Not Forward.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the ballot the elector shall mark the ballot, place it in the secrecy envelope, sign the return mailing envelope supplied with the ballot, and comply with the instructions provided with the ballot. The elector shall mail, deliver, or have delivered the marked ballot so that it reaches the supervisor of elections no later than 7 p.m. on the day of the election. The ballot must be returned in the return mailing envelope.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The return mailing envelope shall contain a statement in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">VOTER’S CERTIFICATE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print Name)</Directions>, do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I am a qualified voter in this election and that I have not and will not vote more than one ballot in this election.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">I understand that failure to sign this certificate and give my residence address will invalidate my ballot.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Residence Address)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the ballot is destroyed, spoiled, lost, or not received by the elector, the elector may obtain a replacement ballot from the supervisor of elections as provided in this subsection. An elector seeking a replacement ballot shall sign a sworn statement that the ballot was destroyed, spoiled, lost, or not received and present such statement to the supervisor of elections prior to 7 p.m. on the day of the election. The supervisor of elections shall keep a record of each replacement ballot provided under this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A ballot shall be counted only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is returned in the return mailing envelope;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The elector’s signature has been verified as provided in this subsection; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is received by the supervisor of elections not later than 7 p.m. on the day of the election.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The supervisor of elections shall verify the signature of each elector on the return mailing envelope with the signature on the elector’s registration records. Such verification may commence at any time prior to the canvass of votes. The supervisor of elections shall safely keep the ballot unopened in his or her office until the county canvassing board canvasses the vote. If the supervisor of elections determines that an elector to whom a replacement ballot has been issued under subsection (4) has voted more than once, the canvassing board shall determine which ballot, if any, is to be counted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The canvassing board may begin the canvassing of mail ballots at 7 a.m. on the sixth day before the election, including processing the ballots through the tabulating equipment. However, results may not be released until after 7 p.m. on election day. Any canvassing board member or election employee who releases any result before 7 p.m. on election day commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to absent electors overseas entitled to vote in the election, the supervisor of elections shall mail an official ballot with a secrecy envelope, a return mailing envelope, and instructions sufficient to describe the voting process to each such elector on a date sufficient to allow such elector time to vote in the election and to have his or her marked ballot reach the supervisor by 7 p.m. on the day of the election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A ballot that otherwise satisfies the requirements of subsection (5) shall be counted even if the elector dies after mailing the ballot but before election day, as long as, prior to the death of the voter, the ballot was:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postmarked by the United States Postal Service;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date-stamped with a verifiable tracking number by common carrier; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Already in the possession of the supervisor of elections.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-364; s. 585, ch. 95-147; s. 42, ch. 2005-277; s. 29, ch. 2007-30.</History></Section>