<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.715" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Accessibility of polling places for people having a disability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All polling places must be accessible and usable by people with disabilities, as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only those polling places complying with the Florida Americans With Disabilities Accessibility Implementation Act, ss. 553.501-553.513, for all portions of the polling place or the structure in which it is located that voters traverse going to and from the polling place and during the voting process, regardless of the age or function of the building, shall be used for federal, state, and local elections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selection of a polling site must ensure accessibility with respect to the following accessible elements, spaces, scope, and technical requirements: accessible route, space allowance and reach ranges, protruding objects, ground and floor surfaces, parking and passenger loading zones, curb ramps, ramps, stairs, elevators, platform lifts, doors, entrances, path of egress, controls and operating mechanisms, signage, and all other minimum requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standards required at each polling place, regardless of the age of the building or function of the building, include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For polling places that provide parking spaces for voters, one or more signed accessible parking spaces for disabled persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signage identifying an accessible path of travel to the polling place if it differs from the primary route or entrance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An unobstructed path of travel to the polling place.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Level, firm, stable, and slip-resistant surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An unobstructed area for voting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient lighting along the accessible path of travel and within the polling place.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may adopt rules in accordance with s. 120.54 which are necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-50; s. 16, ch. 2002-281.</History></Section>