<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0101.6952"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Absentee ballots for absent uniformed services and overseas voters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an absent uniformed services voter’s or an overseas voter’s request for an official absentee ballot pursuant to s. 101.62 includes an e-mail address, the supervisor of elections shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Record the voter’s e-mail address in the absentee ballot record;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Confirm by e-mail that the absentee ballot request was received and include in that e-mail the estimated date the absentee ballot will be sent to the voter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the voter by e-mail when the voted absentee ballot is received by the supervisor of elections.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An absent uniformed services voter or an overseas voter who makes timely application for but does not receive an official absentee ballot may use the federal write-in absentee ballot to vote in any federal election and any state or local election involving two or more candidates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an election for federal office, an elector may designate a candidate by writing the name of a candidate on the ballot. Except for a primary or special primary election, the elector may alternatively designate a candidate by writing the name of a political party on the ballot. A written designation of the political party shall be counted as a vote for the candidate of that party if there is such a party candidate in the race.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an election for a state or local office, an elector may vote in the section of the federal write-in absentee ballot designated for nonfederal races by writing on the ballot the title of each office and by writing on the ballot the name of the candidate for whom the elector is voting. Except for a primary, special primary, or nonpartisan election, the elector may alternatively designate a candidate by writing the name of a political party on the ballot. A written designation of the political party shall be counted as a vote for the candidate of that party if there is such a party candidate in the race.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a joint candidacy, such as for the offices of President/Vice President or Governor/Lieutenant Governor, a valid vote for one or both qualified candidates on the same ticket shall constitute a vote for the joint candidacy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection and except where the context clearly indicates otherwise, such as where a candidate in the election is affiliated with a political party whose name includes the word “Independent,” “Independence,” or similar term, a voter designation of “No Party Affiliation” or “Independent,” or any minor variation, misspelling, or abbreviation thereof, shall be considered a designation for the candidate, other than a write-in candidate, who qualified to run in the race with no party affiliation. If more than one candidate qualifies to run as a candidate with no party affiliation, the designation shall not count for any candidate unless there is a valid, additional designation of the candidate’s name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any abbreviation, misspelling, or other minor variation in the form of the name of an office, the name of a candidate, or the name of a political party must be disregarded in determining the validity of the ballot.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An absent uniformed services voter or an overseas voter who submits a federal write-in absentee ballot and later receives an official absentee ballot may submit the official absentee ballot. An elector who submits a federal write-in absentee ballot and later receives and submits an official absentee ballot should make every reasonable effort to inform the appropriate supervisor of elections that the elector has submitted more than one ballot.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal write-in absentee ballot may not be canvassed until 7 p.m. on the day of the election. Each federal write-in absentee ballot received by 7 p.m. on the day of the election shall be canvassed pursuant to ss. 101.5614(5) and 101.68, unless the elector’s official absentee ballot is received by 7 p.m. on election day. If the elector’s official absentee ballot is received by 7 p.m. on election day, the federal write-in absentee ballot is invalid and the official absentee ballot shall be canvassed. The time shall be regulated by the customary time in standard use in the county seat of the locality.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For absentee ballots received from absent uniformed services voters or overseas voters, there is a presumption that the envelope was mailed on the date stated on the outside of the return envelope, regardless of the absence of a postmark on the mailed envelope or the existence of a postmark date that is later than the date of the election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 2001-40; s. 6, ch. 2004-232; s. 9, ch. 2010-167; s. 1, ch. 2011-162.</History></Section>