<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.5603" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Electronic Voting Systems Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automatic tabulating equipment” includes apparatus necessary to automatically examine, count, and record votes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ballot” means the card, tape, or other vehicle upon which the elector’s choices are recorded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ballot information” means the material containing the names of offices and candidates and the questions to be voted on.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electronic or electromechanical voting system” means a system of casting votes by use of voting devices or marking devices and counting ballots by employing automatic tabulating equipment or data processing equipment, and the term includes touchscreen systems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marking device” means any approved device for marking a ballot with ink or other substance which will enable the ballot to be tabulated by means of automatic tabulating equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secrecy envelope” means an opaque device, used for enclosing a marked ballot, which conceals the voter’s choices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Software” means the programs and routines used to employ and control the capabilities of data processing hardware, including, without limitation, operating systems, compilers, assemblers, utilities, library routines, maintenance routines, applications, and computer networking programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Voting device” means an apparatus by which votes are registered electronically.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 73-156; s. 21, ch. 77-175; s. 8, ch. 84-302; s. 8, ch. 89-348; s. 15, ch. 2001-40.</History></Section>