<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electors seeking assistance in casting ballots; oath to be executed; forms to be furnished.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any elector applying to vote in any election who requires assistance to vote by reason of blindness, disability, or inability to read or write may request the assistance of two election officials or some other person of the elector’s own choice, other than the elector’s employer, an agent of the employer, or an officer or agent of his or her union, to assist the elector in casting his or her vote. Any such elector, before retiring to the voting booth, may have one of such persons read over to him or her, without suggestion or interference, the titles of the offices to be filled and the candidates therefor and the issues on the ballot. After the elector requests the aid of the two election officials or the person of the elector’s choice, they shall retire to the voting booth for the purpose of casting the elector’s vote according to the elector’s choice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to be in the voting booth with any elector except as provided in subsection (1). A person at a polling place or early voting site, or within 100 feet of the entrance of a polling place or early voting site, may not solicit any elector in an effort to provide assistance to vote pursuant to subsection (1). Any person who violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any elector applying to cast an absentee ballot in the office of the supervisor, in any election, who requires assistance to vote by reason of blindness, disability, or inability to read or write may request the assistance of some person of his or her own choice, other than the elector’s employer, an agent of the employer, or an officer or agent of his or her union, in casting his or her absentee ballot.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an elector needs assistance in voting pursuant to the provisions of this section, the clerk or one of the inspectors shall require the elector requesting assistance in voting to take the following oath:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">DECLARATION TO SECURE ASSISTANCE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">State of Florida</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Date <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Precinct <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print name)</Directions>, swear or affirm that I am a registered elector and request assistance from <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print names)</Directions> in voting at the <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of election)</Directions> held on <Directions xml:space="preserve">(date of election)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of voter)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn and subscribed to before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Official Administering Oath)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an elector needing assistance requests that a person other than an election official provide him or her with assistance in voting, the clerk or one of the inspectors shall require the person providing assistance to take the following oath:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">DECLARATION TO PROVIDE ASSISTANCE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">State of Florida</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Date <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Precinct <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print name)</Directions>, have been requested by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(print name of elector needing assistance)</Directions> to provide him or her with assistance to vote. I swear or affirm that I am not the employer, an agent of the employer, or an officer or agent of the union of the voter and that I have not solicited this voter at the polling place or early voting site or within 100 feet of such locations in an effort to provide assistance.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of assistor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn and subscribed to before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Official Administering Oath)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall deliver a sufficient number of these forms to each precinct, along with other election paraphernalia.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 22018, 1943; s. 5, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 2, ch. 59-446; s. 2, ch. 65-60; s. 1, ch. 65-380; s. 13, ch. 77-175; s. 2, ch. 79-366; s. 31, ch. 84-302; s. 12, ch. 85-226; s. 553, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 99-6; s. 10, ch. 2002-281; s. 26, ch. 2005-277; s. 9, ch. 2006-1.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 100.36.</Text></Note></Section>