<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.293" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Competitive sealed bids and proposals required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any purchase of voting equipment, the individual or combined retail value of which is in excess of the threshold amount for CATEGORY TWO purchases provided in s. 287.017, by a governing body shall be by means of competitive sealed bids or competitive sealed proposals from at least two bidders, except under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of the governing body agrees by vote that an emergency situation exists in regard to the purchase of such equipment to the extent that the potential benefits derived from competitive sealed bids or competitive sealed proposals are outweighed by the detrimental effects of a delay in the acquisition of such equipment; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of the governing body finds that there is but a single source from which suitable equipment may be obtained.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If such conditions are found to exist, the chair of the governing body shall certify to the Division of Elections the situation and conditions requiring an exception to the competitive sealed bidding and competitive sealed proposal requirements of this section. Such certification shall be maintained on file by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Elections of the Department of State shall establish bidding procedures for carrying out the provisions and the intent of ss. 101.292-101.295, and each governing body shall follow the procedures so established.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 72-303; s. 18, ch. 73-156; s. 38, ch. 73-333; s. 16, ch. 77-175; s. 5, ch. 84-302; s. 6, ch. 89-348; s. 1, ch. 90-268; s. 566, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>