<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.655" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Supervised voting by absent electors in certain facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections of a county shall provide supervised voting for absent electors residing in any assisted living facility, as defined in s. 429.02, or nursing home facility, as defined in s. 400.021, within that county at the request of any administrator of such a facility. Such request for supervised voting in the facility shall be made by submitting a written request to the supervisor of elections no later than 21 days prior to the election for which that request is submitted. The request shall specify the name and address of the facility and the name of the electors who wish to vote absentee in that election. If the request contains the names of fewer than five voters, the supervisor of elections is not required to provide supervised voting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections may, in the absence of a request from the administrator of a facility, provide for supervised voting in the facility for those persons who have requested absentee ballots. The supervisor of elections shall notify the administrator of the facility that supervised voting will occur.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall, in cooperation with the administrator of the facility, select a date and time when the supervised voting will occur.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall designate supervised voting teams to provide the services prescribed by this section. Each supervised voting team shall include at least two persons. Each supervised voting team must include representatives of more than one political party; however, in any primary election to nominate party nominees in which only one party has candidates appearing on the ballot, all supervised voting team members may be of that party. No candidate may provide supervised voting services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervised voting team shall deliver the ballots to the respective absent electors, and each member of the team shall jointly supervise the voting of the ballots. If any elector requests assistance in voting, the oath prescribed in s. 101.051 shall be completed and the elector may receive the assistance of two members of the supervised voting team or some other person of the elector’s choice to assist the elector in casting the elector’s ballot.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before providing assistance, the supervised voting team shall disclose to the elector that the ballot may be retained to vote at a later time and that the elector has the right to seek assistance in voting from some other person of the elector’s choice without the presence of the supervised voting team.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any elector declines to vote a ballot or is unable to vote a ballot, the supervised voting team shall mark the ballot “refused to vote” or “unable to vote.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the ballots have been voted or marked in accordance with the provisions of this section, the supervised voting team shall deliver the ballots to the supervisor of elections, who shall retain them pursuant to s. 101.67.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 96-57; s. 5, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>