<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0101.6102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mail ballot elections; limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An election may be conducted by mail ballot if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election is a referendum election at which all or a portion of the qualified electors of one of the following subdivisions of government are the only electors eligible to vote:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cities;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School districts covering no more than one county; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special districts;</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body responsible for calling the election and the supervisor of elections responsible for the conduct of the election authorize the use of mail ballots for the election; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of State approves a written plan for the conduct of the election, which shall include a written timetable for the conduct of the election, submitted by the supervisor of elections.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, an annexation referendum which includes only qualified electors of one county may also be voted on by mail ballot election.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following elections may not be conducted by mail ballot:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An election at which any candidate is nominated, elected, retained, or recalled; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An election held on the same date as another election, other than a mail ballot election, in which the qualified electors of that political subdivision are eligible to cast ballots.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections shall be responsible for the conduct of any election held under ss. 101.6101-101.6107.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of a mail ballot election shall be borne by the jurisdiction initiating the calling of the election, unless otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the use of a mail ballot election in a municipal annexation referendum requiring separate vote of the registered electors of the annexing municipality and of the area proposed to be annexed. If a mail ballot election is authorized for a municipal annexation referendum, the provisions of ss. 101.6101-101.6107 shall control over any conflicting provisions of s. 171.0413.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-364; s. 1, ch. 89-52; s. 27, ch. 89-338; s. 18, ch. 90-315.</History></Section>