<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0937.0201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Missing adult” means a person 18 years of age or older whose temporary or permanent residence is in, or is believed to be in, this state, whose location has not been determined, and who has been reported as missing to a law enforcement agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Missing child” means a person younger than 18 years of age whose temporary or permanent residence is in, or is believed to be in, this state, whose location has not been determined, and who has been reported as missing to a law enforcement agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Missing endangered person” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A missing child;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A missing adult younger than 26 years of age; </Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A missing adult 26 years of age or older who is suspected by a law enforcement agency of being endangered or the victim of criminal activity; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A missing adult who meets the criteria for activation of the Silver Alert Plan of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Missing endangered person report” means a report prepared on a form prescribed by the department by rule for use by the public and law enforcement agencies in reporting information to the Missing Endangered Persons Information Clearinghouse about a missing endangered person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2008-162; s. 1, ch. 2011-218.</History></Section>