<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0937.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Missing Endangered Persons Information Clearinghouse.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Missing Endangered Persons Information Clearinghouse within the department to serve as a central repository of information regarding missing endangered persons. Such information shall be collected and disseminated to assist in the location of missing endangered persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clearinghouse shall be supervised by a director who shall be employed upon the recommendation of the executive director. The executive director shall establish services deemed appropriate by the department to aid in the location of missing endangered persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clearinghouse shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a system of intrastate communication of information relating to missing endangered persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a centralized file for the exchange of information on missing endangered persons.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every state, county, or municipal law enforcement agency shall submit to the clearinghouse information concerning missing endangered persons.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person having knowledge may submit a missing endangered person report to the clearinghouse concerning a child or adult younger than 26 years of age whose whereabouts is unknown, regardless of the circumstances, subsequent to reporting such child or adult missing to the appropriate law enforcement agency within the county in which the child or adult became missing, and subsequent to entry by the law enforcement agency of the child or person into the Florida Crime Information Center and the National Crime Information Center databases. The missing endangered person report shall be included in the clearinghouse database.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the case may submit a missing endangered person report to the clearinghouse involving a missing adult age 26 years or older who is suspected by a law enforcement agency of being endangered or the victim of criminal activity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the case may make a request to the clearinghouse for the activation of a state Silver Alert involving a missing adult if circumstances regarding the disappearance have met the criteria for activation of the Silver Alert Plan.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect, process, maintain, and disseminate information on missing endangered persons and strive to maintain or disseminate only accurate and complete information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person responsible for notifying the clearinghouse or a law enforcement agency about a missing endangered person shall immediately notify the clearinghouse or the agency of any child or adult whose location has been determined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over a case involving a missing endangered person shall, upon locating the child or adult, immediately purge information about the case from the Florida Crime Information Center or the National Crime Information Center databases and notify the clearinghouse.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-43; s. 4, ch. 2008-162; s. 3, ch. 2011-218.</History></Section>