<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0937.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Missing child and missing adult reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Law enforcement agencies in this state shall adopt written policies that specify the procedures to be used to investigate reports of missing children and missing adults. The policies must ensure that cases involving missing children and adults are investigated promptly using appropriate resources. The policies must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for accepting missing child and missing adult reports;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for initiating, maintaining, closing, or referring a missing child or missing adult investigation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standards for maintaining and clearing computer data of information concerning a missing child or missing adult which is stored in the Florida Crime Information Center and the National Crime Information Center. The standards must require, at a minimum, a monthly review of each case and a determination of whether the case should be maintained in the database.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entry concerning a missing child or missing adult may not be removed from the Florida Crime Information Center or the National Crime Information Center databases based solely on the age of the missing child or missing adult.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report that a child or adult is missing must be accepted by and filed with the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction in the county or municipality in which the child or adult was last seen. The filing and acceptance of the report imposes the duties specified in this section upon the law enforcement agency receiving the report. This subsection does not preclude a law enforcement agency from accepting a missing child or missing adult report when agency jurisdiction cannot be determined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a police report that a child is missing by the parent or guardian, the Department of Children and Family Services, a community-based care provider, or a sheriff’s office providing investigative services for the department, the law enforcement agency receiving the report shall immediately inform all on-duty law enforcement officers of the missing child report, communicate the report to every other law enforcement agency having jurisdiction in the county, and within 2 hours after receipt of the report, transmit the report for inclusion within the Florida Crime Information Center and the National Crime Information Center databases. A law enforcement agency may not require a reporter to present an order that a child be taken into custody or any other such order before accepting a report that a child is missing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a credible police report that an adult is missing, the law enforcement agency receiving the report shall, within 2 hours after receipt of the report, transmit the report for inclusion within the Florida Crime Information Center and the National Crime Information Center databases.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving a request to record, report, transmit, display, or release Amber Alert or Missing Child Alert information from the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the missing child, the Department of Law Enforcement as the state Amber Alert coordinator, any state or local law enforcement agency, and the personnel of these agencies; any radio or television network, broadcaster, or other media representative; any dealer of communications services as defined in s. 202.11; or any agency, employee, individual, or entity is immune from civil liability for damages for complying in good faith with the request and is presumed to have acted in good faith in recording, reporting, transmitting, displaying, or releasing Amber Alert or Missing Child Alert information pertaining to the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving a request to record, report, transmit, display, or release information and photographs pertaining to a missing adult from the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the missing adult, the department, a state or local law enforcement agency, and the personnel of these agencies; any radio or television network, broadcaster, or other media representative; any dealer of communications services as defined in s. 202.11; or any agency, employee, individual, or person is immune from civil liability for damages for complying in good faith with the request to provide information and is presumed to have acted in good faith in recording, reporting, transmitting, displaying, or releasing information or photographs pertaining to the missing adult.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving a request to record, report, transmit, display, or release Silver Alert information from the law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over the missing adult, the Department of Law Enforcement as the state Silver Alert coordinator, any state or local law enforcement agency, and the personnel of these agencies; any radio or television network, broadcaster, or other media representative; any dealer of communications services as defined in s. 202.11; or any agency, employee, individual, or entity is immune from civil liability for damages for complying in good faith with the request and is presumed to have acted in good faith in recording, reporting, transmitting, displaying, or releasing Silver Alert information pertaining to the missing adult.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The presumption of good faith is not overcome if a technical or clerical error is made by any agency, employee, individual, or entity acting at the request of the local law enforcement agency having jurisdiction, or if the Amber Alert, Missing Child Alert, missing adult information, or Silver Alert information is incomplete or incorrect because the information received from the local law enforcement agency was incomplete or incorrect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither this subsection nor any other provision of law creates a duty of the agency, employee, individual, or entity to record, report, transmit, display, or release the Amber Alert, Missing Child Alert, missing adult information, or Silver Alert information received from the local law enforcement agency having jurisdiction. The decision to record, report, transmit, display, or release information is discretionary with the agency, employee, individual, or entity receiving the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a missing child or missing adult is not located within 90 days after the missing child or missing adult report is filed, the law enforcement agency that accepted the report shall attempt to obtain a biological specimen for DNA analysis from the missing child or missing adult or from appropriate family members in addition to obtaining necessary documentation. This subsection does not prevent a law enforcement agency from attempting to obtain information or approved biological specimens for DNA analysis before the expiration of the 90-day period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules specific to cases involving missing children and missing adults which will:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify biological specimens that are approved by the department for DNA analysis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the documentation necessary for the department to use the biological specimens for DNA analysis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for the collection of biological specimens by law enforcement agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for forwarding biological specimens by law enforcement agencies to the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (6) and (7) are contingent upon the availability of federal funding for the submission and processing of approved biological specimens for DNA analysis.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-32; s. 11, ch. 2003-146; s. 3, ch. 2006-176; s. 3, ch. 2008-162; s. 22, ch. 2008-245; s. 93, ch. 2009-21; s. 2, ch. 2011-218.</History></Section>