<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0655.4185"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of the financial institutions codes or chapter 120, if the office or the appropriate federal regulatory agency, or the appropriate home state regulatory agency for an out-of-state state financial institution, finds that immediate action is necessary to prevent the probable failure of one or more financial institutions; aid in the resolution of a receivership, conservatorship, or liquidation of a financial institution; or otherwise protect the depositors of a failing financial institution, the office may issue an emergency order authorizing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The merger of such failing institution with an appropriate state financial institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appropriate state financial institution to acquire any of the assets or assume any of the liabilities, or any combination thereof, of the failing institution, including all rights, powers, and responsibilities as fiduciary in an instance in which the failing institution is actively engaged in the exercise of trust powers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conversion of a failing institution into a state financial institution that is not failing; </Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chartering of a new state financial institution to acquire any of the assets or assume any of the liabilities, or any combination thereof, of a failing institution and to assume rights, powers, and responsibilities as fiduciary in a case in which such failing institution is engaged in the exercise of trust powers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct or indirect acquisition of control of the failing institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appointment of provisional directors, executive officers, or other employees for the failing institution pursuant to s. 655.03855; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other capital or liquidity restoration plan or action deemed prudent by the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any finding by the office must be based upon reports or other information furnished to it by the failing financial institution, by a state or federal financial institution examiner or regulatory entity, or upon other evidence from which it is reasonable to conclude that the failing institution is insolvent, is threatened with imminent insolvency, or lacks a board of directors or executive management that can operate the entity in a safe and sound manner. The office may disallow intangible assets, deferred tax assets, loan or lease loss reserves, subordinated debt, and illegally obtained currency, monetary instruments, funds, or other financial resources from the capitalization requirements of the financial institutions codes. The stockholders of a failing institution that is acquired by another financial institution are entitled to the same procedural rights and compensation for the remaining value of their shares as is provided for dissenters in s. 658.44, except that they may not vote against the transaction. Any transaction authorized by this section may be accomplished through the organization of a successor financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may provide prior approval of business entities or individuals who, pursuant to this section, may charter a new state financial institution or acquire control of, purchase, merge with, or become directors and executive officers of, a failing financial institution. The application for prior approval must be in the form prescribed by the commission by rule and be accompanied by a nonrefundable filing fee of $7,500.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2005-181; s. 12, ch. 2011-194.</History></Section>