<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.962" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lighting; mirrors; landscaping.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each operator, or other person responsible for an automated teller machine pursuant to ss. 655.960-655.965, shall provide lighting during the hours of darkness with respect to an open and operating automated teller machine and any defined parking area, access area, and the exterior of an enclosed automated teller machine installation, as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a minimum of 10 candlefoot power at the face of the automated teller machine and extending in an unobstructed direction outward 5 feet.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a minimum of 2 candlefoot power within 50 feet in all unobstructed directions from the face of the automated teller machine. If the automated teller machine is located within 10 feet of the corner of the building and the automated teller machine is generally accessible from the adjacent side, there shall be a minimum of 2 candlefoot power along the first 40 unobstructed feet of the adjacent side of the building.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a minimum of 2 candlefoot power in that portion of the defined parking area within 60 feet of the automated teller machine.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator shall provide reflective mirrors or surfaces at each automated teller machine which provide the customer with a rear view while the customer is engaged in using the automated teller machine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator, or other person responsible pursuant to ss. 655.960-655.965 for an automated teller machine, shall ensure that the height of any landscaping, vegetation, or other physical obstructions in the area required to be lighted pursuant to subsection (1) for any open and operating automated teller machine shall not exceed 3 feet, except that trees trimmed to a height of 10 feet and whose diameters are less than 2 feet and manmade physical obstructions required by statute, law, code, ordinance, or other governmental regulation shall not be affected by this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-343; s. 85, ch. 2000-158; s. 14, ch. 2001-64.</History></Section>