<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigations, subpoenas, hearings, and witnesses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may make investigations, within or outside this state, which it deems necessary to determine whether a person has violated or is about to violate any provision of the financial institutions codes or of the rules adopted by the commission pursuant to such codes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of or in connection with an investigation by the office pursuant to the provisions of subsection (1) or an investigation or examination in connection with any application to the office for the organization or establishment of a state financial institution or a branch thereof, and in connection with an examination of a state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation by the office, the office, or any of its officers holding no lesser title and position than examiner in charge or attorney at law, shall have the power:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To administer oaths and affirmations;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To take or cause to be taken testimony and depositions; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue, revoke, quash, or modify subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum under the seal of the office or to cause any such subpoena or subpoena duces tecum to be issued by any county court judge or clerk of the circuit court or county court to require persons to be or appear before the office at a time and place to be therein named and to bring such books, records, and documents for inspection as may be therein designated. Such subpoenas may be served by a representative of the office or may be served as otherwise provided for by law for the service of subpoenas.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with any such investigation or examination, the office may permit a person to file a statement in writing, under oath or otherwise as the office determines, as to facts and circumstances specified by the office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of noncompliance with a subpoena issued or caused to be issued by the office pursuant to this section, the office may petition the circuit court of the county in which the person subpoenaed resides or has its principal place of business for an order requiring the subpoenaed person to appear and testify and to produce such books, records, and documents as are specified in such subpoena duces tecum. The office is entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011, and the court shall advance the cause on its calendar.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the petition shall be served upon the person subpoenaed by any person authorized by this section to serve subpoenas, who shall make and file with the court an affidavit showing the time, place, and date of service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any hearing on any such petition, the person subpoenaed, or any person whose interests will be substantially affected by the investigation, examination, or subpoena, may appear and object to the subpoena and to the granting of the petition. The court may make any order which justice requires to protect a party or other person and his or her personal and property rights, including, but not limited to, protection from annoyance, embarrassment, oppression, or undue burden or expense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with an order granting, in whole or in part, a petition for enforcement of a subpoena is a contempt of court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Witnesses shall be entitled to the same fees and mileage to which they might be entitled by law for attending as witnesses in the circuit court, except that no fees or mileage shall be allowed in the case of testimony of a financial institution-affiliated party if such testimony is taken at the principal office of the state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation or at the residence of the financial institution-affiliated party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by the office and payable to persons in investigations may be assessed against such an applicant, state financial institution, subsidiary, service corporation, or financial institution-affiliated party on the basis of actual costs incurred. Assessable expenses include, but are not limited to: expenses for interpreters; expenses for communications; expenses for legal representation; expenses for economic, legal, or other research, analyses, and testimony; and fees and expenses for witnesses. The failure to reimburse the office is a ground for denial of the application or for revocation of any approval thereof.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-273; s. 4, ch. 84-216; s. 1, ch. 85-65; s. 1, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 12, ch. 92-303; s. 520, ch. 97-102; s. 1705, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 655.025.</Text></Note></Section>