<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.954" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial institution loans; credit cards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a financial institution shall have the power to make loans or extensions of credit to any person on a credit card or overdraft financing arrangement and to charge, in any billing cycle, interest on the outstanding amount at a rate that is specified in a written agreement, between the financial institution and borrower, governing the credit card account. Such credit card agreement may modify any terms or conditions of such credit card account upon prior written notice of such modification as specified by the terms of the agreement governing the credit card account or by the Truth in Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1601 et seq., as amended, and the rules and regulations adopted under such act. Any such notice provided by a financial institution shall specify that the borrower has the right to surrender the credit card whereupon the borrower shall have the right to continue to pay off the borrower’s credit card account in the same manner and under the same terms and conditions as then in effect. The borrower’s failure to surrender the credit card prior to the modifications becoming effective shall constitute a consent to the modifications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with entering into any contract or agreement for a loan, line of credit, or loan extension, a financial institution, insured depository institution as defined in 12 U.S.C. s. 1813, and subsidiaries of such institutions may offer, for a fee or otherwise, optional debt cancellation products pursuant to s. 655.947 and rules adopted under that section. The financial institution may not require the purchase of a debt cancellation product as a condition for making the loan, line of credit, or loan extension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Billing cycle” has the same meaning as ascribed to it under the federal Truth in Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1601 et seq., as amended, and the associated regulations which are in effect as of January 31, 2008.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interest” means those charges considered a finance charge under the federal Truth in Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1601 et seq., as amended, and the associated regulations which are in effect as of January 31, 2008.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-339; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 10, 15, ch. 79-274; s. 1, ch. 79-592; ss. 40, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 88-58; ss. 1, 4, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 212, ch. 92-303; s. 11, ch. 2008-75.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 659.181; s. 658.50.</Text></Note></Section>