<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Convenience accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A convenience account is a deposit account, other than a certificate of deposit, in the name of one individual (principal), in which one or more other individuals have been designated as agents with the right to make deposits to and to withdraw funds from or draw checks on such account. The designation of agents, the substitution or removal of agents, or any other change in the contractual terms or provisions governing a convenience account may be made only by the principal. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the agency relationship created under this account is not affected by the subsequent death or incompetence of the principal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights, interests, and claims in, to, and in respect of, such deposits and convenience account and the additions thereto shall be those of the principal only.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any balance standing to the credit of a convenience account shall be paid to the guardian of the property of the principal, to any person designated in a court order entered pursuant to s. 735.206, to any person designated by letter or other writing as authorized by s. 735.301, or to the personal representative of the deceased principal’s estate, upon presentation of effective written notice and, if applicable, proof of judicial appointment of such guardian or personal representative by a court of competent jurisdiction. No such court order or letter, written notice, or proof of judicial appointment is effective until it is served upon and received by an officer of the institution during regular banking hours and in such time and in such manner as to afford the institution a reasonable opportunity to act on it prior to the happening of any of the events described in s. 674.303. No other notice, knowledge, or other information shown to have been available to an institution affects its right to the protection provided by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment by an institution pursuant to this section is a valid and sufficient release and discharge to the institution from all claims for payments so paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without qualifying any other right to setoff or lien, and subject to any contractual provision, if the principal is indebted to the institution, the institution has a right to setoff against the account.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 92-303.</History></Section>