<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Law applicable to deposits in and contracts relating to extensions of credit by a deposit or lending institution located in this state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law of this state, excluding its law regarding comity and conflict of laws, governs all aspects, including without limitation the validity and effect, of any deposit account in a branch or office in this state of a deposit or lending institution, including a deposit account otherwise covered by s. 671.105(1), regardless of the citizenship, residence, location, or domicile of any other party to the contract or agreement governing such deposit account, and regardless of any provision of any law of the jurisdiction of the residence, location, or domicile of such other party, whether or not such deposit account bears any other relation to this state, except that this section does not apply to any such deposit account:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent provided to the contrary in s. 671.105(2); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that all parties to the contract or agreement governing such deposit account have agreed in writing that the law of another jurisdiction will govern it.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law of this state, excluding its law regarding comity and conflict of laws, governs all aspects, including without limitation the validity and effect, of any contract relating to an extension of credit made by a branch or office in this state of a deposit or lending institution, including a contract otherwise covered by s. 671.105(1), if the contract expressly provides that it will be governed by the law of this state, regardless of the citizenship, residence, location, or domicile of any other party to such contract and regardless of any provision of any law of the jurisdiction of the residence, location, or domicile of such other party, whether or not such contract bears any other relation to this state, except that this section does not apply to any such contract to the extent provided to the contrary in s. 671.105(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deposit or lending institution” means any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank, trust company, credit union, or association organized and existing under the laws of this or any other state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An international bank agency, representative office, or international administrative office operating pursuant to the laws of this state or any branch or other office of an international banking corporation operating pursuant to the laws of this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A national banking corporation organized and existing pursuant to the provisions of the National Bank Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 21 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal association organized and existing pursuant to the provisions of the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, 12 U.S.C. ss. 1461 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal credit union organized and existing pursuant to the provisions of the Federal Credit Union Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 1751 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal agency operating pursuant to the provisions of the International Banking Act of 1978, 12 U.S.C. ss. 3101 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agreement corporation operating pursuant to s. 25 of the Federal Reserve Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 601 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An Edge Act corporation organized pursuant to the provisions of s. 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 611 et seq.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deposit account” means any deposit or account in one or more names including, without limitation, any certificate of deposit, time deposit, credit balance, checking account, interest-bearing account, non-interest-bearing account, individual retirement account (IRA), money market account, NOW account, transaction account, savings account, passbook account, joint account, convenience account, escrow account, trust account, custodial account, fiduciary account, deposit in trust, or Totten trust account.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contract relating to extension of credit” means any contract or agreement relating to any extension of credit, including, without limitation, any loan agreement, letter of credit, promissory note, letter of intent, loan commitment, credit facility agreement, confirmation or advice of letter of credit, letter of credit application or reimbursement agreement, overdraft agreement, revolving credit agreement, construction loan agreement, floor plan agreement, acceptance, pledge agreement, hypothecation agreement, assignment, mortgage, security agreement, power of attorney, subordination agreement, assumption agreement, loan modification agreement, guaranty, surety agreement, indemnity agreement, or workout agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any law that limits or affects the right of a person to maintain an action or proceeding, any person may, to the extent permitted under the United States Constitution, maintain an action or proceeding in this state against any person or other entity residing or located outside this state if the action or proceeding arises out of a deposit account or contract relating to an extension of credit which, pursuant to subsection (1) or subsection (2), is governed in whole or in part by the law of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the law governing any transactions other than deposit accounts or contracts relating to extensions of credit specified herein, nor does this section affect the jurisdiction of the courts of this state over any dispute arising under any transactions other than deposit accounts or contracts relating to extensions of credit specified herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to deposit accounts and contracts relating to extensions of credit entered into before, on, or after July 1, 1988. However, this section does not apply to any deposit accounts existing on July 1, 1988, if either party to the contract or agreement governing the deposit account provides the other party with a written objection to the application of this section within 6 months of July 1, 1988.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-180; s. 1, ch. 89-296; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 41, ch. 92-303.</History></Section>