<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.947" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Debt cancellation products.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Debt cancellation products may be offered, and a fee may be charged, by financial institutions and subsidiaries of financial institutions subject to this section and the rules and orders of the commission or office. As used in this section, the term “financial institutions” includes those defined in s. 655.005, insured depository institutions as defined in 12 U.S.C. s. 1813, and subsidiaries of such institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution shall manage the risks associated with debt cancellation products in accordance with prudent safety and soundness principles. A financial institution shall establish and maintain effective risk management and control processes over its debt cancellation products and programs. Such processes shall include appropriate recognition and financial reporting of income, expenses, assets, and liabilities and appropriate treatment of all expected and unexpected losses associated with the products. Each financial institution shall also assess the adequacy of its internal control and risk mitigation activities in view of the nature and scope of its debt cancellation products and programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer this section, which rules must be consistent with 12 C.F.R. part 37, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section and any rules adopted pursuant to this section, a periodic payment option is not required to be offered for any debt cancellation product designed to protect a customer against a deficiency between the outstanding loan or lease amount and the value of the motor vehicle that is used as collateral for the loan or lease.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2008-75; s. 14, ch. 2011-194.</History></Section>