<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.948" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Significant events; notice required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless exempted by the office pursuant to subsection (4), every financial institution shall notify the office of the occurrence of any of the events listed in subsection (2) by filing with the office a disclosure in a form to be specified by the commission. The form shall include the number and caption of all applicable events, along with a summary of each. Completed forms shall be certified for authenticity and accuracy by the chief executive officer of the financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Events for which disclosure forms must be filed and the filing schedule for each are as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be disclosed within 30 days of the occurrence of the event:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The addition, resignation, or termination of a director, executive officer, independent internal auditor, or independent credit review officer;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition or divestiture of an asset or assets the value of which exceeds 20 percent of capital as of the date of the most recent call report. Any assets listed in s. 657.042(1) or s. 658.67(1) are excluded from such disclosure requirements;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in general counsel or outside auditors who are used to certify financial statements;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interruption of fidelity insurance coverage;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any credit extension to an executive officer and his or her related interests that, when aggregated with the amount of all other extensions of credit to that executive officer and his or her related interests, exceeds 15 percent of the capital accounts of the financial institution;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any suspected criminal act perpetrated against a financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation. However, no liability shall be incurred by any financial institution, subsidiary, service corporation, or financial institution-affiliated party as a result of making a good faith effort to fulfill this disclosure requirement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition or divestiture of a wholly owned or majority owned subsidiary or service corporation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every financial institution shall notify the office within 30 days of the existence of any asset which is defined as a nonaccrual asset and which is in excess of 15 percent of total assets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution which fails to file a disclosure form within 30 days after the occurrence shall be subject to the fines provided in s. 655.041.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office must exempt a financial institution from any of the provisions of this section if the office determines that such financial institution is operating in a safe and sound manner pursuant to commission rules relating to safe and sound operations. The commission shall adopt rules defining the term “safe and sound” and explicitly stating the criteria which shall constitute operating in a safe and sound manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), all newly chartered financial institutions shall be subject to the requirements of subsections (1) and (2) for 3 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 218, ch. 92-303; s. 7, ch. 93-111; s. 532, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 99-138; s. 1737, ch. 2003-261; s. 128, ch. 2005-2.</History></Section>