<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.0322" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts and practices; criminal penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “financial institution” means a financial institution as defined in s. 655.50 which includes a state trust company, state or national bank, state or federal association, state or federal savings bank, state or federal credit union, Edge Act or agreement corporation, international bank agency, international branch, representative office or administrative office or other business entity as defined by the commission by rule, whether organized under the laws of this state, the laws of another state, or the laws of the United States, which institution is located in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any financial institution-affiliated party to ask for, willfully and knowingly receive or consent to receive any commission, emolument, gratuity, money, property, or thing of value for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, or endeavoring to procure, for any person a loan or extension of credit from such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, or endeavoring to procure, the purchase or discount of any note, draft, check, bill of exchange, or other obligation by such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any financial institution-affiliated party to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly receive or possess himself or herself of any of its property otherwise than in payment of a just demand, and, with intent to deceive or defraud, to omit to make or cause to be made a full and true entry thereof in its books and accounts, or concur in omitting to make any material entry thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Embezzle, abstract, or misapply any money, property, or thing of value of the financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation with intent to deceive or defraud such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly make, draw, issue, put forth, or assign any certificate of deposit, draft, order, bill of exchange, acceptance, note, debenture, bond or other obligation, mortgage, judgment, or decree without authority from the board of directors of such financial institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any false entry in any book, report, or statement of such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation with intent to deceive or defraud such financial institution or another person, firm, or corporation, or with intent to deceive the office, any other appropriate federal regulatory agency, or any authorized representative appointed to examine the affairs of such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver or disclose to the office or any of its employees any examination report, report of condition, report of income and dividends, internal audit, account, statement, or document known by him or her to be fraudulent or false as to any material matter.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any financial institution-affiliated party to knowingly place among the assets of such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation any note, obligation, or security which the financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation does not own or which to the individual’s knowledge is fraudulent or otherwise worthless or for any such individual to represent to the office that any note, obligation, or security carried as an asset of such financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation is the property of the financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation and is genuine if it is known to such individual that such representation is false or that such note, obligation, or security is fraudulent or otherwise worthless. Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully makes any false statement or report, or willfully overvalues any land, property, or security, for the purposes of influencing in any way the action of any financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation or any other entity authorized by law to extend credit, upon any application, advance, discount, purchase, purchase agreement, repurchase agreement, commitment, or loan, or any change or extension of any of the same, by renewal, deferment of action or otherwise, or the acceptance, release, or substitution of security therefor, is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly executes, or attempts to execute, a scheme or artifice to defraud a financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation or any other entity authorized by law to extend credit, or to obtain any of the moneys, funds, credits, assets, securities, or other property owned by, or under the custody or control of, a financial institution, subsidiary, service corporation, or any other entity authorized by law to extend credit, by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 92-303; s. 3, ch. 97-30; s. 521, ch. 97-102; s. 1707, ch. 2003-261; s. 6, ch. 2004-340; s. 89, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>