<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations, reports, and internal audits; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall conduct an examination of the condition of each state financial institution during each 18-month period. The office may conduct more frequent examinations based upon the risk profile of the financial institution, prior examination results, or significant changes in the institution or its operations. The office may use continuous, phase, or other flexible scheduling examination methods for very large or complex state financial institutions and financial institutions owned or controlled by a multi-financial institution holding company. The office shall consider examination guidelines from federal regulatory agencies in order to facilitate, coordinate, and standardize examination processes.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to, and examination of, the condition of a state institution, the office may accept an examination made by an appropriate federal regulatory agency, or may make a joint or concurrent examination with the federal agency. The office may furnish a copy of all examinations or reviews made of financial institutions or their affiliates to the state or federal agencies participating in the examination, investigation, or review, or as otherwise authorized by s. 655.057.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, as a part of an examination or investigation of a state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation, the office has reason to believe that the conduct or business operations of an affiliate may have a negative impact on the state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation, the office may conduct such examination or investigation of the affiliate as the office deems necessary. </Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may recover the costs of examination and supervision of a state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation that is determined by the office to be engaged in an unsafe or unsound practice. The office may also recover the costs of any review conducted pursuant to paragraph (b) of any affiliate of a state financial institution determined by the office to have contributed to an unsafe or unsound practice at a state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “costs” means the salary and travel expenses directly attributable to the field staff examining the state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation, and the travel expenses of any supervisory staff required as a result of examination findings. The mailing of any costs incurred under this subsection must be postmarked within 30 days after the date of receipt of a notice stating that such costs are due. The office may levy a late payment of up to $100 per day or part thereof that a payment is overdue, unless excused for good cause. However, for intentional late payment of costs, the office may levy an administrative fine of up to $1,000 per day for each day the payment is overdue.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may require an audit of a state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation by an independent certified public accountant, or other person approved by the office, if the office, after conducting an examination of the state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation, or after accepting an examination of such state financial institution by an appropriate state or federal regulatory agency, determines that an audit is necessary in order to ascertain the condition of the financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation. The cost of such audit shall be paid by the state financial institution, subsidiary, or state service corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation shall submit a report, at least four times each calendar year, as of such dates as the commission or office determines. Such report must include such information as the commission by rule requires for that type of institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall levy an administrative fine of up to $100 per day for each day the report is past due, unless it is excused for good cause. However, for intentional late filing of the report required under paragraph (a), the office shall levy an administrative fine of up to $1,000 per day for each day the report is past due.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of each state financial institution or, in the case of a credit union, the supervisory committee or audit committee shall perform or cause to be performed, within each calendar year, an internal audit of each state financial institution, subsidiary, or service corporation and to file a copy of the report and findings of such audit with the office on a timely basis. Such internal audit must include such information as the commission by rule requires for that type of institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the approval of the office, the board of directors or, in the case of a credit union, the supervisory committee may elect, in lieu of such periodic audits, to adopt and implement an adequate continuous audit system and procedure which must include full, adequate, and continuous written reports to, and review by, the board of directors or, in the case of a credit union, the supervisory committee, together with written statements of the actions taken thereon and reasons for omissions to take actions, all of which shall be noted in the minutes and filed among the records of the board of directors or, in the case of a credit union, the supervisory committee. If at any time such continuous audit system and procedure, including the reports and statements, becomes inadequate, in the judgment of the office, the state financial institution shall promptly make such changes as may be required by the office to cause the same to accomplish the purpose of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any de novo state financial institution open less than 4 months is exempt from the audit requirements of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the report of each examination must be furnished to the entity examined. Such report shall be presented to the board of directors at its next regular or special meeting.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-273; s. 2, ch. 82-214; s. 143, ch. 83-216; s. 1, ch. 85-65; s. 3, ch. 85-82; s. 2, ch. 90-197; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 24, ch. 92-303; s. 5, ch. 93-111; s. 4, ch. 97-30; s. 523, ch. 97-102; s. 1717, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2004-340; s. 91, ch. 2004-390; s. 5, ch. 2011-194.</History></Section>