<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.059" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Access to books and records; confidentiality; penalty for disclosure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The books and records of a financial institution are confidential and shall be made available for inspection and examination only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the office or its duly authorized representative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person duly authorized to act for the financial institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any federal or state instrumentality or agency authorized to inspect or examine the books and records of an insured financial institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an international banking corporation, to the home-country supervisor of the corporation, provided:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor provides advance notice to the office that the supervisor intends to examine the Florida office of the corporation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor confirms to the office that the purpose of the examination is to ensure the safety and soundness of the corporation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The books and records pertaining to customer deposit, investment, and custodial accounts are not disclosed to the supervisor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time during the conduct of the examination, the office reserves the right to have an examiner present or to participate jointly in the examination.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this paragraph, “home-country supervisor” means the governmental entity in the corporation’s home country with responsibility for the supervision and regulation of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As compelled by a court of competent jurisdiction, pursuant to a subpoena issued pursuant to the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure, the Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure, or the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, or pursuant to a subpoena issued in accordance with state or federal law. Prior to the production of the books and records of a financial institution, the party seeking production must reimburse the financial institution for the reasonable costs and fees incurred in compliance with the production. If the parties disagree regarding the amount of reimbursement, the party seeking the records may request the court or agency having jurisdiction to set the amount of reimbursement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As compelled by legislative subpoena as provided by law, in which case the provisions of s. 655.057 apply;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to a subpoena, to any federal or state law enforcement or prosecutorial instrumentality authorized to investigate suspected criminal activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As authorized by the board of directors of the financial institution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As provided in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each depositor, borrower, member, or stockholder has the right to inspect such books and records of a financial institution as pertain to her or his loans or accounts or the determination of her or his voting rights.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The books and records pertaining to the deposit accounts and loans of depositors, borrowers, members, and stockholders of any financial institution shall be kept confidential by the financial institution and its directors, officers, and employees and shall not be released except upon express authorization of the account holder as to her or his own accounts, loans, or voting rights. However, information relating to any loan made by a financial institution may be released without the borrower’s authorization in a manner prescribed by the board of directors for the purpose of meeting the needs of commerce and for fair and accurate credit information. Information may also be released, without the authorization of a member or depositor but in a manner prescribed by the board of directors, to verify or corroborate the existence or amount of a customer’s or member’s account when such information is reasonably provided to meet the needs of commerce and to ensure accurate credit information. In addition, a financial institution, affiliate, and its subsidiaries, and any holding company of the financial institution or subsidiary of such holding company, may furnish to one another information relating to their customers or members, subject to the requirement that each corporation receiving information that is confidential maintain the confidentiality of such information and not provide or disclose such information to any unaffiliated person or entity. Notwithstanding this paragraph, nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a financial institution from disclosing financial information as referenced in this subsection as permitted by Pub. L. No. 106-102(1999), as set forth in 15 U.S.C.A. s. 6802, as amended.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully violates the provisions of this section that relate to unlawful disclosure of confidential information is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 30, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 29, ch. 92-303; s. 524, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 97-109; s. 4, ch. 2001-243; s. 1721, ch. 2003-261; s. 9, ch. 2004-340; s. 92, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>