<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.0385" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disapproval of directors and executive officers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state financial institution shall notify the office of the proposed appointment of any individual to the board of directors or the appointment or employment of any individual as an executive officer or equivalent position at least 60 days before such appointment or employment becomes effective, if the state financial institution:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been chartered for less than 2 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has undergone a change in control or conversion within the preceding 2 years. The office may exempt a financial institution from this paragraph if it operates in a safe and sound manner;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not in compliance with the minimum capital requirements applicable to such financial institution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is otherwise operating in an unsafe and unsound condition, as determined by the office, on the basis of such financial institution’s most recent report of condition or report of examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state financial institution may not appoint any individual to the board of directors, or employ any individual as an executive officer or equivalent position, if the office issues a notice of disapproval with respect to that person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall issue a notice of disapproval if the competence, experience, character, or integrity of the individual to be appointed or employed indicates that it is not in the best interests of the depositors, the members, or the public to permit the individual to be employed by or associated with the state financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning 1 year after opening, each notification of a proposed appointment of an individual to the board of directors must be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee of $35.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 92-303; s. 3, ch. 93-111; s. 1, ch. 99-138; s. 1711, ch. 2003-261; s. 7, ch. 2004-340; s. 90, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>