<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.82" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pay-on-death accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Account” means a contract of deposit between a depositor and an institution, including, but not limited to, a checking account, savings account, certificate of deposit, and share account.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beneficiary” means a person named as one to whom sums on deposit in an account are payable on request after death of all parties or for whom a party is named as trustee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Devisee” means any person designated in a will to receive a testamentary disposition of real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Heirs” means those persons, including a surviving spouse, who are entitled, under the laws of this state regarding intestate succession, to the property of a decedent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Multiple-party account” means an account payable on request to one or more of two or more parties, whether or not a right of survivorship is mentioned.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Party” means a person who, by the terms of an account, has a present right, subject to request, to payment from the account other than as a beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Payment” means disbursement of sums on deposit, and includes withdrawal, payment to a party or third person pursuant to check or other request, and a pledge of sums on deposit by a party, or a setoff, reduction, or other disposition of all or part of an account pursuant to a pledge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pay-on-death designation” means the designation of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficiary in an account payable on request to one party during the party’s lifetime and on the party’s death to one or more beneficiaries, or to one or more parties during their lifetimes and on death of all of them to one or more beneficiaries; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficiary in an account in the name of one or more parties as trustee for one or more beneficiaries if the relationship is established by the terms of the account and there is no subject of the trust other than the sums on deposit in the account, whether or not payment to the beneficiary is mentioned.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal representative” means an executor, administrator, curator, successor personal representative, special administrator, or any other person who performs substantially the same function under the law governing their status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Receive,” as it relates to notice to an institution, means receipt in the office or branch office of the institution in which the account is established, but if the terms of the account require notice at a particular place, in the place required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Request” means a request for payment complying with all terms of the account, including special requirements concerning necessary signatures and regulations of the institution; but, for purposes of this section, if terms of the account condition payment on advance notice, a request for payment is treated as immediately effective and a notice of intent to withdraw is treated as a request for payment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Successor” means any person, other than a creditor, who is entitled to property of a decedent under the decedent’s will or otherwise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sums on deposit” means the balance payable on an account, including interest and dividends earned, whether or not included in the current balance, and any deposit of life insurance proceeds added to the account by reason of death of a party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Terms of the account” means the deposit agreement and other terms and conditions, including the form, of the contract of deposit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficiary in an account having a pay-on-death designation has no right to sums on deposit during the lifetime of any party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an account with a pay-on-death designation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the death of one of two or more parties, sums on deposit in the account belong to the surviving party or parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the death of the sole party or the last survivor of two or more parties, sums on deposit belong to the surviving beneficiary or beneficiaries. If two or more beneficiaries survive, sums on deposit belong to them in equal and undivided shares, and, unless otherwise provided in a depository agreement written between December 31, 1994, and July 1, 2001, there is no right of survivorship in the event of death of a beneficiary thereafter. If no beneficiary survives, sums on deposit belong to the estate of the last surviving party.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pay-on-death designation in a multiple-party account without right of survivorship is ineffective. For purposes of this section, designation of an account as a tenancy in common establishes that the account is without right of survivorship.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ownership right of a surviving party or beneficiary, or of the decedent’s estate, in sums on deposit is subject to requests for payment made by a party before the party’s death, whether paid by the institution before or after death, or unpaid. The surviving party or beneficiary, or the decedent’s estate, is liable to the payee of an unpaid request for payment. The liability is limited to a proportionate share of the amount transferred under this section, to the extent necessary to discharge the request for payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An institution, on request, may pay sums on deposit in an account with a pay-on-death designation to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more of the parties, whether or not another party is disabled, incapacitated, or deceased when the payment is requested and whether or not a party survives another party;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary or beneficiaries, if proof of death is presented to the institution showing that the beneficiary or beneficiaries survived all persons named as parties; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative, if any, or, if there is none, the heirs or devisees of a deceased party, if proof of death is presented to the institution showing that the deceased party was the survivor of all other persons named on the account either as a party or beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment made pursuant to this section discharges the institution from all claims for amounts so paid, whether or not the payment is consistent with the beneficial ownership of the account as between parties, beneficiaries, or their successors. Payment may be made whether or not a party or beneficiary is disabled, incapacitated, or deceased when payment is requested, received, or made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A beneficiary in an account at a credit union having a pay-on-death designation, unless the beneficiary is a member in her or his own right, may not be permitted to vote, obtain an extension of credit, or hold office or be required to pay an entrance or membership fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following is an example of the form of a contract of deposit that may be used to select a pay-on-death account for use by one or more parties:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">SINGLE-PARTY ACCOUNT OR MULTIPLE-PARTY<NewLine />ACCOUNT WITH PAY-ON-DEATH DESIGNATION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">PARTIES (Name each party): <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">OWNERSHIP (Select one and initial):</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />SINGLE-PARTY ACCOUNT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />MULTIPLE-PARTY ACCOUNT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">RIGHTS AT DEATH (Select one and initial):</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />SINGLE-PARTY ACCOUNT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">At death of the party, ownership passes as part of the party’s estate.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />SINGLE-PARTY ACCOUNT WITH A PAY-ON-DEATH DESIGNATION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(Name one or more beneficiaries):</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">At death of the party, ownership passes to the designated pay-on-death beneficiaries and is not part of the party’s estate.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />MULTIPLE-PARTY ACCOUNT WITH RIGHT OF SURVIVORSHIP</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">At death of a party, ownership passes to the surviving party or parties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />MULTIPLE-PARTY ACCOUNT WITH RIGHT OF SURVIVORSHIP AND A PAY-ON-DEATH DESIGNATION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(Name one or more beneficiaries):</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">At death of the last surviving party, ownership passes to the designated pay-on-death beneficiaries and is not part of the last surviving party’s estate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-216; s. 529, ch. 97-102; s. 21, ch. 2001-243.</History></Section>