<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purpose; application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of the financial institutions codes are to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide general regulatory powers to be exercised by the Financial Services Commission and the Office of Financial Regulation in relation to the regulation of financial institutions. The financial institutions codes apply to all state-authorized or state-chartered financial institutions and to the enforcement of all laws relating to state-authorized or state-chartered financial institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for and promote:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safe and sound conduct of the business of the financial institutions subject to the financial institutions codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prudent conservation of the assets of the financial institutions subject to the financial institutions codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance of public confidence in the financial institutions subject to the financial institutions codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The protection of the interests of the public in the safety and soundness, and the preservation, of the financial institution system in this state and the protection of the interests of the depositors and creditors of financial institutions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The protection of the interests of the public in the proper conduct of fiduciary functions; the safety, soundness, and preservation of the system of the conduct in this state of trust business by trust companies and banks and associations that have trust departments; the protection of the interests of beneficiaries and other members of the public using the services of, doing business with, or otherwise affected by trust companies, trust departments of banks and associations, and other business organizations in the conduct of trust business or other exercise of fiduciary functions or powers; and the protection of the interests of the creditors of trust companies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opportunity for state financial institutions to be and remain competitive with each other, with financial institutions or organizations existing under statutes of this state other than the financial institutions codes, and with other financial institutions and organizations organized or existing under, or deriving their authority or powers from, the laws of other states, the United States, or foreign countries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opportunity for financial institutions to serve effectively the convenience and needs of their customers or members and the public and to participate in and promote the economic progress and welfare of this state and the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opportunity for the management of financial institutions in conducting the business and affairs of their institutions, to exercise their business judgment, subject to the provisions of the financial institutions codes and to the extent compatible with, and subject to, the purposes and policies stated in this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The modernization of state law governing financial institutions and governing the exercise of fiduciary and other representative powers by trust companies and trust departments of banks and associations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delegation to the commission of adequate rulemaking power and to the office adequate administrative discretion, subject to the provisions of the financial institutions codes and to the purposes and policies stated in this section, in order that the supervision and regulation of financial institutions may be flexible and readily responsive to changes in economic conditions, in technology, and in financial institution practices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-273; s. 1, ch. 85-65; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 6, ch. 92-303; s. 1699, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>