<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0655.968" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial institutions; transactions relating to Iran or terrorism.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Correspondent account” has the same meaning as defined in 31 U.S.C. s. 5318A.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial institution” has the same meaning as defined in s. 655.005(1)(i).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Payable-through account” has the same meaning as defined in 31 U.S.C. s. 5318A.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution chartered in this state which maintains a correspondent account or a payable-through account with a foreign financial institution must establish due diligence policies, procedures, and controls reasonably designed to detect whether the United States Secretary of the Treasury has found that the foreign financial institution knowingly:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitates the efforts of the Government of Iran, including efforts of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, to acquire or develop weapons of mass destruction or their delivery systems;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides support for an organization designated by the United States as a foreign terrorist organization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitates the activities of a person who is subject to financial sanctions pursuant to a resolution of the United Nations Security Council imposing sanctions on Iran;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engages in money laundering to carry out any activity listed in this subsection;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitates efforts by the Central Bank of Iran or any other Iranian financial institution to carry out an activity listed in this subsection; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitates a significant transaction or provides significant financial services for Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or its agents or affiliates, or any financial institution, whose property or interests in property are blocked pursuant to federal law in connection with Iran’s proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, or delivery systems for those weapons, or Iran’s support for international terrorism.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By July 1, 2012, the Financial Services Commission shall adopt rules establishing minimum standards for due diligence policies, procedures, and controls required by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1, 2013, and each January 1 thereafter, each financial institution chartered in this state must certify to the Office of Financial Regulation that the financial institution has adopted and substantially complies with the due diligence policies, procedures, and controls required by this section and the rules adopted under this section, and that to the best knowledge of the financial institution, the financial institution does not maintain a correspondent account or a payable-through account with a foreign financial institution that knowingly engages in any act described in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 31, 2013, and each January 31 thereafter, the Office of Financial Regulation must submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives which contains a copy of the rules required under subsection (3) and the status of the certifications of compliance received from the financial institutions chartered in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Financial Regulation shall make its annual compliance report under this section available on its website.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Financial Regulation may impose an administrative fine, not to exceed $100,000 per occurrence, against a financial institution that fails to make the annual certification required under subsection (4).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-201.</History></Section>