<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0938.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal justice education for local government.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the costs provided for in s. 938.01, municipalities and counties may assess an additional $2 for expenditures for criminal justice education degree programs and training courses, including basic recruit training, for their respective officers and employing agency support personnel, provided such education degree programs and training courses are approved by the employing agency administrator, on a form provided by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission, for local funding.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workshops, meetings, conferences, and conventions shall, on a form approved by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission for use by the employing agency, be individually approved by the employing agency administrator prior to attendance. The form shall include, but not be limited to, a demonstration by the employing agency of the purpose of the workshop, meeting, conference, or convention; the direct relationship of the training to the officer’s job; the direct benefits the officer and agency will receive; and all anticipated costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission may inspect and copy the documentation of independent audits conducted of the municipalities and counties which make such assessments to ensure that such assessments have been made and that expenditures are in conformance with the requirements of this subsection and with other applicable procedures.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 74-386; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 17, ch. 81-24; s. 8, ch. 83-259; s. 5, ch. 84-156; s. 20, ch. 84-258; s. 11, ch. 85-224; s. 11, ch. 86-154; s. 16, ch. 86-187; s. 2, ch. 86-286; ss. 3, 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 4, ch. 88-51; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 14, ch. 97-271; s. 31, ch. 2010-117.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 943.25(13).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>