<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0334.045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transportation performance and productivity standards; development; measurement; application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Transportation Commission shall develop and adopt measures for evaluating the performance and productivity of the department. The measures may be both quantitative and qualitative and must, to the maximum extent practical, assess those factors that are within the department’s control. The measures must, at a minimum, assess performance in the following areas:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Production;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Finance and administration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preservation of the current state system;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safety of the current state system;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Capacity improvements: highways and all public transportation modes; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disadvantaged business enterprise and minority business programs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish annual performance objectives and standards that can be used to evaluate the department’s performance and productivity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall evaluate the department’s performance and productivity quarterly, using the measures adopted under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As soon as is practical after each annual evaluation, the commission shall submit its findings to the Governor and to the legislative transportation and appropriation committees. If the commission finds that the department failed to perform satisfactorily under these measures, the commission must recommend actions to be taken to improve the department’s performance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 118, ch. 90-136; s. 91, ch. 92-152; s. 55, ch. 93-164; ss. 31, 32, ch. 96-323.</History></Section>