<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0334.049" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Patents, copyrights, trademarks; notice to Department of State; confidentiality of trade secrets.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Department of Transportation is authorized, in its own name, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform all things necessary to secure letters of patent, copyrights, and trademarks on any legitimately acquired work products, and to enforce its rights therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License, lease, assign, or otherwise give written consent to any person, firm, or corporation for the manufacture or use of any product protected by patent, copyright, or trademark, whether on a royalty basis or for such other consideration as the department may deem proper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take any action necessary, including legal action, to enforce its rights under any agreement and to protect its property rights from improper or unlawful use or infringement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the collection of any payments or other obligations due the department for the manufacture or use of any product by any other party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell any product, except where otherwise provided by public records laws, which the department may create or cause to be created, whether or not the product is protected by a department patent, copyright, or trademark, and to execute all instruments necessary to consummate any such sale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do all other acts necessary and proper for the execution of powers and duties herein conferred upon the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall notify the Department of State in writing whenever property rights by patent, copyright, or trademark are secured or exploited by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proceeds from the sale of products or the right to manufacture or use a product shall be deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund and may be appropriated to finance activities of the department. The department’s legislative budget request should give special consideration to using such funds for research and development projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information obtained by the department as a result of research and development projects and revealing a method of process, production, or manufacture which is a trade secret as defined in s. 688.002, is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section the term “product” includes any and all inventions, methodologies, techniques, and creations that may be properly protected by patent, copyright, or trademark.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 93-164; s. 1, ch. 95-122; s. 160, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>