<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0334.046" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department mission, goals, and objectives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing principles to be considered in planning and developing an integrated, balanced statewide transportation system are: preserving the existing transportation infrastructure; enhancing Florida’s economic competitiveness; and improving travel choices to ensure mobility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mission of the Department of Transportation shall be to provide a safe statewide transportation system that ensures the mobility of people and goods, enhances economic prosperity, and preserves the quality of our environment and communities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall document in the Florida Transportation Plan, in accordance with s. 339.155 and based upon the prevailing principles of preserving the existing transportation infrastructure, enhancing Florida’s economic competitiveness, and improving travel choices to ensure mobility, the goals and objectives that provide statewide policy guidance for accomplishing the department’s mission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a minimum, the department’s goals shall address the following prevailing principles.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Preservation.</Font><EmDash />Protecting the state’s transportation infrastructure investment. Preservation includes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring that 80 percent of the pavement on the State Highway System meets department standards;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring that 90 percent of department-maintained bridges meet department standards; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring that the department achieves 100 percent of the acceptable maintenance standard on the state highway system.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Economic competitiveness.</Font><EmDash />Ensuring that the state has a clear understanding of the economic consequences of transportation investments, and how such investments affect the state’s economic competitiveness. The department must develop a macroeconomic analysis of the linkages between transportation investment and economic performance, as well as a method to quantifiably measure the economic benefits of the district-work-program investments. Such an analysis must analyze:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state’s and district’s economic performance relative to the competition.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business environment as viewed from the perspective of companies evaluating the state as a place in which to do business.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state’s capacity to sustain long-term growth.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Mobility.</Font><EmDash />Ensuring a cost-effective, statewide, interconnected transportation system.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 84-309; ss. 8, 31, ch. 85-180; s. 4, ch. 90-136; s. 96, ch. 92-152; ss. 8, 24, ch. 93-164; s. 48, ch. 94-237; s. 66, ch. 95-257; s. 43, ch. 99-385; s. 12, ch. 2000-266.</History></Section>