<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.707" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amendment or pre-effective date financing statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this section, the term “pre-effective date financing statement” means a financing statement filed before this act takes effect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After this act takes effect, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend the information provided in a pre-effective date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in part III. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4), if the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective date financing statement may be amended after this act takes effect only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pre-effective date financing statement and an amendment are filed in the office specified in s. 679.5011;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment is filed in the office specified in s. 679.5011 concurrently with, or after the filing in that office of, an initial financing statement that satisfies s. 679.706(3); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An initial financing statement that provides the information as amended and satisfies s. 679.706(3) is filed in the office specified in s. 679.5011.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective date financing statement may be continued only under s. 679.705(4) and (6) or s. 679.706.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective date financing statement filed in this state may be terminated after this act takes effect by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies s. 679.706(3) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in part III as the office in which to file a financing statement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2001-198; s. 145, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>