<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Processing fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3), the nonrefundable processing fee for filing and indexing a record under this part, other than an initial financing statement of the kind described in s. 679.5021(3), is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing an initial financing statement, $25 for the first page, which shall include the cost of filing a termination statement for the financing statement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing an amendment, $12 for the first page;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For indexing by additional debtor, secured party, or assignee, $3 per additional name indexed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For use of a nonapproved form, $5;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each additional page attached to a record, $3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a certified copy of a financing statement and any and all associated amendments, $30;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a photocopy of a filed record, $1 per page; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing an initial financing statement, an additional $10 for the first page. Receipts from this fee shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund and are not included in the receipts for purposes of calculating the contractor’s compensation for performing services regarding the Florida Secured Transaction Registry.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3), the fee for filing and indexing an initial financing statement of the kind described in s. 679.5021(3) is the amount specified in chapter 28.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not require a fee with respect to a mortgage that is effective as a financing statement filed as a fixture filing or as a financing statement covering as-extracted collateral or timber to be cut under s. 679.5021(3). However, the recording and satisfaction fees that otherwise would be applicable to the mortgage apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2001-198; s. 26, ch. 2007-134; s. 24, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>