<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.3091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security interest perfected upon attachment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following security interests are perfected when they attach:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchase-money security interest in consumer goods, except as otherwise provided in s. 679.3111(2) with respect to consumer goods that are subject to a statute or treaty described in s. 679.3111(1);</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of accounts or payment intangibles which does not by itself or in conjunction with other assignments to the same assignee transfer a significant part of the assignor’s outstanding accounts or payment intangibles;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sale of a payment intangible;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sale of a promissory note;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest created by the assignment of a health-care-insurance receivable to the provider of the health-care goods or services;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest arising under s. 672.401, s. 672.505, s. 672.711(3), or s. 680.508(5), until the debtor obtains possession of the collateral;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest of a collecting bank arising under s. 674.2101;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest of an issuer or nominated person arising under s. 675.118;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest arising in the delivery of a financial asset under s. 679.2061(3);</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest in investment property created by a broker or securities intermediary;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest in a commodity contract or a commodity account created by a commodity intermediary;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment for the benefit of all creditors of the transferor and subsequent transfers by the assignee thereunder; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest created by an assignment of a beneficial interest in a decedent’s estate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>