<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.519" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Numbering, maintaining, and indexing records; communicating information provided in records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each record filed in a filing office, the filing office shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assign a unique number to the filed record;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create a record that bears the number assigned to the filed record and the date and time of filing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the filed record for public inspection; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Index the filed record in accordance with subsections (3), (4), and (5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (9), a file number assigned after January 1, 2002, must include a digit that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is mathematically derived from or related to the other digits of the file number; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enables the filing office to detect whether a number communicated as the file number includes a single-digit or transpositional error.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (4) and (5), the filing office shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Index an initial financing statement according to the name of the debtor and shall index all filed records relating to the initial financing statement in a manner that associates with one another an initial financing statement and all filed records relating to the initial financing statement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Index a record that provides a name of a debtor which was not previously provided in the financing statement to which the record relates also according to the name that was not previously provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a financing statement is filed as a fixture filing or covers as-extracted collateral or timber to be cut, the filing office shall index it:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the names of the debtor and of each owner of record shown on the financing statement as if they were the mortgagors under a mortgage of the real property described; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that the law of this state provides for indexing of mortgages under the name of the mortgagee, under the name of the secured party as if the secured party were the mortgagee thereunder, or, if indexing is by description, as if the financing statement were a mortgage of the real property described.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a financing statement is filed as a fixture filing or covers as-extracted collateral or timber to be cut, the filing office shall index an assignment filed under s. 679.514(1) or an amendment filed under s. 679.514(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the name of the assignor as grantor; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that the law of this state provides for indexing the assignment of a real property mortgage under the name of the assignee, under the name of the assignee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing office shall maintain a capability for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retrieving a record by the name of the debtor and by the file number assigned to the initial financing statement to which the record relates; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Associating and retrieving with one another an initial financing statement and each filed record relating to the initial financing statement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing office may not remove a debtor’s name from the index until 1 year after the effectiveness of a financing statement naming the debtor lapses under s. 679.515 with respect to all secured parties of record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (9), the filing office shall perform the acts required by subsections (1) through (5) at the time and in the manner prescribed by any filing-office rule, but not later than 3 business days after the filing office receives the record in question, if practical.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1), (2), and (8) do not apply to a filing office described in s. 679.5011(1)(a).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2001-198; s. 12, ch. 2002-242.</History></Section>