<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.602" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Waiver and variance of rights and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 679.624, to the extent that they give rights to a debtor or obligor and impose duties on a secured party, the debtor or obligor may not waive or vary the rules stated in the following listed sections:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.2071(2)(d)3., which deals with use and operation of the collateral by the secured party;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.210, which deals with requests for an accounting and requests concerning a list of collateral and statement of account;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.607(3), which deals with collection and enforcement of collateral;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 679.608(1) and 679.615(3) to the extent that they deal with application or payment of noncash proceeds of collection, enforcement, or disposition;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 679.608(1) and 679.615(4) to the extent that they require accounting for or payment of surplus proceeds of collateral;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.609 to the extent that it imposes upon a secured party that takes possession of collateral without judicial process the duty to do so without breach of the peace;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 679.610(2), 679.611, 679.613, and 679.614, which deal with disposition of collateral;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.615(6), which deals with calculation of a deficiency or surplus when a disposition is made to the secured party, a person related to the secured party, or a secondary obligor;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.616, which deals with explanation of the calculation of a surplus or deficiency;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 679.620, 679.621, and 679.622, which deal with acceptance of collateral in satisfaction of obligation;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.623, which deals with redemption of collateral;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.624, which deals with permissible waivers; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 679.625 and 679.626, which deal with the secured party’s liability for failure to comply with this article.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>