<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.2061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security interest arising in purchase or delivery of financial asset.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest in favor of a securities intermediary attaches to a person’s security entitlement if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person buys a financial asset through the securities intermediary in a transaction in which the person is obligated to pay the purchase price to the securities intermediary at the time of the purchase; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The securities intermediary credits the financial asset to the buyer’s securities account before the buyer pays the securities intermediary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The security interest described in subsection (1) secures the person’s obligation to pay for the financial asset.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest in favor of a person who delivers a certificated security or other financial asset represented by a writing attaches to the security or other financial asset if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The security or other financial asset:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the ordinary course of business is transferred by delivery with any necessary indorsement or assignment; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is delivered under an agreement between persons in the business of dealing with such securities or financial assets; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement calls for delivery against payment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The security interest described in subsection (3) secures the obligation to make payment for the delivery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>