<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification before disposition of collateral.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this section, the term “notification date” means the earlier of the date on which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party sends to the debtor and any secondary obligor an authenticated notification of disposition; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The debtor and any secondary obligor waive the right to notification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4), a secured party that disposes of collateral under s. 679.610 shall send to the persons specified in subsection (3) a reasonable authenticated notification of disposition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To comply with subsection (2), the secured party shall send an authenticated notification of disposition to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The debtor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any secondary obligor; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the collateral is other than consumer goods:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person from whom the secured party has received, before the notification date, an authenticated notification of a claim of an interest in the collateral;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other secured party or lienholder that, 10 days before the notification date, held a security interest in or other lien on the collateral perfected by the filing of a financing statement that:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identified the collateral;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was indexed under the debtor’s name as of that date; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was filed in the office in which to file a financing statement against the debtor covering the collateral as of that date; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other secured party that, 10 days before the notification date, held a security interest in the collateral perfected by compliance with a statute, regulation, or treaty described in s. 679.3111(1).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (2) does not apply if the collateral is perishable or threatens to decline speedily in value or is of a type customarily sold on a recognized market.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party complies with the requirement for notification prescribed by subparagraph (3)(c)2. if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not later than 20 days or earlier than 30 days before the notification date, the secured party requests, in a commercially reasonable manner, information concerning financing statements indexed under the debtor’s name in the office indicated in subparagraph (3)(c)2.; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the notification date, the secured party:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Did not receive a response to the request for information; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Received a response to the request for information and sent an authenticated notification of disposition to each secured party or other lienholder named in that response whose financing statement covered the collateral.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of subsection (3), the secured party may send the authenticated notification as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the collateral is other than consumer goods, to the debtor at the address in the financing statement, unless the secured party has received an authenticated record from the debtor notifying the secured party of a different address for such notification purposes or the secured party has actual knowledge of the address of the debtor’s chief executive office or principal residence, as applicable, at the time the notification is sent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the collateral is other than consumer goods, to any secondary obligor at the address, if any, in the authenticated agreement, unless the secured party has received an authenticated record from the secondary obligor notifying the secured party of a different address for such notification purposes or the secured party has actual knowledge of the address of the secondary obligor’s chief executive office or principal residence, as applicable, at the time the notification is sent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the collateral is other than consumer goods:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the person described in subparagraph (3)(c)1., at the address stated in the notification;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the person described in subparagraph (3)(c)2., at the address stated in the financing statement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the person described in subparagraph (3)(c)3., at the address stated in the official records of the recording or registration agency.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>