<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0679.805" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">When initial financing statement suffices to continue effectiveness of financing statement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement in the office specified in s. 679.5011 continues the effectiveness of a financing statement filed before July 1, 2013, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement in that office would be effective to perfect a security interest under this chapter, as amended by ch. 2012-59, Laws of Florida;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financing statement filed before July 1, 2013, was filed in an office in another state; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial financing statement satisfies subsection (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement under subsection (1) continues the effectiveness of the financing statement filed before July 1, 2013, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial financing statement is filed before July 1, 2013, for the period provided in s. 679.515, as it existed before its amendment by ch. 2012-59, Laws of Florida, with respect to an initial financing statement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial financing statement is filed on or after July 1, 2013, for the period provided in s. 679.515, as amended by ch. 2012-59, Laws of Florida, with respect to an initial financing statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be effective for purposes of subsection (1), an initial financing statement must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfy the requirements of part IV, as amended by ch. 2012-59, Laws of Florida, for an initial financing statement;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the financing statement filed before July 1, 2013, by indicating the office in which the financing statement was filed and providing the dates of filing and file numbers, if any, of the financing statement and of the most recent continuation statement filed with respect to the financing statement; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indicate that the financing statement filed before July 1, 2013, remains effective.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 17, 19, ch. 2012-59.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2013.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>