<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0679.4061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discharge of account debtor; notification of assignment; identification and proof of assignment; restrictions on assignment of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, and promissory notes ineffective.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsections (2) through (9), an account debtor on an account, chattel paper, or a payment intangible may discharge its obligation by paying the assignor until, but not after, the account debtor receives a notification, authenticated by the assignor or the assignee, that the amount due or to become due has been assigned and that payment is to be made to the assignee. After receipt of the notification, the account debtor may discharge its obligation by paying the assignee and may not discharge the obligation by paying the assignor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (8), notification is ineffective under subsection (1):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it does not reasonably identify the rights assigned;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that an agreement between an account debtor and a seller of a payment intangible limits the account debtor’s duty to pay a person other than the seller and the limitation is effective under law other than this chapter; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the option of an account debtor, if the notification notifies the account debtor to make less than the full amount of any installment or other periodic payment to the assignee, even if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only a portion of the account, chattel paper, or payment intangible has been assigned to that assignee;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A portion has been assigned to another assignee; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The account debtor knows that the assignment to that assignee is limited.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (8), if requested by the account debtor, an assignee shall seasonably furnish reasonable proof that the assignment has been made. Unless the assignee complies, the account debtor may discharge its obligation by paying the assignor, even if the account debtor has received a notification under subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (5) and ss. 680.303 and 679.4071, and subject to subsection (8), a term in an agreement between an account debtor and an assignor or in a promissory note is ineffective to the extent that it:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prohibits, restricts, or requires the consent of the account debtor or person obligated on the promissory note to the assignment or transfer of, or the creation, attachment, perfection, or enforcement of a security interest in, the account, chattel paper, payment intangible, or promissory note; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides that the assignment or transfer or the creation, attachment, perfection, or enforcement of the security interest may give rise to a default, breach, right of recoupment, claim, defense, termination, right of termination, or remedy under the account, chattel paper, payment intangible, or promissory note.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Reference Number="2"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (4) does not apply to the sale of a payment intangible or promissory note.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in ss. 680.303 and 679.4071 and subject to subsections (8) and (9), a rule of law, statute, or regulation that prohibits, restricts, or requires the consent of a government, governmental body or official, or account debtor to the assignment or transfer of, or creation of a security interest in, an account or chattel paper is ineffective to the extent that the rule of law, statute, or regulation:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prohibits, restricts, or requires the consent of the government, governmental body or official, or account debtor to the assignment or transfer of, or the creation, attachment, perfection, or enforcement of a security interest in the account or chattel paper; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides that the assignment or transfer or the creation, attachment, perfection, or enforcement of the security interest may give rise to a default, breach, right of recoupment, claim, defense, termination, right of termination, or remedy under the account or chattel paper.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (8), an account debtor may not waive or vary its option under paragraph (2)(c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is subject to law other than this chapter which establishes a different rule for an account debtor who is an individual and who incurred the obligation primarily for personal, family, or household purposes. Subsections (4) and (6) do not apply to the creation, attachment, perfection, or enforcement of a security interest in:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim or right to receive compensation for injuries or sickness as described in 26 U.S.C. s. 104(a)(1) or (2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim or right to receive benefits under a special needs trust as described in 42 U.S.C. s. 1396p(d)(4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest of a debtor who is a natural person in reemployment assistance or unemployment, alimony, disability, pension, or retirement benefits or victim compensation funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest of a debtor who is a natural person in other benefits which are designated solely for his or her maintenance, support, or education, the assignability of which is expressly prohibited or restricted by statute.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (4), (6), and (8) apply only to a security interest created after January 1, 2002.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to an assignment of a health-care-insurance receivable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section prevails over any inconsistent statute, rule, or regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2001-198; s. 79, ch. 2012-30; s. 8, ch. 2012-59.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 30, ch. 2001-198, provides that “[n]othing contained in s. 679.4061, Florida Statutes, or s. 679.4081, Florida Statutes, as created by this act, shall supersede the provisions of SB 108 or HB 767, relating to structured settlements, if Senate Bill 108 or House Bill 767 becomes a law.” Senate Bill 108 became ch. 2001-207. House Bill 767 did not pass.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 8, ch. 2012-59, amended subsection (5), effective July 1, 2013, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) Subsection (4) does not apply to the sale of a payment intangible or promissory note, other than a sale pursuant to a disposition under s. 679.610 or an acceptance of collateral under s. 679.620.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>