<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.614" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contents and form of notification before disposition of collateral; consumer-goods transaction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a consumer-goods transaction, the following rules apply:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notification of disposition must provide the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information specified in s. 679.613(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any liability for a deficiency of the person to whom the notification is sent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telephone number from which the amount that must be paid to the secured party to redeem the collateral under s. 679.623 is available; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telephone number or mailing address from which additional information concerning the disposition and the obligation secured is available.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A particular phrasing of the notification is not required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following form of notification, when completed, provides sufficient information:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name and address of secured party)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Date)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">NOTICE OF OUR PLAN TO SELL PROPERTY</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name and address of any obligor who is also a debtor)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Subject:<Directions xml:space="preserve">(Identification of Transaction)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">We have your <Directions xml:space="preserve">(describe collateral)</Directions>, because you broke promises in our agreement.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">[For a public disposition:]</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">We will sell <Directions xml:space="preserve">(describe collateral)</Directions> at public sale. A sale could include a lease or license. The sale will be held as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Date:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Time:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Place:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">You may attend the sale and bring bidders if you want.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">[For a private disposition:]</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">We will sell <Directions xml:space="preserve">(describe collateral)</Directions> at private sale sometime after <Directions xml:space="preserve">(date)</Directions>. A sale could include a lease or license.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The money that we get from the sale (after paying our costs) will reduce the amount you owe. If we get less money than you owe, you <Directions xml:space="preserve">(will or will not, as applicable)</Directions> still owe us the difference. If we get more money than you owe, you will get the extra money, unless we must pay it to someone else.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">You can get the property back at any time before we sell it by paying us the full amount you owe (not just the past due payments), including our expenses. To learn the exact amount you must pay, call us at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(telephone number)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">If you want us to explain to you in writing how we have figured the amount that you owe us, you may call us at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(telephone number)</Directions> or write us at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(secured party’s address)</Directions> and request a written explanation. We will charge you $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for the explanation if we sent you another written explanation of the amount you owe us within the last 6 months.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">If you need more information about the sale, call us at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(telephone number)</Directions> or write us at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(secured party’s address)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">We are sending this notice to the following other people who have an interest in <Directions xml:space="preserve">(describe collateral)</Directions> or who owe money under your agreement:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Names of all other debtors and obligors, if any)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notification in the form of subsection (3) is sufficient, even if additional information appears at the end of the form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notification in the form of subsection (3) is sufficient, even if it includes errors in information not required by subsection (1), unless the error is misleading with respect to rights arising under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a notification under this section is not in the form of subsection (3), law other than this chapter determines the effect of including information not required by subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>