<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.628" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonliability and limitation on liability of secured party; liability of secondary obligor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a secured party knows that a person is a debtor or obligor, knows the identity of the person, and knows how to communicate with the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secured party is not liable to the person, or to a secured party or lienholder that has filed a financing statement against the person, for failure to comply with this chapter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secured party’s failure to comply with this chapter does not affect the liability of the person for a deficiency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party is not liable because of its status as a secured party:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a person who is a debtor or obligor, unless the secured party knows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person is a debtor or obligor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the person; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How to communicate with the person; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a secured party or lienholder that has filed a financing statement against a person, unless the secured party knows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person is a debtor; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the person.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party is not liable to any person, and a person’s liability for a deficiency is not affected, because of any act or omission arising out of the secured party’s reasonable belief that a transaction is not a consumer-goods transaction or a consumer transaction or that goods are not consumer goods, if the secured party’s belief is based on its reasonable reliance on:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A debtor’s representation concerning the purpose for which collateral was to be used, acquired, or held; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An obligor’s representation concerning the purpose for which a secured obligation was incurred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party is not liable to any person under s. 679.625(3)(b) for its failure to comply with s. 679.616.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secured party is not liable under s. 679.625(3)(b) more than once with respect to any one secured obligation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>