<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0679.3101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">When filing required to perfect security interest or agricultural lien; security interests and agricultural liens to which filing provisions do not apply.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) and s. 679.3121(2), a financing statement must be filed to perfect all security interests and agricultural liens.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a financing statement is not necessary to perfect a security interest:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is perfected under s. 679.3081(4), (5), (6), or (7);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is perfected under s. 679.3091 when it attaches;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In property subject to a statute, regulation, or treaty described in s. 679.3111(1);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In goods in possession of a bailee which is perfected under s. 679.3121(4)(a) or (b);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In certificated securities, documents, goods, or instruments which is perfected without filing, control, or possession under s. 679.3121(5), (6), or (7);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In collateral in the secured party’s possession under s. 679.3131;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a certificated security which is perfected by delivery of the security certificate to the secured party under s. 679.3131;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In deposit accounts, electronic chattel paper, electronic documents, investment property, or letter-of-credit rights which is perfected by control under s. 679.3141;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In proceeds which is perfected under s. 679.3151; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is perfected under s. 679.3161.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a secured party assigns a perfected security interest or agricultural lien, a filing under this chapter is not required to continue the perfected status of the security interest against creditors of and transferees from the original debtor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2001-198; s. 63, ch. 2010-131.</History>
</Section>