<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0679.3011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Law governing perfection and priority of security interests.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in ss. 679.1091, 679.3031, 679.3041, 679.3051, and 679.3061, the following rules determine the law governing perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in collateral:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, while a debtor is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in collateral.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While collateral is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a possessory security interest in that collateral.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (4) and (5), while tangible negotiable documents, goods, instruments, money, or tangible chattel paper is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perfection of a security interest in the goods by filing a fixture filing;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perfection of a security interest in timber to be cut; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of perfection or nonperfection and the priority of a nonpossessory security interest in the collateral.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local law of the jurisdiction in which the wellhead or minehead is located governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in as-extracted collateral.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law of this state governs:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The perfection of a security interest in goods that are or are to become fixtures in this state by the filing of a fixture filing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of perfection or nonperfection and the priority of a security interest in goods that are or are to become fixtures in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2001-198; s. 5, ch. 2002-242; s. 62, ch. 2010-131.</History>
</Section>