<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.706" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">When initial financing statement suffices to continue effectiveness of financing statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement in the office specified in s. 679.5011 continues the effectiveness of a financing statement filed before this act takes effect if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement in that office would be effective to perfect a security interest under this act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pre-effective date financing statement was filed in an office in another state or another office in this state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial financing statement satisfies subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of an initial financing statement under subsection (1) continues the effectiveness of the pre-effective date financing statement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the initial financing statement is filed before this act takes effect, for the period provided in s. 679.403, Florida Statutes 2000, with respect to a financing statement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the initial financing statement is filed after this act takes effect, for the period provided in s. 679.515 with respect to an initial financing statement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be effective for purposes of subsection (1), an initial financing statement must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfy the requirements of part V for an initial financing statement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the pre-effective date financing statement by indicating the office in which the financing statement was filed and providing the dates of filing and file numbers, if any, of the financing statement and of the most recent continuation statement filed with respect to the financing statement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indicate that the pre-effective date financing statement remains effective.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2001-198.</History></Section>