<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0679.5031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Name of debtor and secured party.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement sufficiently provides the name of the debtor:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the debtor is a registered organization, only if the financing statement provides the name of the debtor indicated on the public record of the debtor’s jurisdiction of organization which shows the debtor to have been organized;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the debtor is a decedent’s estate, only if the financing statement provides the name of the decedent and indicates that the debtor is an estate;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the debtor is a trust or a trustee acting with respect to property held in trust, only if the financing statement:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides the name, if any, specified for the trust in its organic documents or, if no name is specified, provides the name of the settlor and additional information sufficient to distinguish a debtor from other trusts having one or more of the same settlors; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indicates, in the debtor’s name or otherwise, that the debtor is a trust or is a trustee acting with respect to property held in trust; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In other cases:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the debtor has a name, only if it provides the individual or organizational name of the debtor; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the debtor does not have a name, only if it provides the names of the partners, members, associates, or other persons comprising the debtor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement that provides the name of the debtor in accordance with subsection (1) is not rendered ineffective by the absence of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trade name or other name of the debtor; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless required under subparagraph (1)(d)2., names of partners, members, associates, or other persons comprising the debtor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement that provides only the debtor’s trade name does not sufficiently provide the name of the debtor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to indicate the representative capacity of a secured party or representative of a secured party does not affect the sufficiency of a financing statement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement may provide the name of more than one debtor and the name of more than one secured party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2001-198; s. 11, ch. 2012-59.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 11, ch. 2012-59, amended subsections (1) and (2) and added subsections (6), (7), and (8), effective July 1, 2013, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) A financing statement sufficiently provides the name of the debtor:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (c), if the debtor is a registered organization or the collateral is held in a trust that is a registered organization, only if the financing statement provides the name that is stated to be the registered organization’s name on the public organic record most recently filed with or issued or enacted by the registered organization’s jurisdiction of organization that purports to state, amend, or restate the registered organization’s name;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Subject to subsection (6), if the collateral is being administered by the personal representative of a decedent, only if the financing statement provides, as the name of the debtor, the name of the decedent and, in a separate part of the financing statement, indicates that the collateral is being administered by a personal representative;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) If the collateral is held in a trust that is not a registered organization, only if the financing statement:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. Provides, as the name of the debtor:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. If the organic record of the trust specifies a name for the trust, the name so specified; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. If the organic record of the trust does not specify a name for the trust, the name of the settlor or testator; and</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. In a separate part of the financing statement:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. If the name is provided in accordance with sub-subparagraph 1.a., indicates that the collateral is held in a trust; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. If the name is provided in accordance with sub-subparagraph 1.b., provides additional information sufficient to distinguish the trust from other trusts having one or more of the same settlors or the same testator and indicates that the collateral is held in a trust, unless the additional information so indicates;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Subject to subsection (7), if the debtor is an individual to whom this state has issued a driver license that has not expired or to whom the agency of this state that issues driver licenses has issued, in lieu of a driver license, a personal identification card that has not expired, only if the financing statement provides the name of the individual that is indicated on the driver license or personal identification card;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) If the debtor is an individual to whom paragraph (d) does not apply, only if the financing statement provides the individual name of the debtor or the surname and first personal name of the debtor; and</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) In other cases:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. If the debtor has a name, only if it provides the organizational name of the debtor; and</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. If the debtor does not have a name, only if it provides the names of the partners, members, associates, or other persons comprising the debtor, in a manner that each name provided would be sufficient if the person named were the debtor.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) A financing statement that provides the name of the debtor in accordance with subsection (1) is not rendered ineffective by the absence of:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) A trade name or other name of the debtor; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Unless required under subparagraph (1)(f)2., names of partners, members, associates, or other persons comprising the debtor.</Text>
		<VerticalEllipsis/>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) The name of the decedent indicated on the order appointing the personal representative of the decedent issued by the court having jurisdiction over the collateral is sufficient as the name of the decedent under paragraph (1)(b).</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(7) If this state has issued to an individual more than one driver license or, if none, more than one identification card, of a kind described in paragraph (1)(d), the driver license or identification card, as applicable, that was issued most recently is the one to which paragraph (1)(d) refers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(8) As used in this section, the term “name of the settlor or testator” means:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) If the settlor is a registered organization, the name of the registered organization indicated on the public organic record filed with or issued or enacted by the registered organization’s jurisdiction of organization; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) In other cases, the name of the settlor or testator indicated in the trust’s organic record.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>