<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effectiveness of action taken before effective date.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If action, other than the filing of a financing statement, is taken before this act takes effect and the action would have resulted in priority of a security interest over the rights of a person who becomes a lien creditor had the security interest become enforceable before this act takes effect, the action is effective to perfect a security interest that attaches under this act within 1 year after this act takes effect. An attached security interest becomes unperfected 1 year after this act takes effect unless the security interest becomes a perfected security interest under this act before the expiration of that period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a financing statement before this act takes effect is effective to perfect a security interest to the extent the filing would satisfy the applicable requirements for perfection under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act does not render ineffective an effective financing statement that, before this act takes effect, is filed and satisfies the applicable requirements for perfection under the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in s. 679.103, Florida Statutes 2000. However, except as otherwise provided in subsections (4) and (5) and s. 679.706, the financing statement ceases to be effective at the earlier of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time the financing statement would have ceased to be effective under the law of the jurisdiction in which it is filed; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">December 31, 2006.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a continuation statement after this act takes effect does not continue the effectiveness of the financing statement filed before this act takes effect. However, upon the timely filing of a continuation statement after this act takes effect and in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in part III, the effectiveness of a financing statement filed in the same office in that jurisdiction before this act takes effect continues for the period provided by the law of that jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (3)(b) applies to a financing statement that, before this act takes effect, is filed against a transmitting utility and satisfies the applicable requirements for perfection under the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in s. 679.103, Florida Statutes 2000, only to the extent that part III provides that the law of a jurisdiction other than the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed governs perfection of a security interest in collateral covered by the financing statement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement that includes a financing statement filed before this act takes effect and a continuation statement filed after this act takes effect is effective only to the extent that it satisfies the requirements of part V for an initial financing statement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2001-198; s. 1, ch. 2006-187; s. 70, ch. 2006-213.</History></Section>