<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0679.1091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3) and (4), this chapter applies to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction, regardless of its form, that creates a security interest in personal property or fixtures by contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agricultural lien;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A consignment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest arising under s. 672.401, s. 672.502, s. 672.711, or s. 680.508(5), as provided in s. 679.1101; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A security interest arising under s. 674.2101 or s. 675.118.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of this chapter to a security interest in a secured obligation is not affected by the fact that the obligation is itself secured by a transaction or interest to which this chapter does not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not apply to the extent that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statute, regulation, or treaty of the United States preempts this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights of a transferee beneficiary or nominated person under a letter of credit are independent and superior under s. 675.114.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A landlord’s lien, other than an agricultural lien;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lien, other than an agricultural lien, given by statute or other rule of law for services or materials, but s. 679.333 applies with respect to priority of the lien;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a claim for wages, salary, or other compensation of an employee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes as part of a sale of the business out of which they arose;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes which is for the purpose of collection only;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a right to payment under a contract to an assignee that is also obligated to perform under the contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a single account, payment intangible, or promissory note to an assignee in full or partial satisfaction of a preexisting indebtedness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transfer of an interest in or an assignment of a claim under a policy of insurance, other than an assignment by or to a health-care provider of a health-care-insurance receivable and any subsequent assignment of the right to payment, but ss. 679.3151 and 679.322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a right represented by a judgment, other than a judgment taken on a right to payment that was collateral;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A right of recoupment or set-off, but:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.340 applies with respect to the effectiveness of rights of recoupment or set-off against deposit accounts; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 679.4041 applies with respect to defenses or claims of an account debtor;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The creation or transfer of an interest in or lien on real property, including a lease or rents thereunder, except to the extent that provision is made for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Liens on real property in ss. 679.2031 and 679.3081;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fixtures in s. 679.334;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fixture filings in ss. 679.5011, 679.5021, 679.512, 679.516, and 679.519; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security agreements covering personal and real property in s. 679.604;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a claim arising in tort, other than a commercial tort claim, but ss. 679.3151 and 679.322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assignment of a deposit account, other than a nonnegotiable certificate of deposit, in a consumer transaction, but ss. 679.3151 and 679.322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer by a government or governmental unit; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transfer or pledge of, or creation of a security interest in, any interest or right or portion of any interest or right in any storm-recovery property as defined in s. 366.8260.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-198; s. 2, ch. 2005-107.</History></Section>