<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0422.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation in undertaking housing projects.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of aiding and cooperating in the planning, undertaking, construction or operation of housing projects located within the area in which it is authorized to act, any state public body may upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it may determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dedicate, sell, convey or lease any of its property to a housing authority or the Federal Government;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause parks, playgrounds, recreational, community, educational, water, sewer or drainage facilities or any other works, which it is otherwise empowered to undertake, to be furnished adjacent to or in connection with housing projects;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish, dedicate, close, pave, install, grade, regrade, plan or replan streets, roads, roadways, alleys, sidewalks or other places which it is otherwise empowered to undertake;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan or replan, zone or rezone any part of such state public body; make exceptions from building regulations and ordinances; any city or town also may change its map;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements, which may extend over any period, notwithstanding any provision or rule of law to the contrary, with a housing authority or the Federal Government respecting action to be taken by such state public body pursuant to any of the powers granted by this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do any and all things, necessary or convenient to aid and cooperate in the planning, undertaking, construction or operation of such housing projects;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase or legally invest in any of the debentures of a housing authority and exercise all of the rights of any holder of such debentures;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any housing project which a housing authority has acquired or taken over from the Federal Government and which the housing authority by resolution has found and declared to have been constructed in a manner that will promote the public interest and afford necessary safety, sanitation and other protection, no state public body shall require any changes to be made in the housing project or the manner of its construction or take any other action relating to such construction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with any public improvements made by a state public body in exercising the powers herein granted, such state public body may incur the entire expense thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law or statute to the contrary notwithstanding, any sale, conveyance, lease or agreement provided for in this section may be made by a state public body without appraisal, public notice, advertisement or public bidding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 17982, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-rr).</History></Section>