<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0673.4051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employer’s responsibility for fraudulent indorsement by employee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” includes an independent contractor retained by the employer and also includes an employee of an independent contractor retained by the employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fraudulent indorsement” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an instrument payable to the employer, a forged indorsement purporting to be that of the employer; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an instrument with respect to which the employer is the issuer, a forged indorsement purporting to be that of the person identified as payee.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Responsibility,” with respect to instruments, means authority:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sign or indorse instruments on behalf of the employer;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To process instruments received by the employer for bookkeeping purposes, for deposit to an account, or for other disposition;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare or process instruments for issue in the name of the employer;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To supply information determining the names or addresses of payees of instruments to be issued in the name of the employer;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To control the disposition of instruments to be issued in the name of the employer; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act otherwise with respect to instruments in a responsible capacity.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term “responsibility” does not include authority that merely allows an employee to have access to instruments or blank or incomplete instrument forms that are being stored or transported or are part of incoming or outgoing mail, or similar access.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of determining the rights and liabilities of a person who, in good faith, pays an instrument or takes it for value or for collection, if an employer entrusted an employee with responsibility with respect to the instrument and the employee or a person acting in concert with the employee makes a fraudulent indorsement of the instrument, the indorsement is effective as the indorsement of the person to whom the instrument is payable if it is made in the name of that person. If the person paying the instrument or taking it for value or for collection fails to exercise ordinary care in paying or taking the instrument and that failure substantially contributes to loss resulting from the fraud, the person bearing the loss may recover from the person failing to exercise ordinary care to the extent the failure to exercise ordinary care contributed to the loss.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under subsection (2), an indorsement is made in the name of the person to whom an instrument is payable if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is made in a name substantially similar to the name of that person; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The instrument, whether or not indorsed, is deposited in a depositary bank to an account in a name substantially similar to the name of that person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 92-82.</History></Section>