<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0673.4111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Refusal to pay cashier’s checks, teller’s checks, and certified checks.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this section, the term “obligated bank” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acceptor of a certified check; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuer of a cashier’s check or teller’s check bought from the issuer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligated bank wrongfully refuses to pay a cashier’s check or certified check, wrongfully stops payment of a teller’s check, or wrongfully refuses to pay a dishonored teller’s check, the person asserting the right to enforce the check is entitled to compensation for expenses and loss of interest resulting from the nonpayment and may recover consequential damages if the obligated bank refuses to pay after receiving notice of particular circumstances giving rise to the damages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses or consequential damages under subsection (2) are not recoverable if the refusal of the obligated bank to pay occurs because:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bank suspends payments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligated bank asserts a claim or defense of the bank that it has reasonable grounds to believe is available against the person entitled to enforce the instrument;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligated bank has a reasonable doubt whether the person demanding payment is the person entitled to enforce the instrument; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment is prohibited by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 92-82.</History></Section>