<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Invalid claims, recovery of property, interest and penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall receive unclaimed property that the person is not entitled to receive. Any person who receives, or assists another person to receive, unclaimed property that the person is not entitled to receive is strictly, jointly, personally, and severally liable for the unclaimed property and shall immediately return the property, or the reasonable value of the property if the property has been damaged or disposed of, to the department plus interest at the rate set in accordance with s. 55.03(1). Assisting another person to receive unclaimed property includes executing a claim form on the person’s behalf.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of stocks or bonds which have been sold, the proceeds from the sale shall be returned to the department plus any dividends or interest received thereon plus an amount equal to the brokerage fee plus interest at a rate set in accordance with s. 55.03(1) on the proceeds from the sale of the stocks or bonds, the dividends or interest received, and the brokerage fee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of stocks or bonds which have not been sold, the stocks or bonds and any dividends or interest received thereon shall be returned to the department, together with interest on the dividends or interest received, at a rate set in accordance with s. 55.03(1) of the value of the property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may maintain a civil or administrative action:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To recover unclaimed property that was paid or remitted to a person who was not entitled to the unclaimed property or to offset amounts owed to the department against amounts owed to an owner representative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against a person who assists another person in receiving, or attempting to receive, unclaimed property that the person is not entitled to receive; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against a person who attempts to receive unclaimed property that the person is not entitled to receive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department prevails in any proceeding under subsection (2), a fine not to exceed three times the value of the property received or sought to be received may be imposed on any person who knowingly, or with reckless disregard or deliberate ignorance of the truth, violated this section. If the department prevails in a civil or administrative proceeding under subsection (2), the person who violated subsection (1) shall be ordered to pay the department reasonable costs and attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall knowingly file, knowingly conspire to file, or knowingly assist in filing, a claim for unclaimed property the person is not entitled to receive. Any person who violates this subsection regarding unclaimed property of an aggregate value:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Greater than $50,000, is guilty of a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Greater than $10,000 up to $50,000, is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Greater than $250 up to $10,000, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Greater than $50 up to $250, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to $50, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 138, ch. 2004-390; s. 2, ch. 2011-169.</History></Section>