<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.132" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement; cease and desist orders; fines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce or administer any provision of this chapter, any rule or order promulgated under this chapter, or any written agreement entered into with the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other powers conferred upon it to enforce and administer the provisions of this chapter, the department may issue and serve upon a person an order to cease and desist and to take corrective action whenever the department finds that such person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter, any rule or order promulgated under this chapter, or any written agreement entered into with the department. For purposes of this subsection, the term “corrective action” includes refunding excessive charges, requiring a person to return unclaimed property, requiring a holder to remit unclaimed property, and requiring a holder to correct a report that contains errors or omissions. Any such order shall contain a notice of rights provided by ss. 120.569 and 120.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other powers conferred upon it to enforce and administer the provisions of this chapter, the department or a court of competent jurisdiction may impose fines against any person found to have violated any provision of this chapter, any rule or order promulgated under this chapter, or any written agreement entered into with the department in an amount not to exceed $2,000 for each violation. All fines collected under this subsection shall be deposited as received in the Unclaimed Property Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 87-105; s. 4, ch. 93-280; s. 20, ch. 96-301; s. 298, ch. 96-410; s. 29, ch. 2001-36; s. 133, ch. 2004-390; s. 17, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>