<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1351" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Acquisition of unclaimed property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person desiring to acquire ownership of or entitlement to property reported to the department under s. 717.117 must be an attorney licensed to practice law in this state, a licensed Florida-certified public accountant, a private investigator licensed under chapter 493, or an employer of a licensed private investigator which employer possesses a Class “A” license under chapter 493 and must be registered with the department under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All contracts to acquire ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property from the person or persons entitled to the unclaimed property must be in 10-point type or greater and must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a purchase price that discounts the value of the unclaimed property at the time the agreement is executed by the seller at no greater than 20 percent per account held by the department. An unclaimed property account must not be discounted in excess of $1,000. However, the $1,000 discount limitation does not apply if probate proceedings must be initiated on behalf of the seller for an estate that has never been probated or if the seller of the unclaimed property is not a natural person or is a person outside the United States; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fully disclose that the property is held by the Bureau of Unclaimed Property of the Department of Financial Services pursuant to this chapter, the mailing address of the bureau, the Internet address of the bureau, the person or name of the entity that held the property prior to the property becoming unclaimed, the date of the holder’s last contact with the owner, if known, and the approximate value of the property, and identify which of the following categories of unclaimed property the buyer is seeking to purchase as reported by the holder:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash accounts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stale dated checks.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life insurance or annuity contract assets.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Utility deposits.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securities or other interests in business associations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wages.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounts receivable.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contents of safe-deposit boxes.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The purchase agreement described in this paragraph must state in 12-point type or greater in the order indicated with the blank spaces accurately completed:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">FULL DISCLOSURE STATEMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The property is currently held by the State of Florida Department of Financial Services, Bureau of Unclaimed Property, pursuant to chapter 717, Florida Statutes. The mailing address of the Bureau of Unclaimed Property is <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. The Internet address of the Bureau of Unclaimed Property is <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The property was remitted by: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">Date of last contact: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">Property category: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Immediately above the signature line for the seller, the purchase agreement described in this paragraph must state in 12-point type or greater:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">Seller agrees, by signing below, that the FULL DISCLOSURE STATEMENT has been read and fully understood.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The originals of all such disclosures and agreements to transfer ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property shall be signed and dated by the seller and shall be filed with the claim form. The claimant shall provide the department with a legible copy of a valid driver’s license of the seller at the time the original claim form is filed. If a seller has not been issued a valid driver’s license at the time the original claim form is filed, the department shall be provided with a legible copy of a photographic identification of the seller issued by the United States or a foreign nation, a state or territory of the United States or a foreign nation, or a political subdivision or agency thereof. In lieu of photographic identification, a notarized sworn statement by the seller may be provided which affirms the seller’s identity and states the seller’s full name and address. The seller must produce to the notary his or her photographic identification issued by the United States, a state or territory of the United States, a foreign nation, or a political subdivision or agency thereof or other evidence deemed acceptable by department rule. The notary shall indicate the notary’s full address on the notarized sworn statement. If a claim is filed without the required identification or the sworn statement with the original claim form and the original agreement to acquire ownership of or entitlement to the unclaimed property, the claim is void.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contract to acquire ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property from the person or persons entitled to the unclaimed property must provide for the purchase price to be remitted to the seller or sellers within 10 days after the execution of the contract by the seller or sellers. The contract must specify the unclaimed property account number, the name of the holder who reported the property to the department, the category of unclaimed property, the value of the unclaimed property account, and the number of shares of stock, if applicable. Proof of payment by check must be filed with the department with the claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All agreements to purchase unclaimed property from an owner must use the following form on 8 and <Fraction>1/2</Fraction>-inch by 11-inch paper or on 8 and <Fraction>1/2</Fraction>-inch by 14-inch paper with all of the text on one side of the paper and with the other side of the paper left blank. The agreement must be accurately completed and executed. The title of the agreement shall be in bold 14-point type or greater and underlined. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the rest of the agreement shall be in 10-point type or greater. All unclaimed property accounts to be purchased must be identified on the agreement by account number. The agreement must state, in bold 12-point type or greater at the top of the agreement in the order indicated:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">PURCHASE AGREEMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">$<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> = Approximate Dollar Value of the Property</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> = Number of Shares of Stock (If Applicable)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> = Percent of Property to be Paid to the Buyer</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">$<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> = Amount to be Paid to Buyer</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">$<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> = Net Amount to be Paid to Seller</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceBelow="true">Property Account Number(s): <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All agreements shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and professional license number of the registrant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of the registrant’s firm or employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of the seller.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxpayer identification number or social security number of the seller, if available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address to whom the warrant is to be issued if it is different from the seller’s name and address.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original signature of the registrant and the date signed by the registrant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of bolding, italics, print of different colors, or text borders as a means of highlighting or stressing certain selected items within the text.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the name, address, and telephone number of the registrant’s firm or company in the top margin above the words “PURCHASE AGREEMENT.” No additional writing of any kind may be placed in the top margin, including, but not limited to, logos, license numbers, Internet addresses, or slogans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deletion of the words “Number of Shares of Stock (If Applicable)” if the agreement does not relate to the recovery of securities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deletion of the words “Percent of Property to be Paid to Buyer,” if the purchase agreement provides for a flat fee to be paid as compensation to the buyer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not supersede the licensing requirements of chapter 493.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 140, ch. 2004-390; s. 23, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>