<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lost owners of unclaimed demutualization, rehabilitation, or related reorganization proceeds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property distributable in the course of a demutualization, rehabilitation, or related reorganization of an insurance company is deemed abandoned 2 years after the date the property is first distributable if, at the time of the first distribution, the last known address of the owner on the books and records of the holder is known to be incorrect or the distribution or statements are returned by the post office as undeliverable; and the owner has not communicated in writing with the holder or its agent regarding the interest or otherwise communicated with the holder regarding the interest as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file with the holder or its agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property distributable in the course of demutualization, rehabilitation, or related reorganization of a mutual insurance company that is not subject to subsection (1) shall be reportable as otherwise provided by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property subject to this section shall be reported and delivered no later than May 1 as of the preceding December 31; however, the initial report under this section shall be filed no later than November 1, 2003, as of December 31, 2002.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2003-21; s. 75, ch. 2003-281.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As enacted by s. 75, ch. 2003-281. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Section 717.1071 was also enacted by s. 2, ch. 2003-21, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">717.1071 Unclaimed demutualization proceeds.</Font>—Unclaimed property payable or distributable in the course of a demutualization of an insurance company is presumed unclaimed 5 years after the earlier of the date of last contact with the policyholder or the date the property became payable or distributable.</Text></Note></Section>