<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.117" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Report of unclaimed property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person holding funds or other property, tangible or intangible, presumed unclaimed and subject to custody as unclaimed property under this chapter shall report to the department on such forms as the department may prescribe by rule. In lieu of forms, a report identifying 25 or more different apparent owners must be submitted by the holder via electronic medium as the department may prescribe by rule. The report must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for traveler’s checks and money orders, the name, social security number or taxpayer identification number, and date of birth, if known, and last known address, if any, of each person appearing from the records of the holder to be the owner of any property which is presumed unclaimed and which has a value of $50 or more.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For unclaimed funds which have a value of $50 or more held or owing under any life or endowment insurance policy or annuity contract, the full name, taxpayer identification number or social security number, date of birth, if known, and last known address of the insured or annuitant and of the beneficiary according to records of the insurance company holding or owing the funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all tangible property held in a safe-deposit box or other safekeeping repository, a description of the property and the place where the property is held and may be inspected by the department, and any amounts owing to the holder. Contents of a safe-deposit box or other safekeeping repository which consist of documents or writings of a private nature and which have little or no apparent value shall not be presumed unclaimed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and identifying number, if any, or description of the property and the amount appearing from the records to be due. Items of value under $50 each may be reported in the aggregate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the property became payable, demandable, or returnable, and the date of the last transaction with the apparent owner with respect to the property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or business association or public corporation holding funds presumed unclaimed and having a total value of $10 or less may file a zero balance report for that reporting period. The balance brought forward to the new reporting period is zero.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as the department may prescribe by rule as necessary for the administration of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit balances, customer overpayments, security deposits, and refunds having a value of less than $10 shall not be presumed unclaimed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the holder of property presumed unclaimed and subject to custody as unclaimed property is a successor holder or if the holder has changed the holder’s name while in possession of the property, the holder shall file with the holder’s report all known names and addresses of each prior holder of the property. Compliance with this subsection means the holder exercises reasonable and prudent efforts to determine the names of all prior holders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must be filed before May 1 of each year. The report shall apply to the preceding calendar year. The department may impose and collect a penalty of $10 per day up to a maximum of $500 for the failure to timely report or the failure to include in a report information required by this chapter. The penalty shall be remitted to the department within 30 days after the date of the notification to the holder that the penalty is due and owing. As necessary for proper administration of this chapter, the department may waive any penalty due with appropriate justification. On written request by any person required to file a report and upon a showing of good cause, the department may postpone the reporting date. The department must provide information contained in a report filed with the department to any person requesting a copy of the report or information contained in a report, to the extent the information requested is not confidential, within 45 days after the report has been processed and added to the unclaimed property database subsequent to a determination that the report is accurate and that the reported property is the same as the remitted property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holders of inactive accounts having a value of $50 or more shall use due diligence to locate apparent owners. Not more than 120 days and not less than 60 days prior to filing the report required by this section, the holder in possession of property presumed unclaimed and subject to custody as unclaimed property under this chapter shall send written notice to the apparent owner at the apparent owner’s last known address informing the apparent owner that the holder is in possession of property subject to this chapter, if the holder has in its records an address for the apparent owner which the holder’s records do not disclose to be inaccurate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder of intangible property may file with the department a petition for determination that the property is unclaimed requesting the department to accept custody of the property. The petition shall state any special circumstances that exist, contain the information required by subsection (2), and show that a diligent search has been made to locate the owner. If the department finds that the proof of diligent search is satisfactory, it shall give notice as provided in s. 717.118 and accept custody of the property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon written request by any entity or person required to file a report, stating such entity’s or person’s justification for such action, the department may place that entity or person in an inactive status as an unclaimed property “holder.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to the unclaimed patronage refunds as provided for by contract or through bylaw provisions of entities organized under chapter 425.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to intangible property held, issued, or owing by a business association subject to the jurisdiction of the United States Surface Transportation Board or its successor federal agency if the apparent owner of such intangible property is a business association. The holder of such property does not have any obligation to report, to pay, or to deliver such property to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to credit balances, overpayments, refunds, or outstanding checks owed by a health care provider to a managed care payor with whom the health care provider has a managed care contract, provided that the credit balances, overpayments, refunds, or outstanding checks become due and owing pursuant to the managed care contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “property identifier” means the descriptor used by the holder to identify the unclaimed property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social security numbers and property identifiers contained in reports required under this section, held by the department, are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies to social security numbers and property identifiers held by the department before, on, or after the effective date of this exemption.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15, and shall stand repealed October 2, 2017, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 87-105; s. 1, ch. 92-169; s. 30, ch. 92-319; s. 1, ch. 93-280; s. 9, ch. 96-301; s. 1771, ch. 97-102; s. 17, ch. 2001-36; s. 1, ch. 2002-64; s. 1888, ch. 2003-261; s. 115, ch. 2004-390; s. 4, ch. 2005-163; s. 1, ch. 2007-69; s. 1, ch. 2012-227.</History></Section>