<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Custody by state; holder relieved from liability; reimbursement of holder paying claim; reclaiming for owner; defense of holder; payment of safe-deposit box or repository charges.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the payment or delivery of property to the department, the state assumes custody and responsibility for the safekeeping of property. Any person who pays or delivers property to the department in good faith is relieved of all liability to the extent of the value of the property paid or delivered for any claim then existing or which thereafter may arise or be made in respect to the property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder who has paid money to the department pursuant to this chapter may make payment to any person appearing to be entitled to payment and, upon filing proof that the payee is entitled thereto, the department shall forthwith repay the holder without deduction of any fee or other charges. If repayment is sought for a payment made on a negotiable instrument, including a traveler’s check or money order, the holder must be repaid under this subsection upon filing proof that the instrument was duly presented and that the payee is entitled to payment. The holder shall be repaid for payment made under this subsection even if the payment was made to a person whose claim was barred under s. 717.129(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder who has delivered property, including a certificate of any interest in a business association, other than money to the department pursuant to this chapter may reclaim the property if still in the possession of the department, without payment of any fee or other charges, upon filing proof that the owner has claimed the property from the holder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may accept an affidavit of the holder stating the facts that entitle the holder to recover money and property under this section as sufficient proof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the holder pays or delivers property to the department in good faith and thereafter any other person claims the property from the holder paying or delivering, or another state claims the money or property under that state’s laws relating to escheat or abandoned or unclaimed property, the department, upon written notice of the claim, shall defend the holder against the claim and indemnify the holder against any liability on the claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “good faith” means that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment or delivery was made in a reasonable attempt to comply with this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person delivering the property was not a fiduciary then in breach of trust in respect to the property and had a reasonable basis for believing, based on the facts then known to that person, that the property was unclaimed for the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no showing that the records pursuant to which the delivery was made did not meet reasonable commercial standards of practice in the industry.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property removed from a safe-deposit box or other safekeeping repository is received by the department subject to the holder’s right under this subsection to be reimbursed for the actual cost of the opening and to any valid lien or contract providing for the holder to be reimbursed for unpaid rent or storage charges. The department shall make the reimbursement to the holder out of the proceeds remaining after the deduction of the department’s selling cost.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 87-105; s. 20, ch. 2001-36; s. 118, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>