<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General rules for taking custody of intangible unclaimed property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in this chapter or by other statute of this state, intangible property is subject to the custody of the department as unclaimed property if the conditions leading to a presumption that the property is unclaimed as described in ss. 717.102 and 717.105-717.116 are satisfied and:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address, as shown on the records of the holder, of the apparent owner is in this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records of the holder do not reflect the identity of the person entitled to the property, and it is established that the last known address of the person entitled to the property is in this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records of the holder do not reflect the last known address of the apparent owner, and it is established that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address of the person entitled to the property is in this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder is a domiciliary or a government or governmental subdivision or agency of this state and has not previously paid the property to the state of the last known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property;</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address, as shown on the records of the holder, of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property is in a state that does not provide by law for the escheat or custodial taking of the property, or its escheat or unclaimed property law is not applicable to the property, and the holder is a domiciliary or a government or governmental subdivision or agency of this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address, as shown on the records of the holder, of the apparent owner is in a foreign nation and the holder is a domiciliary or a government or governmental subdivision or agency of this state; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction out of which the property arose occurred in this state, and;</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property is unknown; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property is in a state that does not provide by law for the escheat or custodial taking of the property, or its escheat or unclaimed property law is not applicable to the property; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder is a domiciliary of a state that does not provide by law for the escheat or custodial taking of the property, or its escheat or unclaimed property law is not applicable to the property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 87-105; s. 3, ch. 2001-36.</History></Section>