<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bank deposits and funds in financial organizations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any demand, savings, or matured time deposit with a banking or financial organization, including deposits that are automatically renewable, and any funds paid toward the purchase of shares, a mutual investment certificate, or any other interest in a banking or financial organization is presumed unclaimed unless the owner has, within 5 years:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increased or decreased the amount of the deposit or presented the passbook or other similar evidence of the deposit for the crediting of interest;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communicated in writing or by documented telephone contact with the banking or financial organization concerning the property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise indicated an interest in the property as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file with the banking or financial organization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owned other property to which paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c) is applicable and if the banking or financial organization communicates in writing with the owner with regard to the property that would otherwise be presumed unclaimed under this subsection at the address to which communications regarding the other property regularly are sent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Had another relationship with the banking or financial organization concerning which the owner has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file with the banking or financial organization and if the banking or financial organization communicates in writing with the owner with regard to the property that would otherwise be unclaimed under this subsection at the address to which communications regarding the other relationship regularly are sent.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purpose of paragraph (1)(a), property includes any interest or dividends thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No holder may impose with respect to property described in subsection (1) any charges due to dormancy or inactivity or cease payment of interest unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is an enforceable written contract between the holder and the owner of the property pursuant to which the holder may impose those charges or cease payment of interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For property in excess of $2, the holder, no more than 3 months prior to the initial imposition of those charges or cessation of interest, has given written notice to the owner of the amount of those charges at the last known address of the owner stating that those charges shall be imposed or that interest shall cease, but the notice provided in this section need not be given with respect to charges imposed or interest ceased before July 1, 1987.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder regularly imposes those charges or ceases payment of interest and does not regularly reverse or otherwise cancel those charges or retroactively credit interest with respect to such property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any property described in subsection (1) that is automatically renewable is matured for purposes of subsection (1) upon the expiration of its initial time period except that, in the case of any renewal to which the owner consents at or about the time of renewal by communicating in writing with the banking or financial organization or otherwise indicating consent as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file prepared by an employee of the organization, the property is matured upon the expiration of the last time period for which consent was given. If, at the time provided for delivery in s. 717.119, a penalty or forfeiture in the payment of interest would result from the delivery of the property, the time for delivery is extended until the time when no penalty or forfeiture would result.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the documents establishing a deposit described in subsection (1) state the address of a beneficiary of the deposit, and the account has a value of at least $50, notice shall be given to the beneficiary as provided for notice to the apparent owner under s. 717.117(4). This subsection shall apply to accounts opened on or after October 1, 1990.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 87-105; s. 2, ch. 90-113; s. 63, ch. 91-110; s. 3, ch. 96-301; s. 7, ch. 2001-36; s. 111, ch. 2004-390; s. 2, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>