<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.12404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Claims on behalf of a business entity or trust.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims on behalf of an active or dissolved corporation, for which the last annual report is not available from the Department of State through the Internet, must be accompanied by a microfiche copy of the records on file with the Department of State or, if the corporation has not made a corporate filing with the Department of State, the claim must be accompanied by a uniform resource locator for the address of a free Internet site operated by the state of incorporation of the corporation that provides access to the last corporate filing identifying the officers and directors of the corporation. If available, the claim must be accompanied by a printout of the officers and directors from the Department of State Internet site or the free Internet site operated by the state of incorporation of the corporation. If the free Internet site is not available, the claim must be accompanied by an authenticated copy of the last corporate filing identifying the officers and directors from the appropriate authorized official of the state of incorporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim on behalf of a corporation must be made by an officer or director identified on the last corporate filing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims on behalf of a dissolved corporation, a business entity other than an active corporation, or a trust must include a legible copy of a valid driver’s license of the person acting on behalf of the dissolved corporation, business entity other than an active corporation, or trust. If the person has not been issued a valid driver’s license, the department shall be provided with a legible copy of a photographic identification of the person issued by the United States, a foreign nation, or a political subdivision or agency thereof. In lieu of photographic identification, a notarized sworn statement by the person may be provided which affirms the person’s identity and states the person’s full name and address. The person must produce his or her photographic identification issued by the United States, a state or territory of the United States, a foreign nation, or a political subdivision or agency thereof or other evidence deemed acceptable by the department by rule. The notary shall indicate the notary’s full address on the notarized sworn statement. Any claim filed without the required identification or the sworn statement with the original claim form and the original power of attorney, if applicable, is void.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 123, ch. 2004-390; s. 9, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>