<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1400" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to file claims as a claimant’s representative, acquire ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property, receive a distribution of fees and costs from the department, and obtain unclaimed property dollar amounts, numbers of reported shares of stock, and social security numbers held by the department, a private investigator holding a Class “C” individual license under chapter 493 must register with the department on such form as the department shall prescribe by rule, and must be verified by the applicant. To register with the department, a private investigator must provide:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legible copy of the applicant’s Class “A” business license under chapter 493 or that of the applicant’s firm or employer which holds a Class “A” business license under chapter 493.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legible copy of the applicant’s Class “C” individual license issued under chapter 493.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business address and telephone number of the applicant’s private investigative firm or employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of agents or employees, if any, who are designated to act on behalf of the private investigator, together with a legible copy of their photo identification issued by an agency of the United States, or a state, or a political subdivision thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to enable the department to disburse funds by electronic funds transfer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax identification number of the private investigator’s firm or employer which holds a Class “A” business license under chapter 493.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to file claims as a claimant’s representative, acquire ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property, receive a distribution of fees and costs from the department, and obtain unclaimed property dollar amounts, numbers of reported shares of stock, and social security numbers held by the department, a Florida-certified public accountant must register with the department on such form as the department shall prescribe by rule, and must be verified by the applicant. To register with the department a Florida-certified public accountant must provide:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s Florida Board of Accountancy number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legible copy of the applicant’s current driver’s license showing the full name and current address of such person. If a current driver’s license is not available, another form of identification showing the full name and current address of such person or persons shall be filed with the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business address and telephone number of the applicant’s public accounting firm or employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of agents or employees, if any, who are designated to act on behalf of the Florida-certified public accountant, together with a legible copy of their photo identification issued by an agency of the United States, or a state, or a political subdivision thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to enable the department to disburse funds by electronic funds transfer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax identification number of the accountant’s public accounting firm employer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to file claims as a claimant’s representative, acquire ownership of or entitlement to unclaimed property, receive a distribution of fees and costs from the department, and obtain unclaimed property dollar amounts, numbers of reported shares of stock, and social security numbers held by the department, an attorney licensed to practice in this state must register with the department on such form as the department shall prescribe by rule, and must be verified by the applicant. To register with the department, such attorney must provide:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s Florida Bar number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legible copy of the applicant’s current driver’s license showing the full name and current address of such person. If a current driver’s license is not available, another form of identification showing the full name and current address of such person or persons shall be filed with the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business address and telephone number of the applicant’s firm or employer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of agents or employees, if any, who are designated to act on behalf of the attorney, together with a legible copy of their photo identification issued by an agency of the United States, or a state, or a political subdivision thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to enable the department to disburse funds by electronic funds transfer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax identification number of the attorney’s firm or employer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information and documents already on file with the department prior to the effective date of this provision need not be resubmitted in order to complete the registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a material change in the status of a registration occurs, a registrant must, within 30 days, provide the department with the updated documentation and information in writing. Material changes include, but are not limited to: a designated agent or employee ceasing to act on behalf of the designating person, a surrender, suspension, or revocation of a license, or a license renewal.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a designated agent or employee ceases to act on behalf of the person who has designated the agent or employee to act on such person’s behalf, the designating person must, within 30 days, inform the Bureau of Unclaimed Property in writing of the termination of agency or employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a registrant surrenders the registrant’s license or the license is suspended or revoked, the registrant must, within 30 days, inform the bureau in writing of the surrender, suspension, or revocation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a private investigator’s Class “C” individual license under chapter 493 or a private investigator’s employer’s Class “A” business license under chapter 493 is renewed, the private investigator must provide a copy of the renewed license to the department within 30 days after the receipt of the renewed license by the private investigator or the private investigator’s employer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registrant’s firm or employer may not have a name that might lead another person to conclude that the registrant’s firm or employer is affiliated or associated with the United States, or an agency thereof, or a state or an agency or political subdivision of a state. The department shall deny an application for registration or revoke a registration if the applicant’s or registrant’s firm or employer has a name that might lead another person to conclude that the firm or employer is affiliated or associated with the United States, or an agency thereof, or a state or an agency or political subdivision of a state. Names that might lead another person to conclude that the firm or employer is affiliated or associated with the United States, or an agency thereof, or a state or an agency or political subdivision of a state, include, but are not limited to, the words United States, Florida, state, bureau, division, department, or government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing and other requirements of this section must be maintained as a condition of registration with the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 141, ch. 2004-390; s. 133, ch. 2005-2; s. 25, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>