<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.1101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unclaimed equity and debt of business associations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stock or other equity interest in a business association is presumed unclaimed 3 years after the earliest of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the most recent dividend, stock split, or other distribution unclaimed by the apparent owner;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of a statement of account or other notification or communication that was returned as undeliverable; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the holder discontinued mailings, notifications, or communications to the apparent owner.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unmatured or unredeemed debt, other than a bearer bond or an original issue discount bond, is presumed unclaimed 3 years after the date of the most recent interest payment unclaimed by the owner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Matured or redeemed debt is presumed unclaimed 3 years after the date of maturity or redemption.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time property is presumed unclaimed under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), any other property right accrued or accruing to the owner as a result of the property interest and not previously presumed unclaimed is also presumed unclaimed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The running of such 3-year period ceases if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communicates in writing with the association or its agent regarding the interest or a dividend, distribution, or other sum payable as a result of the interest; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise communicates with the association regarding the interest or a dividend, distribution, or other sum payable as a result of the interest, as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file with the association or its agent.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presents an instrument issued to pay interest or a dividend or other cash distribution. If any future dividend, distribution, or other sum payable to the owner as a result of the interest is subsequently not claimed by the owner, a new period in which the property is presumed unclaimed commences and relates back only to the time a subsequent dividend, distribution, or other sum became due and payable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the same time any interest is presumed unclaimed under this section, any dividend, distribution, or other sum then held for or owing to the owner as a result of the interest, is presumed unclaimed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dividend, profit, distribution, interest redemption, payment on principal, or other sum held or owing by a business association for or to a shareholder, certificateholder, member, bondholder, or other security holder, who has not claimed such amount or corresponded in writing with the business association concerning such amount, within 3 years after the date prescribed for payment or delivery, is presumed unclaimed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 87-105; s. 5, ch. 96-301; s. 11, ch. 2001-36; s. 3, ch. 2003-21; s. 3, ch. 2005-163.</History></Section>