<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0717.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Claim of another state to recover property; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time after property has been paid or delivered to the department under this chapter, another state may recover the property if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property was subjected to custody by this state because the records of the holder did not reflect the last known address of the apparent owner when the property was presumed unclaimed under this chapter, and the other state establishes that the last known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property was in that state and under the laws of that state the property escheated to or was subject to a claim of abandonment or being unclaimed by that state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property, as reflected by the records of the holder, is in the other state and under the laws of that state the property has escheated to or become subject to a claim of abandonment by that state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records of the holder were erroneous in that they did not accurately reflect the actual owner of the property and the last known address of the actual owner is in the other state and under laws of that state the property escheated to or was subject to a claim of abandonment by that state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property was subject to custody by this state under s. 717.103(6) and under the laws of the state of domicile of the holder the property has escheated to or become subject to a claim of abandonment by that state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property is the sum payable on a traveler’s check, money order, or other similar instrument that was subjected to custody by this state under s. 717.104, and the instrument was purchased in the other state, and under the laws of that state the property escheated to or became subject to a claim of abandonment by that state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The claim of another state to recover escheated or unclaimed property under this section must be presented in a form prescribed by the department, and the department shall determine the claim within 90 days after it is presented. Such determination shall contain a notice of rights provided by ss. 120.569 and 120.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require a state, prior to recovery of property under this section, to indemnify this state and its officers and employees against any liability on a claim for the property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 87-105; s. 296, ch. 96-410; s. 26, ch. 2001-36.</History></Section>