<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0916.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Persons with Disabilities. The agency is responsible for training forensic clients who are developmentally disabled due to mental retardation or autism and have been determined incompetent to proceed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Autism” has the same meaning as in s. 393.063.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Chemical weapon” means any shell, cartridge, bomb, gun, or other device capable of emitting chloroacetophenone (CN), chlorobenzalmalononitrile (CS) or any derivatives thereof in any form, or any other agent with lacrimatory properties, and shall include products such as that commonly known as “mace.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Civil facility” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mental health facility established within the department or by contract with the department to serve individuals committed pursuant to chapter 394 and those defendants committed pursuant to this chapter who do not require the security provided in a forensic facility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intermediate care facility for the developmentally disabled, a foster care facility, a group home facility, or a supported living setting, as defined in s. 393.063, designated by the agency to serve those defendants who do not require the security provided in a forensic facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means the circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Defendant” means an adult, or a juvenile who is prosecuted as an adult, who has been arraigned and charged with a felony offense under the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Children and Family Services. The department is responsible for the treatment of forensic clients who have been determined incompetent to proceed due to mental illness or who have been acquitted of a felony by reason of insanity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Express and informed consent” or “consent” means consent given voluntarily in writing after a conscientious and sufficient explanation and disclosure of the purpose of the proposed treatment, the common side effects of the treatment, if any, the expected duration of the treatment, and any alternative treatment available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Forensic client” or “client” means any defendant who has been committed to the department or agency pursuant to s. 916.13, s. 916.15, or s. 916.302.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Forensic facility” means a separate and secure facility established within the department or agency to serve forensic clients. A separate and secure facility means a security-grade building for the purpose of separately housing persons who have mental illness from persons with retardation or autism and separately housing persons who have been involuntarily committed pursuant to this chapter from nonforensic residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Incompetent to proceed” means unable to proceed at any material stage of a criminal proceeding, which shall include trial of the case, pretrial hearings involving questions of fact on which the defendant might be expected to testify, entry of a plea, proceedings for violation of probation or violation of community control, sentencing, and hearings on issues regarding a defendant’s failure to comply with court orders or conditions or other matters in which the mental competence of the defendant is necessary for a just resolution of the issues being considered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Institutional security personnel” means the staff of forensic facilities who meet or exceed the requirements of s. 943.13 and who are responsible for providing security, protecting clients and personnel, enforcing rules, preventing and investigating unauthorized activities, and safeguarding the interests of citizens in the surrounding communities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental illness” means an impairment of the emotional processes that exercise conscious control of one’s actions, or of the ability to perceive or understand reality, which impairment substantially interferes with a defendant’s ability to meet the ordinary demands of living. For the purposes of this chapter, the term does not apply to defendants with only mental retardation or autism and does not include intoxication or conditions manifested only by antisocial behavior or substance abuse impairment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Restraint” means a physical device, method, or drug used to control dangerous behavior.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physical restraint is any manual method or physical or mechanical device, material, or equipment attached or adjacent to a person’s body so that he or she cannot easily remove the restraint and that restricts freedom of movement or normal access to one’s body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drug used as a restraint is a medication used to control the person’s behavior or to restrict his or her freedom of movement and not part of the standard treatment regimen of the person with a diagnosed mental illness who is a client of the department. Physically holding a person during a procedure to forcibly administer psychotropic medication is a physical restraint.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restraint does not include physical devices, such as orthopedically prescribed appliances, surgical dressings and bandages, supportive body bands, or other physical holding when necessary for routine physical examinations and tests; for purposes of orthopedic, surgical, or other similar medical treatment; when used to provide support for the achievement of functional body position or proper balance; or when used to protect a person from falling out of bed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retardation” has the same meaning as in s. 393.063.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Seclusion” means the physical segregation of a person in any fashion or the involuntary isolation of a person in a room or area from which the person is prevented from leaving. The prevention may be by physical barrier or by a staff member who is acting in a manner, or who is physically situated, so as to prevent the person from leaving the room or area. For purposes of this chapter, the term does not mean isolation due to a person’s medical condition or symptoms, the confinement in a forensic facility to a bedroom or area during normal hours of sleep when there is not an active order for seclusion, or during an emergency such as a riot or hostage situation when clients may be temporarily placed in their rooms for their own safety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Social service professional” means a person whose minimum qualifications include a bachelor’s degree and at least 2 years of social work, clinical practice, special education, habilitation, or equivalent experience working directly with persons with retardation, autism, or other developmental disabilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 85-167; s. 1527, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 98-92; s. 2, ch. 2006-195.</History></Section>