<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0916.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Involuntary commitment of defendant adjudicated not guilty by reason of insanity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination of whether a defendant is not guilty by reason of insanity shall be determined in accordance with Rule 3.217, Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant who is acquitted of criminal charges because of a finding of not guilty by reason of insanity may be involuntarily committed pursuant to such finding if the defendant has a mental illness and, because of the illness, is manifestly dangerous to himself or herself or others.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every defendant acquitted of criminal charges by reason of insanity and found to meet the criteria for involuntary commitment may be committed and treated in accordance with the provisions of this section and the applicable Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure. The department shall admit a defendant so adjudicated to an appropriate facility or program for treatment and shall retain and treat such defendant. No later than 6 months after the date of admission, prior to the end of any period of extended commitment, or at any time the administrator or designee shall have determined that the defendant no longer meets the criteria for continued commitment placement, the administrator or designee shall file a report with the court pursuant to the applicable Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all proceedings under this section, both the defendant and the state shall have the right to a hearing before the committing court. Evidence at such hearing may be presented by the hospital administrator or the administrator’s designee as well as by the state and the defendant. The defendant shall have the right to counsel at any such hearing. In the event that a defendant is determined to be indigent pursuant to s. 27.52, the public defender shall represent the defendant. The parties shall have access to the defendant’s records at the treating facilities and may interview or depose personnel who have had contact with the defendant at the treating facilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-75; s. 36, ch. 85-167; s. 1533, ch. 97-102; s. 19, ch. 98-92; s. 121, ch. 2003-402; s. 14, ch. 2006-195.</History></Section>