<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0916.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditional release.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for an inmate currently serving a prison sentence, the committing court may order a conditional release of any defendant who has been found to be incompetent to proceed due to retardation or autism, based on an approved plan for providing community-based training. The committing criminal court may order a conditional release of any defendant to a civil facility in lieu of an involuntary commitment to a forensic facility pursuant to s. 916.302. Upon a recommendation that community-based training for the defendant is appropriate, a written plan for community-based training, including recommendations from qualified professionals, may be filed with the court, with copies to all parties. Such a plan may also be submitted by the defendant and filed with the court, with copies to all parties. The plan must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special provisions for residential care and adequate supervision of the defendant, including recommended location of placement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for auxiliary services such as vocational training, psychological training, educational services, leisure services, and special medical care.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In its order of conditional release, the court shall specify the conditions of release based upon the release plan and shall direct the appropriate agencies or persons to submit periodic reports to the courts regarding the defendant’s compliance with the conditions of the release and progress in training, with copies to all parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of an affidavit or statement under oath by any person that the defendant has failed to comply with the conditions of release, that the defendant’s condition has deteriorated, or that the release conditions should be modified, the court shall hold a hearing within 7 days after receipt of the affidavit or statement under oath. With notice to the court and all parties, the agency may detain a defendant in a forensic facility until the hearing occurs. After the hearing, the court may modify the release conditions. The court may also order that the defendant be placed into more appropriate programs for further training or may order the defendant to be committed to a forensic facility if it is found, after the appointment and report of experts, that the defendant meets the criteria for placement in a forensic facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at any time it is determined after a hearing that the defendant conditionally released under subsection (1) no longer requires court-supervised followup care, the court shall terminate its jurisdiction in the cause and discharge the defendant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 98-92; s. 22, ch. 2006-195.</History></Section>