<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0815.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offenses against computer users.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever willfully, knowingly, and without authorization:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accesses or causes to be accessed any computer, computer system, or computer network;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disrupts or denies or causes the denial of computer system services to an authorized user of such computer system services, which, in whole or part, is owned by, under contract to, or operated for, on behalf of, or in conjunction with another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Destroys, takes, injures, or damages equipment or supplies used or intended to be used in a computer, computer system, or computer network;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Destroys, injures, or damages any computer, computer system, or computer network; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Introduces any computer contaminant into any computer, computer system, or computer network,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits an offense against computer users.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraphs (b) and (c), whoever violates subsection (1) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates subsection (1) and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damages a computer, computer equipment, computer supplies, a computer system, or a computer network, and the monetary damage or loss incurred as a result of the violation is $5,000 or greater;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits the offense for the purpose of devising or executing any scheme or artifice to defraud or obtain property; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interrupts or impairs a governmental operation or public communication, transportation, or supply of water, gas, or other public service,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates subsection (1) and the violation endangers human life commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever willfully, knowingly, and without authorization modifies equipment or supplies used or intended to be used in a computer, computer system, or computer network commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other civil remedy available, the owner or lessee of the computer, computer system, computer network, computer program, computer equipment, computer supplies, or computer data may bring a civil action against any person convicted under this section for compensatory damages.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action brought under this subsection, the court may award reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any computer, computer system, computer network, computer software, or computer data owned by a defendant which is used during the commission of any violation of this section or any computer owned by the defendant which is used as a repository for the storage of software or data obtained in violation of this section is subject to forfeiture as provided under ss. 932.701-932.704.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any person who accesses his or her employer’s computer system, computer network, computer program, or computer data when acting within the scope of his or her lawful employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of bringing a civil or criminal action under this section, a person who causes, by any means, the access to a computer, computer system, or computer network in one jurisdiction from another jurisdiction is deemed to have personally accessed the computer, computer system, or computer network in both jurisdictions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-92; s. 11, ch. 2001-54.</History></Section>