<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0815.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Access” means to approach, instruct, communicate with, store data in, retrieve data from, or otherwise make use of any resources of a computer, computer system, or computer network.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer” means an internally programmed, automatic device that performs data processing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer contaminant” means any set of computer instructions designed to modify, damage, destroy, record, or transmit information within a computer, computer system, or computer network without the intent or permission of the owner of the information. The term includes, but is not limited to, a group of computer instructions commonly called viruses or worms which are self-replicating or self-propagating and which are designed to contaminate other computer programs or computer data; consume computer resources; modify, destroy, record, or transmit data; or in some other fashion usurp the normal operation of the computer, computer system, or computer network.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer network” means any system that provides communications between one or more computer systems and its input or output devices, including, but not limited to, display terminals and printers that are connected by telecommunication facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer program or computer software” means a set of instructions or statements and related data which, when executed in actual or modified form, cause a computer, computer system, or computer network to perform specified functions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer services” include, but are not limited to, computer time; data processing or storage functions; or other uses of a computer, computer system, or computer network.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Computer system” means a device or collection of devices, including support devices, one or more of which contain computer programs, electronic instructions, or input data and output data, and which perform functions, including, but not limited to, logic, arithmetic, data storage, retrieval, communication, or control. The term does not include calculators that are not programmable and that are not capable of being used in conjunction with external files.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Data” means a representation of information, knowledge, facts, concepts, computer software, computer programs, or instructions. Data may be in any form, in storage media or stored in the memory of the computer, or in transit or presented on a display device.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial instrument” means any check, draft, money order, certificate of deposit, letter of credit, bill of exchange, credit card, or marketable security.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intellectual property” means data, including programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” means anything of value as defined in s. 812.012 and includes, but is not limited to, financial instruments, information, including electronically produced data and computer software and programs in either machine-readable or human-readable form, and any other tangible or intangible item of value.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-92; s. 9, ch. 2001-54; s. 4, ch. 2010-117.</History>
</Section>