<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0831.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offenses involving forging or counterfeiting private labels.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever, knowingly and willfully, forges or counterfeits, or causes or procures to be forged or counterfeited, manufactures, distributes or transports, or possesses with intent to distribute or transport, upon or in connection with any goods or services, the trademark or service mark of any person, entity, or association, which goods or services are intended for resale, or knowingly possesses tools or other reproduction materials for reproduction of specific forged or counterfeit trademarks or service marks commits the crime of counterfeiting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever knowingly sells or offers for sale, or knowingly purchases and keeps or has in his or her possession, with intent that the same shall be sold or disposed, or vends any goods having thereon a forged or counterfeit trademark, or who knowingly sells or offers for sale any service which is sold in conjunction with a forged or counterfeit service mark, of any person, entity, or association, knowing the same to be forged or counterfeited, commits the crime of selling or offering for sale counterfeit goods or services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, except that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the offense involves 100 or more but less than 1,000 items bearing one or more counterfeit marks or if the goods involved in the offense have a total retail value of more than $2,500, but less than $20,000.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the offense involves 1,000 or more items bearing one or more counterfeit marks or if the goods involved in the offense have a total retail value of $20,000 or more.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084 if, during the commission or as a result of the commission of the offense, the person engaging in the offense knowingly or by culpable negligence causes or allows to be caused bodily injury to another.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084 if, during the commission or as a result of the commission of the offense, the person engaging in the offense knowingly or by culpable negligence causes or allows to be caused serious bodily injury to another.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084 if, during the commission or as a result of the commission of the offense, the person engaging in the offense knowingly or by culpable negligence causes or allows to be caused death to another.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any person who, having previously been convicted for an offense under this section, is subsequently convicted for another offense under this section, such subsequent offense shall be reclassified as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the second degree, to a felony of the first degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the third degree, to a felony of the second degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a misdemeanor of the first degree, to a felony of the third degree. For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, such offense is ranked in level 4 of the offense severity ranking chart.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, a felony offense that is reclassified under this paragraph is ranked one level above the ranking under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023 of the felony offense committed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of a fine otherwise authorized by law, when any person has been convicted of an offense under this section, the court may fine the person up to three times the retail value of the goods seized, manufactured, or sold, whichever is greater, and may enter orders awarding court costs and the costs of investigation and prosecution, reasonably incurred. The court shall hold a hearing to determine the amount of the fine authorized by this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person is convicted of an offense under this section, the court, pursuant to s. 775.089, shall order the person to pay restitution to the trademark owner and any other victim of the offense. In determining the value of the property loss to the trademark owner, the court shall include expenses incurred by the trademark owner in the investigation or prosecution of the offense as well as the disgorgement of any profits realized by a person convicted of the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All defenses, affirmative defenses, and limitations on remedies that would be applicable in an action under the Lanham Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1051 et seq., or to an action under s. 495.131 shall be applicable in a prosecution under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2008-255.</History></Section>