<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0831.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Counterfeit controlled substance; sale, manufacture, delivery, or possession with intent to sell, manufacture, or deliver.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to sell, manufacture, or deliver, or to possess with intent to sell, manufacture, or deliver, a counterfeit controlled substance. Any person who violates this subsection with respect to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance named or described in s. 893.03(1), (2), (3), or (4) is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance named or described in s. 893.03(5) is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, “counterfeit controlled substance” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance named or described in s. 893.03 which, or the container or labeling of which, without authorization bears the trademark, trade name, or other identifying mark, imprint, or number, or any likeness thereof, of a manufacturer other than the person who in fact manufactured the controlled substance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any substance which is falsely identified as a controlled substance named or described in s. 893.03.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 81-53; s. 4, ch. 89-281; s. 2, ch. 92-19; s. 102, ch. 97-264; s. 104, ch. 99-3; s. 8, ch. 99-186; s. 18, ch. 2000-320; s. 8, ch. 2002-78.</History></Section>