<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0831.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Forging or counterfeiting private labels; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 831.03-831.034, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bodily injury” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cut, abrasion, bruise, burn, or disfigurement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical pain;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Illness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other injury to the body, no matter how temporary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Culpable negligence” means reckless disregard of human life or safety and consciously doing an act or following a course of conduct that the actor knew, or reasonably should have known, was likely to cause bodily injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Forged or counterfeit trademark or service mark” refers to a mark:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is applied to or used in connection with any goods, services, labels, patches, stickers, wrappers, badges, emblems, medallions, charms, boxes, containers, cans, cases, hangtags, documentation, or packaging or any other components of any type or nature that are designed, marketed, or otherwise intended to be used on or in connection with any goods or services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That is identical with or an imitation of a mark registered for those goods or services on the principal register in the United States Patent and Trademark Office or the trademark register for the State of Florida or any other state, or protected by the Amateur Sports Act of 1978, 36 U.S.C. s. 380, whether or not the offender knew such mark was so registered or protected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of which is unauthorized by the owner of the registered mark; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application or use of which is either likely to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive or is otherwise intended to be used on or in connection with the goods or services for which the mark is registered.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">An otherwise legitimate mark is deemed counterfeit for purposes of this definition if, by altering the nature of any item to which it is affixed, the altered item bearing the otherwise legitimate mark is likely, in the course of commerce, to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail value” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The counterfeiter’s regular selling price for the goods or services, unless the goods or services bearing a counterfeit mark would appear to a reasonably prudent person to be authentic, then the retail value shall be the price of the authentic counterpart; or, if no authentic reasonably similar counterpart exists, then the retail value shall remain the counterfeiter’s regular selling price.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of labels, patches, stickers, wrappers, badges, emblems, medallions, charms, boxes, containers, cans, cases, hangtags, documentation, or packaging or any other components of any type or nature that are designed, marketed, or otherwise intended to be used on or in connection with any goods or services, the retail value shall be treated as if each component was a finished good and valued as described in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Serious bodily injury” means bodily injury that involves:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A substantial risk of death;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extreme physical pain;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protracted and obvious disfigurement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 3621, 1885; RS 2481; GS 3361; RGS 5209; CGL 7327; s. 961, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 95-300; s. 1, ch. 2008-255.</History></Section>