<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0831.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Forging or counterfeiting private labels; destruction; forfeiture.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any goods to which forged or counterfeit trademarks or service marks are attached or affixed or any tools or other materials for the reproduction of any specific forged or counterfeit trademark or service mark which are produced or possessed in violation of this section may be seized by any law enforcement officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any personal property, including, but not limited to, any item, object, tool, machine, or vehicle of any kind, employed as an instrumentality in the commission of, or in aiding or abetting in the commission of, the crime of counterfeiting, as proscribed by ss. 831.03-831.034, and not otherwise included in paragraph (a), may be seized and is subject to forfeiture pursuant to ss. 932.701-932.704.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in imposing sentence on a person convicted of an offense under this section, shall order, in addition to any other sentence imposed, that the person forfeit to the state the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any property constituting or derived from any proceeds the person obtained, directly or indirectly, as the result of the offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the person’s property used, or intended to be used, in any manner or part, to commit, facilitate, aid, or abet the commission of the offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any item that bears or consists of a counterfeit mark used in committing the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of all forfeiture proceedings, the court shall order that any forfeited item bearing or consisting of a counterfeit mark be destroyed or alternatively disposed of in another manner with the written consent of the trademark owners. The owners of the registered or protected mark shall be responsible for the costs incurred in the disposition of the forged or counterfeit items.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2008-255.</History></Section>