<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0831.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Making or having instruments and material for counterfeiting driver’s licenses or identification cards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has control, custody, or possession of any plate, block, press, stone, or other tool, instrument, or implement, or any part thereof; engraves, makes, or amends, or begins to engrave, make, or amend, any plate, block, press, stone, or other tool, instrument, or implement; brings into the state any such plate, block, press, stone, or other tool, instrument, or implement, or any part thereof, in the similitude of the driver’s licenses or identification cards issued by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or its duly authorized agents or those of any state or jurisdiction that issues licenses recognized in this state for the operation of a motor vehicle or that issues identification cards recognized in this state for the purpose of indicating a person’s true name and age; has control, custody, or possession of or makes or provides any paper or other material adapted and designed for the making of a false and counterfeit driver’s license or identification card purporting to be issued by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or its duly authorized agents or those of any state or jurisdiction that issues licenses recognized in this state for the operation of a motor vehicle or that issues identification cards recognized in this state for the purpose of indicating a person’s true name and age; has in his or her possession, control, or custody any such plate or block engraved in any part, or any press or other tool or instrument or any paper or other material adapted and designed as aforesaid with intent to sell, issue, publish, pass, or utter the same or to cause or permit the same to be used in forging or making any such false or counterfeit driver’s license or identification card; or prints, photographs, or in any manner makes or executes any engraved photograph, print, or impression by any process whatsoever in the similitude of any such licenses or identification cards with the intent to sell, issue, publish, or utter the same or to cause or permit the same to be used in forging or making any such false and counterfeit driver’s license or identification card of this state or any state or jurisdiction that issues licenses recognized in this state for the operation of a motor vehicle or that issues identification cards recognized in this state for the purpose of indicating a person’s true name and age is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-278; s. 1, ch. 69-313; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 978, ch. 71-136; s. 32, ch. 73-334; s. 58, ch. 89-282; s. 1300, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 97-206.</History></Section>