<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0565.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License fees; vendors; clubs; caterers; and others.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following state license taxes apply to vendors who are permitted to sell any alcoholic beverages regardless of alcoholic content:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where beverages are sold only in sealed containers for consumption off the premises where sold shall pay an amount equal to 75 percent of the amount of the license tax for vendors in the same county as provided in paragraphs (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted in a county having a population of over 100,000, according to the latest population estimate prepared pursuant to s. 186.901, for such county, shall pay $1,820.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted in a county having a population over 75,000 and not over 100,000, according to the latest population estimate prepared pursuant to s. 186.901, for such county, shall pay $1,560.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted in a county having a population of over 50,000 and not over 75,000, according to the latest population estimate prepared pursuant to s. 186.901, for such county, shall pay $1,300.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted in a county having a population of over 25,000 and not over 50,000, according to the latest population estimate prepared pursuant to s. 186.901, for such county, shall pay $858.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted in a county having a population of 25,000 or less, according to the latest population estimate prepared pursuant to s. 186.901, for such county, shall pay $624.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor operating a place of business where consumption on the premises is permitted and which has more than three separate rooms or enclosures in which permanent bars or counters are located from which alcoholic beverages are served for consumption on the licensed premises shall pay, in addition to the license tax imposed in paragraphs (b)-(f), $1,000. However, such permanent bars or counters do not include service bars not accessible to the public or portable or temporary bars being used for a single occasion or event. A golf club licenseholder may operate service bars or portable or temporary bars on the grounds contiguous to its licensed premises and shall pay $100 for a certified copy of the club license, which shall be posted on the bar. The area contiguous to the licensed premises shall be considered an extension of the licensed premises upon payment of the fee, posting of the certified copy of the license, and notation of such extension upon the sketch accompanying the original license application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any operator of railroads or sleeping cars in this state may obtain a license to sell the beverages mentioned in the Beverage Law on passenger trains upon the payment of an annual license tax of $2,500, the tax to be paid to the division. Such license shall authorize the holder thereof to keep for sale and sell all beverages mentioned in the Beverage Law upon any dining, club, parlor, buffet, or observation car operated by it in this state, but such beverages may be sold only to passengers upon the cars and must be served for consumption thereon. It is unlawful for such licensees to purchase or sell any liquor except in miniature bottles of not more than 2 ounces. Every such license shall be good throughout the state. No license shall be required, or tax levied by any municipality or county, for the privilege of selling such beverages for consumption in such cars. Such beverages shall be sold only on cars in which are posted certified copies of the licenses issued to such operator. Such certified copies of such licenses shall be issued by the division upon the payment of a tax of $10.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operators of steamships and steamship lines, buses and bus lines, or airplanes and airlines engaged in interstate or foreign commerce or plying between fixed terminals and upon fixed schedules in this state may obtain licenses to sell the beverages mentioned in the Beverage Law:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On steamships, buses, and airplanes operated by such operators, upon the payment of an annual license tax of $1,100; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no more than one passenger waiting lounge licensed by the division and operated by an airline licensed herein at each of its terminals in the state for ticketed passengers whose flights are scheduled to depart within 24 hours of service and guests in the company of such ticketholders, provided such licensed airline has first obtained an appropriate space lease or permit providing for payment of nondiscriminatory rental and concession fees and upon the payment of an additional license tax of $1,100 per lounge.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All such license taxes shall be paid to the division. Such licenses shall authorize the holders thereof to keep for sale and sell all beverages mentioned in the Beverage Law upon any steamship, bus, or airplane or in any such airline passenger waiting lounge operated by such operators in this state, but such beverages may be sold only to passengers upon such steamships, buses, and airplanes and to ticketed passengers and their guests in such airline passenger waiting lounges and may be served only for consumption on such steamships, buses, and airplanes or in such airline passenger waiting lounges. It is unlawful for such licensees to purchase for resale any liquor except in miniature bottles of not more than 2 ounces or liquor in individual containers of not less than one-fifth of 1 gallon. Such sales are permitted while such steamships, buses, and airplanes are in transit; but such sales are not permitted on airplanes while such airplanes are in airports. Every such license shall be good throughout the state. No license may be required or tax levied by any municipality or county for the privilege of selling such beverages for consumption on such steamships, buses, or airplanes or in such airline passenger waiting lounges. The division shall issue a license to sell alcoholic beverages on steamships, buses, and airplanes to an operator of a steamship line, bus line, or airline, at a central location designated on the sworn application for license. The application for initial issuance of such a license must specify the number of steamships, buses, or airplanes in the fleet scheduled by the operator of the line for operation in this state. An application for renewal of such a license must specify the total number of steamships, buses, or airplanes in the fleet that operated in this state during the preceding license year. In addition to the annual license tax imposed under this subsection, a tax of $25 is imposed for each steamship, bus, or airplane which is disclosed on the application for license or renewal of license. Upon the payment of all applicable license taxes, each such steamship, bus, or airplane is considered a licensed premises under the Beverage Law. However, this paragraph does not apply to operators of pleasure, excursion, sightseeing, or charter boats not having regular round-trip runs of more than 100 miles in each direction; but operators of such boats may obtain licenses, with such boats being designated as their places of business, upon compliance with all the laws relating to vendors operating places of business where consumption on the premises is permitted. However, the operator of any pleasure, excursion, sightseeing, or charter boat which has a Coast Guard-approved capacity of at least 125 passengers may be granted a special liquor license to sell and serve alcoholic beverages to passengers during a period of no longer than 1 hour prior to departure on a scheduled or chartered cruise while the boat is docked at a docking facility or marina and the period during which the boat is in operation on the scheduled or chartered cruise for consumption on the premises only. The fee for such special license shall be the same as that charged pursuant to paragraphs (1)(b)-(f) based on the location of the home port of the boat. Also, no license to sell the beverages herein defined shall be issued to the operator of any boat which plies upon or is anchored upon the waters of any lake within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operators of railroads, sleeping cars, steamships, buses, and airplanes licensed under this section shall not be required to obtain their beverages from licensees under the Beverage Law, but such operators shall keep strict accounts of all such beverages sold within this state and shall make monthly reports to the division on the forms prepared and furnished by the division. Such operators are required to pay an excise tax for such beverages sold within this state as to which such excise tax has not theretofore been paid, equal to the tax assessed against manufacturers and distributors. Such operators shall pay such tax monthly to the division at the same time they furnish the reports hereinabove provided for. Such reports shall be filed on or before the 15th day of each month for sales for the previous calendar month.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons associated together as a chartered or incorporated club, including any social club incorporated by order of a circuit judge after its charter has been found to be for objects authorized by law and approved by the judge as organized for lawful purposes and not for the purpose of evading license taxes on dealers in beverages defined herein, which such organization is a bona fide club, and has been at the time of application for license hereunder in continuous active existence and operation for a period of not less than 2 years in the county where it exists, shall before serving or distributing to its members or nonresident guests the beverages defined herein, whether such service or distribution is made upon contribution to the club of money or by check or other device, pay an annual state license tax of $400. However, any golf club operated by or on behalf of any incorporated municipality in this state, and any veterans’ or fraternal organization of national scope, need not have been, or need not be, in continuous active existence or operation for any required period of time prior to an application for license hereunder. The payment of such club license tax shall authorize the service and distribution to members and nonresident guests of the club only, and such service and distribution to the members and nonresident guests shall not be deemed sales within the meaning of the law in this state; but any service or distribution to anyone other than a member or nonresident guest of such licensed club shall be deemed a sale, and any officer, member, or employee of any such licensed club who sells or distributes or serves any such beverages to any person other than a member or nonresident guest of such club for money or other value shall be deemed guilty of selling such beverages without a license and shall be punished as provided by law. The holders of a golf club license may sell alcoholic beverages to those other than members and their nonresident guests on days when the club is open to the public. For each such day of service to nonmembers, the club shall obtain from the division for a fee of $50 an extension of its license to permit such sales. Such license extensions shall be limited to one event per year, not to exceed 8 consecutive days. Any officer of any such club which has not paid such license who knowingly permits such service or distribution by such club of the beverages herein defined to members or nonresident guests of such club shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished as herein provided. However, this subsection does not apply to a club organized or used for the purpose of evading the payment of the license tax on vendors of such beverages; such club is subject to the payment of the license tax imposed by the Beverage Law upon vendors. The president, vice president, secretary, or treasurer, or officers of corresponding duties by any name they may be called, of any club required by this section to pay a license tax are required to see that such license tax is paid and, in default thereof, shall each be personally liable to the punishment provided by the Beverage Law for nonpayment of the license tax hereby required. Clubs which are not authorized to obtain licenses under this subsection or which do not obtain licenses under this subsection may, if they comply with this provision of the Beverage Law, obtain licenses as vendors. A club obtaining such club license shall not purchase any beverage herein defined from anyone other than a distributor or vendor licensed under the Beverage Law; nor shall such club dispense or serve any beverage defined herein unless such beverage has been purchased by such club from such licensed distributor or vendor; nor shall the club dispense or serve any such beverage on which a tax is required by the Beverage Law unless such beverage tax has been paid as required by that law. Such club license cannot be transferred in any manner whatsoever.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A caterer at a horse or dog racetrack or jai alai fronton may obtain a license upon the payment of an annual state license tax of $675. Such caterer’s license shall permit sales only within the enclosure in which such races or jai alai games are conducted, and such licensee shall be permitted to sell only during the period beginning 10 days before and ending 10 days after racing or jai alai under the authority of the Division of Pari-mutuel Wagering of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation is conducted at such racetrack or jai alai fronton. Except as in this subsection otherwise provided, caterers licensed hereunder shall be treated as vendors licensed to sell by the drink the beverages mentioned herein and shall be subject to all the provisions hereof relating to such vendors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vendor who operates places of business where consumption on the premises is permitted, which premises are located within a theme park complex that is owned, managed, controlled, and operated by such vendor, may operate under a master license issued for the type of service offered if the theme park complex comprises at least 25 enclosed acres of land with permanent exhibitions and a variety of recreational activities, the enclosed area has a controlled entrance to, and exit from, the enclosed area, and at least 1 million visitors annually pay admission fees to the theme park complex. In addition to the license taxes imposed in paragraphs (1)(b)-(f), an additional tax of $1,500 shall be imposed for up to 5 additional bars, $2,500 for 6 to 10 additional bars, and $3,500 for more than 10 additional bars. The enclosed area within the theme park shall be considered an extension of the licensed premises upon the payment of the fee and the notation of such extension on the sketch accompanying the original license application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A marine exhibition park complex may obtain, upon the payment of appropriate fees, a license for on-premises consumption of alcoholic beverages not subject to any quota or limitation if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marine exhibition park complex comprises at least 25 enclosed acres of land.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enclosed area has a controlled entrance to, and exit from, the enclosed area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 450,000 visitors annually pay admission fees to the marine exhibition park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marine exhibition park has been in continuous existence for at least 30 years.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In addition to the license taxes imposed in paragraphs (1)(b)-(f), an additional tax of $1,500 shall be imposed for up to 5 additional bars, $2,500 for 6 to 10 additional bars, and $3,500 for more than 10 additional bars. The enclosed area within the marine exhibition park shall be considered the licensed premises upon the payment of the fee. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, entities licensed under this subsection shall be treated as vendors licensed to sell alcoholic beverages by the drink and shall be subject to all the provisions relating to such vendors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state-chartered legal entity not for profit organized principally for the purpose of supporting or managing the affairs of a symphony orchestra may obtain a license upon the payment of an annual license tax of $400. Such license shall permit sales only within the enclosure in which such symphony normally and regularly performs and in which alcoholic beverages are otherwise authorized; and such licensee shall be permitted to sell only during the hours in which the symphony premises are in use for a cultural event under the auspices or authorization of the licensee. The issuing of a license under this section is not subject to any quota or limitation, except that the license shall be issued only to an entity supporting a well-recognized symphony the reputation of which is known generally in the state or region of operation. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, entities licensed hereunder shall be treated as vendors licensed to sell by the drink the beverages mentioned herein and shall be subject to all the provisions hereof relating to such vendors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the finding of the Legislature that passenger vessels engaged exclusively in foreign commerce are susceptible to a distinct and separate classification for purposes of the sale of alcoholic beverages under the Beverage Law. Upon the filing of an application and payment of an annual fee of $1,100, the director is authorized to issue a permit authorizing the operator, or, if applicable, his or her concessionaire, of a passenger vessel which has cabin-berth capacity for at least 75 passengers, and which is engaged exclusively in foreign commerce, to sell alcoholic beverages on the vessel for consumption on board only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During a period not in excess of 24 hours prior to departure while the vessel is moored at a dock or wharf in a port of this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time while the vessel is located in Florida territorial waters and is in transit to or from international waters.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">One such permit shall be required for each such vessel and shall name the vessel for which it is issued. No license shall be required or tax levied by any municipality or county for the privilege of selling beverages for consumption on board such vessels. The beverages so sold may be purchased outside the state by the permittee, and the same shall not be considered as imported for the purposes of s. 561.14(3) solely because of such sale. The permittee is not required to obtain its beverages from licensees under the Beverage Law, but it shall keep a strict account of all such beverages sold within this state and shall make monthly reports to the division on forms prepared and furnished by the division. A permittee who sells on board the vessel beverages withdrawn from United States Bureau of Customs and Border Protection bonded storage on board the vessel may satisfy such accounting requirement by supplying the division with copies of the appropriate United States Bureau of Customs and Border Protection forms evidencing such withdrawals as importations under United States customs laws. Such permittee shall pay to the state an excise tax for beverages sold pursuant to this section, if such excise tax has not previously been paid, in an amount equal to the tax which would be required to be paid on such sales by a licensed manufacturer or distributor. A vendor holding such permit shall pay the tax monthly to the division at the same time he or she furnishes the required report. Such report shall be filed on or before the 15th day of each month for the sales occurring during the previous calendar month.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state-chartered legal entity not for profit organized principally for the purpose of operating a theater with live performances and not fewer than 100 seats may obtain a license upon the payment of an annual license tax of $400. Such license shall permit sales for consumption on the premises only to patrons during any regularly scheduled live theater performance. No licensee under this special license shall enter into any exclusive contract for its use. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, an entity licensed hereunder shall be treated as a vendor licensed to sell by the drink the beverages mentioned herein and is subject to all the provisions hereof relating to such vendor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art direct-support organization may obtain a license upon the payment of an annual license tax of $400. Such license shall permit sales for consumption on the premises of the museum in conjunction with artistic, educational, cultural, civic, or charitable events held on the premises of the museum under the auspices or authorization of the licensee. The issuing of a license under this subsection is not subject to any quota or limitation, except that the license shall be issued only to the direct-support organization of the museum or its designee. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the entity licensed hereunder shall be treated as a vendor licensed to sell by the drink the beverages mentioned herein and shall be subject to all provisions relating to such vendors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as expressly provided otherwise in this section, a vendor holding a permit is subject to the provisions of the Beverage Law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-42; s. 5, ch. 72-230; s. 2, ch. 72-272; s. 1, ch. 74-96; s. 2, ch. 75-278; s. 1, ch. 80-100; ss. 13, 22, ch. 81-158; s. 2, ch. 83-79; s. 2, ch. 84-142; ss. 2, 3, ch. 84-286; s. 5, ch. 85-161; s. 1, ch. 87-348; s. 1, ch. 89-361; s. 9, ch. 92-176; s. 221, ch. 94-218; s. 13, ch. 95-346; s. 875, ch. 97-103; s. 69, ch. 2000-258; s. 96, ch. 2004-5.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 561.34.</Text></Note></Section>