<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.186" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pharmacist’s order for medicinal drugs; dispensing procedure; development of formulary.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created a committee composed of two members of the Board of Medicine licensed under chapter 458 chosen by said board, one member of the Board of Osteopathic Medicine licensed under chapter 459 chosen by said board, three members of the Board of Pharmacy licensed under this chapter and chosen by said board, and one additional person with a background in health care or pharmacology chosen by the committee. The committee shall establish a formulary of medicinal drug products and dispensing procedures which shall be used by a pharmacist when ordering and dispensing such drug products to the public. Dispensing procedures may include matters related to reception of patient, description of his or her condition, patient interview, patient physician referral, product selection, and dispensing and use limitations. In developing the formulary of medicinal drug products, the committee may include products falling within the following categories:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any medicinal drug of single or multiple active ingredients in any strengths when such active ingredients have been approved individually or in combination for over-the-counter sale by the United States Food and Drug Administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any medicinal drug recommended by the United States Food and Drug Administration Advisory Panel for transfer to over-the-counter status pending approval by the United States Food and Drug Administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any medicinal drug containing any antihistamine or decongestant as a single active ingredient or in combination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any medicinal drug containing fluoride in any strength.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any medicinal drug containing lindane in any strength.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any over-the-counter proprietary drug under federal law that has been approved for reimbursement by the Florida Medicaid Program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any topical anti-infectives excluding eye and ear topical anti-infectives.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, any drug which is sold as an over-the-counter proprietary drug under federal law shall not be included in the formulary or otherwise affected by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Pharmacy, the Board of Medicine, and the Board of Osteopathic Medicine shall adopt by rule a formulary of medicinal drugs and dispensing procedures as established by the committee. A pharmacist may order and dispense a product from the formulary pursuant to the established dispensing procedure, as adopted by the boards, for each drug in conjunction with its inclusion in the formulary. Any drug product ordered by a pharmacist shall be selected and dispensed only by the pharmacist so ordering, and said order shall not be refilled, nor shall another medicinal drug be ordered for the same condition unless such act is consistent with dispensing procedures established by the committee. Appropriate referral to another health care provider is indicated under such circumstances. On each occasion of such dispensing, the pharmacist shall create and maintain a prescription record in the form required by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affixed to the container containing a medicinal drug dispensed pursuant to this section shall be a label bearing the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the pharmacist ordering the medication.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the pharmacy from which the medication was dispensed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of dispensing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order number or other identification adequate to readily identify the order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the patient for whom the medicinal drug was ordered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directions for use of the medicinal drug ordered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear, concise statement that the order may not be refilled.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any pharmacist performing the services authorized by this section shall be eligible for reimbursement by third party prescription programs when so provided by contract or when otherwise provided by such program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person ordering or dispensing medicinal drugs in violation of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, and such violation shall be punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 85-35; ss. 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 56, ch. 87-225; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 21, ch. 91-140; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 21, ch. 91-220; s. 92, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 96, ch. 92-149; s. 249, ch. 97-103; s. 95, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>