<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.0266" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Common database.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the dispensing by a pharmacist licensed in this state or another state of a prescription contained in a common database, and such dispensing shall not constitute a transfer as defined in s. 465.026(1)-(6), provided that the following conditions are met:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All pharmacies involved in the transactions pursuant to which the prescription is dispensed are under common ownership and utilize a common database.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All pharmacies involved in the transactions pursuant to which the prescription is dispensed and all pharmacists engaging in dispensing functions are properly licensed, permitted, or registered in this state or another state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common database maintains a record of all pharmacists involved in the process of dispensing a prescription.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the common database maintains a policy and procedures manual that governs its participating pharmacies, pharmacists, and pharmacy employees and that is available to the board or its agent upon request. The policy and procedures manual shall include the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A best practices model detailing how each pharmacy and each pharmacist accessing the common database will comply with applicable federal and state laws, rules, and regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure for maintaining appropriate records for regulatory oversight for tracking a prescription during each stage of the filling and dispensing process, identifying the pharmacists involved in filling and dispensing the prescription and counseling the patient, and responding to any requests for information made by the board under s. 465.0156.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy and procedure for providing adequate security to protect the confidentiality and integrity of patient information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A quality assurance program designed to objectively and systematically monitor, evaluate, and improve the quality and appropriateness of patient care through the use of the common database.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any pharmacist dispensing a prescription has at all times the right and obligation to exercise his or her independent professional judgment. Notwithstanding other provisions in this section, no pharmacist licensed in this state participating in the dispensing of a prescription pursuant to this section shall be responsible for the acts and omissions of another person participating in the dispensing process provided such person is not under the direct supervision and control of the pharmacist licensed in this state.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2006-243.</History></Section>