<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.0075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by endorsement; requirements; fee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who applies to the department and remits a nonrefundable fee of not more than $100, as set by the board, and whom the board certifies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has met the qualifications for licensure in s. 465.007(1)(b) and (c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has obtained a passing score, as established by rule of the board, on the licensure examination of the National Association of Boards of Pharmacy or a similar nationally recognized examination, if the board certifies that the applicant has taken the required examination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has submitted evidence of the active licensed practice of pharmacy, including practice in community or public health by persons employed by a governmental entity, in another jurisdiction for at least 2 of the immediately preceding 5 years or evidence of successful completion of board-approved postgraduate training or a board-approved clinical competency examination within the year immediately preceding application for licensure; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an internship meeting the requirements of s. 465.007(1)(c) within the 2 years immediately preceding application; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has obtained a passing score on the pharmacy jurisprudence portions of the licensure examination, as required by board rule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant licensed in another state for a period in excess of 2 years from the date of application for licensure in this state shall submit a total of at least 30 hours of board-approved continuing education for the 2 calendar years immediately preceding application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who is under investigation in any jurisdiction for an act or offense that would constitute a violation of this chapter until the investigation is complete, at which time the provisions of s. 465.016 apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license by endorsement to any applicant whose license to practice pharmacy has been suspended or revoked in another state or who is currently the subject of any disciplinary proceeding in another state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-166; s. 1, ch. 2008-216.</History></Section>