<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Pharmacy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Pharmacy is created within the department and shall consist of nine members to be appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the Senate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seven members of the board must be licensed pharmacists who are residents of this state and who have been engaged in the practice of the profession of pharmacy in this state for at least 4 years and, to the extent practicable, represent the various pharmacy practice settings. Of the pharmacist members, one must be currently engaged in the practice of pharmacy in a community pharmacy, one must be currently engaged in the practice of pharmacy in a Class II institutional pharmacy or a Modified Class II institutional pharmacy, and five shall be pharmacists licensed in this state irrespective of practice setting. The remaining two members must be residents of the state who have never been licensed as pharmacists and who are in no way connected with the practice of the profession of pharmacy. No person may be appointed as a consumer member who is in any way connected with a drug manufacturer or wholesaler. At least one member of the board must be 60 years of age or older.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the terms of the members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of 4 years, and such members shall serve until their successors are appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of chapter 456 relating to activities of the board shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 7, ch. 79-226; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 16, ch. 87-172; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 124, ch. 94-218; s. 88, ch. 97-264; s. 67, ch. 98-166; s. 124, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>