<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.0156" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of nonresident pharmacies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any pharmacy which is located outside this state and which ships, mails, or delivers, in any manner, a dispensed medicinal drug into this state shall be considered a nonresident pharmacy, shall be registered with the board, shall provide pharmacy services at a high level of protection and competence, and shall disclose to the board the following specific information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it maintains at all times a valid, unexpired license, permit, or registration to operate the pharmacy in compliance with the laws of the state in which the dispensing facility is located and from which the medicinal drugs shall be dispensed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location, names, and titles of all principal corporate officers and the pharmacist who serves as the prescription department manager for dispensing medicinal drugs to residents of this state. This disclosure shall be made within 30 days after any change of location, corporate officer, or pharmacist serving as the prescription department manager for dispensing medicinal drugs to residents of this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it complies with all lawful directions and requests for information from the regulatory or licensing agency of all states in which it is licensed as well as with all requests for information made by the board pursuant to this section. It shall respond directly to all communications from the board concerning emergency circumstances arising from errors in the dispensing of medicinal drugs to the residents of this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it maintains its records of medicinal drugs dispensed to patients in this state so that the records are readily retrievable from the other business records of the pharmacy and from the records of other medicinal drugs dispensed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That during its regular hours of operation but not less than 6 days per week, for a minimum of 40 hours per week, a toll-free telephone service shall be provided to facilitate communication between patients in this state and a pharmacist at the pharmacy who has access to the patient’s records. This toll-free number must be disclosed on the label affixed to each container of dispensed medicinal drugs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applications for nonresident pharmacy registration under this section shall be made on a form furnished by the board. The board may require such information as the board deems reasonably necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. The board may grant an exemption from the registration requirements of this section to any nonresident pharmacy which confines its dispensing activity to isolated transactions. The board may define by rule the term isolated transactions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration fee and the biennial renewal fee shall be the fee specified in s. 465.022.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may deny, revoke, or suspend registration of, or fine or reprimand, a nonresident pharmacy for failure to comply with s. 465.025 or with any requirement of this section in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the prohibitions of subsection (4) the board may deny, revoke, or suspend registration of, or fine or reprimand, a nonresident pharmacy in accordance with the provisions of this chapter for conduct which causes serious bodily injury or serious psychological injury to a resident of this state if the board has referred the matter to the regulatory or licensing agency in the state in which the pharmacy is located and the regulatory or licensing agency fails to investigate within 180 days of the referral.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any nonresident pharmacy which is not registered pursuant to this section to advertise its services in this state, or for any person who is a resident of this state to advertise the pharmacy services of a nonresident pharmacy which has not registered with the board, with the knowledge that the advertisement will or is likely to induce members of the public in this state to use the pharmacy to fill prescriptions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to Internet pharmacies required to be permitted under s. 465.0197.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 465.003(10), for purposes of this section, the registered pharmacy and the pharmacist designated by the registered pharmacy as the prescription department manager or the equivalent must be licensed in the state of location in order to dispense into this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 3, ch. 89-218; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 31, ch. 95-144; s. 90, ch. 97-264; s. 2, ch. 2004-387.</History></Section>