<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.0125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consultant pharmacist license; application, renewal, fees; responsibilities; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue or renew a consultant pharmacist license upon receipt of an initial or renewal application which conforms to the requirements for consultant pharmacist initial licensure or renewal as promulgated by the board by rule and a fee set by the board not to exceed $250. The consultant pharmacist shall be responsible for maintaining all drug records required by law and for establishing drug handling procedures for the safe handling and storage of drugs. The consultant pharmacist may also be responsible for ordering and evaluating any laboratory or clinical testing when, in the judgment of the consultant pharmacist, such activity is necessary for the proper performance of the consultant pharmacist’s responsibilities. Such laboratory or clinical testing may be ordered only with regard to patients residing in a nursing home facility, and then only when authorized by the medical director of the nursing home facility. The consultant pharmacist must have completed such additional training and demonstrate such additional qualifications in the practice of institutional pharmacy as shall be required by the board in addition to licensure as a registered pharmacist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1), a consultant pharmacist or a doctor of pharmacy licensed in this state may also be responsible for ordering and evaluating any laboratory or clinical testing for persons under the care of a licensed home health agency when, in the judgment of the consultant pharmacist or doctor of pharmacy, such activity is necessary for the proper performance of his or her responsibilities and only when authorized by a practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 461, or chapter 466. In order for the consultant pharmacist or doctor of pharmacy to qualify and accept this authority, he or she must receive 3 hours of continuing education relating to laboratory and clinical testing as established by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall promulgate rules necessary to implement and administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 83-329; s. 1, ch. 85-65; ss. 9, 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-231; s. 89, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>