<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dispensing of medicinal drugs pursuant to facsimile of prescription.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, it is lawful for a pharmacy to dispense medicinal drugs, including controlled substances authorized under subsection (2), based on reception of an electronic facsimile of the original prescription if all of the following conditions are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of the transaction the pharmacy complies with laws and administrative rules relating to pharmacies and pharmacists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except in the case of the transmission of a prescription by a person authorized by law to prescribe medicinal drugs:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facsimile system making the transmission provides the pharmacy receiving the transmission with audio communication via telephonic, electronic, or similar means with the person presenting the prescription.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of the delivery of the medicinal drugs, the pharmacy has in its possession the original prescription for the medicinal drug involved.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recipient of the prescription shall sign a log and shall indicate the name and address of both the recipient and the patient for whom the medicinal drug was prescribed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Controlled substances listed in Schedule II as defined in s. 893.03(2) may be dispensed as provided in this section to the extent allowed by 21 C.F.R. s. 1306.11.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-341; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 8, ch. 91-201; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 94, ch. 97-264; s. 5, ch. 99-186.</History></Section>