<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a pharmacist shall apply to the department to take the licensure examination. The department shall examine each applicant who the board certifies has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the application form and remitted an examination fee set by the board not to exceed $100 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department for purchase of portions of the examination from the National Association of Boards of Pharmacy or a similar national organization. The fees authorized under this section shall be established in sufficient amounts to cover administrative costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted satisfactory proof that she or he is not less than 18 years of age and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a recipient of a degree from a school or college of pharmacy accredited by an accrediting agency recognized and approved by the United States Office of Education; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of a 4-year undergraduate pharmacy program of a school or college of pharmacy located outside the United States, has demonstrated proficiency in English by passing both the Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL) and the Test of Spoken English (TSE), has passed the Foreign Pharmacy Graduate Equivalency Examination that is approved by rule of the board, and has completed a minimum of 500 hours in a supervised work activity program within this state under the supervision of a pharmacist licensed by the department, which program is approved by the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted satisfactory proof that she or he has completed an internship program approved by the board. No such board-approved program shall exceed 2,080 hours, all of which may be obtained prior to graduation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may permit an applicant who has satisfied all requirements of subsection (1), except those relating to age or the internship program, to take the written examination, but the passing of the examination shall confer no rights or privileges upon the applicant in connection with the practice of pharmacy in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), the department shall issue a license to practice pharmacy to any applicant who successfully completes the examination in accordance with this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 7, ch. 79-226; ss. 13, 15, 23, 25, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 30, ch. 83-329; ss. 5, 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 13, ch. 88-205; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 240, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>