<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0465.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administration” means the obtaining and giving of a single dose of medicinal drugs by a legally authorized person to a patient for her or his consumption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Pharmacy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consultant pharmacist” means a pharmacist licensed by the department and certified as a consultant pharmacist pursuant to s. 465.0125.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Data communication device” means an electronic device that receives electronic information from one source and transmits or routes it to another, including, but not limited to, any such bridge, router, switch, or gateway.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dispense” means the transfer of possession of one or more doses of a medicinal drug by a pharmacist to the ultimate consumer or her or his agent. As an element of dispensing, the pharmacist shall, prior to the actual physical transfer, interpret and assess the prescription order for potential adverse reactions, interactions, and dosage regimen she or he deems appropriate in the exercise of her or his professional judgment, and the pharmacist shall certify that the medicinal drug called for by the prescription is ready for transfer. The pharmacist shall also provide counseling on proper drug usage, either orally or in writing, if in the exercise of her or his professional judgment counseling is necessary. The actual sales transaction and delivery of such drug shall not be considered dispensing. The administration shall not be considered dispensing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Institutional formulary system” means a method whereby the medical staff evaluates, appraises, and selects those medicinal drugs or proprietary preparations which in the medical staff’s clinical judgment are most useful in patient care, and which are available for dispensing by a practicing pharmacist in a Class II institutional pharmacy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medicinal drugs” or “drugs” means those substances or preparations commonly known as “prescription” or “legend” drugs which are required by federal or state law to be dispensed only on a prescription, but shall not include patents or proprietary preparations as hereafter defined.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Patent or proprietary preparation” means a medicine in its unbroken, original package which is sold to the public by, or under the authority of, the manufacturer or primary distributor thereof and which is not misbranded under the provisions of the Florida Drug and Cosmetic Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacist” means any person licensed pursuant to this chapter to practice the profession of pharmacy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacy” includes a community pharmacy, an institutional pharmacy, a nuclear pharmacy, a special pharmacy, and an Internet pharmacy.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “community pharmacy” includes every location where medicinal drugs are compounded, dispensed, stored, or sold or where prescriptions are filled or dispensed on an outpatient basis.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “institutional pharmacy” includes every location in a hospital, clinic, nursing home, dispensary, sanitarium, extended care facility, or other facility, hereinafter referred to as “health care institutions,” where medicinal drugs are compounded, dispensed, stored, or sold.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “nuclear pharmacy” includes every location where radioactive drugs and chemicals within the classification of medicinal drugs are compounded, dispensed, stored, or sold. The term “nuclear pharmacy” does not include hospitals licensed under chapter 395 or the nuclear medicine facilities of such hospitals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “special pharmacy” includes every location where medicinal drugs are compounded, dispensed, stored, or sold if such locations are not otherwise defined in this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “Internet pharmacy” includes locations not otherwise licensed or issued a permit under this chapter, within or outside this state, which use the Internet to communicate with or obtain information from consumers in this state and use such communication or information to fill or refill prescriptions or to dispense, distribute, or otherwise engage in the practice of pharmacy in this state. Any act described in this definition constitutes the practice of pharmacy as defined in subsection (13).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pharmacy department of any permittee shall be considered closed whenever a Florida licensed pharmacist is not present and on duty. The term “not present and on duty” shall not be construed to prevent a pharmacist from exiting the prescription department for the purposes of consulting or responding to inquiries or providing assistance to patients or customers, attending to personal hygiene needs, or performing any other function for which the pharmacist is responsible, provided that such activities are conducted in a manner consistent with the pharmacist’s responsibility to provide pharmacy services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacy intern” means a person who is currently registered in, and attending, a duly accredited college or school of pharmacy, or who is a graduate of such a school or college of pharmacy, and who is duly and properly registered with the department as provided for under its rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of the profession of pharmacy” includes compounding, dispensing, and consulting concerning contents, therapeutic values, and uses of any medicinal drug; consulting concerning therapeutic values and interactions of patent or proprietary preparations, whether pursuant to prescriptions or in the absence and entirely independent of such prescriptions or orders; and other pharmaceutical services. For purposes of this subsection, “other pharmaceutical services” means the monitoring of the patient’s drug therapy and assisting the patient in the management of his or her drug therapy, and includes review of the patient’s drug therapy and communication with the patient’s prescribing health care provider as licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 461, or chapter 466, or similar statutory provision in another jurisdiction, or such provider’s agent or such other persons as specifically authorized by the patient, regarding the drug therapy. However, nothing in this subsection may be interpreted to permit an alteration of a prescriber’s directions, the diagnosis or treatment of any disease, the initiation of any drug therapy, the practice of medicine, or the practice of osteopathic medicine, unless otherwise permitted by law. “Practice of the profession of pharmacy” also includes any other act, service, operation, research, or transaction incidental to, or forming a part of, any of the foregoing acts, requiring, involving, or employing the science or art of any branch of the pharmaceutical profession, study, or training, and shall expressly permit a pharmacist to transmit information from persons authorized to prescribe medicinal drugs to their patients. The practice of the profession of pharmacy also includes the administration of vaccines to adults pursuant to s. 465.189.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescription” includes any order for drugs or medicinal supplies written or transmitted by any means of communication by a duly licensed practitioner authorized by the laws of the state to prescribe such drugs or medicinal supplies and intended to be dispensed by a pharmacist. The term also includes an orally transmitted order by the lawfully designated agent of such practitioner. The term also includes an order written or transmitted by a practitioner licensed to practice in a jurisdiction other than this state, but only if the pharmacist called upon to dispense such order determines, in the exercise of her or his professional judgment, that the order is valid and necessary for the treatment of a chronic or recurrent illness. The term “prescription” also includes a pharmacist’s order for a product selected from the formulary created pursuant to s. 465.186. Prescriptions may be retained in written form or the pharmacist may cause them to be recorded in a data processing system, provided that such order can be produced in printed form upon lawful request.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nuclear pharmacist” means a pharmacist licensed by the department and certified as a nuclear pharmacist pursuant to s. 465.0126.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Centralized prescription filling” means the filling of a prescription by one pharmacy upon request by another pharmacy to fill or refill the prescription. The term includes the performance by one pharmacy for another pharmacy of other pharmacy duties such as drug utilization review, therapeutic drug utilization review, claims adjudication, and the obtaining of refill authorizations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automated pharmacy system” means a mechanical system that delivers prescription drugs received from a Florida licensed pharmacy and maintains related transaction information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 7, ch. 79-226; s. 322, ch. 81-259; ss. 14, 15, ch. 81-302; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 82-179; s. 1, ch. 83-101; s. 36, ch. 83-216; s. 3, ch. 83-265; s. 29, ch. 83-329; s. 1, ch. 85-35; ss. 2, 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 1, ch. 88-172; s. 1, ch. 89-77; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 123, ch. 94-218; s. 239, ch. 97-103; s. 87, ch. 97-264; s. 118, ch. 99-397; s. 1, ch. 2002-182; s. 1, ch. 2004-25; s. 1, ch. 2004-387; s. 2, ch. 2007-152; s. 2, ch. 2012-60.</History>
</Section>