<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.017" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority to inspect; disposal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duly authorized agents and employees of the department shall have the power to inspect in a lawful manner at all reasonable hours any pharmacy, hospital, clinic, wholesale establishment, manufacturer, physician’s office, or any other place in the state in which drugs and medical supplies are manufactured, packed, packaged, made, stored, sold, offered for sale, exposed for sale, or kept for sale for the purpose of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining if any of the provisions of this chapter or any rule promulgated under its authority is being violated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securing samples or specimens of any drug or medical supply after paying or offering to pay for such sample or specimen; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securing such other evidence as may be needed for prosecution under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as permitted by this chapter, and chapters 406, 409, 456, 499, and 893, records maintained in a pharmacy relating to the filling of prescriptions and the dispensing of medicinal drugs shall not be furnished to any person other than to the patient for whom the drugs were dispensed, or her or his legal representative, or to the department pursuant to existing law, or, in the event that the patient is incapacitated or unable to request said records, her or his spouse except upon the written authorization of such patient. Such records may be furnished in any civil or criminal proceeding, upon the issuance of a subpoena from a court of competent jurisdiction and proper notice to the patient or her or his legal representative by the party seeking such records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules to establish practice guidelines for pharmacies to dispose of records maintained in a pharmacy relating to the filling of prescriptions and the dispensing of medicinal drugs. Such rules shall be consistent with the duty to preserve the confidentiality of such records in accordance with applicable state and federal law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 7, ch. 79-226; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-151; ss. 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 125, ch. 94-218; s. 245, ch. 97-103; s. 127, ch. 2000-160; s. 1, ch. 2003-166.</History></Section>