<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0465.019" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Institutional pharmacies; permits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any institution desiring to operate an institutional pharmacy shall apply to the department. If the board certifies that the application complies with the laws of the state and the rules of the board governing pharmacies, the department shall issue the permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following classes of institutional pharmacies are established:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Class I institutional pharmacies” are those institutional pharmacies in which all medicinal drugs are administered from individual prescription containers to the individual patient and in which medicinal drugs are not dispensed on the premises, except that nursing homes licensed under part II of chapter 400 may purchase medical oxygen for administration to residents. No medicinal drugs may be dispensed in a Class I institutional pharmacy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Class II institutional pharmacies” are those institutional pharmacies which employ the services of a registered pharmacist or pharmacists who, in practicing institutional pharmacy, shall provide dispensing and consulting services on the premises to patients of that institution, for use on the premises of that institution. However, an institutional pharmacy located in an area or county included in an emergency order or proclamation of a state of emergency declared by the Governor may provide dispensing and consulting services to individuals who are not patients of the institution. However, a single dose of a medicinal drug may be obtained and administered to a patient on a valid physician’s drug order under the supervision of a physician or charge nurse, consistent with good institutional practice procedures. The obtaining and administering of such single dose of a medicinal drug shall be pursuant to drug-handling procedures established by a consultant pharmacist. Medicinal drugs may be dispensed in a Class II institutional pharmacy, but only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Modified Class II institutional pharmacies” are those institutional pharmacies in short-term, primary care treatment centers that meet all the requirements for a Class II permit, except space and equipment requirements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicinal drugs shall be stocked, stored, compounded, dispensed, or administered in any health care institution only when that institution has secured an institutional pharmacy permit from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicinal drugs shall be dispensed in an institutional pharmacy to outpatients only when that institution has secured a community pharmacy permit from the department. However, an individual licensed to prescribe medicinal drugs in this state may dispense up to a 24-hour supply of a medicinal drug to any patient of an emergency department of a hospital that operates a Class II institutional pharmacy, provided that the physician treating the patient in such hospital’s emergency department determines that the medicinal drug is warranted and that community pharmacy services are not readily accessible, geographically or otherwise, to the patient. Such dispensing from the emergency department must be in accordance with the procedures of the hospital. For any such patient for whom a medicinal drug is warranted for a period to exceed 24 hours, an individual licensed to prescribe such drug must dispense a 24-hour supply of such drug to the patient and must provide the patient with a prescription for such drug for use after the initial 24-hour period. The board may adopt rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All institutional pharmacies shall be under the professional supervision of a consultant pharmacist, and the compounding and dispensing of medicinal drugs shall be done only by a licensed pharmacist. Every institutional pharmacy that employs or otherwise uses registered pharmacy technicians shall have a written policy and procedures manual specifying those duties, tasks, and functions that a registered pharmacy technician is allowed to perform.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a Class II institutional pharmacy, an institutional formulary system may be adopted with approval of the medical staff for the purpose of identifying those medicinal drugs and proprietary preparations that may be dispensed by the pharmacists employed in such institution. A facility with a Class II institutional permit which is operating under the formulary system shall establish policies and procedures for the development of the system in accordance with the joint standards of the American Hospital Association and American Society of Hospital Pharmacists for the utilization of a hospital formulary system, which formulary shall be approved by the medical staff.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 7, ch. 79-226; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 83-101; ss. 26, 27, ch. 86-256; s. 59, ch. 91-137; s. 6, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 29, ch. 93-211; s. 244, ch. 98-166; s. 36, ch. 99-397; s. 79, ch. 2001-277; s. 6, ch. 2008-216.</History></Section>