<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.7015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of rules ombudsman; duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall appoint a rules ombudsman, as defined in s. 288.703, in the Executive Office of the Governor, for considering the impact of agency rules on the state’s citizens and businesses. In carrying out duties as provided by law, the ombudsman shall consult with Enterprise Florida, Inc., at which point the department may recommend to improve the regulatory environment of this state. The duties of the rules ombudsman are to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out the responsibility provided in s. 120.54(2), with respect to small businesses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review state agency rules that adversely or disproportionately impact businesses, particularly those relating to small and minority businesses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make recommendations on any existing or proposed rules to alleviate unnecessary or disproportionate adverse effects to businesses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency shall cooperate fully with the rules ombudsman in identifying such rules. Further, each agency shall take the necessary steps to waive, modify, or otherwise minimize such adverse effects of any such rules. However, nothing in this section authorizes any state agency to waive, modify, provide exceptions to, or otherwise alter any rule that is:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expressly required to implement or enforce any statutory provision or the express legislative intent thereof;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designed to protect persons against discrimination on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, age, handicap, or marital status; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Likely to prevent a significant risk or danger to the public health, the public safety, or the environment of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The modification or waiver of any such rule pursuant to this section must be accomplished in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-320; s. 67, ch. 2010-102; s. 171, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>