<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.955" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scripps Florida Funding Corporation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contract” means the contract executed between the corporation and the grantee under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation” means the Scripps Florida Funding Corporation created under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Grantee” means The Scripps Research Institute, a not-for-profit public benefit corporation, or a division, subsidiary, affiliate, or entity formed by The Scripps Research Institute to establish a state-of-the-art biomedical research institution and campus in this state. The grantee is neither an agency nor an entity acting on behalf of an agency for purposes of chapter 119 and s. 286.011.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a not-for-profit corporation known as the Scripps Florida Funding Corporation, which shall be registered, incorporated, organized, and operated under chapter 617.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is not a unit or entity of state government. However, the corporation is subject to the provisions of s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution and chapter 119, relating to public meetings and records, and the provisions of chapter 286 relating to public meetings and records.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation must establish at least one corporate office in this state and appoint a registered agent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall hire or contract for all staff necessary to the proper execution of its powers and duties within the funds appropriated to implement this section and shall require that all officers, directors, and employees of the corporation comply with the code of ethics for public officers and employees under part III of chapter 112. In no case may the corporation expend more than $300,000 in the first year and $200,000 per year thereafter for staffing and necessary administrative expenditures, including, but not limited to, travel and per diem and audit expenditures, using funds appropriated to implement this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide administrative support to the corporation as requested by the corporation. In the event of the dissolution of the corporation, the department shall be the corporation’s successor in interest and shall assume all rights, duties, and obligations of the corporation under any contract to which the corporation is then a party and under law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The corporation shall be organized to receive, hold, invest, administer, and disburse funds appropriated by the Legislature for the establishment and operation of a state-of-the-art biomedical research institution and campus in this state by The Scripps Research Institute. The corporation shall safeguard the state’s commitment of financial support by ensuring that, as a condition for the receipt of these funds, the grantee meets its contractual obligations. In this manner, the corporation shall facilitate and oversee the state goal and public purpose of providing financial support for the institution and campus in order to expand the amount and prominence of biomedical research conducted in this state, provide an inducement for high-technology businesses to locate in this state, create educational opportunities through access to and partnerships with the institution, and promote improved health care through the scientific outcomes of the institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD; MEMBERSHIP.<EmDash />The corporation shall be governed by a board of directors.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall consist of nine voting members, of whom the Governor shall appoint three, the President of the Senate shall appoint three, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall appoint three. The executive director of the department or the director’s designee shall serve as an ex-officio, nonvoting member of the board of directors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors shall serve for a term of 4 years, except that initially the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives each shall appoint one member for a term of 1 year, one member for a term of 2 years, and one member for a term of 4 years to achieve staggered terms among the members of the board. A member is not eligible for reappointment to the board, except, however, that a member appointed to an initial term of 1 year or 2 years may be reappointed for an additional term of 4 years, and a person appointed to fill a vacancy with 2 years or less remaining on the term may be reappointed for an additional term of 4 years. The Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall make their initial appointments to the board by November 15, 2003.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor, the President of the Senate, or the Speaker of the House of Representatives, respectively, shall fill a vacancy on the board of directors, according to who appointed the member whose vacancy is to be filled or whose term has expired. A vacancy that occurs before the scheduled expiration of the term of the member shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors who is not otherwise required to file financial disclosure under s. 8, Art. II of the State Constitution or s. 112.3144 shall file disclosure of financial interests under s. 112.3145.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not be appointed to the board of directors if he or she has had any direct interest in any contract, franchise, privilege, or other benefit granted by The Scripps Research Institute or any of its affiliate organizations within 5 years before appointment. A person appointed to the board of directors must agree to refrain from having any direct interest in any contract, franchise, privilege, or other benefit granted by The Scripps Research Institute or any of its affiliate organizations during the term of his or her appointment and for 5 years after the termination of such appointment. It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083 or s. 775.084, for a person to accept appointment to the board of directors in violation of this paragraph or to accept a direct interest in any contract, franchise, privilege, or other benefit granted by the institution or affiliate within 5 years after the termination of his or her service on the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors shall serve without compensation, but shall receive travel and per diem expenses as provided in s. 112.061 while in the performance of his or her duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors is accountable for the proper performance of the duties of office, and each member owes a fiduciary duty to the people of the state to ensure that funds provided in furtherance of this section are disbursed and used as prescribed by law and contract. The Governor, the President of the Senate, or the Speaker of the House of Representatives, according to which officer appointed the member, may remove a member for malfeasance, misfeasance, neglect of duty, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, unexcused absence from three consecutive meetings of the board, arrest or indictment for a crime that is a felony or a misdemeanor involving theft or a crime of dishonesty, or pleading nolo contendere to, or being found guilty of, any crime.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ORGANIZATION; MEETINGS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall annually elect a chairperson and a vice chairperson from among the board’s members. The members may, by a vote of five of the nine board members, remove a member from the position of chairperson or vice chairperson prior to the expiration of his or her term as chairperson or vice chairperson. His or her successor shall be elected to serve for the balance of the removed chairperson’s or vice chairperson’s term.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chairperson is responsible to ensure that records are kept of the proceedings of the board of directors and is the custodian of all books, documents, and papers filed with the board; the minutes of meetings of the board; and the official seal of the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall meet upon the call of the chairperson or at the request of a majority of the members, but no less than three times per calendar year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the voting members of the board of directors constitutes a quorum. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the board may take official action by a majority vote of the members present at any meeting at which a quorum is present. Members may not vote by proxy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the board may participate in a meeting of the board by telephone or videoconference through which each member may hear every other member.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS AND DUTIES.<EmDash />The corporation is organized to receive, hold, invest, administer, and disburse funds appropriated by the Legislature in support of this section and to disburse any income generated from the investment of these funds consistent with the purpose and provisions of this section. In addition to the powers and duties prescribed in chapter 617 and the articles and bylaws adopted under that chapter, the corporation:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May make and enter into contracts and assume any other functions that are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May enter into leases and contracts for the purchase of real property and hold notes, mortgages, guarantees, or security agreements to secure the performance of obligations of the grantee under the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May perform all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers expressly granted in this section and a contract entered into between the corporation and the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May make expenditures, from funds provided by this state, including any necessary administrative expenditures consistent with its powers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May indemnify, and purchase and maintain insurance on behalf of, directors, officers, and employees of the corporation against any personal liability or accountability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall disburse funds pursuant to the provisions of this section and a contract entered into between the corporation and the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall receive and review reports and financial documentation provided by the grantee to ensure compliance with the provisions of this section and provisions of the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall prepare an annual report as prescribed in subsection (14).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT OF FUNDS.<EmDash />The corporation must enter into an agreement with the State Board of Administration under which funds received by the corporation from the department which are not disbursed to the grantee shall be invested by the State Board of Administration on behalf of the corporation. Funds shall be invested in suitable instruments authorized under s. 215.47 and specified in investment guidelines established and agreed to by the State Board of Administration and the corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTRACT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 30, 2004, the corporation shall negotiate and execute a contract with the grantee for a term of 20 years. Such contract shall govern the disbursement and use of funds under this section. The board may, by a simple majority vote, authorize one 45-day extension of this deadline. The corporation may not execute the contract unless the contract is approved by the affirmative vote of at least seven of the nine members of the board of directors. At least 14 days before execution of the contract, The Scripps Research Institute must submit to the board, the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives an organizational plan, in a form and manner prescribed by the board, for the establishment of a state-of-the-art biomedical research institution and campus in this state, and the board must submit a copy of the proposed contract to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract, at a minimum, must contain provisions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifying the procedures and schedules that govern the disbursement of funds under this section and specifying the conditions or deliverables that the grantee must satisfy before the release of each disbursement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to submit to the corporation a business plan in a form and manner prescribed by the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prohibiting The Scripps Research Institute or the grantee from establishing other biomedical science or research facilities in any state other than this state or California for a period of 12 years from the commencement of the contract. Nothing in this subparagraph shall prohibit the grantee from establishing or engaging in normal collaborative activities with other organizations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governing the ownership of or security interests in real property and personal property, including, but not limited to, research equipment, obtained through the financial support of state or local government, including a provision that in the event of a breach of the contract or in the event the grantee ceases operations in this state, such property purchased with state funds shall revert to the state and such property purchased with local funds shall revert to the local governing authority.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to be an equal opportunity employer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to maintain a policy of awarding preference in employment to residents of this state, as defined by law, except for professional scientific staff positions requiring a doctoral degree, postdoctoral training positions, and graduate student positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to maintain a policy of making purchases from vendors in this state, to the extent it is cost-effective and scientifically sound.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to use the Internet-based job-listing system of the department in advertising employment opportunities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to establish accredited science degree programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to establish internship programs to create learning opportunities for educators and secondary, postsecondary, graduate, and doctoral students.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to submit data to the corporation on the activities and performance during each fiscal year and to provide to the corporation an annual accounting of the expenditure of funds disbursed under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing that the corporation shall review the activities of the grantee to assess the grantee’s financial and operational compliance with the provisions of the contract and with relevant provisions of law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizing the grantee, when feasible, to use information submitted by it to the Federal Government or to other organizations awarding research grants to the grantee to help meet reporting requirements imposed under this section or the contract, if the information satisfies the reporting standards of this section and the contract.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee during the first 7 years of the contract to create 545 positions and to acquire associated research equipment for the grantee’s facility in this state, and pay for related maintenance of the equipment, in a total amount of not less than $45 million.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to progress in the creation of the total number of jobs prescribed in subparagraph 14. on the following schedule: At least 38 positions in the 1st year, 168 positions in the 2nd year, 280 positions in the 3rd year, 367 positions in the 4th year, 436 positions in the 5th year, 500 positions in the 6th year, and 545 positions in the 7th year. The board may allow the grantee to deviate downward from such employee levels by 25 percent in any year, to allow the grantee flexibility in achieving the objectives set forth in the business plan provided to the corporation; however, the grantee must have no fewer than 545 positions by the end of the 7th year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to allow the corporation to retain an independent certified public accountant licensed in this state pursuant to chapter 473 to inspect the records of the grantee in order to audit the expenditure of funds disbursed to the grantee. The independent certified public accountant shall not disclose any confidential or proprietary scientific information of the grantee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the grantee to purchase liability insurance and governing the coverage level of such insurance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment to the contract is not effective unless it is approved by the affirmative vote of at least seven of the nine members of the board of directors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERFORMANCE EXPECTATIONS.<EmDash />In addition to the provisions prescribed in subsection (8), the contract between the corporation and the grantee shall include a provision that the grantee, in cooperation with the department, shall report to the corporation on performance expectations that reflect the aspirations of the Governor and the Legislature for the benefits accruing to this state as a result of the funds appropriated pursuant to this section. These shall include, but are not limited to, performance expectations addressing:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and dollar value of research grants obtained from the Federal Government or sources other than this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of total research dollars received by The Scripps Research Institute from sources other than this state which is used to conduct research activities by the grantee in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number or value of patents obtained by the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number or value of licensing agreements executed by the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which research conducted by the grantee results in commercial applications.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of collaborative agreements reached and maintained with colleges and universities in this state and with research institutions in this state, including agreements that foster participation in research opportunities by public and private colleges and universities and research institutions in this state with significant minority populations, including historically black colleges and universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of collaborative partnerships established and maintained with businesses in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of funding received by the grantee from sources other than the State of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number or value of spin-off businesses created in this state as a result of commercialization of the research of the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number or value of businesses recruited to this state by the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment and implementation of policies to promote supplier diversity using the guidelines developed by the Office of Supplier Diversity under s. 287.09451 and to comply with the ordinances, including any small business ordinances, enacted by the county and which are applicable to the biomedical research institution and campus located in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designation by the grantee of a representative to coordinate with the Office of Supplier Diversity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment and implementation of a program to conduct workforce recruitment activities at public and private colleges and universities and community colleges in this state which request the participation of the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The contract shall require the grantee to provide information to the corporation on the progress in meeting these performance expectations on an annual basis. It is the intent of the Legislature that, in fulfilling its obligation to work with Florida’s public and private colleges and universities, Scripps Florida work with such colleges and universities regardless of size.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISBURSEMENT CONDITIONS.<EmDash />In addition to the provisions prescribed in subsection (8), the contract between the corporation and the grantee shall include disbursement conditions that must be satisfied by the grantee as a condition for the continued disbursement of funds under this section. These disbursement conditions shall be negotiated between the corporation and the grantee and shall not be designed to impede the ability of the grantee to attain full operational status. The disbursement conditions may be appropriately varied as to timeframes, numbers, values, and percentages. The disbursement conditions shall include, but are not limited to, the following areas:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate creation of jobs and report on the average salaries paid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning 18 months after the grantee’s occupancy of its permanent facility, the grantee shall annually obtain $100,000 of nonstate funding for each full-time equivalent tenured-track faculty member employed at the Florida facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 3 years after the grantee’s occupancy of its permanent facility, the grantee shall apply to the relevant accrediting agency for accreditation of its Florida graduate program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee shall purchase equipment for its Florida facility as scheduled in its contract with the corporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 18 months after occupying its permanent facility, the grantee shall establish a program for qualified graduate students from Florida universities permitting them access to the facility for doctoral, thesis-related research.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 18 months after occupancy of the permanent facility, the grantee shall establish a summer internship for high school students.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 3 years after occupancy of the permanent facility, the grantee shall establish a research program for middle and high school teachers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 18 months after occupancy of the permanent facility, the grantee shall establish a program for adjunct professors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 6 months after commissioning its high throughput technology, the grantee shall establish a program to allow open access for qualified science projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning June 2004, the grantee shall commence collaborative efforts with Florida public and private colleges and universities, and shall continue cooperative collaboration through the term of the agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning 18 months after the grantee occupies the permanent facility, the grantee shall establish an annual seminar series featuring a review of the science work done by the grantee and its collaborators at the Florida facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning June 2004, the grantee shall commence collaboration efforts with the department by complying with reasonable requests for cooperation in economic development efforts in the biomed/biotech industry. No later than July 2004, the grantee shall designate a person who shall be charged with assisting in these collaborative efforts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISBURSEMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall disburse funds to the grantee over a period of 7 calendar years starting in the calendar year beginning January 1, 2004, under the terms and conditions of the contract. The corporation shall complete disbursement of the total amount of funds payable to the grantee under the contract no later than December 31, 2010, unless the grantee fails to satisfy the terms and conditions of the contract. Any funds of the corporation that are not disbursed by December 31, 2010, shall be paid to the Biomedical Research Trust Fund of the Department of Health.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall provide for a reduction or elimination of funding in any year if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee is no longer operating in this state;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee has failed to commit in writing to maintain operations in the state for the succeeding year; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee commits a material default or breach of the contract, as defined and governed by the contract. Determination of material default or breach of contract shall require the affirmative vote of at least seven of the nine members of the board.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each disbursement by the corporation to the grantee under this section is conditioned upon the affirmative approval of at least five of the nine members of the board of directors and upon demonstration by the grantee that it has met the particular contractual deliverables that are the basis for that disbursement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF FUNDS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated in furtherance of this section may not be disbursed or expended for activities that do not principally benefit or that are not directly related to the establishment or operation of the grantee in this state, except upon approval of the affirmative vote of at least seven of the nine members of the board of directors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No funds appropriated in furtherance of this section may be used for the purpose of lobbying any branch or agency of state government or any political subdivision of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee must provide for separate accounts for any funds appropriated in furtherance of this section and separate books and records relating to The Scripps Research Institute’s Florida operation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REINVESTMENT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee shall reinvest 15 percent of the net royalty revenues, including the revenues from the sale of stock, received by The Scripps Research Institute from the licensing or transfer of inventions, methods, processes, and other patentable discoveries conceived or reduced to practice using the grantee’s Florida facilities or Florida employees, in whole or in part, and to which the grantee becomes entitled during the 20 years following the effective date of the contract between the corporation and the grantee. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “net royalty revenues” means all royalty revenues less the cost of obtaining, maintaining, and enforcing related patent and intellectual property rights, both foreign and domestic. Reinvestment payments under this paragraph shall commence no later than 6 months after the grantee has received the final disbursement under the contract and shall continue until the maximum reinvestment has been paid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee shall reinvest 15 percent of the gross revenues it receives from naming opportunities associated with any facility it builds in this state. For purposes of this section, the term “naming opportunities” includes charitable donations from any person or entity in consideration for the right to have all or a portion of the facility named for or in the memory of any person, living or dead, or for any entity. The obligation to make reinvestment payments under this section shall commence upon the execution of the contract between the corporation and the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All reinvestment payments made pursuant to this section shall be remitted to the state for deposit in the Biomedical Research Trust Fund or, if such fund has ceased to exist, in another trust fund that supports biomedical research, as determined by law. The maximum reinvestment required of the grantee pursuant to this subsection shall not exceed $200 million. At such time as the reinvestment payments equal $155 million or the contract expires, whichever is earlier, the board of the corporation shall determine whether the performance expectations and disbursement conditions have been met. If the board determines that the performance expectations and disbursement conditions have been met, the amount of $200 million shall be reduced to $155 million. The grantee shall annually submit a schedule of the shares of stock held by it as payment of the royalty referred to in paragraph (a) and report on any trades or activity concerning such stock. The grantee’s obligations under this subsection shall survive the expiration or termination of the contract between the corporation and the grantee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL REPORT.<EmDash />By December 1 of each year, the corporation shall prepare a report of the activities and outcomes under this section for the preceding fiscal year. The report, at a minimum, must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the activities of the corporation in managing and enforcing the contract with the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accounting of the amount of funds disbursed during the preceding fiscal year to the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accounting of expenditures by the grantee during the fiscal year of funds disbursed under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information on the number and salary level of jobs created by the grantee, including the number and salary level of jobs created for residents of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information on the amount and nature of economic activity generated through the activities of the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of factors affecting the progress toward achieving the projected biotech industry cluster associated with the grantee’s operations, as projected by economists on behalf of the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A compliance and financial audit of the accounts and records of the corporation at the end of the preceding fiscal year conducted by an independent certified public accountant in accordance with rules of the Auditor General.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the status of the performance expectations under subsection (9) and the disbursement conditions under subsection (10).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The corporation shall submit the report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIABILITY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriation or disbursement of funds under this section does not constitute a debt, liability, or obligation of the State of Florida, any political subdivision thereof, or the corporation or a pledge of the faith and credit of the state or of any such political subdivision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriation or disbursement of funds under this section does not subject the State of Florida, any political subdivision thereof, or the corporation to liability related to the research activities and research products of the grantee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FORCE MAJEURE.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provisions contained in this act, if the grantee is prevented from timely achieving any deadlines set forth in this act due to its inability to occupy its permanent Florida facility within 2 years after entering into the memorandum of agreement pursuant to s. 403.973, as a result of permitting delays and related administrative or judicial proceedings, acts of God, labor disturbances, or other similar events beyond the control of the grantee, the deadline shall be extended by the number of days by which the grantee was delayed in commencing its occupancy of its permanent Florida facility. In no event shall the extension be for more than 4 years. Upon the occurrence of a force majeure event, the Scripps Florida Funding Corporation shall continue to fund the grantee at a level that permits it to sustain its current level of operations until the force majeure event ceases and the grantee is able to resume the contract schedule governing disbursement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 2003-420; s. 1, ch. 2009-236; s. 187, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 4, ch. 2003-420, provides that “[n]otwithstanding any other provision of law, the county in which the projects that are part of or ancillary to the state-of-the-art biomedical research institution and campus to be established in this state by the grantee under section 288.955, Florida Statutes, are to be located shall have the exclusive right, which right may be assigned in whole or in part by the governing body of the county in its sole discretion, to provide water and wastewater services to such projects to the extent deemed necessary by the governing body of the county. The county may plan, acquire, construct, reconstruct, enlarge or extend, operate, and maintain water and wastewater systems and facilities within or without the boundaries of such projects for the provision of water and wastewater services.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>