<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.904" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Funding for Enterprise Florida, Inc.; performance and return on the public’s investment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature may annually appropriate to Enterprise Florida, Inc., a sum of money for its operations, and separate line-item appropriations for each of the divisions listed in s. 288.92.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state’s operating investment in Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions is the budget contracted by the department to Enterprise Florida, Inc., less any funding that is directed by the Legislature to be subcontracted to a specific recipient entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall adopt for each upcoming fiscal year an operating budget for the organization, including its divisions, which specifies the intended uses of the state’s operating investment and a plan for securing private sector support.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that it is a priority to maximize private sector support in operating Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions, as an endorsement of its value and as an enhancement of its efforts. Thus, the state appropriations must be matched with private sector support equal to at least 100 percent of the state operational funding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private sector support in operating Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions includes:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash given directly to Enterprise Florida, Inc., for its operations, including contributions from at-large members of the board of directors;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash donations from organizations assisted by the divisions;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash jointly raised by Enterprise Florida, Inc., and a private local economic development organization, a group of such organizations, or a statewide private business organization that supports collaborative projects;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash generated by fees charged for products or services of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions by sponsorship of events, missions, programs, and publications; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copayments, stock, warrants, royalties, or other private resources dedicated to Enterprise Florida, Inc., or its divisions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifically for the marketing and advertising activities of the Division of Tourism Marketing or as contracted through the Florida Tourism Industry Corporation, a one-to-one match is required of private to public contributions within 4 calendar years after the implementation date of the marketing plan pursuant to s. 288.923.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of calculating the required one-to-one match, matching private funds shall be divided into four categories. Documentation for the components of the four private match categories shall be kept on file for inspection as determined necessary. The four private match categories are:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct cash contributions, which include, but are not limited to, cash derived from strategic alliances, contributions of stocks and bonds, and partnership contributions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees for services, which include, but are not limited to, event participation, research, and brochure placement and transparencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperative advertising, which is the value based on cost of contributed productions, air time, and print space.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In-kind contributions, which include, but are not limited to, the value of strategic alliance services contributed, the value of loaned employees, discounted service fees, items contributed for use in promotions, and radio or television air time or print space for promotions. The value of air time or print space shall be calculated by taking the actual time or space and multiplying by the nonnegotiated unit price for that specific time or space which is known as the media equivalency value. In order to avoid duplication in determining media equivalency value, only the value of the promotion itself shall be included; the value of the items contributed for the promotion may not be included.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall fully comply with the performance measures, standards, and sanctions in its contract with the department, under s. 20.60. The department shall ensure, to the maximum extent possible, that the contract performance measures are consistent with performance measures that it is required to develop and track under performance-based program budgeting. The contract shall also include performance measures for the divisions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature intends to review the performance of Enterprise Florida, Inc., in achieving the performance goals stated in its annual contract with the department to determine whether the public is receiving a positive return on its investment in Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions. It also is the intent of the Legislature that Enterprise Florida, Inc., coordinate its operations with local economic development organizations to maximize the state and local return on investment to create jobs for Floridians.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the annual report required under s. 288.906, Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall provide the Legislature with information quantifying the return on the public’s investment each fiscal year. Enterprise Florida, Inc., in consultation with the Office of Economic and Demographic Research, shall hire an economic analysis firm to develop the methodology for establishing and reporting the return on the public’s investment and in-kind contributions as described in this section. The Office of Economic and Demographic Research shall review and offer feedback on the methodology before it is implemented.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 92-277; s. 84, ch. 96-320; s. 31, ch. 97-278; s. 31, ch. 99-251; s. 81, ch. 2000-165; s. 7, ch. 2005-66; s. 71, ch. 2010-102; s. 25, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>