<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Economic development incentive application process.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving a submitted economic development incentive application, the Division of Strategic Business Development of the Department of Economic Opportunity and designated staff of Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall review the application to ensure that the application is complete, whether and what type of state and local permits may be necessary for the applicant’s project, whether it is possible to waive such permits, and what state incentives and amounts of such incentives may be available to the applicant. The department shall recommend to the executive director to approve or disapprove an applicant business. If review of the application demonstrates that the application is incomplete, the executive director shall notify the applicant business within the first 5 business days after receiving the application.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 business days after the department receives the submitted economic development incentive application, the executive director shall approve or disapprove the application and issue a letter of certification to the applicant which includes a justification of that decision, unless the business requests an extension of that time.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract or agreement with the applicant shall specify the total amount of the award, the performance conditions that must be met to obtain the award, the schedule for payment, and sanctions that would apply for failure to meet performance conditions. The department may enter into one agreement or contract covering all of the state incentives that are being provided to the applicant. The contract must provide that release of funds is contingent upon sufficient appropriation of funds by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The release of funds for the incentive or incentives awarded to the applicant depends upon the statutory requirements of the particular incentive program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall validate contractor performance. Such validation shall be reported in the annual incentive report required under s. 288.907.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2009-51; s. 18, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>