<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0288.854" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Support for a free and independent Cuba.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the policy of Florida to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Support the self-determination of the Cuban people.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitate a peaceful transition to representative democracy and a free market economy in Cuba.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be impartial toward any individual or entity in the selection by the Cuban people of their future government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once the President has determined that a democratically elected government exists in Cuba, the Legislature of Florida supports the United States policy to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restore diplomatic recognition and support the reintegration of Cuba into entities of the Inter-American System.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remove the economic embargo.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursue a mutually beneficial trading relationship.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida’s participation in the economic embargo on Cuba shall be terminated by Florida upon transmittal to Congress of a presidential determination that a democratically elected government is in power in Cuba.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this act, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “transition government in Cuba” means one which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is demonstrably in transition from communist totalitarian dictatorship to democracy.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has released all political prisoners.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has dissolved the present Department of State Security in the Cuban Ministry of the Interior.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also “makes public commitments” to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing an independent judiciary.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Respecting internationally recognized human rights and basic freedoms.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guaranteeing the rights of free speech and freedom of the press.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permitting the reinstatement of citizenship to Cuban-born nationals returning to Cuba.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizing free and fair elections for a new government.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assuring the right to private property.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking appropriate steps either to return to United States citizens property taken by the government of Cuba on or after January 1, 1959, or to provide equitable compensation to United States citizens for such property.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a currency that is fully convertible domestically and internationally.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Granting permits to privately owned telecommunications and media companies to operate in Cuba.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allowing the establishment of an independent labor movement and of independent social, economic, and political associations.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not include Fidel Castro or Raul Castro.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has given adequate assurances that it will allow the speedy and efficient distribution of assistance to the Cuban people.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits the deployment throughout Cuba of independent and unfettered international human rights monitors.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “democratic government in Cuba” means one which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is the product of free and fair elections in which opposition parties had sufficient time to organize and were permitted full access to media.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is showing respect for basic civil liberties and human rights.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has established an independent judiciary.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is moving toward a market-oriented economic system based on the right to own and enjoy property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is committed to making constitutional changes that would ensure regular free and fair elections.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has returned to United States citizens, and entities which are 50 percent or more beneficially owned by United States citizens, property taken by the government of Cuba from such citizens and entities on or after January 1, 1959, or provides full compensation in accordance with international law standards.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 96-188.</History></Section>