<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">One-Stop Business Registration Portal.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1, 2013, the Department of Revenue shall establish and implement the One-Stop Business Registration Portal that, through an Internet website, provides individuals and businesses with a single point of entry for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completing and submitting applications for various licenses, registrations, or permits that must be issued by a state department or agency in order for the applicants to transact business in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing various documents that must be filed with a state department or agency in order for the filers to transact business in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remitting payment for various fees that must be paid to a state department or agency, including, but not limited to, application fees, license fees, registration fees, permit fees, and filing fees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue, after establishment of the Internet website for the One-Stop Business Registration Portal, shall implement, in the most timely manner practicable, the capabilities described in subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may competitively procure and contract for services to develop and maintain the Internet website for the One-Stop Business Registration Portal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following departments shall cooperate with the Department of Revenue in the development and implementation of the One-Stop Business Registration Portal:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Financial Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of the Lottery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1 of each year, beginning in 2013, the Department of Revenue shall submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives on the implementation of the One-Stop Business Registration Portal. The report must include a complete and detailed description of the department’s activities and accomplishments related to implementation of the One-Stop Business Registration Portal during the previous calendar year. The report must also include a plan for expansion of the One-Stop Business Registration Portal to allow individuals and businesses to submit applications through the portal for various licenses, registrations, or permits issued by local governments. The report may also include recommendations for improving the effectiveness of the One-Stop Business Registration Portal and increasing participation by state departments and agencies and local governments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may provide information relative to this section to each state department or agency and local government that, in the conduct of its official duties, participates in the One-Stop Business Registration Portal. However, to the extent that such information is not otherwise confidential, information collected from an individual or business by a state department or agency or local government does not become confidential solely because the information is collected through the One-Stop Business Registration Portal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 99-244; s. 8, ch. 2000-197; s. 6, ch. 2001-278; s. 51, ch. 2002-20; s. 23, ch. 2003-1; s. 342, ch. 2003-261; s. 156, ch. 2011-142; s. 1, ch. 2012-139.</History>
</Section>