<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.1252" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Film and Entertainment Advisory Council; creation; purpose; membership; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREATION.<EmDash />There is created within the department, for administrative purposes only, the Florida Film and Entertainment Advisory Council.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The purpose of the council is to serve as an advisory body to the department and to the Office of Film and Entertainment to provide these offices with industry insight and expertise related to developing, marketing, promoting, and providing service to the state’s entertainment industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEMBERSHIP.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall consist of 17 members, 7 to be appointed by the Governor, 5 to be appointed by the President of the Senate, and 5 to be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When making appointments to the council, the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall appoint persons who are residents of the state and who are highly knowledgeable of, active in, and recognized leaders in Florida’s motion picture, television, video, sound recording, or other entertainment industries. These persons shall include, but not be limited to, representatives of local film commissions, representatives of entertainment associations, a representative of the broadcast industry, representatives of labor organizations in the entertainment industry, and board chairs, presidents, chief executive officers, chief operating officers, or persons of comparable executive position or stature of leading or otherwise important entertainment industry businesses and offices. Council members shall be appointed in such a manner as to equitably represent the broadest spectrum of the entertainment industry and geographic areas of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Council members shall serve for 4-year terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent appointments shall be made by the official who appointed the council member whose expired term is to be filled.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> A representative of Enterprise Florida, Inc., a representative of Workforce Florida, Inc., and a representative of VISIT Florida shall serve as ex officio, nonvoting members of the council, and shall be in addition to the 17 appointed members of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Absence from three consecutive meetings shall result in automatic removal from the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy on the council shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term by the official who appointed the vacating member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than one member of the council may be an employee of any one company, organization, or association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member shall be eligible for reappointment but may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEETINGS; ORGANIZATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet no less frequently than once each quarter of the calendar year, but may meet more often as set by the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall annually elect from its appointed membership one member to serve as chair of the council and one member to serve as vice chair. The Office of Film and Entertainment shall provide staff assistance to the council, which shall include, but not be limited to, keeping records of the proceedings of the council, and serving as custodian of all books, documents, and papers filed with the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the members of the council shall constitute a quorum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses in accordance with s. 112.061 while in performance of their duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS AND DUTIES.<EmDash />The Florida Film and Entertainment Advisory Council shall have all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this act, including, but not limited to, the power to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt bylaws for the governance of its affairs and the conduct of its business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consult with the Office of Film and Entertainment on the content, development, and implementation of the 5-year strategic plan to guide the activities of the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the Commissioner of Film and Entertainment’s administration of the programs related to the strategic plan, and advise the commissioner on the programs and any changes that might be made to better meet the strategic plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider and study the needs of the entertainment industry for the purpose of advising the film commissioner and the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and make recommendations on state agency and local government actions that may have an impact on the entertainment industry or that may appear to industry representatives as an official state or local action affecting production in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider all matters submitted to it by the film commissioner and the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consult with the film commissioner and the department, at their request or upon its own initiative, regarding the promulgation, administration, and enforcement of all laws and rules relating to the entertainment industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suggest policies and practices for the conduct of business by the Office of Film and Entertainment or by the department that will improve internal operations affecting the entertainment industry and will enhance the economic development initiatives of the state for the industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appear on its own behalf before boards, commissions, departments, or other agencies of municipal, county, or state government, or the Federal Government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 99-251; s. 6, ch. 2001-106; s. 26, ch. 2010-147; s. 168, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>