<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0288.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financing construction or acquisition of roads and bridges; additional method.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of any county, any road or bridge district, or any authority, evidenced by a resolution duly adopted by the governing body thereof, the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration is authorized and empowered to issue and sell interest-bearing bonds, notes, or certificates in its own name for and on behalf of said county, road or bridge district, or authority, for the purpose of financing the construction of roads or bridges within the county, district, or authority, or the acquisition of rights-of-way for such roads. The governing body of the county, district, or authority may request in said resolution that the division construct or acquire said project by and through its statutory agent, the Department of Transportation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county, road or bridge district, or authority making application to the Division of Bond Finance pursuant to this section may prescribe the terms, conditions, and limitations under which said bonds, notes, or certificates shall be issued and sold and the proceeds of the sale of said bonds, notes, and certificates shall be applied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds, notes, or certificates issued by the division pursuant to this section may be secured by and payable as to both principal and interest, in whole or in part, from the 20-percent surplus gasoline tax funds accruing under the provisions of s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution, tolls or other revenue derived from the operation of the project, or ad valorem taxes or any combination thereof that may be legally available to said county, road or bridge district, or authority. If authorized by the Department of Transportation bonds, notes, or certificates may be additionally secured by and payable as to both principal and interest from legally available 80-percent surplus gasoline tax funds accruing to the Department of Transportation under the provisions of s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is intended to be cumulative of other powers granted to the Division of Bond Finance, the Department of Transportation, the counties, districts, and authorities under other provisions of law and is not intended to repeal, abrogate, or modify any such provisions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-433; ss. 22, 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 18, ch. 69-216; s. 272, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326.</History></Section>