<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.9015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of Enterprise Florida, Inc.; board of directors.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall integrate its efforts in business recruitment and expansion, job creation, marketing the state for tourism and sports, and promoting economic opportunities for minority-owned businesses and promoting economic opportunities for rural and distressed urban communities with those of the department, to create an aggressive, agile, and collaborative effort to reinvigorate the state’s economy.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of Enterprise Florida, Inc., may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure funding for its programs and activities, and for its boards from federal, state, local, and private sources and from fees charged for services and published materials.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicit, receive, hold, invest, and administer any grant, payment, or gift of funds or property and make expenditures consistent with the powers granted to it.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and enter into contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient for the exercise of its powers and functions. A contract executed by Enterprise Florida, Inc., with a person or organization under which such person or organization agrees to perform economic development services or similar business assistance services on behalf of Enterprise Florida, Inc., or the state must include provisions requiring a performance report on the contracted activities and must account for the proper use of funds provided under the contract, coordinate with other components of state and local economic development systems, and avoid duplication of existing state and local services and activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Elect or appoint such officers, employees, and agents as required for its activities and for its divisions and pay such persons reasonable compensation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry forward any unexpended state appropriations into succeeding fiscal years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create and dissolve advisory councils pursuant to s. 288.92, working groups, task forces, or similar organizations, as necessary to carry out its mission. Members of advisory councils, working groups, task forces, or similar organizations created by Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for reasonable, necessary, and actual expenses, as determined by the board of directors of Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish an executive committee consisting of the chairperson or a designee, the vice chairperson, and as many additional members of the board of directors as the board deems appropriate, except that such committee must have a minimum of five members. The executive committee shall have such authority as the board of directors delegates to it, except that the board may not delegate the authority to hire or fire the president or the authority to establish or adjust the compensation paid to the president.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued, and appear and defend in all actions and proceedings, in its corporate name to the same extent as a natural person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, use, and alter a common corporate seal for Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions. Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 617 to the contrary, this seal is not required to contain the words “corporation not for profit.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, not inconsistent with the powers granted to it or the articles of incorporation, for the administration of the activities of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and the exercise of its corporate powers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire, enjoy, use, and dispose of patents, copyrights, and trademarks and any licenses, royalties, and other rights or interests thereunder or therein.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the state seal, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 15.03, when appropriate, for standard corporate identity applications. Use of the state seal is not intended to replace use of a corporate seal as provided in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procure insurance or require bond against any loss in connection with the property of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions, in such amounts and from such insurers as is necessary or desirable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers granted to Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall be liberally construed in order that Enterprise Florida, Inc., may pursue and succeed in its responsibilities under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under no circumstances may the credit of the State of Florida be pledged on behalf of Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any indemnification available under chapter 617, Enterprise Florida, Inc., may indemnify, and purchase and maintain insurance on behalf of, its directors, officers, and employees of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions against any personal liability or accountability by reason of actions taken while acting within the scope of their authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 81, ch. 96-320; s. 29, ch. 97-278; s. 28, ch. 99-251; s. 14, ch. 2001-201; s. 10, ch. 2002-180; s. 5, ch. 2005-66; s. 64, ch. 2006-60; s. 6, ch. 2006-291; s. 11, ch. 2006-301; s. 16, ch. 2007-157; s. 58, ch. 2008-4; s. 24, ch. 2009-51; s. 1, ch. 2010-143; s. 23, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>