<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.9604" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of the authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> There is created a public body corporate and politic known as the “Florida Development Finance Corporation.” The corporation shall be constituted as a public instrumentality, and the exercise by the corporation of the powers conferred by this act shall be deemed and held to be the performance of an essential public function. The corporation has the power to function within the corporate limits of any public agency with which it has entered into an interlocal agreement for any of the purposes of this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate, shall appoint the board of directors of the corporation, who shall be five in number. The terms of office for the directors shall be for 4 years from the date of their appointment. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled for the unexpired term. A director shall be eligible for reappointment. At least three of the directors of the corporation shall be bankers who have been selected by the Governor from a list of bankers who were nominated by Enterprise Florida, Inc., and one of the directors shall be an economic development specialist.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director shall receive no compensation for his or her services, but is entitled to the necessary expenses, including travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of his or her duties. Each director shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of the corporation shall be exercised by the directors thereof. A majority of the directors constitutes a quorum for the purposes of conducting business and exercising the powers of the corporation and for all other purposes. Action may be taken by the corporation upon a vote of a majority of the directors present, unless in any case the bylaws require a larger number. Any person may be appointed as director if he or she resides, or is engaged in business, which means owning a business, practicing a profession, or performing a service for compensation or serving as an officer or director of a corporation or other business entity so engaged, within the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directors of the corporation shall annually elect one of their members as chair and one as vice chair. The corporation may employ a president, technical experts, and such other agents and employees, permanent and temporary, as it requires and determine their qualifications, duties, and compensation. For such legal services as it requires, the corporation may employ or retain its own counsel and legal staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may remove a director for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or misconduct in office only after a hearing and only if he or she has been given a copy of the charges at least 10 days before such hearing and has had an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel. The removal of a director shall create a vacancy on the board which shall be filled pursuant to subsection (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 28, 62, ch. 93-187; s. 1, ch. 93-402; s. 11, ch. 94-136; s. 882, ch. 95-148; s. 101, ch. 96-320; s. 43, ch. 97-100; s. 41, ch. 99-251; s. 38, ch. 2002-1; s. 73, ch. 2010-102; s. 4, ch. 2010-139; s. 15, ch. 2011-4; s. 188, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>