<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.1171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motorsports entertainment complex; definitions; certification; duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means the owner of a motorsports entertainment complex.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motorsports entertainment complex” means a closed-course racing facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motorsports event” means a motorsports race that has been sanctioned by a sanctioning body.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means a unit of local government which owns a motorsports entertainment complex or owns the land on which the motorsports entertainment complex is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sanctioning body” means the American Motorcycle Association (AMA), Championship Auto Racing Teams (CART), Grand American Road Racing Association (Grand Am), Indy Racing League (IRL), National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing (NASCAR), National Hot Rod Association (NHRA), Professional Sportscar Racing (PSR), Sports Car Club of America (SCCA), United States Auto Club (USAC), or any successor organization, or any other nationally recognized governing body of motorsports which establishes an annual schedule of motorsports events and grants rights to conduct such events, has established and administers rules and regulations governing all participants involved in such events and all persons conducting such events, and requires certain liability assurances, including insurance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unit of local government” has the meaning ascribed in s. 218.369.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall serve as the state agency for screening applicants for local option funding under s. 218.64(3) and for certifying an applicant as a motorsports entertainment complex. The department shall develop and adopt rules for the receipt and processing of applications for funding under s. 218.64(3). The department shall make a determination regarding any application filed by an applicant not later than 120 days after the application is filed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before certifying an applicant as a motorsports entertainment complex, the department must determine that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit of local government holds title to the land on which the motorsports entertainment complex is located or holds title to the motorsports entertainment complex.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The municipality in which the motorsports entertainment complex is located, or the county if the motorsports entertainment complex is located in an unincorporated area, has certified by resolution after a public hearing that the application serves a public purpose.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determining that an applicant meets the requirements of subsection (3), the department shall notify the applicant and the executive director of the Department of Revenue of such certification by means of an official letter granting certification. If the applicant fails to meet the certification requirements of subsection (3), the department shall notify the applicant not later than 10 days following such determination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motorsports entertainment complex that has been previously certified under this section and has received funding under such certification is ineligible for any additional certification.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant certified as a motorsports entertainment complex may use funds provided pursuant to s. 218.64(3) only for the following public purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying for the construction, reconstruction, expansion, or renovation of a motorsports entertainment complex.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying debt service reserve funds, arbitrage rebate obligations, or other amounts payable with respect to bonds issued for the construction, reconstruction, expansion, or renovation of the motorsports entertainment complex or for the reimbursement of such costs or the refinancing of bonds issued for such purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying for construction, reconstruction, expansion, or renovation of transportation or other infrastructure improvements related to, necessary for, or appurtenant to the motorsports entertainment complex, including, without limitation, paying debt service reserve funds, arbitrage rebate obligations, or other amounts payable with respect to bonds issued for the construction, reconstruction, expansion, or renovation of such transportation or other infrastructure improvements, and for the reimbursement of such costs or the refinancing of bonds issued for such purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying for programs of advertising and promotion of or related to the motorsports entertainment complex or the municipality in which the motorsports entertainment complex is located, or the county if the motorsports entertainment complex is located in an unincorporated area, if such programs of advertising and promotion are designed to increase paid attendance at the motorsports entertainment complex or increase tourism in or promote the economic development of the community in which the motorsports entertainment complex is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may audit, as provided in s. 213.34, to verify that the distributions pursuant to this section have been expended as required in this section. Such information is subject to the confidentiality requirements of chapter 213. If the Department of Revenue determines that the distributions pursuant to certification under this section have not been expended as required by this section, it may pursue recovery of such funds pursuant to the laws and rules governing the assessment of taxes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-262; s. 162, ch. 2011-142; s. 43, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>