<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.905" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">President and employees of Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Catchline>

	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall appoint a president, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. The president shall also be known as the “secretary of commerce” and shall serve as the Governor’s chief negotiator for business recruitment and business expansion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president is the chief administrative and operational officer of the board of directors and of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and shall direct and supervise the administrative affairs of the board of directors and any divisions, councils, or boards. The board of directors may delegate to the president those powers and responsibilities it deems appropriate, including hiring and management of all staff, except for the appointment of a president.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall establish and adjust the president’s compensation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No employee of Enterprise Florida, Inc., may receive compensation for employment that exceeds the salary paid to the Governor, unless the board of directors and the employee have executed a contract that prescribes specific, measurable performance outcomes for the employee, the satisfaction of which provides the basis for the award of incentive payments that increase the employee’s total compensation to a level above the salary paid to the Governor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>

	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 92-277; s. 85, ch. 96-320; s. 42, ch. 97-100; s. 32, ch. 97-278; s. 71, ch. 99-13; s. 32, ch. 99-251; s. 82, ch. 2000-165; s. 5, ch. 2000-317; s. 28, ch. 2005-2; s. 26, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>