<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.714" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Quarterly and annual reports.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each recipient of state funds under s. 288.7102 shall provide to the department a quarterly report within 15 days after the end of each calendar quarter that includes a detailed summary of the recipient’s performance of the duties imposed by s. 288.7102, including, but not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dollar amount of all loans or loan guarantees made to black business enterprises, the percentages of the loans guaranteed, and the names and identification of the types of businesses served.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loan performance information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and nature of all other financial assistance provided to black business enterprises.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and nature of technical assistance provided to black business enterprises, including technical assistance services provided in areas in which such services are otherwise unavailable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A balance sheet for the recipient, including an explanation of all investments and administrative and operational expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of all services provided to nonblack business enterprises, including the dollar value and nature of such services and the names and identification of the types of businesses served.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information as required by policies adopted by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must compile a summary of all quarterly reports within 30 days after the end of each calendar quarter which includes a detailed summary of the recipient’s performance of the duties imposed by s. 288.7102.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By August 31 of each year, the department shall provide to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a detailed report of the performance of the Black Business Loan Program. The report must include a cumulative summary of quarterly report data required by subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 85-104; s. 4, ch. 89-352; s. 66, ch. 96-320; s. 8, ch. 2002-180; s. 5, ch. 2003-268; s. 15, ch. 2007-157; s. 7, ch. 2010-39; s. 177, ch. 2011-142; s. 45, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>