<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.7102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Black Business Loan Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Black Business Loan Program is established in the department, which shall annually certify eligible recipients and subsequently disburse funds appropriated by the Legislature, through such eligible recipients, to black business enterprises that cannot obtain capital through conventional lending institutions but that could otherwise compete successfully in the private sector.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish an application and annual certification process for entities seeking funds to participate in providing loans, loan guarantees, or investments in black business enterprises pursuant to the Florida Black Business Investment Act. The department shall process all applications and recertifications submitted by June 1 on or before July 31.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Black Business Loan Program is appropriated any funding in a fiscal year, the department shall distribute an equal amount of the appropriation, calculated as the total annual appropriation divided by the total number of program recipients certified on or before July 31 of that fiscal year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to receive funds and provide loans, loan guarantees, or investments under this section, a recipient must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a corporation registered in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an existing recipient, annually submit to the department a financial audit performed by an independent certified public accountant for the most recently completed fiscal year, which audit does not reveal any material weaknesses or instances of material noncompliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a new recipient:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that its board of directors includes citizens of the state experienced in the development of black business enterprises.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that the recipient has a business plan that allows the recipient to operate in a manner consistent with this section and the rules of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that the recipient has the technical skills to analyze and evaluate applications by black business enterprises for loans, loan guarantees, or investments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that the recipient has established viable partnerships with public and private funding sources, economic development agencies, and workforce development and job referral networks.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that the recipient can provide a private match equal to 20 percent of the amount of funds provided by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an existing or new recipient, agree to maintain the recipient’s books and records relating to funds received by the department according to generally accepted accounting principles and in accordance with the requirements of s. 215.97(7) and to make those books and records available to the department for inspection upon reasonable notice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each eligible recipient must meet the requirements of this section, the terms of the contract between the recipient and the department, and any other applicable state or federal laws. An entity may not receive funds unless the entity meets annual certification requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval by the department and before release of the funds as provided in this section, the department shall issue a letter certifying the applicant as qualified for an award. The department and the applicant shall enter into an agreement that sets forth the conditions for award of the funds. The agreement must include the total amount of funds awarded; the performance conditions that must be met once the funding has been awarded, including, but not limited to, compliance with all of the requirements of this section for eligible recipients of funds under this section; and sanctions for failure to meet performance conditions, including any provisions to recover awards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A black business investment corporation certified by the department as an eligible recipient under this section is authorized to use funds appropriated for the Black Business Loan Program in any of the following forms:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchases of stock, preferred or common, voting or nonvoting; however, no more than 40 percent of the funds may be used for direct investments in black business enterprises;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loans or loan guarantees, with or without recourse, in either a subordinated or priority position; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Technical support to black business enterprises, not to exceed 9 percent of the funds received, and direct administrative costs, not to exceed 12 percent of the funds received.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that if any one type of investment mechanism authorized in subsection (8) is held to be invalid, all other valid mechanisms remain available.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All loans, loan guarantees, and investments, and any income related thereto, shall be used to carry out the public purpose to develop black business enterprises. This subsection does not preclude a reasonable profit for the participating black business investment corporation or for return of equity developed to the state and participating financial institutions upon any distribution of the assets or excess income of the investment corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2007-157; s. 2, ch. 2008-140; s. 4, ch. 2010-39; s. 176, ch. 2011-142; s. 34, ch. 2012-5; s. 46, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>