<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.906" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual report of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions; audits.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before December 1 of each year, Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Senate Minority Leader, and the House Minority Leader a complete and detailed report including, but not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the operations and accomplishments of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions, boards, and advisory councils or similar entities created by Enterprise Florida, Inc., and an identification of any major trends, initiatives, or developments affecting the performance of any program or activity. The individual annual reports prepared by each division shall be included as addenda.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An evaluation of progress toward achieving organizational goals and specific performance outcomes, both short-term and long-term, established pursuant to this part or under the agreement with the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Methods for implementing and funding the operations of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions, including the private sector support required under s. 288.904.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the operations and accomplishments of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions with respect to aggressively marketing Florida’s rural communities and distressed urban communities as locations for potential new investment and job creation, aggressively assisting in the creation, retention, and expansion of existing businesses and job growth in these communities, and aggressively assisting these communities in the identification and development of new economic development opportunities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description and evaluation of the operations and accomplishments of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and its divisions with respect to interaction with local and private economic development organizations, including the identification of each organization that is a primary partner and any specific programs or activities which promoted the activities of such organizations and an identification of any specific programs or activities that promoted a comprehensive and coordinated approach to economic development in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of job creation that directly benefits participants in the welfare transition program or other programs designed to put long-term unemployed persons back to work.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of a customer-satisfaction survey of businesses served. The survey shall be conducted by an independent entity with expertise in survey research that is under contract with Enterprise Florida, Inc., to develop, analyze, and report the results.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual compliance and financial audit of accounts and records by an independent certified public accountant at the end of its most recent fiscal year performed in accordance with rules adopted by the Auditor General.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The detailed report required by this section shall also include the information identified in subsection (1), if applicable, for each division established within Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 92-277; s. 231, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 95-369; s. 86, ch. 96-320; s. 145, ch. 96-406; s. 33, ch. 97-278; s. 33, ch. 99-251; s. 83, ch. 2000-165; s. 141, ch. 2001-266; s. 27, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>