<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0288.976" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Military base closure and reuse.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State agencies and departments shall, consistent with their statutory authorities and responsibility:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consult with the appropriate federal agencies, local governments, and federally recognized community base reuse commissions as early as possible to coordinate information gathering, issue identification, impact assessment, potential land use options, citizen participation, review timelines, and all other aspects of base closure and reuse approvals. Such agencies shall invite federal and local government representatives to attend any agency preapplication conferences related to military base closure or reuse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make every effort to avoid duplicate reviews of impacts and, when possible and appropriate, use information analyses, and recommendations generated by the federal environmental impact statement process and the community base reuse plan process in state planning and permitting reviews.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be authorized to enter into memorandums of agreement with federal agencies in order to facilitate the coordination of reviews.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate a person to serve as the agency coordinator for military base closure and reuse matters and notify the Governor in writing of the designation. The Governor shall notify the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the appropriate community base reuse commission chair, and the commanding officer of the affected installation of the appointment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 94-323.</History></Section>