<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.8175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Linkage institutes between postsecondary institutions in this state and foreign countries.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are created Florida linkage institutes. A primary purpose of these institutes is to assist in the development of stronger economic, cultural, educational, and social ties between this state and strategic foreign countries through the promotion of expanded public and private dialogue on cooperative research and technical assistance activities, increased bilateral commerce, student and faculty exchange, cultural exchange, and the enhancement of language training skills between the postsecondary institutions in this state and those of selected foreign countries. Each institute must ensure that minority students are afforded an equal opportunity to participate in the exchange programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each institute must be governed by an agreement between the Board of Governors of the State University System for a state university and the State Board of Education for a community college with the counterpart organization in a foreign country. Each institute must report to the Department of Education regarding its program activities, expenditures, and policies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each institute must be co-administered in this state by a university-community college partnership, as designated in subsection (5), and must have a private sector and public sector advisory committee. The advisory committee must be representative of the international education and commercial interests of the state and may have members who are native to the foreign country partner. Six members must be appointed by the Department of Education. The Department of Education must appoint at least one member who is an international educator. The presidents, or their designees, of the participating university and community college must also serve on the advisory committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institutes are:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Brazil Institute (University of Florida and Miami Dade College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Costa Rica Institute (Florida State University and Valencia College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Caribbean Institute (Florida International University and Daytona State College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Canada Institute (University of Central Florida and Palm Beach State College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-China Institute (University of West Florida, University of South Florida, and Brevard Community College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Japan Institute (University of South Florida, University of West Florida, and St. Petersburg College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-France Institute (New College of the University of South Florida, Miami Dade College, and Florida State University).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Israel Institute (Florida Atlantic University and Broward College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-West Africa Institute (Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, University of North Florida, and Florida State College at Jacksonville).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Eastern Europe Institute (University of Central Florida and Lake Sumter Community College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida-Mexico Institute (Florida International University and Polk State College).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each institute is allowed to exempt from s. 1009.21 up to 25 full-time equivalent students per year from the respective host countries to study in any of the state universities or community colleges in this state as resident students for tuition purposes. The institute directors shall develop criteria, to be approved by the Department of Education, for the selection of these students. Students must return home within 3 years after their tenure of graduate or undergraduate study for a length of time equal to their exemption period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state university and community college linkage institute partner may enter into an agreement for a student exchange program, that requires that the tuition and fees of a student who is enrolled in a state university or community college and who is participating in an exchange program be paid to the university or community college while the student is participating in the exchange program. The agreement may also require that the tuition and fees of a student who is enrolled in a postsecondary institution in a foreign country and who is participating in an exchange program be paid to the foreign institution of enrollment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A linkage institute may not be created or funded except upon the recommendation of the Department of Education and except by amendment to this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 87-329; s. 1, ch. 88-162; s. 78, ch. 90-201; s. 34, ch. 90-302; s. 21, ch. 91-5; s. 26, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 66, ch. 93-187; s. 78, ch. 96-320; s. 27, ch. 97-278; s. 36, ch. 2000-258; s. 947, ch. 2002-387; s. 10, ch. 2004-242; s. 41, ch. 2007-217; s. 57, ch. 2008-4; s. 26, ch. 2009-21; s. 9, ch. 2009-228; s. 1, ch. 2010-23; s. 69, ch. 2010-102; s. 2, ch. 2011-102; s. 184, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 240.137.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>