<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.9605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporation powers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of the corporation created by s. 288.9604 shall include all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is authorized and empowered to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have perpetual succession as a body politic and corporate and adopt bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt an official seal and alter the same at its pleasure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain an office at such place or places as it may designate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued in its own name and plead and be impleaded.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into interlocal agreements pursuant to s. 163.01(7) with public agencies of this state for the exercise of any power, privilege, or authority consistent with the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue, from time to time, revenue bonds, notes, or other evidence of indebtedness, including, but not limited to, taxable bonds and bonds the interest on which is exempt from federal income taxation, for the purpose of financing and refinancing any capital projects that promote economic development within the state, thereby benefiting the citizens of the state, and exercise all powers in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds, subject to the provisions of s. 288.9606.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue bond anticipation notes in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of such bonds, pursuant to the provisions of s. 288.9606.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of its powers under the act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate information about itself and its activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire, by purchase, lease, option, gift, grant, bequest, devise, or otherwise, real property, together with any improvements thereon, or personal property for its administrative purposes or in furtherance of the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold, improve, clear, or prepare for development any such property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mortgage, pledge, hypothecate, or otherwise encumber or dispose of any real or personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insure or provide for insurance of any real or personal property or operations of the corporation or any private enterprise against any risks or hazards, including the power to pay premiums on any such insurance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and fund a guaranty fund in furtherance of the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Invest funds held in reserve or sinking funds or any such funds not required for immediate disbursement in property or securities in such manner as the board shall determine, subject to the authorizing resolution on any bonds issued, and to terms established in the investment agreement pursuant to ss. 288.9606, 288.9607, and 288.9608, and redeem such bonds as have been issued pursuant to s. 288.9606 at the redemption price established therein or purchase such bonds at less than redemption price, all such bonds so redeemed or purchased to be canceled.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow money and apply for and accept advances, loans, grants, contributions, and any other form of financial assistance from the Federal Government or the state, county, or other public agency or from any sources, public or private, for the purposes of this act and give such security as may be required and enter into and carry out contracts or agreements in connection therewith; and include in any contract for financial assistance with the Federal Government or the state, county, or other public agency for, or with respect to, any purposes under this act and related activities such conditions imposed pursuant to federal laws as the county or municipality or other public agency deems reasonable and appropriate which are not inconsistent with the provisions of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or have all surveys and plans necessary for the carrying out of the purposes of this act, contract with any person, public or private, in making and carrying out such plans, and adopt, approve, modify, and amend such plans.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, test, and report methods and techniques and carry out demonstrations and other activities for the promotion of any of the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply for, accept, and utilize grants from the Federal Government or the state, county, or other public agency available for any of the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make expenditures necessary to carry out the purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise all or any part or combination of powers granted in this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into investment agreements with Enterprise Florida, Inc., concerning the issuance of bonds and other forms of indebtedness and capital.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the situations and circumstances for participation in partnerships by agreement with local governments, financial institutions, and others associated with the redevelopment of brownfield areas pursuant to the Brownfields Redevelopment Act for a limited state guaranty of revenue bonds, loan guarantees, or loan loss reserves.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 29, 62, ch. 93-187; s. 1, ch. 93-402; s. 12, ch. 94-136; s. 12, ch. 98-75; s. 73, ch. 99-13; s. 5, ch. 2010-139; s. 189, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>