<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.853" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">International sanctions against Castro government.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature hereby finds that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acts of Fidel Castro and his government, including human rights violations, are a threat to international peace and to the peace of the State of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President should instruct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to seek, in the Security Council, an international embargo against the Castro dictatorship, similar to consultations conducted with respect to Haiti.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There should be a detrimental impact on United States assistance to any independent state of the former Soviet Union which resumes efforts to make operational the nuclear facility at Cienfuegos, Cuba.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature hereby supports and reaffirms s. 1704(a) of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992, which states that the President should encourage foreign countries to restrict trade and credit relations with Cuba, and urges the President to take immediate steps to apply sanctions described in s. 1704(b)(1) of such act against countries assisting Cuba.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent allowed by federal law, no loan, credit, or other financing may be extended knowingly by a citizen or legal resident of Florida, a state agency, or a financial institution located or doing business in Florida to any person for the purpose of financing transactions involving any confiscated property, as defined by s. 4 of the federal Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity Act of 1996, the claim to which is owned by a citizen or legal resident of Florida as of July 1, 1996, except for financing by the citizen or legal resident of Florida owning such claim for a transaction permitted under state and federal law. Any person who violates this subsection commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084 so long as the imposition of the state penalty does not in any way interfere with full federal prosecution and penalties.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature hereby requests:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Congress and the President to withhold payment to any international financial institution that approves a loan or other assistance to Cuba in an amount equal to the amount of the loan or assistance provided to Cuba.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President to instruct the United States Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States to oppose the readmission of Cuba to the Organization of American States until a democratically elected government exists in Cuba.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the termination of Fidel Castro’s government in Cuba to take steps during the period that a transition government is in power in Cuba to support the processing of Cuba’s application for membership in any international financial institution, to take effect after a democratically elected government is in power in Cuba.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is illegal for any person, firm, or corporation to import into Florida any sugars, syrups, or molasses that are the product of a country that the President determines has imported sugar, syrup, or molasses from Cuba. The intent of this section is to prevent indirect subsidization of the Cuban sugar industry through countries that buy Cuban sugar for domestic consumption and sell their own sugar to the United States at inflated prices under the sugar quota allotment program. Any person who violates this subsection commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084 so long as the imposition of the state penalty does not in any way interfere with full federal prosecution and penalties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of paragraph (a) shall not apply if the country described in paragraph (a) certifies to the President that the country will not import sugar, syrup, or molasses that is the product of Cuba until free and fair elections are held in Cuba.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-188; s. 70, ch. 99-13; s. 70, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>