<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0288.907" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual incentives report.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the annual report required under s. 288.906, Enterprise Florida, Inc., by December 30 of each year, shall provide the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a detailed incentives report quantifying the economic benefits for all of the economic development incentive programs marketed by Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual incentives report must include for each incentive program:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brief description of the incentive program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of awards granted, by year, since inception.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The economic benefits, as defined in s. 288.005, based on the actual amount of private capital invested, actual number of jobs created, and actual wages paid for incentive agreements completed during the previous 3 years.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report shall also include the actual amount of private capital invested, actual number of jobs created, and actual wages paid for incentive agreements completed during the previous 3 years for each target industry sector.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For projects completed during the previous state fiscal year, the report must include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of economic development incentive applications received.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of recommendations made to the department by Enterprise Florida, Inc., including the number recommended for approval and the number recommended for denial.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of final decisions issued by the department for approval and for denial.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The projects for which a tax refund, tax credit, or cash grant agreement was executed, identifying:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of jobs committed to be created.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of capital investments committed to be made.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual average wage committed to be paid.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of state economic development incentives committed to the project from each incentive program under the project’s terms of agreement with the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and type of local matching funds committed to the project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For economic development projects that received tax refunds, tax credits, or cash grants under the terms of an agreement for incentives, the report must identify:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of jobs actually created.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of capital investments actually made.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual average wage paid.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a project receiving economic development incentives approved by the department and receiving federal or local incentives, the report must include a description of the federal or local incentives, if available.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must state the number of withdrawn or terminated projects that did not fulfill the terms of their agreements with the department and consequently are not receiving incentives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must include an analysis of the economic benefits, as defined in s. 288.005, of tax refunds, tax credits, or other payments made to projects locating or expanding in state enterprise zones, rural communities, brownfield areas, or distressed urban communities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must identify the target industry businesses and high-impact businesses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must describe the trends relating to business interest in, and usage of, the various incentives, and the number of minority-owned or woman-owned businesses receiving incentives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report must identify incentive programs not utilized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Strategic Business Development within the department shall assist Enterprise Florida, Inc., in the preparation of the annual incentives report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>