<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0288.777" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">President of the corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall appoint a president. The president shall be knowledgeable about private and public export assistance and export financing programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president shall serve at the pleasure of the board and shall receive a salary and benefits as shall be fixed by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president shall administer the programs of the corporation and perform such duties as shall be delegated by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president may, upon approval of the board:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract for services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold public hearings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Call upon and reimburse for services any state agency or department for assistance in carrying out the objectives of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate with government or private industry in programs for technical assistance, loans, technology transfer, or any other programs related to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undertake or commission studies on methods to increase financial resources to expand the exports of goods and services by small and medium-sized businesses in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hire staff and provide export finance training for them and other individuals involved in export finance assistance, including such training sessions as may be provided by the United States Export-Import Bank and other organizations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise any other powers as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president shall provide staff to the board as requested.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president shall submit an annual budget to be approved by the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 93-187; s. 73, ch. 96-320; s. 24, ch. 97-278.</History></Section>