<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0585.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation with United States authorities and United States Department of Agriculture accredited private veterinarians.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may cooperate with:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authorities of the United States in the enforcement of all acts of Congress for the control, prevention, suppression, and eradication of contagious, infectious, and communicable diseases affecting animals, or animal diseases which may affect humans, and in connection therewith may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint inspectors of the United States Department of Agriculture as temporary assistant state veterinarians or livestock inspectors; provided, they shall first consent to act without compensation or profit from the state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept aid or assistance from the United States in conducting work related to the control or eradication of tuberculosis, brucellosis, pseudorabies, hog cholera, and any other such dangerous disease, or from any of its officers, representatives, or agents, in carrying out such work.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officials of the United States Department of Agriculture in the control or eradication of tuberculosis, brucellosis, pseudorabies, and hog cholera and with the owners of animals, who accept indemnity for animals found to be diseased and slaughtered in accordance with the <Reference Number="1" />special Acts of Congress now in effect and appropriating funds for this purpose, or that may hereafter be available from such source.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States Department of Agriculture in carrying out the provisions of the National Poultry Improvement Plan and the National Turkey Improvement Plan in Florida, and in connection therewith, may promulgate rules necessary to carry out the provisions of the National Poultry Improvement Plan and the National Turkey Improvement Plan in Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appointed United States Department of Agriculture accredited private veterinarians in conducting work related to the control or eradication of contagious and infectious diseases, who may be compensated for services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 7345, 1917; RGS 2112; s. 12, ch. 9201, 1923; CGL 3341; s. 7, ch. 17273, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 3323(7); s. 1, ch. 22581, 1945; s. 3, ch. 25358, 1949; s. 6, ch. 59-457; s. 2, ch. 61-408; s. 15, ch. 90-321; s. 36, ch. 2002-295.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As enacted by s. 7, ch. 17273, Acts of 1935.</Text></Note></Section>