<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0585.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In construing this part, where the context permits, the word, phrase, or term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Approved brucella vaccine” means a Brucella abortus immunization product approved and licensed by the United States Department of Agriculture for injection into cattle and bison to enhance their resistance to brucellosis infection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beef cattle” means animals of the genus <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Bos</Font> of various breeds which are raised primarily for the production of meat.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Biological products” means all viruses, serums, toxins, and analogous products of natural or synthetic origin, such as diagnostics, antitoxins, vaccines, live microorganisms, killed microorganisms, and the antigenic or immunizing components of microorganisms intended for use in the diagnoses, treatment, or prevention of diseases of animals and sometimes referred to as biologics, biologicals, or products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Biological or chemical residues” means potentially harmful substances and their metabolites not normally present in animal tissues, which result from treatment or exposure to a pesticide, organic or inorganic compound, hormone, hormone-like substance, growth promoter, antibiotic, anthelmintic, tranquilizer, vaccine, or other therapeutic or prophylactic agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Carcass” means the body of any animal which dies other than by slaughter, or any part of such animal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cattle” means any bull, steer, ox, cow, heifer, calf, or any other bovine animal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dairy cattle” means animals of the genus <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Bos</Font> of various breeds which are raised primarily for the production of milk or milk products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the director of the Division of Animal Industry of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. The director is also known as the State Veterinarian, the Chief Animal Health Official of the state, and the Chief Livestock Regulatory Official of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Animal Industry of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Domestic animal” shall include any equine or bovine animal, goat, sheep, swine, domestic cat, dog, poultry, ostrich, emu, rhea, or other domesticated beast or bird. The term “animal,” as used in this chapter, shall include wild or game animals whenever necessary to effectively control or eradicate dangerous transmissible diseases or pests which threaten the agricultural interests of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency” means any situation in which the department has declared a pest, a communicable, contagious, or infectious disease of animals, or the presence of biological or chemical residue to be a public nuisance or any situation in which, in the opinion of the department, a pest, disease, or residue endangers or threatens the animals or citizens of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Garbage” means all refuse matter, animal or vegetable, byproducts of a restaurant, kitchen, or slaughterhouse; and shall include every accumulation of animal, fruit, or vegetable matter, liquid, or otherwise. “Garbage” shall also include “swill” as commonly used; provided, however, “garbage” shall not include fruit or vegetable matter which does not contain or has not been in contact or mixed with meat or meat parts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Livestock” means grazing animals, such as cattle, horses, sheep, swine, goats, other hoofed animals, ostriches, emus, and rheas which are raised for private use or commercial purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” shall include any owner, custodian, or other person in charge of any animal, domestic or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pathogenic organisms” means microorganisms, such as bacteria, viruses, rickettsia, etc., capable of causing diseases in animals or humans. “Virulent organisms” are pathogenic organisms that are extremely dangerous and are characterized by being highly contagious.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Quarantine” means a strict isolation imposed on animals, or premises or other defined geographic areas, to prevent the spread of disease or pests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Technical council” means the Animal Industry Technical Council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transmissible,” “communicable,” “contagious,” and “infectious” all refer to diseases which are readily transferred between or among animals in a group or to susceptible animals in proximity to diseased animals. Such transference may be directly from one animal to another, by contact with objects contaminated by disease-causing agents, or by insect (vector) transmission of disease-causing agents from diseased animals into susceptible animals or humans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Violative levels” means levels above the tolerances established by the United States Food and Drug Administration or the United States Environmental Protection Agency, as adopted by department rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 9201, 1923; s. 2, ch. 17273, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 3321, 3323(2); s. 1, ch. 25358, 1949; s. 1, ch. 59-457; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 246, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 78-57; s. 10, ch. 90-321; s. 4, ch. 91-294; s. 1, ch. 92-206; s. 50, ch. 92-291; s. 63, ch. 93-169; s. 8, ch. 96-231; s. 1188, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>