<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0570.0705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advisory committees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From time to time the commissioner may appoint any advisory committee to assist the department with its duties and responsibilities.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advisory committee may exist for no more than 3 years, but may be reestablished as necessary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person serving on an advisory committee shall serve at the pleasure of the commissioner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each advisory committee, whether created by the commissioner or the Legislature, including technical councils, shall be governed by the following provisions, in addition to those specified for that committee:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Composition.</Font><EmDash />Membership and appointments of advisory committees shall be made by the commissioner in accordance with the criteria set forth in the provisions establishing the committee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Powers and duties.</Font><EmDash />Each advisory committee shall have the power and duty to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider and study the entire field relating to its area of responsibility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider all matters submitted to it by the commissioner or the division directors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit proposed legislation and rules to the commissioner.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consult with the commissioner and the division directors of the department, at their request or upon its own initiative, regarding the promulgation, administration, and enforcement of all laws and rules relating to its area of responsibility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suggest policies and practices for the conduct of departmental business which shall be duly considered by the commissioner or division directors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall meet at least annually and elect a chair, a vice chair, and a secretary for 1-year terms.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each advisory committee shall meet at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the department, or at the times prescribed by its rules of procedure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide administrative and staff support services to the committee and shall provide suitable space in the offices of the department for the meetings and records of the committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting its meetings, each advisory committee shall use accepted rules of procedure. The secretary shall keep a complete record of the proceedings of each meeting, which shall show the names of the members present and the actions taken. These records shall be kept on file with the department, and records and other documents about matters within the jurisdiction of the advisory committee shall be subject to inspection by the members of the advisory committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum, and action by a majority of a quorum shall be official.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 20.052(4)(d), members of each advisory committee, council, board, working group, task force, or other advisory body created by law within the department or created by the department under this section may not be reimbursed for per diem or travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 92-151; s. 2, ch. 93-169; s. 12, ch. 94-335; s. 886, ch. 97-103; s. 153, ch. 2010-102; s. 34, ch. 2011-206; s. 15, ch. 2012-190.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 570.07(33), (34).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>