<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.076" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Environmental Stewardship Certification Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, by rule, establish the Environmental Stewardship Certification Program consistent with this section. A rule adopted under this section must be developed in consultation with state universities, agricultural organizations, and other interested parties.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be integrated, to the maximum extent practicable, with programs that are sponsored by agricultural organizations or state universities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be designed to recognize and promote agricultural operations or homeowner practices that demonstrate exemplary resource management that is related to environmental stewardship.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include a process to periodically review a certification to ensure compliance with the program requirements, including implementation by the certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require periodic continuing education in relevant environmental stewardship issues in order to maintain certification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide an agricultural certification under this program for implementation of one or more of the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voluntary agreement between an agency and an agricultural producer for environmental improvement or water-resource protection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conservation plan that meets or exceeds the requirements of the United States Department of Agriculture.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Best management practices adopted by rule pursuant to s. 403.067(7)(c) or s. 570.085(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Soil and Water Conservation Council created by s. 582.06 may develop and recommend to the department for adoption additional criteria for receipt of an agricultural certification which may include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comprehensive management of all on-farm resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promotion of environmental awareness and responsible resource stewardship in agricultural or urban communities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of a curriculum of study that is related to environmental issues and regulation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If needed, the department and the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences at the University of Florida may jointly develop a curriculum that provides instruction concerning environmental issues pertinent to agricultural certification and deliver such curriculum to, and certify its completion by, any person seeking certification or to maintain certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into agreements with third-party providers to administer or implement all or part of the program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2005-210; s. 68, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>