<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.249" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agricultural Economic Development Program disaster loans and grants and aid.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF LOAN FUNDS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loan funds to agricultural producers who have experienced losses from a natural disaster or a socioeconomic condition or event may be used to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restore or replace essential physical property or remove debris from essential physical property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay all or part of production costs associated with the disaster year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay essential family living expenses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restructure farm debts.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible, agricultural producers must have a parcel or parcels of land in production not exceeding 300 acres.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds may be issued as direct loans, or as loan guarantees for up to 90 percent of the total loan, in amounts not less than $30,000 nor more than $300,000. Applicants must provide at least 10 percent equity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, the term:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Losses” means loss or damage to crops, agricultural products, agricultural facilities, infrastructure, or farmworker housing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Essential physical property” means fences, equipment, structural production facilities such as shade houses and greenhouses, other agricultural facilities, infrastructure, or farmworker housing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBLE CROPS.<EmDash />Crops eligible for the emergency loan program include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crops grown for human consumption.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crops planted and grown for livestock consumption, including, but not limited to, grain, seed, and forage crops.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crops grown for fiber, except for trees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specialty crops, such as seafood and aquaculture, including, but not limited to, the products of shellfish cultivation and harvesting, ornamental fish farming, and commercial fishing; floricultural or ornamental nursery crops; Christmas trees; turf for sod; industrial crops; and seed crops used to produce eligible crops.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FARMING INFORMATION.<EmDash />A borrower must keep complete and acceptable farm records and present them as proof of production levels. A borrower must operate in accordance with a farm plan that he or she develops and that is approved by the commissioner. A borrower may be required to participate in a financial management training program and obtain crop insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOAN APPLICATION.<EmDash />In order to qualify for a loan under this section, an applicant must submit an application to the department within 90 days after the date the natural disaster or socioeconomic condition or event occurs or the crop damage becomes apparent. An applicant must be a citizen of the United States and a bona fide resident of the state and must also demonstrate the need for economic assistance and demonstrate that he or she has the ability to repay the loan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOAN SECURITY REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />All loans must be secured. A first lien is required on all property or product acquired, produced, or refinanced with loan funds. The specific type of collateral required may vary depending upon the loan purpose, repayment ability, and the particular circumstances of the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOAN REPAYMENT.<EmDash />Repayment of loans for crops, livestock, and non-real-estate losses shall normally be made within 7 years or, in special circumstances, within 20 years. Loans for physical losses to real estate and buildings shall not exceed 30 years. Borrowers are expected to return to conventional credit sources when they are financially able. Loans are a temporary source of credit, and borrowers must be reviewed periodically to determine whether they can return to conventional credit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GRANTS AND AID.<EmDash />The department shall establish a grant program to provide aid to agribusinesses to assist in market development.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 2000-308; s. 25, ch. 2001-279; s. 13, ch. 2006-289.</History></Section>