<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.072" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commodity distribution; responsibility of department; functions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct, supervise, and administer all commodity distribution services that will be carried on using federal or state funds, or funds from any other source, or commodities received and distributed from the United States or any of its agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall determine the benefits each applicant or recipient of assistance is entitled to receive under this chapter, provided that each applicant or recipient is a resident of this state and a citizen of the United States or is an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence or otherwise permanently residing in the United States under color of law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall cooperate fully with the United States Government and its agencies and instrumentalities so that the department may receive the benefit of all federal financial allotments and assistance possible to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept any duties with respect to commodity distribution services as are delegated to it by an agency of the Federal Government or any state, county, or municipal government;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as agent of, or contract with, the Federal Government, state government, or any county or municipal government in the administration of commodity distribution services to secure the benefits of any public assistance that is available from the Federal Government or any of its agencies, and in the distribution of funds received from the Federal Government, state government, or any county or municipal government for commodity distribution services within the state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept from any person or organization all offers of personal services, commodities, or other aid or assistance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not limit, abrogate, or abridge the powers and duties of any other state agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 54, ch. 92-58; s. 4, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>