<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following words and phrases as used in this chapter and in the agricultural laws of this state, unless the context otherwise requires, shall have the meanings respectively ascribed to them in this section:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agriculture” means the science and art of production of plants and animals useful to humans, including to a variable extent the preparation of these products for human use and their disposal by marketing or otherwise, and includes aquaculture, horticulture, floriculture, viticulture, forestry, dairy, livestock, poultry, bees, and any and all forms of farm products and farm production. For the purposes of marketing and promotional activities, seafood shall also be included in this definition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural business products” means nonconsumable products used in the producing, processing, distribution, and marketing of consumable farm products, including, but not limited to, machinery, equipment, and supplies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural marketing facilities” means state-owned wholesale and retail markets managed by the Bureau of State Farmers’ Market.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 215, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 87-36; s. 1, ch. 88-341; s. 5, ch. 92-291; s. 1, ch. 93-169; s. 11, ch. 94-335; s. 21, ch. 96-247; s. 1182, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>