<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0570.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Marketing and Development; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and duties of the Division of Marketing and Development include, but are not limited to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managing the operation of all agricultural marketing facilities and managing or leasing state livestock and crop pavilions owned by the state. The department shall give first priority to those engaged in the production or sale of Florida’s agricultural products when negotiating leases for the use of agricultural marketing facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing other related duties and responsibilities which are required of the department by s. 570.07(18), including authorizing the removal of a vehicle by a towing service when the vehicle is parked in a manner that restricts the normal operation of business at any such agricultural marketing facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcing the provisions of ss. 604.15-604.34, the dealers in agricultural products law, and ss. 534.47-534.53.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining and disseminating current price, supply, and movement data and other such pertinent information on the agricultural economy of the state as required of the department by ss. 570.07(4) and (17) and 570.21.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stimulating, encouraging, and fostering the production and consumption of agricultural products and conducting activities that may foster a better understanding and more efficient cooperation among producers, buyers, food editors, and the consuming public in the promotion and marketing of Florida agricultural products as required of the department by s. 570.07(20).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining and disseminating production statistics, historical data, and other such pertinent information on the agricultural economy of the state as required of the department by ss. 570.07(4) and (17) and 570.21.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing professional marketing services to the agricultural agribusiness industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing and maintaining programs which will aid in the orderly marketing of agricultural products.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting in providing efficient and effective distribution of agricultural products.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing plans and recommendations designed to support the agricultural industry in meeting its marketing needs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extending in every practicable way the distribution and sale of Florida agricultural products throughout the markets of the world as required of the department by s. 570.07(7), (8), (10), and (11) and chapters 571, 573, and 574.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entering into contracts with private persons for the renovation or construction of agricultural marketing facilities. These contracts may include provisions for private financing and leaseback agreements for the recoupment of initial private investment. All schematic and conceptual construction plans shall be subject to approval by the division. The department shall promulgate rules and develop policies for using these contracts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administering the provisions of chapter 616, including the Florida State Fair Authority and other fair or exposition charters, permits, applications, fees, premiums and awards, agricultural exhibits, and youth activities, but excluding amusement ride inspection, inspection fees, and safety requirements, at public fairs and expositions, carnivals, festivals, celebrations, bazaars, permanent facilities, and parking lot still dates.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; s. 4, ch. 65-459; ss. 4, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-195; s. 5, ch. 79-122; s. 11, ch. 84-165; s. 1, ch. 85-36; s. 4, ch. 88-341; s. 1, ch. 91-253; s. 35, ch. 92-291; s. 29, ch. 93-169; s. 22, ch. 2012-190.</History>
</Section>