<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0570.451" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agricultural Feed, Seed, and Fertilizer Advisory Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agricultural Feed, Seed, and Fertilizer Advisory Council is created within the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council is composed of the following 15 members appointed by the commissioner:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the dean for extension of the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences at the University of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative each from the state’s beef cattle, poultry, aquaculture, field crops, citrus, vegetable, and dairy production industries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two representatives each from the state’s fertilizer, seed, and commercial feed industries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Each member shall be appointed for a <Reference Number="1"/>term not to exceed 4 years and shall serve until his or her successor is appointed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the council members constitutes a quorum for all purposes, and an act by a majority of such quorum at any meeting constitutes an official act of the council. The secretary shall keep a complete record of each meeting, which must show the names of members present and the actions taken. Such records must be kept on file with the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall meet and organize by electing a chair, a vice chair, and a secretary whose terms shall be for 2 years each. Council officers may not serve consecutive terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its members, at the request of the department, or at such time as an agricultural or environmental emergency arises, but not less than twice per year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The meetings, powers and duties, procedures, and recordkeeping of the council shall be in accordance with the provisions of s. 570.0705 relating to advisory committees established within the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive reports of relevant enforcement activity conducted by the Division of Agricultural Environmental Services, including the number of inspections, the number of administrative actions, the number of complaints received and investigated, and the dispositions of complaints.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide advice to the department on the conduct of relevant enforcement activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive reports on disciplinary actions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make recommendations to the commissioner for actions to be taken with respect to the regulation of agricultural feed, seed, and fertilizer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2012-190.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “of” following the word “term” was deleted by the editors.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>