<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Plant Industry; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the Division of Plant Industry include, but are not limited to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifying insects, mites, and mollusks submitted; surveying agricultural and horticultural crops to determine the presence of insect, mite, or mollusk populations; and investigating methods of control, eradication, and prevention of dissemination of insect, mite, or mollusk pests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifying plant diseases from samples submitted; surveying agricultural and horticultural crops to determine the presence of plant diseases; and investigating methods of control, eradication, and prevention of dissemination of plant diseases.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifying nematodes submitted; surveying agricultural and horticultural crops to determine the presence of nematode population; and investigating methods of control, eradication, and prevention of dissemination of nematode pests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcing the laws of the state and the rules of the department relating to honeybees and the control and eradication of honeybee pests and unwanted races of honeybees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surveying for all plant pests, inspecting all plants or plant products grown or held in any area of the state, and enforcing the laws of the state and the rules of the department pertaining to plants and plant products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting plant pest and noxious weed eradication and control programs and all plant pest surveys associated with eradication and control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testing citrus trees for diseases and desirable horticultural characteristics; registering trees meeting the requirements of the test; maintaining a source of budwood of the superior, tested varieties for distribution to the citrus industry; verifying propagations of citrus varieties and special rootstocks for growers when requested; and maintaining appropriate records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developing, investigating, and implementing new ideas, techniques, and methods for the survey, detection, control, and eradication of plant pests.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; s. 2, ch. 65-459; ss. 4, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 79-127; s. 4, ch. 84-165; s. 1, ch. 87-17; s. 17, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>