<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, law enforcement officers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner may create an Office of Agricultural Law Enforcement under the supervision of a senior manager exempt under s. 110.205 in the Senior Management Service. The commissioner may designate law enforcement officers, as necessary, to enforce any criminal law or conduct any criminal investigation or to enforce the provisions of any statute or any other laws of this state. Officers appointed under this section shall have the primary responsibility for enforcing laws relating to agriculture and consumer services, as outlined <Reference Number="1" />in this section, and <Reference Number="2" />have jurisdiction over violations of law which threaten the overall security and safety of this state’s agriculture and consumer services. The primary responsibilities of officers appointed under this section include the enforcement of laws relating to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Domesticated animals, including livestock, poultry, aquaculture products, and other wild or domesticated animals or animal products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Farms, farm equipment, livery tack, citrus or citrus products, or horticultural products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trespass, littering, forests, forest fires, and open burning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damage to or theft of forest products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of a marketing order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protection of consumers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Civil traffic offenses as <Reference Number="3" />provided in state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of alcohol or drugs which occurs on property owned, managed, or occupied by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any emergency situation in which the life, limb, or property of any person is placed in immediate and serious danger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any crime incidental to or related to paragraphs (a)-(i).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Reference Number="4" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The responsibilities of the Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each law enforcement officer shall meet the qualifications of law enforcement officers under s. 943.13 and shall be certified as a law enforcement officer by the Department of Law Enforcement under the provisions of chapter 943. Upon certification, each law enforcement officer is subject to and shall have the same arrest and other authority provided for law enforcement officers generally in chapter 901 and shall have statewide jurisdiction. Each officer shall also have arrest authority as provided for state law enforcement officers in s. 901.15. Such officers have full law enforcement powers granted to other peace officers of this state, including the authority to make arrests, carry firearms, serve court process, and seize contraband and the proceeds of illegal activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner may also appoint part-time, reserve, or auxiliary law enforcement officers under chapter 943.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All department law enforcement officers, upon certification under s. 943.1395, shall have the same right and authority to carry arms as do the sheriffs of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each law enforcement officer in the state who is certified pursuant to chapter 943 has the same authority as law enforcement officers designated in this section to enforce the laws of this state as described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 92-291; s. 5, ch. 93-169; s. 2, ch. 95-141; s. 42, ch. 98-34; s. 111, ch. 2002-20; s. 47, ch. 2002-295.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 47, ch. 2002-295. The amendment by s. 111, ch. 2002-20, substitutes the word “below” for the words “in this section.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 47, ch. 2002-295. The amendment by s. 111, ch. 2002-20, does not include the words “have jurisdiction over.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 47, ch. 2002-295. The amendment by s. 111, ch. 2002-20, substituted the words “outlined under” for the words “provided in.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As enacted by s. 47, ch. 2002-295. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Paragraph (k) was also enacted by s. 111, ch. 2002-20, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(k) Any law over which the Commissioner of Agriculture has responsibility.</Text></Note></Section>