<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.242" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Agricultural Economic Development Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this act, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agriculturally depressed area” means a rural area which has declining profitability from agricultural enterprises and one or more of the following characteristics:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stable or declining population.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stable or declining real per capita income.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A traditional economy based on agriculture or extraction of solid minerals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A low ad valorem tax base.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A need for agribusiness and leadership training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crop losses or economic depression resulting from a natural disaster or socioeconomic conditions or events which negatively impact a crop.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assistance” means financial or nonfinancial assistance issued pursuant to the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial assistance” means the providing of funds to an agribusiness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonfinancial assistance” means the providing of personnel to work with an agribusiness to establish an infrastructure, including, but not limited to, the development of an accounting system, management procedures, and a marketing plan. Nonfinancial assistance shall also include the providing of equipment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 10, ch. 91-268; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 12, ch. 92-291; s. 24, ch. 2000-308.</History></Section>