<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0570.48" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Fruit and Vegetables; powers and duties; records.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the Division of Fruit and Vegetables include, but are not limited to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing the duties relating to the inspection and certification of fresh citrus fruit shipments for maturity and grade required by rules promulgated under the Florida Citrus Code; performing the inspection and certification duties assigned in connection with regulations issued under federal or state marketing agreements or orders; and performing the other inspection and certification assignments requested by and agreed upon with the applicant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing the duties relating to inspection and certification of the maturity and condition of fresh citrus fruits to be processed required by the rules promulgated under the Florida Citrus Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspecting and certifying the grade, quality, or condition of the finished processed pack, as required by rules promulgated under the Florida Citrus Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing the inspection and certification duties as are assigned in connection with regulations issued under federal or state marketing agreements or orders for other fruit and vegetables.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting inspections of internal quality for any fruit or vegetable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing tomato food safety inspections under s. 500.70 on tomato farms, in tomato greenhouses, and in tomato packinghouses and repackers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing other inspection and certification assignments as requested by and agreed upon with the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining the records of the division. The records of the division are public records; however, trade secrets as defined in s. 812.081 are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). This section shall not be construed to prohibit:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disclosure necessary to enforcement procedures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department from releasing information to other governmental agencies. Other governmental agencies that receive confidential information from the department under this subsection shall maintain the confidentiality of that information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or other agencies from compiling and publishing appropriate data regarding procedures, yield, recovery, quality, and related matters, provided such released data do not reveal by whom the activity to which the data relate was conducted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing such duties relating to inspection and certification of vegetables, other fruits, melons, and nuts as are requested by and agreed upon with the applicant and performing such inspection and certification duties as are assigned in connection with regulations issued under federal or state marketing agreements or orders.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing such duties relating to enforcement of the citrus bond and license law as are required by chapter 601.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing analyses on waxes, dyes, and other substances used on citrus fruit and issuing authorization for the use of such waxes, dyes, and other substances; issuing equipment to inspectors and maintaining the equipment; conducting necessary technical investigations relative to inspectional procedures; and carrying out the technical duties prescribed under the arsenical spray provisions of chapter 601 and other technical duties prescribed by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, appointing, certifying, licensing, and supervising inspectors whose duties are to inspect fruit and vegetables that are regulated by state law, if federal law does not require such inspectors to be licensed or certified by the federal government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; ss. 4, 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 82-165; s. 50, ch. 83-216; s. 9, ch. 84-165; s. 3, ch. 92-4; ss. 3, 4, ch. 92-290; ss. 29, 30, ch. 92-291; s. 25, ch. 93-169; s. 348, ch. 96-406; s. 8, ch. 99-391; s. 12, ch. 2007-67; s. 4, ch. 2010-25.</History>
</Section>