<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Publication of department’s bulletins, publications, and reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Divisions of Administration and Marketing and Development may publish bulletins or other publications and reports containing data and statistics and information relating to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agriculture, agricultural production, agricultural labor, and the agricultural conditions of the state, and their development and improvement to increase farm production and values.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sources, supply, and prices of food; their storage and accumulation at different places; and the quantity and location of the available supply.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The market prices of foods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities afforded for transportation, marketing, and distribution of foods within the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Matters pertaining generally to the production of foods, food safety, the actual food value of articles used in food, and the sale and distribution to the consumer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigations, hearings, and inquiries conducted as provided in this chapter; conclusions reached; and the orders and recommendations made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules and orders of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other matter of an agricultural nature which the department deems proper and that is not within the jurisdiction of the agricultural experiment station or the agricultural extension service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such bulletins, publications, reports, rules, and orders and the information contained therein shall be published and distributed in the manner deemed best by the department for the dissemination of knowledge as to the agricultural interest of the state and the production, sale, purchase, storage, marketing, and distribution of food, and the economic and food value of articles used as food. The cost of publishing these materials shall be paid in the same manner as other expenses of the department. Copies of these materials may also be sold to the public at their estimated cost, in accordance with a schedule of charges adopted by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; ss. 14, 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-283; s. 2, ch. 77-289; s. 14, ch. 93-169; s. 2, ch. 93-270; s. 35, ch. 2001-63.</History></Section>