<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0570.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dairy Industry Technical Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPOSITION.<EmDash />The Dairy Industry Technical Council is hereby created in the department and shall be composed of seven members as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two citizens of the state, one of whom shall be associated with the Agricultural Extension Service of the University of Florida and the other with the College of Agriculture of the University of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee of the Department of Health.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two dairy farmers who are actively engaged in the production of milk in this state and who earn a major portion of their income from the production of milk. The commissioner shall appoint the two members provided for in this paragraph from no fewer than four nor more than six nominees submitted by the recognized statewide organizations representing this group. In the absence of nominations, the commissioner shall appoint other persons qualified under the provisions of this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two distributors of milk. “Distributor” means any milk dealer who operates a milk gathering station or processing plant where milk is collected and bottled or otherwise processed and prepared for sale. The commissioner shall appoint the two members provided for in this paragraph from no fewer than four nor more than six nominees submitted by the recognized statewide organizations representing this group. In the absence of nominations, the commissioner shall appoint other persons qualified under the provisions of this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All members shall serve 4-year terms or until their successors are duly qualified and appointed. If a vacancy occurs, it shall be filled for the remainder of the term in the manner of an initial appointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS AND DUTIES; MEETINGS; PROCEDURES; RECORDS.<EmDash />The meetings, powers and duties, procedures, and recordkeeping of the Dairy Industry Technical Council shall be governed by the provisions of s. 570.0705 relating to advisory committees established within the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; s. 6, ch. 61-407; ss. 14, 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 11, ch. 77-108; s. 461, ch. 77-147; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 81-79; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 3, 6, 7, ch. 87-15; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 23, ch. 92-291; s. 23, ch. 93-169; s. 18, ch. 94-335; s. 254, ch. 99-8; s. 42, ch. 2011-206.</History>
</Section>