<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.97" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gertrude Maxwell Save a Pet Direct-Support Organization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Gertrude Maxwell Save a Pet Direct-Support Organization is created within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and shall be governed by this section and ss. 570.902 and 570.903. The purpose of this direct-support organization is to provide grants to animal shelters for spaying and neutering animals, provide grants for shelters and services during times of emergencies, and develop and disseminate pet care education materials. The direct-support organization shall not participate in, endorse, or financially support political activities at the national, state, or local level.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the direct-support organization shall include one representative of each of the following groups as recommended by that group: the Florida Veterinary Medical Association, the Cat Fanciers’ Association, the Florida Association of Kennel Clubs, a humane organization designated by the commissioner, the Florida Animal Control Association, the National Rifle Association, a consumer member not affiliated with any of the aforementioned associations, and the commissioner or his or her designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the direct-support organization may appoint up to three nonvoting honorary members. Nominees should be individuals, companies, or organizations that have exemplified themselves or have made significant contributions to the health, safety, or well-being of animals. Honorary board members shall serve for a maximum of two consecutive annual terms. The commissioner shall appoint the board of directors as well as the honorary board members.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2008-72.</History></Section>