<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.952" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park Authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park Authority which shall be governed by this section and s. 570.903.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall be composed of 21 members appointed by the commissioner.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initially, the commissioner shall appoint 11 members for 4-year terms and 10 members for 2-year terms. Thereafter, each member shall be appointed for a term of 4 years from the date of appointment, except that a vacancy shall be filled by appointment for the remainder of the term.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the authority who fails to attend three consecutive authority meetings without good cause shall be deemed to have resigned from the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terms for members appointed prior to July 1, 2005, shall expire on July 1, 2005.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park Authority shall have the power and duty to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint, with approval from the commissioner, an executive director for the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish rules of procedure for conducting its meetings and approving matters before the authority that are consistent with s. 570.903.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, document, and implement strategies for the planning, construction, and operation of the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consult with the commissioner on matters related to the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider all matters submitted to the authority by the commissioner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall meet at least semiannually and elect a chairperson, a vice chairperson, and a secretary for 1-year terms.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall meet at the call of its chairperson, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the commissioner, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules of procedure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall be responsible for providing administrative and staff support services relating to the meetings of the authority and shall provide suitable space in the offices of the department for the meetings and the storage of records of the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting its meetings, the authority shall use accepted rules of procedure. The secretary shall keep a complete record of the proceedings of each meeting, which record shall show the names of the members present and the actions taken. These records shall be kept on file with the department, and such records and other documents regarding matters within the jurisdiction of the authority shall be subject to inspection by members of the authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 94-301; s. 8, ch. 95-220; s. 7, ch. 98-396; s. 9, ch. 99-391; s. 28, ch. 2000-308; s. 17, ch. 2005-210.</History></Section>