<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0570.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Administration; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Administration shall render services required by the department and its other divisions, or by the commissioner in the exercise of constitutional and cabinet responsibilities, that can advantageously and effectively be centralized and administered and any other function of the department that is not specifically assigned by law to some other division. The duties of this division include, but are not limited to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting all of the accounting and budgeting work of the department, including, but not restricted to, budget preparation and planning, revenue, auditing, payroll, property, inventories, insurance coverage and claims, federal funds, fixed construction, and all other contracts and grants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting a sound personnel management program for the department, including, but not restricted to, the handling of all official personnel actions, records, training, recruiting, organizational changes, and employee relations and any other personnel matters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminating information concerning the programs and activities of the department as set forth in s. 570.21.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Researching and disseminating information concerning the constitutional and cabinet responsibilities of the commissioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing electronic data processing and management information systems support for the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing support for the department, including, but not limited to, mailing, printing, purchasing, maintenance, supplies inventory, communications, and such other services as may be assigned.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-54; s. 4, ch. 61-407; ss. 4, 14, 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 77-289; s. 229, ch. 79-400; s. 3, ch. 84-165; s. 16, ch. 92-291; s. 16, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>