<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0775.0877" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal transmission of HIV; procedures; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which a person has been convicted of or has pled nolo contendere or guilty to, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld, any of the following offenses, or the attempt thereof, which offense or attempted offense involves the transmission of body fluids from one person to another:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.011, relating to sexual battery;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 826.04, relating to incest;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04, relating to lewd or lascivious offenses committed upon or in the presence of persons less than 16 years of age;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 784.011, 784.07(2)(a), and 784.08(2)(d), relating to assault;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 784.021, 784.07(2)(c), and 784.08(2)(b), relating to aggravated assault;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 784.03, 784.07(2)(b), and 784.08(2)(c), relating to battery;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 784.045, 784.07(2)(d), and 784.08(2)(a), relating to aggravated battery;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.03(2)(c), relating to child abuse;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.03(2)(a), relating to aggravated child abuse;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 825.102(1), relating to abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 825.102(2), relating to aggravated abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.071, relating to sexual performance by person less than 18 years of age;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 796.03, 796.07, and 796.08, relating to prostitution; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 381.0041(11)(b), relating to donation of blood, plasma, organs, skin, or other human tissue,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the court shall order the offender to undergo HIV testing, to be performed under the direction of the Department of Health in accordance with s. 381.004, unless the offender has undergone HIV testing voluntarily or pursuant to procedures established in s. 381.004(2)(h)6. or s. 951.27, or any other applicable law or rule providing for HIV testing of criminal offenders or inmates, subsequent to her or his arrest for an offense enumerated in paragraphs (a)-(n) for which she or he was convicted or to which she or he pled nolo contendere or guilty. The results of an HIV test performed on an offender pursuant to this subsection are not admissible in any criminal proceeding arising out of the alleged offense.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of the HIV test must be disclosed under the direction of the Department of Health, to the offender who has been convicted of or pled nolo contendere or guilty to an offense specified in subsection (1), the public health agency of the county in which the conviction occurred and, if different, the county of residence of the offender, and, upon request pursuant to s. 960.003, to the victim or the victim’s legal guardian, or the parent or legal guardian of the victim if the victim is a minor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender who has undergone HIV testing pursuant to subsection (1), and to whom positive test results have been disclosed pursuant to subsection (2), who commits a second or subsequent offense enumerated in paragraphs (1)(a)-(n), commits criminal transmission of HIV, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. A person may be convicted and sentenced separately for a violation of this subsection and for the underlying crime enumerated in paragraphs (1)(a)-(n).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender may challenge the positive results of an HIV test performed pursuant to this section and may introduce results of a backup test performed at her or his own expense.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section requires that an HIV infection have occurred in order for an offender to have committed criminal transmission of HIV.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an alleged violation of any offense enumerated in paragraphs (1)(a)-(n) for which the consent of the victim may be raised as a defense in a criminal prosecution, it is an affirmative defense to a charge of violating this section that the person exposed knew that the offender was infected with HIV, knew that the action being taken could result in transmission of the HIV infection, and consented to the action voluntarily with that knowledge.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 93-227; s. 7, ch. 96-221; s. 2, ch. 96-293; s. 16, ch. 96-322; s. 4, ch. 97-37; s. 1811, ch. 97-102; s. 95, ch. 99-3; s. 291, ch. 99-8; s. 2, ch. 2010-64; s. 4, ch. 2010-113; s. 1, ch. 2010-117; s. 11, ch. 2012-155; s. 127, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>