<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of convicted felons, exemptions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “convicted” means, with respect to a person’s felony offense, a determination of guilt which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has been convicted of a felony in any court of this state shall, within 48 hours after entering any county in this state, register with the sheriff of said county, be fingerprinted and photographed, and list the crime for which convicted, place of conviction, sentence imposed, if any, name, aliases, if any, address, and occupation. If the felony conviction is for an offense that was found, pursuant to s. 874.04, to have been committed for the purpose of benefiting, promoting, or furthering the interests of a criminal gang, the registrant shall identify himself or herself as such an offender. The Department of Law Enforcement, in consultation with appropriate local law enforcement agencies, may develop standardized practices for the inclusion of gang affiliation at the time of offender registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has been convicted of a crime in any federal court or in any court of a state other than Florida, or of any foreign state or country, which crime if committed in Florida would be a felony, shall forthwith within 48 hours after entering any county in this state register with the sheriff of said county in the same manner as provided for in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to an offender:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has had his or her civil rights restored;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has received a full pardon for the offense for which convicted;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been lawfully released from incarceration or other sentence or supervision for a felony conviction for more than 5 years prior to such time for registration, unless the offender is a fugitive from justice on a felony charge or has been convicted of any offense since release from such incarceration or other sentence or supervision;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is a parolee or probationer under the supervision of the United States Parole Commission if the commission knows of and consents to the presence of the offender in Florida or is a probationer under the supervision of any federal probation officer in the state or who has been lawfully discharged from such parole or probation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is a sexual predator and has registered as required under s. 775.21;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is a sexual offender and has registered as required in s. 943.0435 or s. 944.607; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is a career offender who has registered as required in s. 775.261 or s. 944.609.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of any such convicted felon to comply with this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to any felon not listed in paragraph (b), constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to any felon who has been found, pursuant to s. 874.04, to have committed any offense for the purpose of benefiting, promoting, or furthering the interests of a criminal gang, constitutes a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any law of this state relating to registration of criminals where the penalties for registration, notification, or reporting obligations are in addition to, or in excess of, those imposed by this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, ch. 57-19; s. 1, ch. 57-371; s. 1, ch. 63-191; s. 1, ch. 65-453; s. 3, ch. 67-2207; ss. 20, 33, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 699, ch. 71-136; s. 11, ch. 77-120; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 18, ch. 79-3; s. 21, ch. 79-8; s. 161, ch. 83-216; s. 63, ch. 96-388; s. 4, ch. 97-299; s. 2, ch. 98-81; s. 1, ch. 2000-328; s. 1, ch. 2002-266; s. 5, ch. 2004-371; s. 1, ch. 2008-238.</History></Section>