<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0775.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residency restriction for persons convicted of certain sex offenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child care facility” has the same meaning as provided in s. 402.302.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Park” means all public and private property specifically designated as being used for recreational purposes and where children regularly congregate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Playground” means a designated independent area in the community or neighborhood that is designated solely for children and has one or more play structures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“School” has the same meaning as provided in s. 1003.01 and includes a private school as defined in s. 1002.01, a voluntary prekindergarten education program as described in s. 1002.53(3), a public school as described in s. 402.3025(1), the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind, the Florida Virtual School as established under s. 1002.37, and a K-8 Virtual School as established under s. 1002.415, but does not include facilities dedicated exclusively to the education of adults.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been convicted of a violation of s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, in which the victim of the offense was less than 16 years of age, may not reside within 1,000 feet of any school, child care facility, park, or playground. However, a person does not violate this subsection and may not be forced to relocate if he or she is living in a residence that meets the requirements of this subsection and a school, child care facility, park, or playground is subsequently established within 1,000 feet of his or her residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this subsection and whose conviction under s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145 was classified as a felony of the first degree or higher commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A person who violates this subsection and whose conviction under s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145 was classified as a felony of the second or third degree commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection applies to any person convicted of a violation of s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145 for offenses that occur on or after October 1, 2004, excluding persons who have been removed from the requirement to register as a sexual offender or sexual predator pursuant to s. 943.04354.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been convicted of an offense in another jurisdiction that is similar to a violation of s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145, regardless of whether adjudication has been withheld, in which the victim of the offense was less than 16 years of age, may not reside within 1,000 feet of any school, child care facility, park, or playground. However, a person does not violate this subsection and may not be forced to relocate if he or she is living in a residence that meets the requirements of this subsection and a school, child care facility, park, or playground is subsequently established within 1,000 feet of his or her residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this subsection and whose conviction in another jurisdiction resulted in a penalty that is substantially similar to a felony of the first degree or higher commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A person who violates this subsection and whose conviction in another jurisdiction resulted in a penalty that is substantially similar to a felony of the second or third degree commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection applies to any person convicted of an offense in another jurisdiction that is similar to a violation of s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145 if such offense occurred on or after May 26, 2010, excluding persons who have been removed from the requirement to register as a sexual offender or sexual predator pursuant to s. 943.04354.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2004-55; s. 21, ch. 2008-172; ss. 3,18, ch. 2010-92.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Former s. 794.065.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>