<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.0861" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offenses against persons on the grounds of religious institutions; reclassification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Religious institution” is as defined in s. 496.404.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Religious service” is a religious ceremony, prayer, or other activity according to a form and order prescribed for worship, including a service related to a particular occasion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The felony or misdemeanor degree of any violation of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.011, relating to assault;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.021, relating to aggravated assault;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.03, relating to battery;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.041, relating to felony battery;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statute defining any offense listed in s. 775.084(1)(b)1.; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other statute defining an offense that involves the use or threat of physical force or violence against any individual</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be reclassified as provided in this section if the offense is committed on the property of a religious institution while the victim is on the property for the purpose of participating in or attending a religious service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a misdemeanor of the second degree, the offense is reclassified to a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a misdemeanor of the first degree, the offense is reclassified to a felony of the third degree. For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921, such offense is ranked in level 2 of the offense severity ranking chart.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the third degree, the offense is reclassified to a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the second degree, the offense is reclassified to a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the first degree, the offense is reclassified to a life felony.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, a felony offense that is reclassified under this subsection is ranked one level above the ranking under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023 of the offense committed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-77.</History></Section>