<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0775.089" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restitution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any punishment, the court shall order the defendant to make restitution to the victim for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damage or loss caused directly or indirectly by the defendant’s offense; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damage or loss related to the defendant’s criminal episode,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">unless it finds clear and compelling reasons not to order such restitution. Restitution may be monetary or nonmonetary restitution. The court shall make the payment of restitution a condition of probation in accordance with s. 948.03. An order requiring the defendant to make restitution to a victim does not remove or diminish the requirement that the court order payment to the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund pursuant to chapter 960. Payment of an award by the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund shall create an order of restitution to the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund, unless specifically waived in accordance with subparagraph (b)1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court does not order restitution, or orders restitution of only a portion of the damages, as provided in this section, it shall state on the record in detail the reasons therefor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order of restitution entered as part of a plea agreement is as definitive and binding as any other order of restitution, and a statement to such effect must be made part of the plea agreement. A plea agreement may contain provisions that order restitution relating to criminal offenses committed by the defendant to which the defendant did not specifically enter a plea.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “victim” as used in this section and in any provision of law relating to restitution means each person who suffers property damage or loss, monetary expense, or physical injury or death as a direct or indirect result of the defendant’s offense or criminal episode, and also includes the victim’s estate if the victim is deceased, the victim’s next of kin if the victim is deceased as a result of the offense, and the victim’s trade association if the offense is a violation of s. 540.11(3)(a)3. involving the sale, or possession for purposes of sale, of physical articles and the victim has granted the trade association written authorization to represent the victim’s interests in criminal legal proceedings and to collect restitution on the victim’s behalf. The restitution obligation in this paragraph relating to violations of s. 540.11(3)(a)3. applies only to physical articles and does not apply to electronic articles or digital files that are distributed or made available online. As used in this paragraph, the term “trade association” means an organization founded and funded by businesses that operate in a specific industry to protect their collective interests.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an offense has resulted in bodily injury to a victim, a restitution order entered under subsection (1) shall require that the defendant:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the cost of necessary medical and related professional services and devices relating to physical, psychiatric, and psychological care, including nonmedical care and treatment rendered in accordance with a recognized method of healing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the cost of necessary physical and occupational therapy and rehabilitation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reimburse the victim for income lost by the victim as a result of the offense.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an offense which resulted in bodily injury that also resulted in the death of a victim, pay an amount equal to the cost of necessary funeral and related services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an offense has not resulted in bodily injury to a victim, a restitution order entered under subsection (1) may require that the defendant reimburse the victim for income lost by the victim as a result of the offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may require that the defendant make restitution under this section within a specified period or in specified installments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The end of such period or the last such installment shall not be later than:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The end of the period of probation if probation is ordered;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five years after the end of the term of imprisonment imposed if the court does not order probation; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five years after the date of sentencing in any other case.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding this subsection, a court that has ordered restitution for a misdemeanor offense shall retain jurisdiction for the purpose of enforcing the restitution order for any period, not to exceed 5 years, that is pronounced by the court at the time restitution is ordered.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If not otherwise provided by the court under this subsection, restitution must be made immediately.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the restitution ordered by the court is not made within the time period specified, the court may continue the restitution order through the duration of the civil judgment provision set forth in subsection (5) and as provided in s. 55.10.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a defendant is placed on probation or paroled, complete satisfaction of any restitution ordered under this section shall be a condition of such probation or parole. The court may revoke probation, and the Parole Commission may revoke parole, if the defendant fails to comply with such order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order of restitution may be enforced by the state, or by a victim named in the order to receive the restitution, in the same manner as a judgment in a civil action. The outstanding unpaid amount of the order of restitution bears interest in accordance with s. 55.03, and, when properly recorded, becomes a lien on real estate owned by the defendant. If civil enforcement is necessary, the defendant shall be liable for costs and attorney’s fees incurred by the victim in enforcing the order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in determining whether to order restitution and the amount of such restitution, shall consider the amount of the loss sustained by any victim as a result of the offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The criminal court, at the time of enforcement of the restitution order, shall consider the financial resources of the defendant, the present and potential future financial needs and earning ability of the defendant and his or her dependents, and such other factors which it deems appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dispute as to the proper amount or type of restitution shall be resolved by the court by the preponderance of the evidence. The burden of demonstrating the amount of the loss sustained by a victim as a result of the offense is on the state attorney. The burden of demonstrating the present financial resources and the absence of potential future financial resources of the defendant and the financial needs of the defendant and his or her dependents is on the defendant. The burden of demonstrating such other matters as the court deems appropriate is upon the party designated by the court as justice requires.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conviction of a defendant for an offense involving the act giving rise to restitution under this section shall estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of that offense in any subsequent civil proceeding. An order of restitution hereunder will not bar any subsequent civil remedy or recovery, but the amount of such restitution shall be set off against any subsequent independent civil recovery.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a corporation or unincorporated association is ordered to make restitution, the person authorized to make disbursements from the assets of such corporation or association shall pay restitution from such assets, and such person may be held in contempt for failure to make such restitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any default in payment of restitution may be collected by any means authorized by law for enforcement of a judgment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The restitution obligation is not subject to discharge in bankruptcy, whether voluntary or involuntary, or to any other statutory or common-law proceeding for relief against creditors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order the clerk of the court to collect and dispense restitution payments in any case.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order the Department of Corrections to collect and dispense restitution and other payments from persons remanded to its custody or supervision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Issuance of income deduction order with an order for restitution.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the entry of an order for restitution, the court shall enter a separate order for income deduction if one has not been entered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The income deduction order shall direct a payor to deduct from all income due and payable to the defendant the amount required by the court to meet the defendant’s obligation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The income deduction order shall be effective so long as the order for restitution upon which it is based is effective or until further order of the court.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the court orders the income deduction, the court shall furnish to the defendant a statement of his or her rights, remedies, and duties in regard to the income deduction order. The statement shall state:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees or interest which shall be imposed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of income to be deducted for each pay period.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the income deduction order applies to current and subsequent payors and periods of employment.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a copy of the income deduction order will be served on the defendant’s payor or payors.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That enforcement of the income deduction order may only be contested on the ground of mistake of fact regarding the amount of restitution owed.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the defendant is required to notify the clerk of court within 7 days after changes in the defendant’s address, payors, and the addresses of his or her payors.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Enforcement of income deduction orders.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of court or probation officer shall serve an income deduction order and the notice to payor on the defendant’s payor unless the defendant has applied for a hearing to contest the enforcement of the income deduction order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service by or upon any person who is a party to a proceeding under this subsection shall be made in the manner prescribed in the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure for service upon parties.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service upon the defendant’s payor or successor payor under this subsection shall be made by prepaid certified mail, return receipt requested, or in the manner prescribed in chapter 48.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant, within 15 days after having an income deduction order entered against him or her, may apply for a hearing to contest the enforcement of the income deduction order on the ground of mistake of fact regarding the amount of restitution owed. The timely request for a hearing shall stay the service of an income deduction order on all payors of the defendant until a hearing is held and a determination is made as to whether the enforcement of the income deduction order is proper.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice to payor shall contain only information necessary for the payor to comply with the income deduction order. The notice shall:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the payor to deduct from the defendant’s income the amount specified in the income deduction order and to pay that amount to the clerk of court.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instruct the payor to implement the income deduction order no later than the first payment date which occurs more than 14 days after the date the income deduction order was served on the payor.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instruct the payor to forward within 2 days after each payment date to the clerk of court the amount deducted from the defendant’s income and a statement as to whether the amount totally or partially satisfies the periodic amount specified in the income deduction order.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify that, if a payor fails to deduct the proper amount from the defendant’s income, the payor is liable for the amount the payor should have deducted plus costs, interest, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that the payor may collect up to $5 against the defendant’s income to reimburse the payor for administrative costs for the first income deduction and up to $2 for each deduction thereafter.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that the income deduction order and the notice to payor are binding on the payor until further notice by the court or until the payor no longer provides income to the defendant.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instruct the payor that, when he or she no longer provides income to the defendant, the payor shall notify the clerk of court and shall also provide the defendant’s last known address and the name and address of the defendant’s new payor, if known, and that, if the payor violates this provision, the payor is subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $250 for the first violation or $500 for any subsequent violation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that the payor shall not discharge, refuse to employ, or take disciplinary action against the defendant because of an income deduction order and shall state that a violation of this provision subjects the payor to a civil penalty not to exceed $250 for the first violation or $500 for any subsequent violation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform the payor that, when he or she receives income deduction orders requiring that the income of two or more defendants be deducted and sent to the same clerk of court, the payor may combine the amounts that are to be paid to the depository in a single payment as long as he or she identifies that portion of the payment attributable to each defendant.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform the payor that if the payor receives more than one income deduction order against the same defendant, he or she shall contact the court for further instructions.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of court shall enforce income deduction orders against the defendant’s successor payor who is located in this state in the same manner prescribed in this subsection for the enforcement of an income deduction order against an original payor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not discharge, refuse to employ, or take disciplinary action against an employee because of the enforcement of an income deduction order. An employer who violates this provision is subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $250 for the first violation or $500 for any subsequent violation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a payor no longer provides income to a defendant, the payor shall notify the clerk of court and shall provide the defendant’s last known address and the name and address of the defendant’s new payor, if known. A payor who violates this provision is subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $250 for the first violation or $500 for a subsequent violation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-150; s. 288, ch. 79-400; s. 5, ch. 84-363; s. 2, ch. 88-96; s. 38, ch. 88-122; s. 10, ch. 89-526; s. 2, ch. 92-107; s. 1, ch. 93-37; s. 3, ch. 93-69; s. 19, ch. 94-342; s. 1, ch. 95-160; s. 1187, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-358; s. 1, ch. 2012-17.</History>
</Section>