<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duty of the court to uphold laws governing sexual predators and sexual offenders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that, for the purpose of approving a plea agreement or for other reasons, certain courts enter orders that effectively limit or nullify requirements imposed upon sexual predators and sexual offenders pursuant to the laws of this state and prevent persons or entities from carrying out the duties imposed, or exercising the authority conferred, by such laws. The laws relating to sexual predators and sexual offenders are substantive law. Furthermore, the Congress of the United States has expressly encouraged every state to enact such laws, and has provided that, to the extent that a state’s laws do not meet certain federal requirements, the state will lose significant federal funding provided to the state for law enforcement and public safety programs. Unless a court that enters such an order determines that a person or entity is not operating in accordance with the laws governing sexual predators or sexual offenders, or that such laws or any part of such laws are unconstitutional or unconstitutionally applied, the court unlawfully encroaches on the Legislature’s exclusive power to make laws and places at risk significant public interests of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person meets the criteria in this chapter for designation as a sexual predator or meets the criteria in s. 943.0435, s. 944.606, s. 944.607, or any other law for classification as a sexual offender, the court may not enter an order, for the purpose of approving a plea agreement or for any other reason, which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exempts a person who meets the criteria for designation as a sexual predator or classification as a sexual offender from such designation or classification, or exempts such person from the requirements for registration or community and public notification imposed upon sexual predators and sexual offenders;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restricts the compiling, reporting, or release of public records information that relates to sexual predators or sexual offenders; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevents any person or entity from performing its duties or operating within its statutorily conferred authority as such duty or authority relates to sexual predators or sexual offenders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court enters an order that affects an agency’s performance of a duty imposed under the laws governing sexual predators or sexual offenders, or that limits the agency’s exercise of authority conferred under such laws, the Legislature strongly encourages the affected agency to file a motion in the court that entered such order. The affected agency may, within 1 year after the receipt of any such order, move to modify or set aside the order or, if such order is in the nature of an injunction, move to dissolve the injunction. Grounds for granting any such motion include, but need not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affected agency was not properly noticed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court is not authorized to enjoin the operation of a statute that has been duly adjudged constitutional and operative unless the statute is illegally applied or unless the statute or the challenged part of it is unconstitutional on adjudicated grounds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jurisdiction may not be conferred by consent of the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that the order is based upon actions the agency might take, the court’s order is premature and, if and when such actions are taken, these actions may be challenged in appropriate proceedings to determine their enforceability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The injunction affects the public interest and would cause injury to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order creates an unenforceable, perpetual injunction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order seeks to restrict the agency in the performance of its duties outside the court’s territorial jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-81; s. 2, ch. 2002-58; s. 7, ch. 2004-371.</History></Section>