<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classes and definitions of offenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in the laws of this state:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “felony” shall mean any criminal offense that is punishable under the laws of this state, or that would be punishable if committed in this state, by death or imprisonment in a state penitentiary. “State penitentiary” shall include state correctional facilities. A person shall be imprisoned in the state penitentiary for each sentence which, except an extended term, exceeds 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “misdemeanor” shall mean any criminal offense that is punishable under the laws of this state, or that would be punishable if committed in this state, by a term of imprisonment in a county correctional facility, except an extended term, not in excess of 1 year. The term “misdemeanor” shall not mean a conviction for any noncriminal traffic violation of any provision of chapter 316 or any municipal or county ordinance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “noncriminal violation” shall mean any offense that is punishable under the laws of this state, or that would be punishable if committed in this state, by no other penalty than a fine, forfeiture, or other civil penalty. A noncriminal violation does not constitute a crime, and conviction for a noncriminal violation shall not give rise to any legal disability based on a criminal offense. The term “noncriminal violation” shall not mean any conviction for any violation of any municipal or county ordinance. Nothing contained in this code shall repeal or change the penalty for a violation of any municipal or county ordinance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “crime” shall mean a felony or misdemeanor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1(11), ch. 1637, 1868; RS 2352; GS 3176; RGS 5006; CGL 7105; s. 1, ch. 71-136; s. 4, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 88-196.</History></Section>