<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Drug offenses; additional penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided by law, a person who has been convicted of sale of or trafficking in, or conspiracy to sell or traffic in, a controlled substance under chapter 893, if such offense is a felony, or who has been convicted of an offense under the laws of any state or country which, if committed in this state, would constitute the felony of selling or trafficking in, or conspiracy to sell or traffic in, a controlled substance under chapter 893, is:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disqualified from applying for employment by any agency of the state, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has completed all sentences of imprisonment or supervisory sanctions imposed by the court, by the Parole Commission, or by law; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has complied with the conditions of subparagraphs 1. and 2. which shall be monitored by the Department of Corrections while the person is under any supervisory sanctions. The person under supervision may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek evaluation and enrollment in, and once enrolled maintain enrollment in until completion, a drug treatment and rehabilitation program which is approved by the Department of Children and Family Services, unless it is deemed by the program that the person does not have a substance abuse problem. The treatment and rehabilitation program may be specified by:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in the case of court-ordered supervisory sanctions;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Parole Commission, in the case of parole, control release, or conditional release; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections, in the case of imprisonment or any other supervision required by law.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to periodic urine drug testing pursuant to procedures prescribed by the Department of Corrections. If the person is indigent, the costs shall be paid by the Department of Corrections.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disqualified from applying for a license, permit, or certificate required by any agency of the state to practice, pursue, or engage in any occupation, trade, vocation, profession, or business, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has completed all sentences of imprisonment or supervisory sanctions imposed by the court, by the Parole Commission, or by law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has complied with the conditions of subparagraphs 1. and 2. which shall be monitored by the Department of Corrections while the person is under any supervisory sanction. If the person fails to comply with provisions of these subparagraphs by either failing to maintain treatment or by testing positive for drug use, the department shall notify the licensing, permitting, or certifying agency, which may refuse to reissue or reinstate such license, permit, or certification. The licensee, permittee, or certificateholder under supervision may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek evaluation and enrollment in, and once enrolled maintain enrollment in until completion, a drug treatment and rehabilitation program which is approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services, unless it is deemed by the program that the person does not have a substance abuse problem. The treatment and rehabilitation program may be specified by:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in the case of court-ordered supervisory sanctions;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Parole Commission, in the case of parole, control release, or conditional release; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections, in the case of imprisonment or any other supervision required by law.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to periodic urine drug testing pursuant to procedures prescribed by the Department of Corrections. If the person is indigent, the costs shall be paid by the Department of Corrections; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has successfully completed an appropriate program under the Correctional Education Program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The provisions of this section do not apply to any of the taxes, fees, or permits regulated, controlled, or administered by the Department of Revenue in accordance with the provisions of s. 213.05.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 90-266; s. 21, ch. 92-310; s. 13, ch. 95-325; s. 292, ch. 99-8.</History></Section>