<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.0847" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Possession or promotion of certain images of child pornography; reclassification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child” means any person, whose identity is known or unknown, less than 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child pornography” means any image depicting a minor engaged in sexual conduct.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sadomasochistic abuse” means flagellation or torture by or upon a person or the condition of being fettered, bound, or otherwise physically restrained, for the purpose of deriving sexual satisfaction, or satisfaction brought about as a result of sadistic violence, from inflicting harm on another or receiving such harm oneself.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual battery” means oral, anal, or vaginal penetration by, or union with, the sexual organ of another or the anal or vaginal penetration of another by any other object; however, sexual battery does not include an act done for a bona fide medical purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual bestiality” means any sexual act, actual or simulated, between a person and an animal involving the sex organ of the one and the mouth, anus, or vagina of the other.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual conduct” means actual or simulated sexual intercourse, deviate sexual intercourse, sexual bestiality, masturbation, or sadomasochistic abuse; actual lewd exhibition of the genitals; actual physical contact with a person’s clothed or unclothed genitals, pubic area, buttocks, or, if such person is a female, breast with the intent to arouse or gratify the sexual desire of either party; or any act or conduct which constitutes sexual battery or simulates that sexual battery is being or will be committed. A mother’s breastfeeding of her baby does not under any circumstance constitute “sexual conduct.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of s. 827.071, s. 847.0135, s. 847.0137, or s. 847.0138 shall be reclassified to the next higher degree as provided in subsection (3) if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offender possesses 10 or more images of any form of child pornography regardless of content; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The content of at least one image contains one or more of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is younger than the age of 5.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sadomasochistic abuse involving a child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery involving a child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual bestiality involving a child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any movie involving a child, regardless of length and regardless of whether the movie contains sound.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the third degree, the offense is reclassified to a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the second degree, the offense is reclassified to a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, a felony offense that is reclassified under this section is ranked one level above the ranking under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023 of the offense committed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2007-143.</History></Section>