<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0775.08435" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibition on withholding adjudication in felony cases.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 948.01, the court may not withhold adjudication of guilt upon the defendant for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any capital, life, or first degree felony offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A second degree felony offense unless:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney requests in writing that adjudication be withheld; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court makes written findings that the withholding of adjudication is reasonably justified based on circumstances or factors in accordance with those set forth in s. 921.0026.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding any provision of this section, no adjudication of guilt shall be withheld for a second degree felony offense if the defendant has a prior withholding of adjudication for a felony that did not arise from the same transaction as the current felony offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A third degree felony offense if the defendant has a prior withholding of adjudication for a felony offense that did not arise from the same transaction as the current felony offense unless:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney requests in writing that adjudication be withheld; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court makes written findings that the withholding of adjudication is reasonably justified based on circumstances or factors in accordance with those set forth in s. 921.0026.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding any provision of this section, no adjudication of guilt shall be withheld for a third degree felony offense if the defendant has two or more prior withholdings of adjudication for a felony that did not arise from the same transaction as the current felony offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any adjudication or withholding of adjudication under chapter 985.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The withholding of adjudication in violation of this section is subject to appellate review under chapter 924.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-60.</History></Section>