<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0775.0823" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violent offenses committed against law enforcement officers, correctional officers, state attorneys, assistant state attorneys, justices, or judges.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature does hereby provide for an increase and certainty of penalty for any person convicted of a violent offense against any law enforcement or correctional officer, as defined in s. 943.10(1), (2), (3), (6), (7), (8), or (9); against any state attorney elected pursuant to s. 27.01 or assistant state attorney appointed under s. 27.181; or against any justice or judge of a court described in Art. V of the State Constitution, which offense arises out of or in the scope of the officer’s duty as a law enforcement or correctional officer, the state attorney’s or assistant state attorney’s duty as a prosecutor or investigator, or the justice’s or judge’s duty as a judicial officer, as follows:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For murder in the first degree as described in s. 782.04(1), if the death sentence is not imposed, a sentence of imprisonment for life without eligibility for release.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For attempted murder in the first degree as described in s. 782.04(1), a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For attempted felony murder as described in s. 782.051, a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For murder in the second degree as described in s. 782.04(2) and (3), a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For attempted murder in the second degree as described in s. 782.04(2) and (3), a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For murder in the third degree as described in s. 782.04(4), a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For attempted murder in the third degree as described in s. 782.04(4), a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For manslaughter as described in s. 782.07 during the commission of a crime, a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For kidnapping as described in s. 787.01, a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For aggravated battery as described in s. 784.045, a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For aggravated assault as described in s. 784.021, a sentence pursuant to s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 948.01, with respect to any person who is found to have violated this section, adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence shall not be suspended, deferred, or withheld.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 89-100; s. 1, ch. 90-77; s. 16, ch. 93-406; s. 17, ch. 95-184; s. 11, ch. 97-194; s. 5, ch. 98-417; s. 3, ch. 2001-236; s. 1, ch. 2007-212; s. 2, ch. 2010-121; s. 5, ch. 2012-21.</History>
</Section>