<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0411.243" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Teen Pregnancy Prevention Community Initiative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the availability of funds, the Department of Health shall create a Teen Pregnancy Prevention Community Initiative. The purpose of this initiative is to create collaborative community partnerships to reduce teen pregnancy. Participating communities shall examine their needs and resources relative to teen pregnancy prevention and develop plans which provide for a collaborative approach to how existing, enhanced, and new initiatives together will reduce teen pregnancy in a community. Community incentive grants shall provide funds for communities to implement plans which provide for a collaborative, comprehensive, outcome-focused approach to reducing teen pregnancy.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of the community incentive grants are as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The goal required of all grants is to reduce the incidence of teen pregnancy. All grants must be designed and required to maintain the data to substantiate reducing the incidence of teen pregnancy in the targeted area in their community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The target population is teens through 19 years of age, including both males and females and mothers and fathers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grants must target a specified geographic area or region, for which data can be maintained to substantiate the teen pregnancy rate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to receive funding, communities must demonstrate collaboration in the provision of existing and new teen pregnancy prevention initiatives. This collaboration shall include developing linkages to the health care, social services, and education systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans must be developed for how a community will reduce the incidence of teen pregnancy in a specified geographic area or region. These plans must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision for collaboration between existing and new initiatives for a comprehensive, well-planned, outcome-focused approach. All organizations involved in teen pregnancy prevention in the community must be involved in the planning and implementation of the community incentive grant initiative.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision in the targeted area or region for all of the components identified below. These components may be addressed through a collaboration of existing initiatives, enhancements, or new initiatives. Community incentive grant funds must address current gaps in the comprehensive teen pregnancy prevention plan for communities.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Primary prevention components are:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevention strategies targeting males.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Role modeling and monitoring.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intervention strategies targeting abused or neglected children.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Human sexuality education.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="V"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual advances protection education.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="VI"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reproductive health care.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="VII"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intervention strategies targeting younger siblings of teen mothers.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="VIII"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community and public awareness.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="IX"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Innovative programs to facilitate prosecutions under s. 794.011, s. 794.05, or s. 800.04.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secondary prevention components are:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home visiting.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parent education, skill building, and supports.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care coordination and case management.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Career development.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="V"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Goal setting and achievement.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Community plans must provide for initiatives which are culturally competent and relevant to the families’ values.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state shall conduct an independent process and outcome evaluation of all the community incentive grant initiatives. The evaluation shall be conducted in three phases: The first phase shall focus on process, including implementation and operation, to be reported on after the first year of operation; the second phase shall be an interim evaluation of the outcome, to be completed after the third year of operation; the third phase shall be a final evaluation of process, outcome, and achievement of the overall goal of reducing the incidence of teen pregnancy, to be completed at the end of the fifth year of operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state shall provide technical assistance, training, and quality assurance to assist the initiative in achieving its goals.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 102, ch. 96-175; s. 198, ch. 99-8.</History></Section>