<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0411.01013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prevailing market rate schedule.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Market rate” means the price that a child care provider charges for daily, weekly, or monthly child care services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prevailing market rate” means the annually determined 75th percentile of a reasonable frequency distribution of the market rate in a predetermined geographic market at which child care providers charge a person for child care services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall establish procedures for the adoption of a prevailing market rate schedule. The schedule must include, at a minimum, county-by-county rates:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the prevailing market rate, plus the maximum rate, for child care providers that hold a Gold Seal Quality Care designation under s. 402.281.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the prevailing market rate for child care providers that do not hold a Gold Seal Quality Care designation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing market rate schedule, at a minimum, must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Differentiate rates by type, including, but not limited to, a child care provider that holds a Gold Seal Quality Care designation under s. 402.281, a child care facility licensed under s. 402.305, a public or nonpublic school exempt from licensure under s. 402.3025, a faith-based child care facility exempt from licensure under s. 402.316 that does not hold a Gold Seal Quality Care designation, a large family child care home licensed under s. 402.3131, or a family day care home licensed or registered under s. 402.313.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Differentiate rates by the type of child care services provided for children with special needs or risk categories, infants, toddlers, preschool-age children, and school-age children.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Differentiate rates between full-time and part-time child care services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider discounted rates for child care services for multiple children in a single family.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing market rate schedule must be based exclusively on the prices charged for child care services. If a conflict exists between this subsection and federal requirements, the federal requirements shall control.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing market rate shall be considered by an early learning coalition in the adoption of a payment schedule in accordance with s. 411.01(5)(e)2.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning may contract with one or more qualified entities to administer this section and provide support and technical assistance for child care providers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 for establishing procedures for the collection of child care providers’ market rate, the calculation of a reasonable frequency distribution of the market rate, and the publication of a prevailing market rate schedule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 91-300; s. 78, ch. 96-175; s. 11, ch. 99-304; s. 33, ch. 2004-357; s. 10, ch. 2010-210; s. 307, ch. 2011-142; s. 49, ch. 2011-213.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 402.3051.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>