<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0411.01015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consultation to child care centers and family day care homes regarding health, developmental, disability, and special needs issues.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, the Office of Early Learning shall administer a statewide toll-free Warm-Line for the purpose of providing assistance and consultation to child care centers and family day care homes regarding health, developmental, disability, and special needs issues of the children they are serving, particularly children with disabilities and other special needs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the Warm-Line is to provide advice to child care personnel concerning strategies, curriculum, and environmental adaptations that allow a child with a disability or special need to derive maximum benefit from child care services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning shall annually inform child care centers and family day care homes of the availability of this service through the child care resource and referral network under s. 411.0101.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, the Office of Early Learning shall expand, or contract for the expansion of, the Warm-Line to maintain at least one Warm-Line site in each early learning coalition service area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each regional Warm-Line shall provide assistance and consultation to child care centers and family day care homes regarding health, developmental, disability, and special needs issues of the children they are serving, particularly children with disabilities and other special needs. Regional Warm-Line staff shall provide onsite technical assistance, when requested, to assist child care centers and family day care homes with inquiries relative to the strategies, curriculum, and environmental adaptations the child care centers and family day care homes may need as they serve children with disabilities and other special needs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 99-304; s. 9, ch. 2010-210; s. 309, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 402.3018.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>