<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0411.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records of children in school readiness programs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual records of children enrolled in school readiness programs provided under s. 411.01, held by an early learning coalition or the Office of Early Learning, are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. For purposes of this section, records include assessment data, health data, records of teacher observations, and personal identifying information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent, guardian, or individual acting as a parent in the absence of a parent or guardian has the right to inspect and review the individual school readiness program record of his or her child and to obtain a copy of the record.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School readiness records may be released to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States Secretary of Education, the United States Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Comptroller General of the United States for the purpose of federal audits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals or organizations conducting studies for institutions to develop, validate, or administer assessments or improve instruction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accrediting organizations in order to carry out their accrediting functions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate parties in connection with an emergency if the information is necessary to protect the health or safety of the child enrollee or other individuals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General in connection with his or her official functions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of competent jurisdiction in compliance with an order of that court in accordance with a lawfully issued subpoena.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parties to an interagency agreement among early learning coalitions, local governmental agencies, providers of school readiness programs, state agencies, and the Office of Early Learning for the purpose of implementing the school readiness program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Agencies, organizations, or individuals that receive school readiness records in order to carry out their official functions must protect the data in a manner that does not permit the personal identification of a child enrolled in a school readiness program and his or her parents by persons other than those authorized to receive the records.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2000-299; s. 9, ch. 2004-484; s. 1, ch. 2005-131; s. 314, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>