<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0411.228" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Accountability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The steering committee shall provide information to the School Readiness Estimating Conference and the Enrollment Conference for Public Schools regarding estimates of the population of children from birth through age 9 who are at risk of learning problems and learning disabilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The steering committee, in conjunction with the demonstration projects, shall develop accountability mechanisms to ensure that the demonstration programs are effective and that resources are used as efficiently as possible. Accountability should be addressed through a multilevel evaluation system, including measurement of outcomes and operational indicators. Measurable outcomes must be developed to address improved child development, improved child health, and success in school. Indicators of system improvements must be developed to address quality of programs and integration of services. Agency monitoring of programs shall include a review of child and family outcomes and system effectiveness indicators with a specific focus on elimination of unnecessary duplication of planning, screening, and services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The steering committee shall oversee a formative evaluation of the project during implementation, including reporting short-term outcomes and system improvements. By January 2005, the steering committee shall make recommendations to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Commissioner of Education related to the merits of expansion of the demonstration projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1, 2005, the steering committee, in conjunction with the demonstration projects, shall develop a model county-level strategic plan to formalize the goals, objectives, strategies, and intended outcomes of the comprehensive system, and to support the integration and efficient delivery of all services and supports for parents of children from birth through age 9 who have learning problems or learning disabilities. The model county-level strategic plan must include, but need not be limited to, strategies to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a system whereby parents can access information about learning problems in young children and receive services at their discretion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improve early identification of those who are at risk for learning problems and learning disabilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide access to an appropriate array of services within the child’s natural environment or regular classroom setting or specialized training in other settings;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improve and coordinate screening for children from birth through age 9;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improve and coordinate services for children from birth through age 9;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address training of professionals in effectively identifying factors, across all domains, which place children from birth through age 9 at risk of school failure and in appropriate interventions for the learning differences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide appropriate support to families;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Share best practices with caregivers and referral sources;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address resource needs of the assessment and intervention system; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address development of implementation plans to establish protocols for requiring and receiving parental consent for services; to identify action steps, responsible parties, and implementation schedules; and to ensure appropriate alignment with agency strategic plans.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2002-265.</History></Section>