<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0411.0104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Early Head Start collaboration grants.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, the Office of Early Learning shall establish a program to award collaboration grants to assist local agencies in securing Early Head Start programs through Early Head Start program federal grants. The collaboration grants shall provide the required matching funds for public and private nonprofit agencies that have been approved for Early Head Start program federal grants.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public and private nonprofit agencies providing Early Head Start programs applying for collaborative grants must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure quality performance by meeting the requirements in the Head Start program performance standards and other applicable rules and regulations;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure collaboration with other service providers at the local level; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that a comprehensive array of health, nutritional, and other services are provided to the program’s pregnant women and very young children, and their families.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Early Learning may adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 as necessary for the award of collaboration grants to competing agencies and the administration of the collaboration grants program under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 99-304; s. 8, ch. 2004-484; s. 109, ch. 2010-102; s. 8, ch. 2010-210; s. 311, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 402.3016.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>