<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0045.045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitations on supersedeas bond; exception.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for certified class actions subject to s. 768.733, in any civil action brought under any legal theory, the amount of a supersedeas bond necessary to obtain an automatic stay of execution of a judgment granting any type of relief during the entire course of all appeals or discretionary reviews, may not exceed $50 million for each appellant, regardless of the amount of the judgment appealed. The $50 million amount shall be adjusted annually to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index compiled by the United States Department of Labor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil action brought under any legal theory, a party seeking a stay of execution of a judgment pending review of any amount may move the court to reduce the amount of a supersedeas bond required to obtain such a stay. The court, in the interest of justice and for good cause shown, may reduce the supersedeas bond or may set other conditions for the stay with or without a bond. The court may not reduce the supersedeas bond if the appellant has an insurance or indemnification policy applicable to the case. This subsection does not apply to certified class actions subject to s. 768.733.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an appellant has posted a supersedeas bond for an amount less than that which would be required for an automatic stay pursuant to Rule 9.310(b)(1), Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure, the appellee may engage in discovery for the limited purpose of determining whether the appellant has dissipated or diverted assets outside the course of its ordinary business or is in the process of doing so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the trial or appellate court determines that an appellant has dissipated or diverted assets outside the course of its ordinary business or is in the process of doing so, the court may enter orders necessary to protect the appellee, require the appellant to post a supersedeas bond in an amount up to, but not more than, the amount that would be required for an automatic stay pursuant to Rule 9.310(b)(1), Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure, and impose other remedies and sanctions as the court deems appropriate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2006-280.</History></Section>