<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0045.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Execution of supersedeas bond when required of the state or its political subdivisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a supersedeas bond is required by the appellate court under Rule 9.310(b)(2), Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure or an appeal or other proceeding is taken in any court and there is no court rule or statute exempting the parties from giving supersedeas, cost, or other required bond, the parties are authorized to make and execute the required bond with a corporate surety thereon duly licensed to do business in this state. The premium or other cost for the bond may be paid from the general necessary and regular appropriation of the party taking the appeal, in the case of the state or any of its officers, boards, commissioners or other agencies, and from the county general fund, district school general fund, or otherwise as the case may be, in the case of a political subdivision of the state or any of its officers, boards, commissions or other agencies. The officers of the state and its political subdivisions and the executive officers of their boards, commissions, and other agencies aforesaid, are authorized to make and execute the bonds on behalf of the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In connection with an appeal taken by a state employee or official of a judgment against that employee or official in an individual capacity, as part of the legal defense being provided by the state risk management program, the Division of Risk Management may enter into an indemnification agreement for the purpose of securing an appellate supersedeas bond, provided that, under any such agreement, the liability of the State of Florida is limited to the amount of the judgment being appealed and any costs imposed by law or the appropriate court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 22854, 1945; s. 4, ch. 71-316; s. 10, ch. 95-280; s. 11, ch. 2001-266.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 59.14(3).</Text></Note></Section>