<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0045.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sale or assignment of rights to surplus funds in a property subject to foreclosure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established a rebuttable presumption that the owner of record of real property on the date of the filing of a lis pendens is the person entitled to surplus funds after payment of subordinate lienholders who have timely filed a claim. A person claiming a legal right to the surplus as an assignee of the rights of the owner of record must prove entitlement to the surplus funds pursuant to this section. It is the intent of the Legislature to abrogate the common law rule that surplus proceeds in a foreclosure case are the property of the owner of the property on the date of the foreclosure sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The presumption may be rebutted only by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee or assignee of a voluntary transfer or assignment establishing a right to collect the surplus funds or any portion or percentage of the surplus funds by proving that the transfer or assignment qualifies as a voluntary transfer or assignment as provided in subsection (3); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grantee or assignee proving that the grantee or assignee is a grantee or assignee by virtue of an involuntary transfer or assignment of the right to collect the surplus. An involuntary transfer or assignment may be as a result of inheritance or as a result of the appointment of a guardian.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voluntary transfer or assignment shall be a transfer or assignment qualified under this subsection, thereby entitling the transferee or assignee to the surplus funds or a portion or percentage of the surplus funds, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment is in writing and the instrument:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If executed prior to the foreclosure sale, includes a financial disclosure that specifies the assessed value of the property, a statement that the assessed value may be lower than the actual value of the property, the approximate amount of any debt encumbering the property, and the approximate amount of any equity in the property. If the instrument was executed after the foreclosure sale, the instrument must also specify the foreclosure sale price and the amount of the surplus.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Includes a statement that the owner does not need an attorney or other representative to recover surplus funds in a foreclosure.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies all forms of consideration paid for the rights to the property or the assignment of the rights to any surplus funds.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment is filed with the court on or before 60 days after the filing of the certificate of disbursements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are funds available to pay the transfer or assignment after payment of timely filed claims of subordinate lienholders.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transferor or assignee is qualified as a surplus trustee, or could qualify as a surplus trustee, pursuant to s. 45.034.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total compensation paid or payable, or earned or expected to be earned, by the transferee or assignee does not exceed 12 percent of the surplus.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall honor a transfer or assignment that complies with the requirements of subsection (3), in which case the court shall order the clerk to pay the transferor or assignee from the surplus.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that a voluntary transfer or assignment does not qualify under subsection (3) but that the transfer or assignment was procured in good faith and with no intent to defraud the transferor or assignor, the court may order the clerk to pay the claim of the transferee or assignee after payment of timely filed claims of subordinate lienholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a voluntary transfer or assignment of the surplus is set aside, the owner of record shall be entitled to payment of the surplus after payment of timely filed claims of subordinate lienholders, but the transferee or assignee may seek in a separate proceeding repayment of any consideration paid for the transfer or assignment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a deed, mortgage, or deed in lieu of foreclosure unless a person other than the owner of record is claiming that a deed or mortgage entitles the person to surplus funds. Nothing in this section affects the title or marketability of the real property that is the subject of the deed or other instrument. Nothing in this section affects the validity of a lien evidenced by a mortgage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2006-175.</History></Section>