<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0877.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inhalation, ingestion, possession, sale, purchase, or transfer of harmful chemical substances; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to inhale or ingest, or to possess with intent to breathe, inhale, or drink, any compound, liquid, or chemical containing toluol, hexane, trichloroethylene, acetone, toluene, ethyl acetate, methyl ethyl ketone, trichloroethane, isopropanol, methyl isobutyl ketone, ethylene glycol monomethyl ether acetate, cyclohexanone, nitrous oxide, diethyl ether, alkyl nitrites (butyl nitrite), or any similar substance for the purpose of inducing a condition of intoxication or which distorts or disturbs the auditory, visual, or mental processes. This section does not apply to the possession and use of these substances as part of the care or treatment of a disease or injury by a practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, part I of chapter 464, or chapter 466 or to beverages controlled by the provisions of chapter 561, chapter 562, chapter 563, chapter 564, or chapter 565.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to possess, buy, sell, or otherwise transfer any chemical substance specified in subsection (1) for the purpose of inducing or aiding any other person to violate the provisions of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4) with respect to nitrous oxide, any person who violates subsection (1) or subsection (2) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly distributes, sells, purchases, transfers, or possesses more than 16 grams of nitrous oxide commits a felony of the third degree which shall be known as unlawful distribution of nitrous oxide, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. For purposes of this subsection, in addition to proving by any other means that nitrous oxide was knowingly possessed, distributed, sold, purchased, or transferred, proof that any person discharged, or aided another in discharging, nitrous oxide to inflate a balloon or any other object suitable for subsequent inhalation creates an inference of the person’s knowledge that the nitrous oxide’s use was for an unlawful purpose. This subsection does not apply to the possession and use of nitrous oxide as part of the care and treatment of a disease or injury by a practitioner licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 464, chapter 466, or chapter 474; as a food-processing propellant; as a semiconductor oxidizer; as an analytical chemistry oxidizer in atomic absorption spectrometry; in the production of chemicals used to inflate airbags; as an oxidizer for chemical production, combustion, or jet propulsion; or as a motor vehicle induction additive when mixed with sulphur dioxide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any of the provisions of this section may, in the discretion of the trial judge, be required to participate in a substance abuse services program approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services pursuant to the provisions of chapter 397, provided the director of the program approves the placement of the defendant in the program. Such required participation may be imposed in addition to, or in lieu of, any penalty or probation otherwise prescribed by law. However, the total time of such penalty, probation, and program participation shall not exceed the maximum length of sentence possible for the offense.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-187; s. 39, ch. 93-39; s. 299, ch. 99-8; s. 1, ch. 2000-116; s. 146, ch. 2000-318; s. 4, ch. 2001-57.</History></Section>