<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0877.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Escrow business by unauthorized persons; use of name.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), in connection with the purchase and sale of real property, a person may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transact business under any name or title that contains the word “escrow” or words of similar import; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use any name, word, sign, symbol, or device in any context or in any manner; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Circulate or use any letterhead, billhead, circular, paper, or writing of any kind or otherwise advertise or represent in any manner</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">that indicates or reasonably implies that the business being conducted or advertised is the kind or character of business transacted that is regulated by this state as an escrow agent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution as defined in s. 655.005;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An attorney who is a member of The Florida Bar or his or her law firm;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is licensed pursuant to chapter 475 or his or her brokerage firm; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A title insurance agent who is licensed pursuant to s. 626.8417, a title insurance agency that is licensed pursuant to s. 626.8418, or a title insurer who is authorized to transact business in this state pursuant to s. 624.401.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person aggrieved by a violation of this section may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction to obtain a declaratory judgment that an act or practice violates this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action brought by a person who has suffered a loss as a result of a violation of this section, such person may recover actual damages, plus attorney’s fees and court costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully violates this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-200.</History></Section>