<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0877.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identification card or document purporting to contain applicant’s age or date of birth; penalties for failure to comply with requirements for sale or issuance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, except a governmental agency or instrumentality, to sell or issue, or to offer to sell or issue, in this state any identification card or document purporting to contain the age or date of birth of the person in whose name it was issued, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to selling or issuing such card or document, the person has first obtained from the applicant and retains for a period of 3 years from the date of sale:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authenticated or certified copy of proof of age as provided in s. 1003.21(4); and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notarized affidavit from the applicant attesting to the applicant’s age and that the proof-of-age document required by subparagraph 1. is for such applicant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to offering to sell such cards in this state, the person has included in any offer for sale of identification cards or documents that such cards cannot be sold or issued without the applicants’ first submitting the documents required by paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification card or document contains the business name and street address of the person selling or issuing such card or document.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “offer to sell” includes every inducement, solicitation, attempt, or printed or media advertisement to encourage a person to purchase an identification card.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All records required to be maintained by this section shall be available for inspection without warrant upon reasonable demand by any law enforcement officer, including, but not limited to, a state attorney investigator or an investigator for the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates the provisions of this section is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. The failure to produce the documents required by subsection (1), upon lawful request therefor, is prima facie evidence of a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney for any county in which a violation of this section occurs or the Attorney General may enjoin any sale or offer for sale in violation of this section by temporary and permanent injunction by application to any court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 84-297; s. 1040, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>