<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0877.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonapplication of s. 877.22.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 877.22 does not apply to a minor who is:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accompanied by his or her parent or by another adult authorized by the minor’s parent to have custody of the minor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involved in an emergency or engaged, with his or her parent’s permission, in an emergency errand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attending or traveling directly to or from an activity that involves the exercise of rights protected under the First Amendment of the United States Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Going directly to or returning directly from lawful employment, or who is in a public place or establishment in connection with or as required by a business, trade, profession, or occupation in which the minor is lawfully engaged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Returning directly home from a school-sponsored function, a religious function, or a function sponsored by a civic organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the property of, or on the sidewalk of, the place where the minor resides, or who is on the property or sidewalk of an adult next-door neighbor with that neighbor’s permission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaged in interstate travel or bona fide intrastate travel with the consent of the minor’s parent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attending an organized event held at and sponsored by a theme park or entertainment complex as defined in s. 509.013(9).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 86, ch. 94-209; s. 1433, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>