<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0375.251" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation on liability of persons making available to public certain areas for recreational purposes without charge.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to encourage persons to make land, water areas, and park areas available to the public for outdoor recreational purposes by limiting their liability to persons using these areas and to third persons who may be damaged by the acts or omissions of persons using these areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner or lessee who provides the public with an area for outdoor recreational purposes owes no duty of care to keep that area safe for entry or use by others, or to give warning to persons entering or going on that area of any hazardous conditions, structures, or activities on the area. An owner or lessee who provides the public with an area for outdoor recreational purposes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not presumed to extend any assurance that the area is safe for any purpose;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not incur any duty of care toward a person who goes on the area; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not liable or responsible for any injury to persons or property caused by the act or omission of a person who goes on the area.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the inclusion of the term “public” in this subsection and subsection (1), an owner or lessee who makes available to any person an area primarily for the purposes of hunting, fishing, or wildlife viewing is entitled to the limitation on liability provided herein so long as the owner or lessee provides written notice of this provision to the person before or at the time of entry upon the area or posts notice of this provision conspicuously upon the area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that an area offered for outdoor recreational purposes may be subject to multiple uses. The limitation of liability extended to an owner or lessee under this subsection applies only if no charge is made for entry to or use of the area for outdoor recreational purposes and no other revenue is derived from patronage of the area for outdoor recreational purposes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner of an area who enters into a written agreement concerning the area with the state for outdoor recreational purposes, where such agreement recognizes that the state is responsible for personal injury, loss, or damage resulting in whole or in part from the state’s use of the area under the terms of the agreement subject to the limitations and conditions specified in s. 768.28, owes no duty of care to keep the area safe for entry or use by others, or to give warning to persons entering or going on the area of any hazardous conditions, structures, or activities thereon. An owner who enters into a written agreement concerning the area with the state for outdoor recreational purposes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not presumed to extend any assurance that the area is safe for any purpose;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not incur any duty of care toward a person who goes on the area that is subject to the agreement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not liable or responsible for any injury to persons or property caused by the act or omission of a person who goes on the area that is subject to the agreement.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection applies to all persons going on the area that is subject to the agreement, including invitees, licensees, and trespassers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this subsection that an agreement entered into pursuant to this subsection should not result in compensation to the owner of the area above reimbursement of reasonable costs or expenses associated with the agreement. An agreement that provides for such does not subject the owner or the state to liability even if the compensation exceeds those costs or expenses. This paragraph applies only to agreements executed after July 1, 2012.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not relieve any person of liability that would otherwise exist for deliberate, willful, or malicious injury to persons or property. This section does not create or increase the liability of any person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Area” includes land, water, and park areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Outdoor recreational purposes” includes, but is not limited to, hunting, fishing, wildlife viewing, swimming, boating, camping, picnicking, hiking, pleasure driving, nature study, water skiing, motorcycling, and visiting historical, archaeological, scenic, or scientific sites.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 63-313; s. 1, ch. 75-17; s. 7, ch. 87-328; s. 1, ch. 2012-203.</History></Section>