<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0957.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for contractors operating private correctional facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contractor entering into a contract under this chapter is liable in tort with respect to the care and custody of inmates under its supervision and for any breach of contract. Sovereign immunity may not be raised by a contractor, or the insurer of that contractor on the contractor’s behalf, as a defense in any action arising out of the performance of any contract entered into under this chapter or as a defense in tort, or any other application, with respect to the care and custody of inmates under the contractor’s supervision and for any breach of contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The training requirements, including inservice training requirements, for employees of a contractor that assumes the responsibility for the operation and maintenance of a private correctional facility must meet or exceed the requirements for similar employees of the department or the training requirements mandated for accreditation by the American Correctional Association, whichever of those requirements are the more demanding. All employee training expenses are the responsibility of the contractor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees of a contractor who are responsible for the supervision of inmates shall have the same legal authority to rely on nondeadly and deadly force as do similar employees of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contractor or person employed by a contractor operating a correctional or detention facility pursuant to a contract executed under this chapter shall be exempt from the requirements of chapter 493, relating to licensure of private investigators and security officers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 93-406; s. 57, ch. 96-312.</History></Section>