<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0957.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contract requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract entered into under this chapter for the operation of private correctional facilities shall maximize the cost savings of such facilities and shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be negotiated with the firm found most qualified. However, a contract for private correctional services may not be entered into by the Department of Management Services unless the Department of Management Services determines that the contractor has demonstrated that it has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualifications, experience, and management personnel necessary to carry out the terms of the contract.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability to expedite the siting, design, and construction of correctional facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability to comply with applicable laws, court orders, and national correctional standards.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indemnify the state and the department, including their officials and agents, against any and all liability, including, but not limited to, civil rights liability. Proof of satisfactory insurance is required in an amount to be determined by the Department of Management Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that the contractor seek, obtain, and maintain accreditation by the American Correctional Association for the facility under that contract. Compliance with amendments to the accreditation standards of the association is required upon the approval of such amendments by the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that the proposed facilities and the management plans for the inmates meet applicable American Correctional Association standards and the requirements of all applicable court orders and state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish operations standards for correctional facilities subject to the contract. However, if the department and the contractor disagree with an operations standard, the contractor may propose to waive any rule, policy, or procedure of the department related to the operations standards of correctional facilities which is inconsistent with the mission of the contractor to establish cost-effective, privately operated correctional facilities. The Department of Management Services shall be responsible for considering all proposals from the contractor to waive any rule, policy, or procedure and shall render a final decision granting or denying such request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the contractor to be responsible for a range of dental, medical, and psychological services; diet; education; and work programs at least equal to those provided by the department in comparable facilities. The work and education programs must be designed to reduce recidivism, and include opportunities to participate in such work programs as authorized pursuant to s. 946.523.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the selection and appointment of a full-time contract monitor. The contract monitor shall be appointed and supervised by the Department of Management Services. The contractor is required to reimburse the Department of Management Services for the salary and expenses of the contract monitor. It is the obligation of the contractor to provide suitable office space for the contract monitor at the correctional facility. The contract monitor shall have unlimited access to the correctional facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be for a period of 3 years and may be renewed for successive 2-year periods thereafter. However, the state is not obligated for any payments to the contractor beyond current annual appropriations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract entered into for the design and construction of a private correctional facility or juvenile commitment facility must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 255 to the contrary, a specific provision authorizing the use of tax-exempt financing through the issuance of tax-exempt bonds, certificates of participation, lease-purchase agreements, or other tax-exempt financing methods. Pursuant to s. 255.25, approval is hereby provided for the lease-purchase of up to two private correctional facilities and any other facility authorized by the General Appropriations Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific provision requiring the design and construction of the proposed facilities to meet the applicable standards of the American Correctional Association and the requirements of all applicable court orders and state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific provision requiring the contractor, and not the Department of Management Services, to obtain the financing required to design and construct the private correctional facility or juvenile commitment facility built under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific provision stating that the state is not obligated for any payments that exceed the amount of the current annual appropriation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract for the designing, financing, acquiring, leasing, constructing, and operating of a private correctional facility shall be subject to ss. 255.2502 and 255.2503.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract for the designing, financing, acquiring, leasing, and constructing of a private juvenile commitment facility shall be subject to ss. 255.2502 and 255.2503.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract entered into under this chapter does not accord third-party beneficiary status to any inmate or juvenile offender or to any member of the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract entered into by the Department of Management Services must include substantial minority participation unless demonstrated by evidence, after a good faith effort, as impractical and must also include any other requirements the Department of Management Services considers necessary and appropriate for carrying out the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025(7), the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund need not approve a lease-purchase agreement negotiated by the Department of Management Services if the Department of Management Services finds that there is a need to expedite the lease-purchase.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025 or s. 287.057, whenever the Department of Management Services finds it to be in the best interest of timely site acquisition, it may contract without the need for competitive selection with one or more appraisers whose names are contained on the list of approved appraisers maintained by the Division of State Lands of the Department of Environmental Protection in accordance with s. 253.025(6)(b). In those instances when the Department of Management Services directly contracts for appraisal services, it shall also contract with an approved appraiser who is not employed by the same appraisal firm for review services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 253.025(6), the Department of Management Services may negotiate and enter into lease-purchase agreements before an appraisal is obtained. Any such agreement must state that the final purchase price cannot exceed the maximum value allowed by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 93-406; s. 2, ch. 94-148; s. 56, ch. 96-312; s. 13, ch. 96-420; s. 22, ch. 96-422; s. 124, ch. 99-3; s. 26, ch. 99-4; s. 6, ch. 99-271; s. 12, ch. 2001-242; s. 1939, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2004-248; s. 23, ch. 2006-2; s. 3, ch. 2006-32.</History></Section>