<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0876.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal anarchy, Communism, and other specified doctrines; prohibitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By word of mouth or writing advocates, advises, or teaches the duty, necessity, or propriety of overthrowing or overturning existing forms of constitutional government by force or violence; of disobeying or sabotaging or hindering the carrying out of the laws, orders, or decrees of duly constituted civil, naval, or military authorities; or by the assassination of officials of the Government of the United States or of the state, or by any unlawful means or under the guidance of, or in collaboration with, officials, agents, or representatives of a foreign state or an international revolutionary party or group; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prints, publishes, edits, issues, or knowingly circulates, sells, distributes, or publicly displays any book, paper, document, or written or printed matter in any form, containing or advocating, advising, or teaching the doctrine that constitutional government should be overthrown by force, violence, or any unlawful means; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Openly, willfully and deliberately urges, advocates, or justifies by word of mouth or writing the assassination or unlawful killing or assaulting of any official of the Government of the United States or of this state because of his or her official character, or any other crime, with intent to teach, spread, or advocate the propriety of the doctrines of criminal anarchy, criminal Communism, criminal Naziism, or criminal Fascism; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizes or helps to organize or becomes a member of any society, group, or assembly of persons formed to teach or advocate such doctrines; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Becomes a member of, associated with or promotes the interest of any criminal anarchistic, Communistic, Naziistic or Fascistic organization, or helps to organize or becomes a member of or affiliated with any subsidiary organization or associated group of persons who advocates, teaches, or advises the principles of criminal anarchy, criminal Communism, criminal Naziism or criminal Fascism;</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 20216, 1941; s. 1137, ch. 71-136; s. 1411, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>