<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0876.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subversive activities unlawful; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be a felony for any person knowingly and willfully to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commit, attempt to commit, or aid in the commission of any act intended to overthrow, destroy, to assist the overthrow or destruction of the constitutional form of the Government of the United States, or of the state, or any political subdivision of either of them, by revolution, force, violence, or other unlawful means; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocate, abet, advise, or teach by any means any person to commit, attempt to commit, or assist in the commission of any such act under such circumstances as to constitute a clear and present danger to the security of the United States, or of this state, or of any political subdivision of either of them; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspire with one or more persons to commit any such act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in the formation or participate in the management or to contribute to the support of any subversive organization or foreign subversive organization knowing said organization to be a subversive organization or a foreign subversive organization; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Destroy any books, records, or files, or secrete any funds in this state of a subversive organization or a foreign subversive organization, knowing said organization to be such.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any of the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28221, 1953; s. 1143, ch. 71-136.</History></Section>