<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.321" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of the department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a comprehensive state plan for the provision of substance abuse services. The plan must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of incidence and prevalence of problems related to substance abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Description of current services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Need for services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cost of services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Priorities for funding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strategies to address the identified needs and priorities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resource planning.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that a plan for substance abuse services is developed at the local substate entity level in accordance with the provisions of part IV of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide on a direct or contractual basis, within the context of funds made available by appropriation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public education programs and an information clearinghouse to disseminate information about the nature and effects of substance abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training for personnel who provide substance abuse services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A data collection and dissemination system, in accordance with applicable federal confidentiality regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic epidemiological and statistical research and the dissemination of results.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research in cooperation with qualified researchers on services delivered pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a funding program for the dissemination of available federal, state, and private funds through contractual agreements with community-based organizations or units of state or local government which deliver local substance abuse services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assume responsibility for adopting rules as necessary to comply with this chapter, including other state agencies in this effort, as appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assume responsibility for licensing and regulating licensable service components delivering substance abuse services on behalf of service providers pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that each licensed service provider develops a system and procedures for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical assessment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Treatment planning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Referral.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Progress reviews.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Followup.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the systematic and comprehensive program evaluation of substance abuse service providers that are state-owned, state-operated, or state-contracted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the Governor in the preparation of plans to be submitted for federal funding and support.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a system of documentation and reporting commensurate with the requirements of federal and other agencies providing funding to the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, within available funds, training and technical assistance to other state agencies relative to the problem of substance abuse and develop joint agreements with other state agencies to enhance the sharing of information and services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop standards for employee assistance programs for employees of state government, local governments, and private business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that service provider personnel have background checks as required in this chapter and meet the minimum standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with service providers, foster and actively seek additional funding to enhance resources for prevention, intervention, clinical treatment, and recovery support services, including, but not limited to, the development of partnerships with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intradepartmental and interdepartmental program offices, including, but not limited to, child care services; family safety; delinquency services; health services; economic services; and children’s medical services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State agencies, including, but not limited to, the Department of Corrections, the Department of Education, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Department of Elderly Affairs, the Department of Health, the Department of Financial Services, and the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a substance abuse impairment coordinator to represent the department in efforts initiated by the statewide substance abuse impairment prevention and treatment coordinator established in s. 397.801 and to assist the statewide coordinator in fulfilling the responsibilities of that position.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize a statewide certification process for addiction professionals and identify and endorse one or more agencies responsible for such certification of service provider personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a certification process by rule for community substance abuse prevention coalitions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide sufficient and qualified staff to oversee all contracting, licensing, and planning functions within each of its substate offices, as permitted by legislative appropriation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the department develops and ensures the implementation of procedures between its Substance Abuse Program Office and other departmental programs regarding the referral of substance abuse impaired persons to service providers, information on service providers, information on methods of identifying substance abuse impaired juveniles, and procedures for referring such juveniles to appropriate service providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate addictions receiving facilities for the purpose of ensuring that only qualified service providers render services within the context of a secure facility setting.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 93-39; s. 2, ch. 97-208; s. 34, ch. 97-271; s. 6, ch. 98-152; ss. 53, 54, ch. 2000-139; s. 17, ch. 2000-349; s. 9, ch. 2009-132; s. 273, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>