<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.702" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorization of local ordinances for treatment of habitual abusers in licensed secure facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Due to the severity in certain areas of the state of chronic and habitual public impairment which infringes upon the public health, safety, and welfare of the citizens, counties and municipalities are authorized to adopt ordinances in strict compliance with this section, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 397.701.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinances for the treatment of habitual abusers must provide:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the construction and funding, either individually or jointly with other counties or municipalities, of a licensed secure facility to be used exclusively for the treatment of habitual abusers who meet the criteria in paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That when seeking treatment of a habitual abuser, the county or municipality, through an officer or agent specified in the ordinance, must file with the court a petition which alleges the following information about the alleged habitual abuser (the respondent):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, age, and gender of the respondent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of any spouse, adult child, other relative, or guardian of the respondent, if known to the petitioner, and the efforts by the petitioner, if any, to ascertain this information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the petitioner, the name of the person who has physical custody of the respondent, and the current location of the respondent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the respondent has been taken into custody for impairment in a public place, or has been arrested for an offense committed while impaired, three or more times during the preceding 12 months.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specific facts indicating that the respondent meets the criteria for involuntary admission in s. 397.675.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the respondent was advised of his or her right to be represented by counsel and to request that the court appoint an attorney if he or she is unable to afford one, and whether the respondent indicated to petitioner his or her desire to have an attorney appointed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the court with jurisdiction to make the determination authorized by this section shall hear the petition on an emergency basis as soon as practicable but not later than 10 days after the date the petition was filed. If the allegations of the petition indicate that the respondent has requested the appointment of an attorney, or otherwise indicate the absence of any competent person to speak at the hearing on behalf of the respondent, the court shall immediately appoint an attorney to represent the respondent pursuant to s. 397.501(8), and shall provide notice of the hearing to the attorney. When the court sets a hearing date the petitioner shall provide notice of the hearing and a copy of the petition to all of the persons named in the petition pursuant to subparagraph (b)2., and to such other persons as may be ordered by the court to receive notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, upon the court’s determination that the allegations of the petition as stated in paragraph (b) are established, the respondent is a habitual abuser and must be detained at the licensed secure facility for a period of up to 90 days as determined by the court for the purpose of participating in a treatment program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, if the individual still meets the criteria for involuntary admission in s. 397.675 at or near the expiration of the treatment period ordered by the court pursuant to paragraph (d), the agent of the county or municipality may file another habitual abuser petition pursuant to paragraph (b) for a period not exceeding 180 days for each such petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a person who is reasonably suspected of meeting the criteria in paragraph (b) may be detained at a licensed service provider or at a licensed secure facility for a period not exceeding 96 hours for purposes of the preparation and filing of the petition.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a petition is filed under an ordinance authorized by this section, alleging a reasonable suspicion that the respondent meets the criteria in paragraph (2)(b), the department and any licensed service provider director with relevant information must, upon the court’s request and in accordance with federal confidentiality regulations, furnish the court with all information necessary to determine the accuracy of the allegations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the operation under contract of any licensed secure correctional facility or licensed service provider at a secure correctional facility which is not operating pursuant to an ordinance adopted under authorization of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 93-39; s. 756, ch. 95-148; s. 41, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>