<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions from licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from the licensing provisions of this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hospital or hospital-based component licensed under chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nursing home facility as defined in s. 400.021.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A substance abuse education program established pursuant to s. 1003.42.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility or institution operated by the Federal Government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician or physician assistant licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A psychologist licensed under chapter 490.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A social worker, marriage and family therapist, or mental health counselor licensed under chapter 491.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legally cognizable church or nonprofit religious organization or denomination providing substance abuse services, including prevention services, which are solely religious, spiritual, or ecclesiastical in nature. A church or nonprofit religious organization or denomination providing any of the licensed service components itemized under s. 397.311(18) is not exempt from substance abuse licensure but retains its exemption with respect to all services which are solely religious, spiritual, or ecclesiastical in nature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities licensed under chapter 393 which, in addition to providing services to persons with developmental disabilities, also provide services to persons developmentally at risk as a consequence of exposure to alcohol or other legal or illegal drugs while in utero.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUI education and screening services provided pursuant to ss. 316.192, 316.193, 322.095, 322.271, and 322.291. Persons or entities providing treatment services must be licensed under this chapter unless exempted from licensing as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility licensed under s. 394.875 as a crisis stabilization unit.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The exemptions from licensure in this section do not apply to any service provider that receives an appropriation, grant, or contract from the state to operate as a service provider as defined in this chapter or to any substance abuse program regulated pursuant to s. 397.406. Furthermore, this chapter may not be construed to limit the practice of a physician or physician assistant licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, a psychologist licensed under chapter 490, a psychotherapist licensed under chapter 491, or an advanced registered nurse practitioner licensed under part I of chapter 464, who provides substance abuse treatment, so long as the physician, physician assistant, psychologist, psychotherapist, or advanced registered nurse practitioner does not represent to the public that he or she is a licensed service provider and does not provide services to individuals pursuant to part V of this chapter. Failure to comply with any requirement necessary to maintain an exempt status under this section is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-39; s. 734, ch. 95-148; s. 65, ch. 97-190; s. 208, ch. 99-13; s. 9, ch. 2000-350; s. 51, ch. 2001-45; s. 31, ch. 2001-62; s. 3, ch. 2002-196; s. 985, ch. 2002-387; s. 91, ch. 2004-267; s. 4, ch. 2005-55; s. 44, ch. 2006-1; s. 40, ch. 2006-227; s. 13, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>