<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0397.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, except part VIII, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ancillary services” are services that include, but are not limited to, special diagnostic, prenatal and postnatal, other medical, mental health, legal, economic, vocational, employment, and educational services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authorized agent of the department” means a person designated by the department to conduct any audit, inspection, monitoring, evaluation, or other duty imposed upon the department pursuant to this chapter. An authorized agent must be qualified by expertise and experience to perform these functions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beyond the safe management capabilities of the service provider” refers to an individual who is in need of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervision;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical care; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">beyond that which the service provider or service component can deliver.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clinical assessment” means the collection of detailed information concerning an individual’s substance use, emotional and physical health, social roles, and other areas that may reflect the severity of the individual’s abuse of alcohol or drugs. The collection of information serves as a basis for identifying an appropriate treatment regimen.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means the court of legal jurisdiction in the context in which the term is used in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the chief administrative or executive officer of a service provider.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disclose” or “disclosure” means a communication of identifying information, the affirmative verification of another person’s communication of identifying information, or the communication of any information regarding an individual who has received services. Any disclosure made pursuant to this chapter must be limited to that information which is necessary to carry out the purpose of the disclosure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fee system” means a method of establishing charges for services rendered, in accordance with an individual’s ability to pay, used by providers that receive state funds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“For profit” means registered as for profit by the Secretary of State and recognized by the Internal Revenue Service as a for-profit entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Habitual abuser” means a person who is brought to the attention of law enforcement for being substance impaired, who meets the criteria for involuntary admission in s. 397.675, and who has been taken into custody for such impairment three or more times during the preceding 12 months.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hospital” means a hospital or hospital-based component licensed under chapter 395.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Identifying information” means the name, address, social security number, fingerprints, photograph, and similar information by which the identity of an individual can be determined with reasonable accuracy directly or by reference to other publicly available information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Impaired” or “substance abuse impaired” means a condition involving the use of alcoholic beverages or any psychoactive or mood-altering substance in such a manner as to induce mental, emotional, or physical problems and cause socially dysfunctional behavior.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Individual” means a person who receives alcohol or other drug abuse treatment services delivered by a service provider. The term does not include an inmate pursuant to part VIII of this chapter unless expressly so provided.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement officer” means a law enforcement officer as defined in s. 943.10(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed service provider” means a public agency under this chapter, a private for-profit or not-for-profit agency under this chapter, a physician or any other private practitioner licensed under this chapter, or a hospital that offers substance abuse services through one or more licensed service components.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed service components include a comprehensive continuum of accessible and quality substance abuse prevention, intervention, and clinical treatment services, including the following services:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clinical treatment” means a professionally directed, deliberate, and planned regimen of services and interventions that are designed to reduce or eliminate the misuse of drugs and alcohol and promote a healthy, drug-free lifestyle. As defined by rule, “clinical treatment services” include, but are not limited to, the following licensable service components:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Addictions receiving facility” is a secure, acute care facility that provides, at a minimum, detoxification and stabilization services; is operated 24 hours per day, 7 days per week; and is designated by the department to serve individuals found to be substance use impaired as described in s. 397.675 who meet the placement criteria for this component.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Day or night treatment” is a service provided in a nonresidential environment, with a structured schedule of treatment and rehabilitative services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Day or night treatment with community housing” means a program intended for individuals who can benefit from living independently in peer community housing while participating in treatment services for a minimum of 5 hours a day for a minimum of 25 hours per week.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Detoxification” is a service involving subacute care that is provided on an inpatient or an outpatient basis to assist individuals to withdraw from the physiological and psychological effects of substance abuse and who meet the placement criteria for this component.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intensive inpatient treatment” includes a planned regimen of evaluation, observation, medical monitoring, and clinical protocols delivered through an interdisciplinary team approach provided 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, in a highly structured, live-in environment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intensive outpatient treatment” is a service that provides individual or group counseling in a more structured environment, is of higher intensity and duration than outpatient treatment, and is provided to individuals who meet the placement criteria for this component.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medication-assisted treatment for opiate addiction” is a service that uses methadone or other medication as authorized by state and federal law, in combination with medical, rehabilitative, and counseling services in the treatment of individuals who are dependent on opioid drugs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Outpatient treatment” is a service that provides individual, group, or family counseling by appointment during scheduled operating hours for individuals who meet the placement criteria for this component.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential treatment” is a service provided in a structured live-in environment within a nonhospital setting on a 24-hours-per-day, 7-days-per-week basis, and is intended for individuals who meet the placement criteria for this component.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intervention” means structured services directed toward individuals or groups at risk of substance abuse and focused on reducing or impeding those factors associated with the onset or the early stages of substance abuse and related problems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prevention” means a process involving strategies that are aimed at the individual, family, community, or substance and that preclude, forestall, or impede the development of substance use problems and promote responsible lifestyles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medication-assisted treatment (MAT)” is the use of medications approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration, in combination with counseling and behavioral therapies, to provide a holistic approach to the treatment of substance abuse.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical monitoring” means oversight and treatment, 24 hours per day by medical personnel who are licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, or chapter 464, of individuals whose subacute problems are so severe that the individuals require intensive inpatient treatment by an interdisciplinary team.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Not for profit” means registered as not for profit by the Secretary of State and recognized by the Internal Revenue Service as a not-for-profit entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a person licensed under chapter 458 to practice medicine or licensed under chapter 459 to practice osteopathic medicine, and may include, if the context so indicates, an intern or resident enrolled in an intern or resident training program affiliated with an approved medical school, hospital, or other facility through which training programs are normally conducted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician assistant” means a person licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 to practice medicine under the supervision of a physician or psychiatrist whose specialty includes substance abuse treatment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private practitioner” means a physician or a physician assistant licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, a psychologist licensed under chapter 490, or a clinical social worker, marriage and family therapist, or mental health counselor licensed under chapter 491.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Program evaluation” or “evaluation” means a systematic measurement of a service provider’s achievement of desired individual or service outcomes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified professional” means a physician or a physician assistant licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459; a professional licensed under chapter 490 or chapter 491; an advanced registered nurse practitioner having a specialty in psychiatry licensed under part I of chapter 464; or a person who is certified through a department-recognized certification process for substance abuse treatment services and who holds, at a minimum, a bachelor’s degree. A person who is certified in substance abuse treatment services by a state-recognized certification process in another state at the time of employment with a licensed substance abuse provider in this state may perform the functions of a qualified professional as defined in this chapter but must meet certification requirements contained in this subsection no later than 1 year after his or her date of employment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Quality improvement” means a systematic and organized approach to monitor and continuously improve the quality of services in order to maintain, restore, or improve outcomes in individuals and populations throughout a system of care.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recovery” means a process of personal change through which individuals achieve abstinence from alcohol or drug use and improve health, wellness, and quality of life.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="29">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recovery support” means services designed to strengthen or assist individuals to regain skills, develop the environmental supports necessary to help the individual thrive in the community, and meet life goals that promote recovery from alcohol and drug use. These services include, but are not limited to, economic, vocational, employment, educational, housing, and other ancillary services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="30">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Screening” means the gathering of initial information to be used in determining a person’s need for assessment, services, or referral.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="31">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secure facility,” except where the context indicates a correctional system facility, means a provider that has the authority to deter the premature departure of involuntary individuals whose leaving constitutes a violation of a court order or community-based supervision as provided by law. The term “secure facility” includes addictions receiving facilities and facilities authorized by local ordinance for the treatment of habitual abusers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="32">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service component” or “component” means a discrete operational entity within a service provider which is subject to licensing as defined by rule. Service components include prevention, intervention, and clinical treatment described in subsection (18).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="33">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service provider” or “provider” means a public agency, a private for-profit or not-for-profit agency, a person who is a private practitioner, or a hospital licensed under this chapter or exempt from licensure under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="34">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service provider personnel” or “personnel” includes all owners, directors, chief financial officers, staff, and volunteers, including foster parents, of a service provider.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="35">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stabilization” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alleviation of a crisis condition; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevention of further deterioration,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and connotes short-term emergency treatment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="36">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substance abuse” means the misuse or abuse of, or dependence on alcohol, illicit drugs, or prescription medications. As an individual progresses along this continuum of misuse, abuse, and dependence, there is an increased need for substance abuse intervention and treatment to help abate the problem.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="37">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substate entity” means a departmental office designated to serve a geographical area specified by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="38">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“System of care” means a coordinated continuum of community-based services and supports that are organized to meet the challenges and needs of individuals who are at risk of developing substance abuse problems or individuals who have substance abuse problems.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="39">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Treatment plan” means an immediate and a long-range plan based upon an individual’s assessed needs and used to address and monitor an individual’s recovery from substance abuse.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 93-39; s. 55, ch. 95-228; s. 1, ch. 98-107; s. 1, ch. 98-262; s. 107, ch. 99-8; s. 52, ch. 2000-139; s. 1, ch. 2002-196; s. 78, ch. 2004-11; s. 2, ch. 2005-55; s. 8, ch. 2009-132; s. 80, ch. 2010-5.</History>
</Section>