<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.6971" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Early release from involuntary substance abuse treatment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time prior to the end of the 60-day involuntary treatment period, or prior to the end of any extension granted pursuant to s. 397.6975, an individual admitted for involuntary treatment may be determined eligible for discharge to the most appropriate referral or disposition for the individual when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual no longer meets the criteria for involuntary admission and has given his or her informed consent to be transferred to voluntary treatment status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the individual was admitted on the grounds of likelihood of infliction of physical harm upon himself or herself or others, such likelihood no longer exists; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the individual was admitted on the grounds of need for assessment and stabilization or treatment, accompanied by inability to make a determination respecting such need, either:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such inability no longer exists; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is evident that further treatment will not bring about further significant improvements in the individual’s condition;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual is no longer in need of services; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the service provider determines that the individual is beyond the safe management capabilities of the provider.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a qualified professional determines that an individual admitted for involuntary treatment is ready for early release for any of the reasons listed in subsection (1), the service provider shall immediately discharge the individual, and must notify all persons specified by the court in the original treatment order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 93-39; s. 755, ch. 95-148; s. 38, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>