<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.998" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Drug-free communities support match grants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The purposes of drug-free communities match grants are to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist community coalitions in an effort to secure federal drug-free communities support program grants under Pub. L. No. 105-20.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce substance abuse among youth and, over time, to reduce substance abuse among adults.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enable community coalitions to strengthen collaboration efforts among public and private agencies to reduce substance abuse among youth.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION PROCESS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, the department shall establish a program to provide drug-free communities match grants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grants shall be used for all or part of the match required for community coalitions to secure a federal drug-free communities support program grant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBLE APPLICANTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community coalitions whose members have worked together on substance abuse reduction initiatives for a period of not less than 6 months are eligible to apply for match grant funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coalition must represent the targeted community and include at least one representative of each of the following groups: local Department of Children and Family Services official; youth; parents; business community; media; schools; organizations serving youth; law enforcement agencies; religious or fraternal organizations; civic and volunteer groups; health care professionals; other local or tribal governmental agencies with an expertise in the field of substance abuse, including, if applicable, the state authority with primary authority for substance abuse; and other organizations involved in reducing substance abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To demonstrate that the coalition meets the stated criteria, the applicant must submit examples or formal agreements, such as memorandums of understanding, previous newsletters or publications, or other examples of print media coverage that are dated within 6 months prior to submittal of the application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RELEASE OF FUNDS.<EmDash />Match grant funds shall be released as required by federal regulations to community coalitions upon documentation that a community coalition has been awarded a drug-free communities support program grant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN-KIND MATCH.<EmDash />The department may provide other in-kind services or goods allowed by federal regulations in lieu of money, to achieve the purpose of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The department is authorized to adopt rules specifically to address procedures necessary to administer the drug-free communities match grants as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 99-396.</History></Section>