<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.6798" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alternative involuntary assessment procedure for minors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to protective custody, emergency admission, and involuntary assessment and stabilization, an addictions receiving facility may admit a minor for involuntary assessment and stabilization upon the filing of an application to an addictions receiving facility by the minor’s parent, guardian, or legal custodian. The application must establish the need for involuntary assessment and stabilization based on the criteria for involuntary admission in s. 397.675. Within 72 hours after involuntary admission of a minor, the minor must be assessed to determine the need for further services. Assessments must be performed by a qualified professional. If, after the 72-hour period, it is determined by the attending physician that further services are necessary, the minor may be kept for a period of up to 5 days, inclusive of the 72-hour period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for alternative involuntary assessment for a minor must establish the need for immediate involuntary admission and contain the name of the minor to be admitted, the name and signature of the applicant, the relationship between the minor to be admitted and the applicant, and factual allegations with respect to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason for the applicant’s belief that the minor is substance abuse impaired; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason for the applicant’s belief that because of such impairment the minor has lost the power of self-control with respect to substance abuse; and either</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason the applicant believes that the minor has inflicted or is likely to inflict physical harm on himself or herself or others unless admitted; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason the applicant believes that the minor’s refusal to voluntarily receive substance abuse services is based on judgment so impaired by reason of substance abuse that he or she is incapable of appreciating his or her need for such services and of making a rational decision regarding his or her need for services.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 93-39; s. 744, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>