<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.93" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Children’s substance abuse services; target populations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The target populations for children’s substance abuse services are children at risk for substance abuse and children with substance abuse problems.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children at risk for substance abuse include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children who are at risk due to regular or periodic exposure to negative factors related to family, community, school, self, or peers. Children in this category are typically placed in special prevention programs which are often school-based and which emphasize the importance of protective factors to reduce risk.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children who are at risk due to experimental and social use of substances. Children in this category are typically placed in early intervention programs which may occur in the community or school.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children with substance abuse problems include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children who use substances on a daily, weekly, or monthly basis. Children in this category typically need outpatient counseling and in some cases more structured day or night treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children with a substance dependency or addiction. Children in this category typically need structured day or night treatment or more intensive and longer term residential treatment, with some severe cases initially in need of detoxification and stabilization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 99-396.</History></Section>