<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.407" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure process; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule the licensure process to include fees and categories of licenses. The rule must prescribe a fee range that is based, at least in part, on the number and complexity of programs listed in s. 397.311(18) which are operated by a licensee. The fees from the licensure of service components are sufficient to cover at least 50 percent of the costs of regulating the service components. The department shall specify by rule a fee range for public and privately funded licensed service providers. Fees for privately funded licensed service providers must exceed the fees for publicly funded licensed service providers. During adoption of the rule governing the licensure process and fees, the department shall carefully consider the potential adverse impact on small, not-for-profit service providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall assess a fee of $100 per licensed service component for the late filing of an application for renewal of a license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure and renewal fees must be deposited in the Operations and Maintenance Trust Fund to be used for the actual cost of monitoring, inspecting, and overseeing licensed service providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for licensure or renewal must be accompanied by the required fee, except that a service provider that has an all-volunteer staff is exempt from the licensure and renewal fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue probationary, regular, and interim licenses. After adopting the rule governing the licensure process and fees, the department shall issue one license for each service component that is operated by a service provider and defined in rule pursuant to s. 397.311(18). The license is valid only for the specific service components listed for each specific location identified on the license. The licensed service provider shall apply for a new license at least 60 days before the addition of any service components or 30 days before the relocation of any of its service sites. Provision of service components or delivery of services at a location not identified on the license may be considered an unlicensed operation that authorizes the department to seek an injunction against operation as provided in s. 397.401, in addition to other sanctions authorized by s. 397.415. Probationary and regular licenses may be issued only after all required information has been submitted. A license may not be transferred. As used in this subsection, the term “transfer” includes, but is not limited to, the transfer of a majority of the ownership interest in the licensed entity or transfer of responsibilities under the license to another entity by contractual arrangement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A probationary license may be issued to a service provider applicant in the initial stages of developing services that are not yet fully operational upon completion of all application requirements itemized in s. 397.403(1) and upon demonstration of the applicant’s ability to comply with all applicable statutory and regulatory requirements. A probationary license expires 90 days after issuance and may be reissued once for an additional 90-day period if the applicant has substantially complied with all requirements for regular licensure or has initiated action to satisfy all requirements. During the probationary period the department shall monitor the delivery of services. Notwithstanding s. 120.60(5), the department may order a probationary licensee to cease and desist operations at any time it is found to be substantially out of compliance with licensure standards. This cease-and-desist order is exempt from the requirements of s. 120.60(6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A regular license may be issued to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A new applicant at the end of the probationary period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed applicant that holds a regular license and is seeking renewal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a service component operating under an interim license upon successful satisfaction of the requirements for a regular license.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In order to be issued a regular license, the applicant must be in compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements. Standards and timeframes for the issuance of a regular license must be established by rule. An application for renewal of a regular license must be submitted to the department at least 60 days before the license expires.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue an interim license to a service provider for a period established by the department which does not exceed 90 days if the department finds that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A service component of the provider is in substantial noncompliance with licensure standards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service provider has failed to provide satisfactory proof of conformance to fire, safety, or health requirements; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service provider is involved in license suspension or revocation proceedings.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">An interim license applies only to the licensable service component of the provider’s services which is in substantial noncompliance with statutory or regulatory requirements. An interim license expires 90 days after it is issued; however, it may be reissued once for an additional 90-day period in a case of extreme hardship in which the noncompliance is not attributable to the licensed service provider. If the service provider is appealing the final disposition of license suspension or revocation proceedings, the court before which the appeal is taken may order the extension of the interim license for a period specified in the order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate license is required for each service component maintained by the service provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license must be displayed in a conspicuous place inside the facility providing the licensed service component.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-39; s. 22, ch. 96-418; s. 57, ch. 2000-158; s. 10, ch. 2000-338; s. 4, ch. 2002-196; s. 5, ch. 2005-55; s. 15, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>