<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.6793" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Physician’s certificate for emergency admission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician’s certificate must include the name of the person to be admitted, the relationship between the person and the physician, the relationship between the applicant and the physician, any relationship between the physician and the licensed service provider, and a statement that the person has been examined and assessed within 5 days of the application date, and must include factual allegations with respect to the need for emergency admission, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason for the physician’s belief that the person is substance abuse impaired; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason for the physician’s belief that because of such impairment the person has lost the power of self-control with respect to substance abuse; and either</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason the physician believes that the person has inflicted or is likely to inflict physical harm on himself or herself or others unless admitted; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason the physician believes that the person’s refusal to voluntarily receive care is based on judgment so impaired by reason of substance abuse that the person is incapable of appreciating his or her need for care and of making a rational decision regarding his or her need for care.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician’s certificate must recommend the least restrictive type of service that is appropriate for the person. The certificate must be signed by the physician.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A signed copy of the physician’s certificate shall accompany the person, and shall be made a part of the person’s clinical record, together with a signed copy of the application. The application and physician’s certificate authorize the involuntary admission of the person pursuant to, and subject to the provisions of ss. 397.679-397.6797.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician’s certificate must indicate whether the person requires transportation assistance for delivery for emergency admission and specify, pursuant to s. 397.6795, the type of transportation assistance necessary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 93-39; s. 743, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>