<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.697" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court determination; effect of court order for involuntary substance abuse treatment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the court finds that the conditions for involuntary substance abuse treatment have been proved by clear and convincing evidence, it may order the respondent to undergo involuntary treatment by a licensed service provider for a period not to exceed 60 days. If the court finds it necessary, it may direct the sheriff to take the respondent into custody and deliver him or her to the licensed service provider specified in the court order, or to the nearest appropriate licensed service provider, for involuntary treatment. When the conditions justifying involuntary treatment no longer exist, the individual must be released as provided in s. 397.6971. When the conditions justifying involuntary treatment are expected to exist after 60 days of treatment, a renewal of the involuntary treatment order may be requested pursuant to s. 397.6975 prior to the end of the 60-day period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all cases resulting in an order for involuntary substance abuse treatment, the court shall retain jurisdiction over the case and the parties for the entry of such further orders as the circumstances may require. The court’s requirements for notification of proposed release must be included in the original treatment order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An involuntary treatment order authorizes the licensed service provider to require the individual to undergo such treatment as will benefit him or her, including treatment at any licensable service component of a licensed service provider.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 93-39; s. 754, ch. 95-148; s. 37, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>