<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.96" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Case management for complex substance abuse cases.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon specific appropriations, it is the intent of the Legislature to provide for a more intensive level of case management for complex cases involving children who need substance abuse services. Such services shall be directed toward children receiving services from several agencies or programs to address the complex problems created by substance abuse, dependency, or addiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall determine when a child receiving children’s substance abuse services under this part shall have a case manager.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “case management” means those activities aimed at:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implementing a treatment plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocacy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Linking services providers to a child and family;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitoring services delivery; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collecting information to determine the effect of services and treatment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case manager shall periodically review services utilization to ascertain compliance with plans approved by the planning team.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule standards to coordinate case management activities from various referral points, in order to minimize fragmentation and duplication and promote stability of case managers assigned to a child and family. In the attempt to minimize duplication, it is the intent of the Legislature that a child have no more than one case manager.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 99-396.</History></Section>