<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.92" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Children’s substance abuse services system; goals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the children’s substance abuse services system achieve the following performance outcomes for children who are eligible for services:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of the presenting problems and conditions of substance abuse through the use of valid assessment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improvement in the child’s ability to function in the family with minimum supports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improvement in the child’s ability to function in school with minimum supports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improvement in the child’s ability to function in the community with minimum supports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improvement in the child’s ability to live drug-free.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduction of behaviors and conditions that may be linked to substance abuse, such as unintended pregnancy, delinquency, sexually transmitted diseases, and smoking, and other negative behaviors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increased return of children in state custody, drug-free, to their homes, or the placement of such children, drug-free, in an appropriate setting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to <Reference Number="1" />s. 216.0166, the department shall annually develop performance outcomes and performance measures to assess the performance of the children’s substance abuse services system in achieving the intent of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 99-396.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 61, ch. 2000-371.</Text></Note></Section>