<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.431" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Individual responsibility for cost of substance abuse impairment services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before accepting an individual for admission and in accordance with confidentiality guidelines, both the full charge for services and the fee charged to the individual for such services under the provider’s fee system or payment policy must be disclosed to each individual or his or her authorized personal representative, or parent or legal guardian if the individual is a minor who did not seek treatment voluntarily and without parental consent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual or his or her authorized personal representative, or parent or legal guardian if the individual is a minor, is required to contribute toward the cost of substance abuse services in accordance with his or her ability to pay, unless otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent, legal guardian, or legal custodian of a minor is not liable for payment for any substance abuse services provided to the minor without parental consent pursuant to s. 397.601(4), unless the parent, legal guardian, or legal custodian participates or is ordered to participate in the services, and only for the substance abuse services rendered. If the minor is receiving services as a juvenile offender, the obligation to pay is governed by the law relating to juvenile offenders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service providers that do not contract for state funds to provide substance abuse services as defined in this chapter may establish their own admission policies regarding provisions for payment for services. Such policies must comply with other statutory and regulatory requirements governing state or federal reimbursements to a provider for services delivered to individuals. As used in this subsection, the term “contract for state funds” does not include Medicaid funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service providers that contract for state funds to provide substance abuse services as defined in this chapter must establish a fee system based upon an individual’s ability to pay and, if space and sufficient state resources are available, may not deny an individual access to services solely on the basis of the individual’s inability to pay.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-39; s. 735, ch. 95-148; s. 22, ch. 2009-132.</History></Section>