<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.6818" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court determination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the hearing initiated in accordance with s. 397.6811(1), the court shall hear all relevant testimony. The respondent must be present unless the court has reason to believe that his or her presence is likely to be injurious to him or her, in which event the court shall appoint a guardian advocate to represent the respondent. The respondent has the right to examination by a court-appointed qualified professional. After hearing all the evidence, the court shall determine whether there is a reasonable basis to believe the respondent meets the involuntary admission criteria of s. 397.675.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on its determination, the court shall either dismiss the petition or immediately enter an order authorizing the involuntary assessment and stabilization of the respondent; or, if in the course of the hearing the court has reason to believe that the respondent, due to mental illness other than or in addition to substance abuse impairment, is likely to injure himself or herself or another if allowed to remain at liberty, the court may initiate involuntary proceedings under the provisions of part I of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court enters an order authorizing involuntary assessment and stabilization, the order shall include the court’s findings with respect to the availability and appropriateness of the least restrictive alternatives and the need for the appointment of an attorney to represent the respondent, and may designate the specific licensed service provider to perform the involuntary assessment and stabilization of the respondent. The respondent may choose the licensed service provider to deliver the involuntary assessment where possible and appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds it necessary, it may order the sheriff to take the respondent into custody and deliver him or her to the licensed service provider specified in the court order or, if none is specified, to the nearest appropriate licensed service provider for involuntary assessment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 93-39; s. 749, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>