<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0397.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Referral of substance abuse impaired offenders to service providers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORITY TO REFER.<EmDash />If any offender, including but not limited to any minor, is charged with or convicted of a crime, the court or criminal justice authority with jurisdiction over that offender may require the offender to receive services from a service provider licensed under this chapter. If referred by the court, the referral shall be in addition to final adjudication, imposition of penalty or sentence, or other action. The court may consult with or seek the assistance of a service provider concerning such a referral. Assignment to a service provider is contingent upon availability of space, budgetary considerations, and manageability of the offender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REFERRAL AND TREATMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order referring an offender under subsection (1) must be in writing and must be signed by the referral source. The order must specify the name of the offender, the name and address of the service provider to which the offender is referred, the date of the referral, the duration of the offender’s sentence, and all conditions stipulated by the referral source. The total amount of time the offender is required to receive treatment may not exceed the maximum length of sentence possible for the offense with which the offender is charged or convicted. A copy of the order must be delivered to the service provider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director may refuse to admit any offender referred to the service provider under subsection (1). The director’s refusal to admit the offender must be communicated immediately and in writing within 72 hours to the referral source, stating the basis for such refusal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director may, after consulting with the referral source, discharge any offender referred to the service provider under subsection (1) when, in the judgment of the director, the offender is beyond the safe management capabilities of the service provider. The director must orally communicate a decision to discharge an offender to the offender and to the referral source, immediately, and must communicate the decision in writing within 72 hours thereafter, stating the basis for the determination that the offender is beyond the safe management capabilities of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an offender successfully completes treatment or when the time period during which the offender is required to receive treatment expires, the director shall communicate such fact to the referral source.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 93-39; s. 38, ch. 97-194.</History></Section>