<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0327.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Boating Advisory Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Boating Advisory Council is created within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and shall be composed of 18 members. The members include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, who shall serve as the chair of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative each from the Department of Environmental Protection, the United States Coast Guard Auxiliary, the United States Power Squadron, and the inland navigation districts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of manatee protection interests, one representative of the marine industries, one representative of water-related environmental groups, one representative of canoe or kayak enthusiasts, one representative of marine manufacturers, one representative of commercial vessel owners or operators, one representative of marine special events, one representative actively involved and working full-time in the scuba diving industry who has experience in recreational boating, one representative of either the commercial fishing industry or the commercial shellfishing industry, and two representatives of the boating public, each of whom shall be nominated by the executive director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and appointed by the Governor to serve staggered 3-year terms. Members appointed by the Governor may serve no more than two full consecutive terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member of the House of Representatives, who shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member of the Senate, who shall be appointed by the President of the Senate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall meet at the call of the chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, or at such times as may be prescribed by rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the council is to make recommendations to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and the Department of Economic Opportunity regarding issues affecting the boating community, including, but not limited to, issues related to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boating and diving safety education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boating-related facilities, including marinas and boat testing facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boat usage.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boat access.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Working waterfronts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation but are entitled to reimbursement of expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy on the council shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. Members whose terms have expired may continue to serve until replaced or reappointed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council may be removed for cause.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 94-241; s. 34, ch. 99-245; s. 25, ch. 2000-362; s. 1, ch. 2005-158; s. 229, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>