<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0327.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Noncriminal infractions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violations of the following provisions of the vessel laws of this state are noncriminal infractions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.46, relating to operation of unregistered and unnumbered vessels.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.48(4), relating to display of number and possession of registration certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.48(5), relating to display of decal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.52(2), relating to display of number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.54, relating to spacing of digits and letters of identification number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.60, relating to military personnel and registration of vessels.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 328.72(13), relating to operation with an expired registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.33(2), relating to careless operation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.37, relating to water skiing, aquaplaning, parasailing, and similar activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.44, relating to interference with navigation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violations relating to boating-restricted areas and speed limits:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Established by the commission or by local governmental authorities pursuant to s. 327.46.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Speed limits established pursuant to s. 379.2431(2).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.48, relating to regattas and races.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.50(1) and (2), relating to required safety equipment, lights, and shapes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.65, relating to muffling devices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.33(3)(b), relating to a violation of navigation rules:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That does not result in an accident; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That results in an accident not causing serious bodily injury or death, for which the penalty is:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first offense, up to a maximum of $250.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second offense, up to a maximum of $750.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a third or subsequent offense, up to a maximum of $1,000.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.39(1), (2), (3), and (5), relating to personal watercraft.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.53(1), (2), and (3), relating to marine sanitation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.53(4), (5), and (7), relating to marine sanitation, for which the civil penalty is $250.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.395, relating to boater safety education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.52(3), relating to operation of overloaded or overpowered vessels.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.331, relating to divers-down flags, except for violations meeting the requirements of s. 327.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.391(1), relating to the requirement for an adequate muffler on an airboat.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 327.391(3), relating to the display of a flag on an airboat.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 253.04(3)(a), relating to carelessly causing seagrass scarring, for which the civil penalty upon conviction is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first offense, $50.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second offense occurring within 12 months after a prior conviction, $250.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a third offense occurring within 36 months after a prior conviction, $500.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a fourth or subsequent offense occurring within 72 months after a prior conviction, $1,000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person cited for a violation of any provision of this subsection shall be deemed to be charged with a noncriminal infraction, shall be cited for such an infraction, and shall be cited to appear before the county court. The civil penalty for any such infraction is $50, except as otherwise provided in this section. Any person who fails to appear or otherwise properly respond to a uniform boating citation shall, in addition to the charge relating to the violation of the boating laws of this state, be charged with the offense of failing to respond to such citation and, upon conviction, be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A written warning to this effect shall be provided at the time such uniform boating citation is issued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person cited for an infraction under this section may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Post a bond, which shall be equal in amount to the applicable civil penalty; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sign and accept a citation indicating a promise to appear.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The officer may indicate on the citation the time and location of the scheduled hearing and shall indicate the applicable civil penalty.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully refuses to post a bond or accept and sign a summons is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person charged with a noncriminal infraction under this section may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the civil penalty, either by mail or in person, within 30 days of the date of receiving the citation; or,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If he or she has posted bond, forfeit bond by not appearing at the designated time and location.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the person cited follows either of the above procedures, he or she shall be deemed to have admitted the noncriminal infraction and to have waived the right to a hearing on the issue of commission of the infraction. Such admission shall not be used as evidence in any other proceedings. If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 327.395 can show a boating safety identification card issued to that person and valid at the time of the citation, the clerk of the court may dismiss the case and may assess a dismissal fee of up to $10. If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 328.72(13) can show proof of having a registration for that vessel which was valid at the time of the citation, the clerk may dismiss the case and may assess the dismissal fee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person electing to appear before the county court or who is required so to appear shall be deemed to have waived the limitations on the civil penalty specified in subsection (1). The court, after a hearing, shall make a determination as to whether an infraction has been committed. If the commission of an infraction has been proven, the court may impose a civil penalty not to exceed $500 or a higher amount as specified in subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a hearing under this chapter the commission of a charged infraction must be proved beyond a reasonable doubt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person is found by the hearing official to have committed an infraction, he or she may appeal that finding to the circuit court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees and civil penalties assessed and collected pursuant to this section shall be remitted by the clerk of the court to the Department of Revenue to be deposited into the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund for boating safety education purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with the court’s requirements or who fails to pay the civil penalties specified in this section within the 30-day period provided for in s. 327.72 must pay an additional court cost of up to $20, which shall be used by the clerks of the courts to defray the costs of tracking unpaid uniform boating citations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with the court’s requirements as to civil penalties specified in this section due to demonstrated financial hardship shall be authorized to satisfy such civil penalties by public works or community service. Each hour of such service shall be applied, at the rate of the minimum wage, toward payment of the person’s civil penalties; provided, however, that if the person has a trade or profession for which there is a community service need and application, the rate for each hour of such service shall be the average standard wage for such trade or profession. Any person who fails to comply with the court’s requirements as to such civil penalties who does not demonstrate financial hardship may also, at the discretion of the court, be authorized to satisfy such civil penalties by public works or community service in the same manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the noncriminal infraction has caused or resulted in the death of another, the court may require the person who committed the infraction to perform 120 community service hours in addition to any other penalties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person cited for any noncriminal infraction which results in an accident that causes the death of another, or which results in an accident that causes “serious bodily injury” of another as defined in s. 327.353(1), shall not have the provisions of subsection (4) available to him or her but must appear before the designated official at the time and location of the scheduled hearing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Court costs that are to be in addition to the stated civil penalty shall be imposed by the court in an amount not less than the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For swimming or diving infractions, $4.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For nonmoving boating infractions, $18.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For boating infractions listed in s. 327.731(1), $35.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the court cost assessed under paragraph (a), the court shall impose a $3 court cost for each noncriminal infraction, to be distributed as provided in s. 938.01, and a $2 court cost as provided in s. 938.15 when assessed by a municipality or county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Court costs imposed under this subsection may not exceed $45. A criminal justice selection center or both local criminal justice access and assessment centers may be funded from these court costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-35; s. 7, ch. 87-392; s. 6, ch. 88-133; s. 4, ch. 88-144; s. 5, ch. 89-136; s. 32, ch. 91-221; s. 2, ch. 93-83; s. 2, ch. 93-254; s. 7, ch. 94-241; s. 955, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 96-187; s. 60, ch. 96-413; s. 3, ch. 97-16; s. 2, ch. 99-162; s. 31, ch. 99-289; s. 48, ch. 2000-152; ss. 22, 23, ch. 2000-362; s. 13, ch. 2001-122; s. 3, ch. 2002-46; s. 13, ch. 2003-143; s. 103, ch. 2003-402; s. 6, ch. 2004-74; s. 65, ch. 2004-265; s. 4, ch. 2006-172; s. 36, ch. 2008-111; s. 196, ch. 2008-247; s. 18, ch. 2009-86; s. 63, ch. 2010-5; s. 20, ch. 2011-4; s. 4, ch. 2011-152.</History>
</Section>