<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0327.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform boating citations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall prepare, and supply to every law enforcement agency in this state which enforces the laws of this state regulating the operation of vessels, an appropriate form boating citation containing a notice to appear (which shall be issued in prenumbered books with citations in quintuplicate) and meeting the requirements of this chapter or any laws of this state regulating boating, which form shall be consistent with the state’s county court rules and the procedures established by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courts, enforcement agencies, and the commission are jointly responsible to account for all uniform boating citations in accordance with the procedures promulgated by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every law enforcement officer, upon issuing a boating citation to an alleged violator of any provision of the boating laws of this state or any boating ordinance of any municipality, shall deposit the original and one copy of such boating citation with a court having jurisdiction over the alleged offense or with its traffic violations bureau within 5 days after issuance to the violator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief administrative officer of every law enforcement agency shall require the return to him or her of the commission record copy of every boating citation issued by an officer under his or her supervision to an alleged violator of any boating law or ordinance and all copies of every boating citation which has been spoiled or upon which any entry has been made and not issued to an alleged violator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the deposit of the original and one copy of such boating citation with a court having jurisdiction over the alleged offense or with its traffic violations bureau as aforesaid, the original or copy of such boating citation may be disposed of only by trial in the court or other official action by a judge of the court, including forfeiture of the bail, or by the deposit of sufficient bail with, or payment of a fine to, the traffic violations bureau by the person to whom such boating citation has been issued by the law enforcement officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief administrative officer shall transmit, on a form approved by the commission, the commission record copy of the uniform boating citation to the commission within 5 days after submission of the original and one copy to the court. A copy of such transmittal shall also be provided to the court having jurisdiction for accountability purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful and official misconduct for any law enforcement officer or other officer or public employee to dispose of a boating citation or copies thereof or of the record of the issuance of the same in a manner other than as required in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such citations shall not be admissible evidence in any trial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a uniform boating citation has not been issued with respect to a criminal boating offense, and the prosecution is by affidavit, information, or indictment, the prosecutor shall direct the arresting officer to prepare a citation. In the absence of an arresting officer, the prosecutor shall prepare the citation. For the purpose of this subsection, the term “arresting officer” means the law enforcement officer who apprehended or took into custody the alleged offender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon final disposition of any alleged offense for which a uniform boating citation has been issued, the court shall, within 10 days, certify said disposition to the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-392; s. 6, ch. 89-136; s. 466, ch. 95-148; s. 33, ch. 99-245.</History></Section>