<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0327.35215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalty for failure to submit to test.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is lawfully arrested for an alleged violation of s. 327.35 and who refuses to submit to a blood test, breath test, or urine test pursuant to s. 327.352 is subject to a civil penalty of $500.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person refuses to submit to a blood test, breath test, or urine test pursuant to s. 327.352, a law enforcement officer who is authorized to make arrests for violations of this chapter shall file with the clerk of the court, on a form provided by the department, a certified statement that probable cause existed to arrest the person for a violation of s. 327.35 and that the person refused to submit to a test as required by s. 327.352. Along with the statement, the officer must also submit a sworn statement on a form provided by the department that the person has been advised of both the penalties for failure to submit to the blood, breath, or urine test and the procedure for requesting a hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been advised of the penalties pursuant to subsection (2) may, within 30 days afterwards, request a hearing before a county court judge. A request for a hearing tolls the period for payment of the civil penalty, and, if assessment of the civil penalty is sustained by the hearing and any subsequent judicial review, the civil penalty must be paid within 30 days after final disposition. The clerk of the court shall notify the department of the final disposition of all actions filed under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person who has not paid a civil penalty imposed pursuant to this section, or who has not requested a hearing with respect to the civil penalty, within 30 calendar days after receipt of notice of the civil penalty to operate a vessel upon the waters of this state. Violation of this subsection is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys collected by the clerk of the court pursuant to this section shall be disposed of in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the arresting officer was employed or appointed by a state law enforcement agency, the moneys shall be deposited into the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund and used to directly enhance the ability of law enforcement officers to perform law enforcement functions on state waters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the arresting officer was employed or appointed by a county or municipal law enforcement agency, the moneys shall be deposited into the law enforcement trust fund of that agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 98-308; s. 23, ch. 99-245; s. 3, ch. 2004-74.</History></Section>