<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0327.395" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Boating safety identification cards.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person born on or after January 1, 1988, may not operate a vessel powered by a motor of 10 horsepower or greater unless such person has in his or her possession aboard the vessel photographic identification and a boater safety identification card issued by the commission which shows that he or she has:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed a commission-approved boater education course that meets the minimum 8-hour instruction requirement established by the National Association of State Boating Law Administrators;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passed a course equivalency examination approved by the commission; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passed a temporary certificate examination developed or approved by the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may obtain a boater safety identification card by complying with the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commission-approved boater education or boater safety course, course-equivalency examination developed or approved by the commission, or temporary certificate examination developed or approved by the commission must include a component regarding diving vessels, awareness of divers in the water, divers-down flags, and the requirements of s. 327.331.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may appoint liveries, marinas, or other persons as its agents to administer the course, course equivalency examination, or temporary certificate examination and issue identification cards under guidelines established by the commission. An agent must charge the $2 examination fee, which must be forwarded to the commission with proof of passage of the examination and may charge and keep a $1 service fee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification card issued to a person who has completed a boating education course or a course equivalency examination is valid for life. A card issued to a person who has passed a temporary certification examination is valid for 12 months from the date of issuance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is exempt from subsection (1) if he or she:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is licensed by the United States Coast Guard to serve as master of a vessel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operates a vessel only on a private lake or pond.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is accompanied in the vessel by a person who is exempt from this section or who holds an identification card in compliance with this section, is 18 years of age or older, and is attendant to the operation of the vessel and responsible for the safe operation of the vessel and for any violation that occurs during the operation of the vessel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a nonresident who has in his or her possession proof that he or she has completed a boater education course or equivalency examination in another state which meets or exceeds the requirements of subsection (1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is operating a vessel within 90 days after the purchase of that vessel and has available for inspection aboard that vessel a bill of sale meeting the requirements of s. 328.46(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is operating a vessel within 90 days after completing the requirements of paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b) and has a photographic identification card and a boater education certificate available for inspection as proof of having completed a boater education course. The boater education certificate must provide, at a minimum, the student’s first and last name, the student’s date of birth, and the date that he or she passed the course examination.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is exempted by rule of the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a vessel in violation of subsection (1) commits a noncriminal infraction, punishable as provided in s. 327.73.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall design forms and adopt rules to administer this section. Such rules shall include provision for educational and other public and private entities to offer the course and administer examinations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall institute and coordinate a statewide program of boating safety instruction and certification to ensure that boating courses and examinations are available in each county of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is authorized to establish and to collect a $2 examination fee to cover administrative costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is authorized to adopt rules pursuant to chapter 120 to implement the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Osmany ‘Ozzie’ Castellanos Boating Safety Education Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 96-187; s. 24, ch. 99-245; s. 13, ch. 2000-362; s. 35, ch. 2005-2; s. 9, ch. 2009-86; s. 2, ch. 2011-152.</History>
</Section>