<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0327.65" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Muffling devices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exhaust of every internal combustion engine used on any vessel operated on the waters of this state shall be effectively muffled by equipment so constructed and used as to muffle the noise of the exhaust in a reasonable manner. The use of cutouts is prohibited, except for vessels competing in a regatta or official boat race, and for such vessels while on trial runs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county wishing to impose additional noise pollution and exhaust regulations on vessels may, pursuant to s. 327.60(2), adopt by county ordinance the following regulations:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall operate or give permission for the operation of any vessel on the waters of any county or on a specified portion of the waters of any county, including the Florida Intracoastal Waterway, which has adopted the provisions of this section in such a manner as to exceed the following sound levels at a distance of 50 feet from the vessel: for all vessels, a maximum sound level of 90 dB A.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who refuses to submit to a sound level test when requested to do so by a law enforcement officer is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following words and phrases, when used in this section, shall have the meanings respectively assigned to them in this subsection.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“dB A” means the composite abbreviation for the A-weighted sound level and the unit of sound level, the decibel.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sound level” means the A-weighted sound pressure level measured with fast response using an instrument complying with the specification for sound level meters of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., or its successor bodies, except that only a weighting and fast dynamic response need be provided.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 59-400; s. 11, ch. 63-105; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 5, ch. 86-35; s. 47, ch. 91-224; s. 15, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.56.</Text></Note></Section>