<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0327.33" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reckless or careless operation of vessel.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to operate a vessel in a reckless manner. A person is guilty of reckless operation of a vessel who operates any vessel, or manipulates any water skis, aquaplane, or similar device, in willful or wanton disregard for the safety of persons or property at a speed or in a manner as to endanger, or likely to endanger, life or limb, or damage the property of, or injure any person. Reckless operation of a vessel includes, but is not limited to, a violation of s. 327.331(6). Any person who violates a provision of this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating a vessel upon the waters of this state shall operate the vessel in a reasonable and prudent manner, having regard for other waterborne traffic, posted speed and wake restrictions, and all other attendant circumstances so as not to endanger the life, limb, or property of any person. The failure to operate a vessel in a manner described in this subsection constitutes careless operation. However, vessel wake and shoreline wash resulting from the reasonable and prudent operation of a vessel shall, absent negligence, not constitute damage or endangerment to property. Any person who violates the provisions of this subsection commits a noncriminal violation as defined in s. 775.08.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person operating a vessel upon the waters of this state shall comply with the navigation rules.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates the navigation rules and the violation results in a boating accident causing serious bodily injury as defined in s. 327.353 or death, but the violation does not constitute reckless operation of a vessel, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates the navigation rules and the violation does not constitute reckless operation of a vessel commits a noncriminal violation as defined in s. 775.08, punishable as provided in s. 327.73.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Law enforcement vessels may deviate from the navigational rules when such diversion is necessary to the performance of their duties and when such deviation may be safely accomplished.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in this chapter, the ascertainment of fault in vessel operations and boating accidents shall be determined according to the navigation rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-400; s. 3, ch. 63-105; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 6, ch. 81-100; s. 6, ch. 84-188; s. 6, ch. 86-35; s. 2, ch. 88-133; s. 2, ch. 89-136; s. 45, ch. 91-224; s. 1, ch. 92-92; s. 6, ch. 2000-362; s. 1, ch. 2011-152.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.50.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>