<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0327.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions of terms used in this chapter and in chapter 328.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter and in chapter 328, unless the context clearly requires a different meaning, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Airboat” means a vessel that is primarily designed for use in shallow waters and powered by an internal combustion engine with an airplane-type propeller mounted above the stern and used to push air across a set of rudders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alien” means a person who is not a citizen of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Boating accident” means a collision, accident, or casualty involving a vessel in or upon, or entering into or exiting from, the water, including capsizing, collision with another vessel or object, sinking, personal injury, death, disappearance of any person from on board under circumstances which indicate the possibility of death or injury, or property damage to any vessel or dock.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Canoe” means a light, narrow vessel with curved sides and with both ends pointed. A canoe-like vessel with a transom may not be excluded from the definition of a canoe if the width of its transom is less than 45 percent of the width of its beam or it has been designated as a canoe by the United States Coast Guard.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial vessel” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vessel primarily engaged in the taking or landing of saltwater fish or saltwater products or freshwater fish or freshwater products, or any vessel licensed pursuant to s. 379.361 from which commercial quantities of saltwater products are harvested, from within and without the waters of this state for sale either to the consumer, retail dealer, or wholesale dealer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other vessel, except a recreational vessel as defined in this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means any person authorized by the Department of Revenue to buy, sell, resell, or otherwise distribute vessels. Such person shall have a valid sales tax certificate of registration issued by the Department of Revenue and a valid commercial or occupational license required by any county, municipality, or political subdivision of the state in which the person operates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Law Enforcement of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Documented vessel” means a vessel for which a valid certificate of documentation is outstanding pursuant to 46 C.F.R. part 67.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Floating structure” means a floating entity, with or without accommodations built thereon, which is not primarily used as a means of transportation on water but which serves purposes or provides services typically associated with a structure or other improvement to real property. The term “floating structure” includes, but is not limited to, each entity used as a residence, place of business or office with public access, hotel or motel, restaurant or lounge, clubhouse, meeting facility, storage or parking facility, mining platform, dredge, dragline, or similar facility or entity represented as such. Floating structures are expressly excluded from the definition of the term “vessel” provided in this section. Incidental movement upon water or resting partially or entirely on the bottom shall not, in and of itself, preclude an entity from classification as a floating structure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida Intracoastal Waterway” means the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway, the Georgia state line north of Fernandina to Miami; the Port Canaveral lock and canal to the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway; the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway, Miami to Key West; the Okeechobee Waterway, Stuart to Fort Myers; the St. Johns River, Jacksonville to Sanford; the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway, Anclote to Fort Myers; the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway, Carrabelle to Tampa Bay; Carrabelle to Anclote open bay section (using Gulf of Mexico); the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway, Carrabelle to the Alabama state line west of Pensacola; and the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers in Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Homemade vessel” means any vessel built after October 31, 1972, for which a federal hull identification number is not required to be assigned by the manufacturer pursuant to federal law, or any vessel constructed or assembled prior to November 1, 1972, by other than a licensed manufacturer for his or her own use or the use of a specific person. A vessel assembled from a manufacturer’s kit or constructed from an unfinished manufactured hull shall be considered to be a homemade vessel if such a vessel is not required to have a hull identification number assigned by the United States Coast Guard. A rebuilt or reconstructed vessel shall in no event be construed to be a homemade vessel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Houseboat” means any vessel which is used primarily as a residence for a minimum of 21 days during any 30-day period, in a county of this state, and this residential use of the vessel is to the preclusion of the use of the vessel as a means of transportation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Length” means the measurement from end to end over the deck parallel to the centerline excluding sheer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lien” means a security interest which is reserved or created by a written agreement recorded with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles pursuant to s. 328.15 which secures payment or performance of an obligation and is generally valid against third parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lienholder” means a person holding a security interest in a vessel, which interest is recorded with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles pursuant to s. 328.15.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Live-aboard vessel” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vessel used solely as a residence and not for navigation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vessel represented as a place of business or a professional or other commercial enterprise; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vessel for which a declaration of domicile has been filed pursuant to s. 222.17.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A commercial fishing boat is expressly excluded from the term “live-aboard vessel.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Livery vessel” means any vessel leased, rented, or chartered to another for consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufactured vessel” means any vessel built after October 31, 1972, for which a federal hull identification number is required pursuant to federal law, or any vessel constructed or assembled prior to November 1, 1972, by a duly licensed manufacturer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marina” means a licensed commercial facility which provides secured public moorings or dry storage for vessels on a leased basis. A commercial establishment authorized by a licensed vessel manufacturer as a dealership shall be considered a marina for nonjudicial sale purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marine sanitation device” means any equipment other than a toilet, for installation on board a vessel, which is designed to receive, retain, treat, or discharge sewage, and any process to treat such sewage. Marine sanitation device Types I, II, and III shall be defined as provided in 33 C.F.R. part 159.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marker” means any channel mark or other aid to navigation, information or regulatory mark, isolated danger mark, safe water mark, special mark, inland waters obstruction mark, or mooring buoy in, on, or over the waters of the state or the shores thereof, and includes, but is not limited to, a sign, beacon, buoy, or light.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motorboat” means any vessel equipped with machinery for propulsion, irrespective of whether the propulsion machinery is in actual operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Muffler” means an automotive-style sound-suppression device or system designed to effectively abate the sound of exhaust gases emitted from an internal combustion engine and prevent excessive sound when installed on such an engine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Navigation rules” means the International Navigational Rules Act of 1977, 33 U.S.C. appendix following s. 1602, as amended, including the annexes thereto, for vessels on waters outside of established navigational lines of demarcation as specified in 33 C.F.R. part 80 or the Inland Navigational Rules Act of 1980, 33 U.S.C. ss. 2001 et seq., as amended, including the annexes thereto, for vessels on all waters not outside of such lines of demarcation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonresident” means a citizen of the United States who has not established residence in this state and has not continuously resided in this state for 1 year and in one county for the 6 months immediately preceding the initiation of a vessel titling or registration action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operate” means to be in charge of or in command of or in actual physical control of a vessel upon the waters of this state, or to exercise control over or to have responsibility for a vessel’s navigation or safety while the vessel is underway upon the waters of this state, or to control or steer a vessel being towed by another vessel upon the waters of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means a person, other than a lienholder, having the property in or title to a vessel. The term includes a person entitled to the use or possession of a vessel subject to an interest in another person, reserved or created by agreement and securing payment of performance of an obligation, but the term excludes a lessee under a lease not intended as security.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, partnership, firm, corporation, association, or other entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal watercraft” means a vessel less than 16 feet in length which uses an inboard motor powering a water jet pump, as its primary source of motive power and which is designed to be operated by a person sitting, standing, or kneeling on the vessel, rather than in the conventional manner of sitting or standing inside the vessel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="31"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Portable toilet” means a device consisting of a lid, seat, containment vessel, and support structure that is specifically designed to receive, retain, and discharge human waste and that is capable of being removed from a vessel by hand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="32"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prohibited activity” means such activity as will impede or disturb navigation or creates a safety hazard on waterways of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="33"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Racing shell,” “rowing scull,” or “racing kayak” means a manually propelled vessel which is recognized by national or international racing associations for use in competitive racing and in which all occupants, with the exception of a coxswain, if one is provided, row, scull, or paddle and which is not designed to carry and does not carry any equipment not solely for competitive racing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="34"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recreational vessel” means any vessel:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufactured and used primarily for noncommercial purposes; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leased, rented, or chartered to a person for the person’s noncommercial use.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="35"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registration” means a state operating license on a vessel which is issued with an identifying number, an annual certificate of registration, and a decal designating the year for which a registration fee is paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="36"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a citizen of the United States who has established residence in this state and has continuously resided in this state for 1 year and in one county for the 6 months immediately preceding the initiation of a vessel titling or registration action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="37"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sailboat” means any vessel whose sole source of propulsion is the wind.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="38"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unclaimed vessel” means any undocumented vessel, including its machinery, rigging, and accessories, which is in the physical possession of any marina, garage, or repair shop for repairs, improvements, or other work with the knowledge of the vessel owner and for which the costs of such services have been unpaid for a period in excess of 90 days from the date written notice of the completed work is given by the marina, garage, or repair shop to the vessel owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="39"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vessel” is synonymous with boat as referenced in s. 1(b), Art. VII of the State Constitution and includes every description of watercraft, barge, and airboat, other than a seaplane on the water, used or capable of being used as a means of transportation on water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="40"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Waters of this state” means any navigable waters of the United States within the territorial limits of this state, and the marginal sea adjacent to this state and the high seas when navigated as a part of a journey or ride to or from the shore of this state, and all the inland lakes, rivers, and canals under the jurisdiction of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-399; s. 1, ch. 63-103; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 17, ch. 69-216; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 70-336; s. 132, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 72-16; s. 1, ch. 72-55; ss. 1, 15, ch. 74-327; s. 23, ch. 79-334; s. 1, ch. 81-100; s. 1, ch. 81-114; s. 76, ch. 82-226; s. 1, ch. 83-20; s. 2, ch. 84-184; s. 1, ch. 85-252; s. 1, ch. 88-133; s. 1, ch. 89-136; s. 2, ch. 89-250; s. 2, ch. 94-241; s. 152, ch. 94-356; s. 951, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 95-333; s. 3, ch. 98-308; ss. 18, 89, ch. 99-245; s. 2, ch. 2000-362; s. 1, ch. 2006-172; s. 194, ch. 2008-247; s. 6, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.021.</Text></Note></Section>