<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0327.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local regulations; limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter and chapter 328 shall govern the operation, equipment, and all other matters relating thereto whenever any vessel shall be operated upon the waters of this state or when any activity regulated hereby shall take place thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter or chapter 328 shall be construed to prevent the adoption of any ordinance or local regulation relating to operation of vessels, except that a county or municipality shall not enact, continue in effect, or enforce any ordinance or local regulation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a vessel or associated equipment performance or other safety standard, imposing a requirement for associated equipment, or regulating the carrying or use of marine safety articles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relating to the design, manufacture, installation, or use of any marine sanitation device on any vessel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulating any vessel upon the Florida Intracoastal Waterway;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discriminating against personal watercraft;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discriminating against airboats, for ordinances adopted after July 1, 2006, unless adopted by a two-thirds vote of the governing body enacting such ordinance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulating the anchoring of vessels other than live-aboard vessels outside the marked boundaries of mooring fields permitted as provided in s. 327.40;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulating engine or exhaust noise, except as provided in s. 327.65; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That conflicts with any provisions of this chapter or any amendments thereto or rules adopted thereunder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit local governmental authorities from the enactment or enforcement of regulations which prohibit or restrict the mooring or anchoring of floating structures or live-aboard vessels within their jurisdictions or of any vessels within the marked boundaries of mooring fields permitted as provided in s. 327.40. However, local governmental authorities are prohibited from regulating the anchoring outside of such mooring fields of vessels other than live-aboard vessels as defined in s. 327.02.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 59-400; s. 16, ch. 63-105; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 3, ch. 72-55; s. 2, ch. 83-20; s. 38, ch. 95-143; s. 30, ch. 99-289; s. 20, ch. 2000-362; s. 3, ch. 2006-172; s. 3, ch. 2006-309; s. 14, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.59.</Text></Note></Section>