<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0874.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil cause of action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or organization establishing, by clear and convincing evidence, coercion, intimidation, threats, or other harm to that person or organization in violation of this chapter has a civil cause of action for treble damages, an injunction, or any other appropriate relief in law or equity. Upon prevailing, the plaintiff may recover attorney’s fees in the trial and appellate courts and the costs of investigation and litigation that are reasonably incurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, the term “state” includes any of the state’s agencies, instrumentalities, subdivisions, or municipalities, and includes, but is not limited to, state attorneys and the Office of Statewide Prosecution of the Department of Legal Affairs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any remedies provided for by ss. 60.05 and 823.05, the state has a civil cause of action against any person or organization if it proves by clear and convincing evidence that it has been injured by reason of a violation of this chapter by the person or organization. The state has a civil cause of action for treble damages, injunctive relief, or any other relief in law or equity which the court deems appropriate. If the state prevails, it may also recover attorney’s fees in the trial and appellate courts and the costs of investigation and litigation that are reasonably incurred. The state may not recover punitive damages. The defendant is entitled to recover reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs if the court finds that the state raised a claim that was without factual or legal support and was vexatious, frivolous, or brought in bad faith.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prevailing plaintiff under subsection (1) has a right or claim that is superior to any right or claim that the state has in the same property or proceeds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly violates a temporary or permanent order issued under this section or s. 60.05 commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-207; s. 39, ch. 96-388; s. 11, ch. 2008-238.</History></Section>