<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0874.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gang-related offenses; enhanced penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a finding by the factfinder that the defendant committed the charged offense for the purpose of benefiting, promoting, or furthering the interests of a criminal gang, the penalty for any felony or misdemeanor, or any delinquent act or violation of law which would be a felony or misdemeanor if committed by an adult, may be enhanced. Penalty enhancement affects the applicable statutory maximum penalty only. Each of the findings required as a basis for such sentence shall be found beyond a reasonable doubt. The enhancement will be as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the second degree may be punished as if it were a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the first degree may be punished as if it were a felony of the third degree. For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, such offense is ranked in level 1 of the offense severity ranking chart. The criminal gang multiplier in s. 921.0024 does not apply to misdemeanors enhanced under this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the third degree may be punished as if it were a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the second degree may be punished as if it were a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the first degree may be punished as if it were a life felony.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944, such felony offense is ranked as provided in s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023, and without regard to the penalty enhancement in this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-207; s. 76, ch. 94-209; s. 23, ch. 95-184; s. 37, ch. 96-388; s. 21, ch. 97-194; s. 1, ch. 2001-126; s. 8, ch. 2008-238.</History></Section>