<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0401.245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created an advisory council for the purpose of acting as the advisory body to the emergency medical services program. The duties of the council include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifying and making recommendations to the department concerning the appropriateness of suggested changes to statutes and administrative rules.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acting as a clearinghouse for information specific to changes in the provision of emergency medical services and trauma care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing technical support to the department in the areas of emergency medical services and trauma systems design, required medical and rescue equipment, required drugs and dosages, medical treatment protocols and emergency medical services personnel education and training requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting in developing the emergency medical services portion of the department’s annual legislative package.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing a forum for discussing significant issues facing the emergency medical services and trauma care communities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing a forum for planning the continued development of the state’s emergency medical services system through the joint production of the emergency medical services state plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting the department in developing the emergency medical services quality management program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting the department in setting program priorities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing feedback to the department on the administration and performance of the emergency medical services program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing technical support to the emergency medical services grants program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting the department in emergency medical services public education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting in the development of the department’s injury prevention and control program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 15 members may be appointed to this council. Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms in such a manner that each year the terms of approximately one-fourth of the members expire. The chair of the council shall be designated by the State Surgeon General. Vacancies shall be filled for the remainder of unexpired terms in the same manner as the original appointment. Members shall receive no compensation but may be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representation on the Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council shall include: two licensed physicians who are “medical directors” as defined in s. 401.23(15) or whose medical practice is closely related to emergency medical services; two emergency medical service administrators, one of whom is employed by a fire service; two certified paramedics, one of whom is employed by a fire service; two certified emergency medical technicians, one of whom is employed by a fire service; one emergency medical services educator; one emergency nurse; one hospital administrator; one representative of air ambulance services; one representative of a commercial ambulance operator; and two laypersons who are in no way connected with emergency medical services, one of whom is a representative of the elderly. Ex officio members of the advisory council from state agencies shall include, but shall not be limited to, representatives from the Department of Education, the Department of Management Services, the State Fire Marshal, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Transportation, and the Division of Emergency Management.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appointments to the council shall be made by the State Surgeon General, except that state agency representatives shall be appointed by the respective agency head.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council member shall be removed from office for malfeasance; misfeasance; neglect of duty; incompetence; permanent inability to perform official duties; or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to, or being found guilty of, a felony.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall hold meetings at the call of the chair, upon the written request of five members of the council, or at the call of the staff director of the emergency medical services program office. A majority of the members of the council shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be recorded for all meetings of the council and shall be maintained on file in the emergency medical services program office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established a committee to advise the Department of Health on matters concerning preventative, prehospital, hospital, rehabilitative, and other posthospital medical care for children.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committee members shall be appointed by the State Surgeon General, and shall include, but not be limited to, physicians and other medical professionals that have experience in emergency medicine or expertise in emergency and critical care for children.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appointments to the committee shall be for a term of 2 years. Vacancies may be filled for the unexpired term at the discretion of the State Surgeon General. The members shall serve without compensation, and shall not be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties, unless there is funding available from the Federal Government or contributions or grants from private sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 13, ch. 83-196; ss. 14, 56, ch. 86-220; s. 5, ch. 88-186; s. 13, ch. 89-275; s. 11, ch. 89-283; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 92-46; s. 36, ch. 92-78; s. 7, ch. 92-174; s. 76, ch. 95-143; s. 791, ch. 95-148; s. 45, ch. 95-196; s. 43, ch. 97-237; s. 422, ch. 2003-261; s. 51, ch. 2008-6; s. 281, ch. 2011-142; s. 87, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>