<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee must maintain accurate records of emergency calls on forms that contain such information as is required by the department. These records must be available for inspection by the department at any reasonable time, and copies thereof must be furnished to the department upon request. The department shall give each licensee notice of what information such forms must contain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee must provide the receiving hospital with a copy of an individual patient care record for each patient who is transported to the hospital. The information contained in the record and the method and timeframe for providing the record shall be prescribed by rule of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports to the department from licensees which cover statistical data are public records, except that the names of patients and other patient-identifying information contained in such reports are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). Any record furnished by a licensee at the request of the department must be a true and certified copy of the original record and may not be altered or have information deleted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records of emergency calls which contain patient examination or treatment information are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and may not be disclosed without the consent of the person to whom they pertain, but appropriate limited disclosure may be made without such consent:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the person’s guardian, to the next of kin if the person is deceased, or to a parent if the person is a minor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To hospital personnel for use in conjunction with the treatment of the patient;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the department;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the service medical director;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For use in a critical incident stress debriefing. Any such discussions during a critical incident stress debriefing shall be considered privileged communication under s. 90.503;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil or criminal action, unless otherwise prohibited by law, upon the issuance of a subpoena from a court of competent jurisdiction and proper notice by the party seeking such records, to the patient or his or her legal representative; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a local trauma agency or a regional trauma agency, or a panel or committee assembled by such an agency to assist the agency in performing quality assurance activities in accordance with a plan approved under s. 395.401. Records obtained under this paragraph are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This subsection does not prohibit the department or a licensee from providing information to any law enforcement agency or any other regulatory agency responsible for the regulation or supervision of emergency medical services and personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt and enforce all rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 73-126; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 254, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 24, 25, ch. 82-402; s. 13, ch. 83-196; s. 11, ch. 84-317; s. 40, ch. 87-225; s. 17, ch. 90-344; ss. 12, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 5, ch. 94-260; s. 1058, ch. 95-148; s. 233, ch. 96-406; s. 21, ch. 98-151; s. 33, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>