<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.272" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency medical services community health care.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to encourage more effective utilization of the skills of emergency medical technicians and paramedics by enabling them to perform, in partnership with local county health departments, specific additional health care tasks that are consistent with the public health and welfare.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paramedics or emergency medical technicians may perform health promotion and wellness activities and blood pressure screenings in a nonemergency environment, within the scope of their training, and under the direction of a medical director. As used in this paragraph, the term “health promotion and wellness” means the provision of public health programs pertaining to the prevention of illness and injury.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paramedics may administer immunizations in a nonemergency environment, within the scope of their training, and under the direction of a medical director. There must be a written agreement between the paramedic’s medical director and the county health department located in each county in which the paramedic administers immunizations. This agreement must establish the protocols, policies, and procedures under which the paramedic must operate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each medical director under whose direction a paramedic administers immunizations must verify and document that the paramedic has received sufficient training and experience to administer immunizations. The verification must be documented on forms developed by the department, and the completed forms must be maintained at the service location of the licensee and made available to the department upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt and enforce all rules necessary to enforce the provisions relating to a paramedic’s administration of immunizations and the performance of health promotion and wellness activities and blood pressure screenings by a paramedic or emergency medical technician in a nonemergency environment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-87.</History></Section>