<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.252" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interfacility transfer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed basic or advanced life support ambulance service may conduct interfacility transfers in a permitted ambulance, using a registered nurse in place of an emergency medical technician or paramedic, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registered nurse holds a current certificate of successful course completion in advanced cardiac life support;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician in charge has granted permission for such a transfer, has designated the level of service required for such transfer, and has deemed the patient to be in such a condition appropriate to this type of ambulance staffing; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registered nurse operates within the scope of part I of chapter 464.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed basic or advanced life support service may conduct interfacility transfers in a permitted ambulance if the patient’s treating physician certifies that the transfer is medically appropriate and the physician provides reasonable transfer orders. An interfacility transfer must be conducted in a permitted ambulance if it is determined that the patient needs, or is likely to need, medical attention during transport. If the emergency medical technician or paramedic believes the level of patient care required during the transfer is beyond his or her capability, the medical director, or his or her designee, must be contacted for clearance prior to conducting the transfer. If necessary, the medical director, or his or her designee, shall attempt to contact the treating physician for consultation to determine the appropriateness of the transfer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Infants less than 28 days old or infants weighing less than 5 kilograms, who require critical care interfacility transport to a neonatal intensive care unit, shall be transported in a permitted advanced life support or basic life support transport ambulance, or in a permitted advanced life support or basic life support ambulance that is recognized by the department as meeting designated criteria for neonatal interfacility critical care transport.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt and enforce rules to carry out this section, including rules for permitting, equipping, and staffing transport ambulances and that govern the medical direction under which interfacility transfers take place.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 25, ch. 82-402; s. 13, ch. 83-196; ss. 6, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 792, ch. 95-148; s. 44, ch. 97-237; s. 108, ch. 2000-318.</History></Section>