<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure as a basic life support or an advanced life support service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person, firm, corporation, association, or governmental entity owning or acting as agent for the owner of any business or service which furnishes, operates, conducts, maintains, advertises, engages in, proposes to engage in, or professes to engage in the business or service of providing prehospital or interfacility advanced life support services or basic life support transportation services must be licensed as a basic life support service or an advanced life support service, whichever is applicable, before offering such service to the public. The application for such license must be submitted to the department on forms provided for this purpose. The application must include documentation that the applicant meets the appropriate requirements for a basic life support service or an advanced life support service, whichever is applicable, as specified by rule of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license for operation to any applicant who complies with the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has paid the fees required by s. 401.34.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ambulances, equipment, vehicles, personnel, communications systems, staffing patterns, and services of the applicant meet the requirements of this part, including the appropriate rules for either a basic life support service or an advanced life support service, whichever is applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has furnished evidence of adequate insurance coverage for claims arising out of injury to or death of persons and damage to the property of others resulting from any cause for which the owner of such business or service would be liable. The applicant must provide insurance in such sums and under such terms as required by the department. In lieu of such insurance, the applicant may furnish a certificate of self-insurance evidencing that the applicant has established an adequate self-insurance plan to cover such risks and that the plan has been approved by the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has obtained a certificate of public convenience and necessity from each county in which the applicant will operate. In issuing the certificate of public convenience and necessity, the governing body of each county shall consider the recommendations of municipalities within its jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may suspend or revoke a license at any time if it determines that the licensee has failed to maintain compliance with the requirements prescribed for operating a basic or advanced life support service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license issued in accordance with this part will expire automatically 2 years after the date of issuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements for renewal of any license issued under this part are the same as the requirements for original licensure that are in effect at the time of renewal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of each county may adopt ordinances that provide reasonable standards for certificates of public convenience and necessity for basic or advanced life support services and air ambulance services. In developing standards for certificates of public convenience and necessity, the governing body of each county must consider state guidelines, recommendations of the local or regional trauma agency created under chapter 395, and the recommendations of municipalities within its jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each permitted basic life support ambulance not specifically exempted from this part, when transporting a person who is sick, injured, wounded, incapacitated, or helpless, must be occupied by at least two persons: one patient attendant who is a certified emergency medical technician, certified paramedic, or licensed physician; and one ambulance driver who meets the requirements of s. 401.281. This paragraph does not apply to interfacility transfers governed by s. 401.252(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each permitted advanced life support ambulance not specifically exempted from this part, when transporting a person who is sick, injured, wounded, incapacitated, or helpless, must be occupied by at least two persons: one who is a certified paramedic or licensed physician; and one who is a certified emergency medical technician, certified paramedic, or licensed physician who also meets the requirements of s. 401.281 for drivers. The person with the highest medical certifications shall be in charge of patient care. This paragraph does not apply to interfacility transfers governed by s. 401.252(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 16, ch. 73-126; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 249, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 6, 10, ch. 79-280; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 24, 25, ch. 82-402; ss. 5, 13, ch. 83-196; s. 54, ch. 83-218; s. 6, ch. 84-317; s. 57, ch. 86-220; s. 14, ch. 89-275; s. 12, ch. 89-283; ss. 5, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 29, ch. 99-397; s. 423, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>