<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.445" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency examination and treatment of incapacitated persons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No recovery shall be allowed in any court in this state against any emergency medical technician, paramedic, or physician as defined in this chapter, any advanced registered nurse practitioner certified under s. 464.012, or any physician assistant licensed under s. 458.347 or s. 459.022, or any person acting under the direct medical supervision of a physician, in an action brought for examining or treating a patient without his or her informed consent if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient at the time of examination or treatment is intoxicated, under the influence of drugs, or otherwise incapable of providing informed consent as provided in s. 766.103;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient at the time of examination or treatment is experiencing an emergency medical condition; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient would reasonably, under all the surrounding circumstances, undergo such examination, treatment, or procedure if he or she were advised by the emergency medical technician, paramedic, physician, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant in accordance with s. 766.103(3).</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Examination and treatment provided under this subsection shall be limited to reasonable examination of the patient to determine the medical condition of the patient and treatment reasonably necessary to alleviate the emergency medical condition or to stabilize the patient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In examining and treating a person who is apparently intoxicated, under the influence of drugs, or otherwise incapable of providing informed consent, the emergency medical technician, paramedic, physician, advanced registered nurse practitioner, or physician assistant, or any person acting under the direct medical supervision of a physician, shall proceed wherever possible with the consent of the person. If the person reasonably appears to be incapacitated and refuses his or her consent, the person may be examined, treated, or taken to a hospital or other appropriate treatment resource if he or she is in need of emergency attention, without his or her consent, but unreasonable force shall not be used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not limit medical treatment provided pursuant to court order or treatment provided in accordance with chapter 394 or chapter 397.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 89-275; s. 15, ch. 89-283; s. 3, ch. 89-336; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 25, ch. 92-78; s. 3, ch. 93-12; s. 25, ch. 93-39; s. 802, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 2007-176.</History></Section>