<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide regional emergency medical telecommunication system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services is authorized and directed to develop a statewide system of regional emergency medical telecommunications. For the purpose of this part, the term “telecommunications” means those voice, data, and signaling transmissions and receptions between emergency medical service components, including, but not limited to: ambulances; rescue vehicles; hospitals or other related emergency receiving facilities; emergency communications centers; physicians and emergency medical personnel; paging facilities; law enforcement and fire protection agencies; and poison control, suicide, and emergency management agencies. In formulating such a system, the department shall divide the state into appropriate regions and shall develop a program which includes, but is not limited to, the following provisions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A requirements provision, which shall state the telecommunications requirements for each emergency medical entity comprising the region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interfacility communications provision, which shall depict the telecommunications interfaces between the various medical service entities which operate within the region and state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An organizational layout provision, which shall include each emergency medical entity and the number of radio operating units (base, mobile, handheld, etc.) per entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A frequency allocation and use provision, which shall include on an entity basis each assigned and planned radio channel and the type of operation (simplex, duplex, half duplex, etc.) on each channel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An operational provision, which shall include dispatching, logging, and operating procedures pertaining to telecommunications on an entity basis and regional basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency medical service telephone provision, which shall include the telephone and the numbering plan throughout the region for both the public and interface requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 73-254; s. 41, ch. 83-334; s. 302, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 101, ch. 98-279.</History></Section>