<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Drivers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee is responsible for assuring that its vehicles are driven only by trained, experienced, and otherwise qualified personnel. The licensee must, at a minimum, document that each of its drivers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certifies under oath that he or she is not addicted to alcohol or any controlled substance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certifies under oath that he or she is free from any physical or mental defect or disease that might impair his or her ability to drive an ambulance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon initial designation as a driver, has not, within the past 3 years, been convicted of driving under the influence of alcohol or controlled substances and has not had a driver’s license suspended under the point system provided for in chapter 322;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a valid driver’s license issued under chapter 322, is trained in the safe operation of emergency vehicles, and has completed an emergency vehicle operator’s course or the reasonable equivalent as approved by the department; however, this paragraph applies only to a driver of a land vehicle;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a valid American Red Cross or National Safety Council standard first aid course card or its equivalent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a valid American Red Cross or American Heart Association cardiopulmonary resuscitation card.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall periodically inspect licensees for verification of compliance with this section. Services that are unable to verify compliance are subject to disciplinary action as provided in this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 25, ch. 82-402; ss. 8, 13, ch. 83-196; s. 10, ch. 84-317; s. 60, ch. 86-220; s. 56, ch. 89-282; ss. 10, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 796, ch. 95-148; s. 2, ch. 2009-181.</History></Section>