<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0401.2915" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Automated external defibrillators.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that an automated external defibrillator may be used by any person for the purpose of saving the life of another person in cardiac arrest. In order to achieve that goal, the Legislature intends to encourage training in lifesaving first aid and set standards for and encourage the use of automated external defibrillators.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automated external defibrillator” means a device as defined in s. 768.1325(2)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Defibrillation” means the administration of a controlled electrical charge to the heart to restore a viable cardiac rhythm.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to promote public health and safety:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons who use an automated external defibrillator are encouraged to obtain appropriate training, to include completion of a course in cardiopulmonary resuscitation or successful completion of a basic first aid course that includes cardiopulmonary resuscitation training, and demonstrated proficiency in the use of an automated external defibrillator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity in possession of an automated external defibrillator is encouraged to notify the local emergency medical services medical director or the local public safety answering point, as defined in s. 365.172(3), of the location of the automated external defibrillator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who uses an automated external defibrillator shall activate the emergency medical services system as soon as possible upon use of the automated external defibrillator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who intentionally or willfully:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tampers with or otherwise renders an automated external defibrillator inoperative, except during such time as the automated external defibrillator is being serviced, tested, repaired, recharged, or inspected or except pursuant to court order; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obliterates the serial number on an automated external defibrillator for purposes of falsifying service records,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Paragraph (a) does not apply to the owner of the automated external defibrillator or the owner’s authorized representative or agent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local and state law enforcement vehicle may carry an automated external defibrillator.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-34; s. 3, ch. 2001-76; s. 1, ch. 2005-109; s. 1, ch. 2006-206; s. 1, ch. 2008-101; s. 3, ch. 2012-177.</History>
</Section>