<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses or attempts to use a certificate, license, or permit that has been suspended, revoked, or terminated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practices or holds himself or herself out as an emergency medical technician, paramedic, or ambulance driver without being so certified;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly conceals information relating to violations of this part; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly makes false or fraudulent claims to procure, attempt to procure, or renew a certificate, license, or permit</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever willfully and with intent to defraud obtains or attempts to obtain services from a licensee is guilty of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for the first offense; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any subsequent offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever summons any emergency medical services vehicle pursuant to this part or reports that an emergency medical services vehicle is needed when he or she knows or has reason to know that the services of the vehicle are not needed is guilty of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for the first offense; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any subsequent offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each day that a violation of this part is committed or permitted to continue constitutes a separate and distinct offense under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 73-126; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 18, 24, 25, ch. 82-402; ss. 12, 13, ch. 83-196; s. 73, ch. 91-224; ss. 20, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 799, ch. 95-148; s. 7, ch. 96-293.</History></Section>