<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vehicle permits for basic life support and advanced life support services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every licensee shall possess a valid permit for each transport vehicle, advanced life support nontransport vehicle, and aircraft in use. Applications for such permits shall be made upon forms prescribed by the department. The licensee shall provide documentation that each vehicle for which a permit is sought meets the appropriate requirements for a basic life support or advanced life support service vehicle, whichever is applicable, as specified by rule of the department. A permit is not required for an advanced life support nontransport vehicle that is intended to be used for scene supervision, incident command, or the augmentation of supplies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive a valid permit, the applicant must submit a completed application form for each vehicle or aircraft for which a permit is desired, pay the appropriate fees established as provided in s. 401.34, and provide documentation that each vehicle or aircraft meets the following requirements as established by rule of the department; the vehicle or aircraft must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be furnished with essential medical supplies and equipment which is in good working order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet appropriate standards for design and construction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be equipped with an appropriate communication system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet appropriate safety standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet sanitation and maintenance standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be insured for an appropriate sum against injuries to or the death of any person arising out of an accident.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit if it determines that the vehicle, aircraft, or equipment fails to meet the requirements specified in this part or in the rules of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit issued in accordance with this section will expire automatically concurrent with the service license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to renew a vehicle or aircraft permit issued pursuant to this part, the applicant must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a renewal application. Such application must be received by the department not more than 90 days or less than 30 days prior to the expiration of the permit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit the appropriate fee or fees, established as provided in s. 401.34.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide documentation that current standards for issuance of a permit are met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish criteria and time limits for substitution of permitted vehicles that are out of service for maintenance purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt and enforce rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 73-126; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 250, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 7, 10, ch. 79-280; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 9, 24, 25, ch. 82-402; s. 13, ch. 83-196; s. 56, ch. 83-218; s. 8, ch. 84-317; s. 58, ch. 86-220; ss. 7, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 19, ch. 98-151.</History></Section>