<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0401.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Injunctive relief; cease and desist notice; civil penalty; enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General may cause to be instituted a civil action in circuit court for preliminary or permanent injunctive relief to remedy or prevent a violation of this part or any rule adopted by the department under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department has probable cause to believe that any person not licensed by the department has provided prehospital or interfacility advanced life support or basic life support procedures or transportation services in this state not specifically authorized by law, the department may issue and deliver to such person a notice to cease and desist from such services. For the purpose of enforcing a cease and desist order, the department may file a petition, in the name of the state, seeking issuance of an injunction or a writ of mandamus against any person who violates any provisions of such order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to or in lieu of any remedy provided in paragraph (a), the department may seek the imposition of a civil penalty by the circuit court for any violation for which the department may issue a notice to cease and desist under paragraph (a). The civil penalty must be no less than $500 and no more than $5,000 for each offense. The court may, in addition to any other remedy it finds appropriate, award to the prevailing party court costs and a reasonable attorney’s fee, and, if the department prevails, the court may also award reasonable costs of investigation. All amounts collected by the department under this paragraph must be deposited into the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 13, ch. 83-196; ss. 23, 36, ch. 92-78; s. 52, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>