<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0667.009" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of savings bank generally.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every savings bank incorporated pursuant to or operating under the provisions of the financial institutions codes shall have all the powers enumerated, authorized, and permitted by this chapter and such other rights, privileges, and powers as may be incidental to or reasonably necessary or appropriate for the accomplishment of the objectives and purposes of the savings bank. Except as otherwise limited by the provisions of the financial institutions codes, every savings bank shall have the following powers:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROPERTY TRANSFERS.<EmDash />To acquire, hold, sell, dispose of, and convey real and personal estate consistent with its objects and powers; to mortgage, pledge, or lease any real or personal estate; and to take property by gifts, devise, or bequest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUBORDINATED DEBT.<EmDash />To issue and sell, directly or through underwriters, subordinated debt which shall represent nonwithdrawable capital contributions and shall constitute part of the equity capital of the savings bank. Such debt shall have no voting rights; shall be subordinate to all savings accounts, debt obligations, and claims of creditors of the savings bank; and shall constitute a claim in liquidation against any other equity capital account remaining after the payment in full of all savings accounts, debt obligations, and claims of creditors. Such subordinated debt shall be entitled to the payment of earnings prior to the allocation of any income to surplus or other equity capital accounts of the savings bank and may be issued with a fixed rate of earnings or with a prior claim to distribution of a specified percentage of any net income remaining after required allocations to reserves, or a combination thereof. Losses shall be charged against subordinated debt only after other equity capital accounts have been exhausted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SALE OF LOANS.<EmDash />To sell with or without recourse any loan, including any participating interests therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SERVICING.<EmDash />To service loans and investments for others.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AGENT.<EmDash />To act as agent or escrowee for others in any transaction incidental to the operation of its business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIMITED TRUSTEESHIP.<EmDash />To act, and receive compensation therefor, as trustee of any trust created or organized in the United States and forming a part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan which qualifies or is qualified for specific tax treatment under s. 401 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended, and to act as trustee or custodian of an individual retirement account within the meaning of s. 408 of such code if the funds of such trust or account are invested only in savings accounts of such savings bank or in obligations or securities issued by such savings bank. All funds held in a fiduciary capacity by any such savings bank under the authority of this subsection may be commingled and consolidated for appropriate purposes of investment, provided that records reflecting each separate beneficial interest are maintained by the fiduciary unless such responsibility is lawfully assumed by another appropriate party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOOL SAVINGS.<EmDash />To contract with the proper authorities of any public or nonpublic elementary or secondary school or institution of higher learning, or any public or charitable institution caring for minors, for the participation and implementation by the savings bank in any school or institutional thrift or savings plan, and to accept savings accounts at such a school or institution, either by its own collector or by any representative of the school or institution which becomes the agent of the savings bank for such purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PAYROLL SAVINGS.<EmDash />To contract with any employer with respect to the solicitation, collection, and receipt of savings by payroll deduction to be credited to a designated account or accounts of his or her or its employee or employees who voluntarily may participate or with respect to the direct deposit of wages or salary paid by such employer to the account of the employee in a financial depository institution by electronic or other medium upon authorization in writing by the employee and his or her designation of the savings bank or other financial depository institution as the recipient of such deposits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DRAFTS.<EmDash />To issue drafts and similar instruments drawn on the savings bank to aid in effecting withdrawals and for other purposes of the savings bank.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 97-30.</History></Section>