<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.822" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of guardian ad litem for abused, abandoned, or neglected child.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian ad litem shall be appointed by the court at the earliest possible time to represent the child in any child abuse, abandonment, or neglect judicial proceeding, whether civil or criminal. Any person participating in a civil or criminal judicial proceeding resulting from such appointment shall be presumed prima facie to be acting in good faith and in so doing shall be immune from any liability, civil or criminal, that otherwise might be incurred or imposed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In those cases in which the parents are financially able, the parent or parents of the child shall reimburse the court, in part or in whole, for the cost of provision of guardian ad litem services. Reimbursement to the individual providing guardian ad litem services shall not be contingent upon successful collection by the court from the parent or parents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon presentation by a guardian ad litem of a court order appointing the guardian ad litem:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency, as defined in chapter 119, shall allow the guardian ad litem to inspect and copy records related to the best interests of the child who is the subject of the appointment, including, but not limited to, records made confidential or exempt from s. 119.07(1) or s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. The guardian ad litem shall maintain the confidential or exempt status of any records shared by an agency under this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or organization, other than an agency under paragraph (a), shall allow the guardian ad litem to inspect and copy any records related to the best interests of the child who is the subject of the appointment, including, but not limited to, confidential records.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this subsection, the term “records related to the best interests of the child” includes, but is not limited to, medical, mental health, substance abuse, child care, education, law enforcement, court, social services, and financial records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guardian ad litem or the program representative shall review all disposition recommendations and changes in placements, and must be present at all critical stages of the dependency proceeding or submit a written report of recommendations to the court. Written reports must be filed with the court and served on all parties whose whereabouts are known at least 72 hours prior to the hearing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 63-24; s. 941, ch. 71-136; ss. 1, 1A, ch. 71-97; s. 32, ch. 73-334; s. 65, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 75-101; s. 1, ch. 75-185; s. 4, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 3, ch. 77-429; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-322; s. 3, ch. 78-326; s. 22, ch. 78-361; s. 1, ch. 78-379; s. 181, ch. 79-164; s. 1, ch. 79-203; s. 10, ch. 84-226; s. 3, ch. 90-211; s. 103, ch. 98-403; s. 51, ch. 99-193; s. 26, ch. 2005-236.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 828.041, 827.07(16); s. 415.508.</Text></Note></Section>