<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.9055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certified domestic violence centers; capital improvement grant program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established a certified domestic violence center capital improvement grant program.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified domestic violence center as defined in s. 39.905 may apply to the Department of Children and Family Services for a capital improvement grant. The grant application must provide information that includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement specifying the capital improvement that the certified domestic violence center proposes to make with the grant funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed strategy for making the capital improvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organizational structure that will carry out the capital improvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence that the certified domestic violence center has difficulty in obtaining funding or that funds available for the proposed improvement are inadequate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence that the funds will assist in meeting the needs of victims of domestic violence and their children in the certified domestic violence center service area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of a satisfactory recordkeeping system to account for fund expenditures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of ability to generate local match.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified domestic violence centers as defined in s. 39.905 may receive funding subject to legislative appropriation, upon application to the Department of Children and Family Services, for projects to construct, acquire, repair, improve, or upgrade systems, facilities, or equipment, subject to availability of funds. An award of funds under this section must be made in accordance with a needs assessment developed by the Florida Coalition Against Domestic Violence and the Department of Children and Family Services. The department annually shall perform this needs assessment and shall rank in order of need those centers that are requesting funds for capital improvement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall, in collaboration with the Florida Coalition Against Domestic Violence, establish criteria for awarding the capital improvement funds that must be used exclusively for support and assistance with the capital improvement needs of the certified domestic violence centers, as defined in s. 39.905.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall ensure that the funds awarded under this section are used solely for the purposes specified in this section. The department will also ensure that the grant process maintains the confidentiality of the location of the certified domestic violence centers, pursuant to s. 39.908. The total amount of grant moneys awarded under this section may not exceed the amount appropriated for this program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-220.</History></Section>