<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.6012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Case plan tasks; services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services to be provided to the parent and the tasks that must be completed are subject to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services described in the case plan must be designed to improve the conditions in the home and aid in maintaining the child in the home, facilitate the child’s safe return to the home, ensure proper care of the child, or facilitate the child’s permanent placement. The services offered must be the least intrusive possible into the life of the parent and child, must focus on clearly defined objectives, and must provide the most efficient path to quick reunification or permanent placement given the circumstances of the case and the child’s need for safe and proper care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan must describe each of the tasks with which the parent must comply and the services to be provided to the parent, specifically addressing the identified problem, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the department will provide each service or referral for the service if the service is being provided by the department or its agent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date by which the parent must complete each task.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The frequency of services or treatment provided. The frequency of the delivery of services or treatment provided shall be determined by the professionals providing the services or treatment on a case-by-case basis and adjusted according to their best professional judgment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the delivery of the services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The staff of the department or service provider accountable for the services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the measurable objectives, including the timeframes specified for achieving the objectives of the case plan and addressing the identified problem.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan must include all available information that is relevant to the child’s care including, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the identified needs of the child while in care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the plan for ensuring that the child receives safe and proper care and that services are provided to the child in order to address the child’s needs. To the extent available and accessible, the following health, mental health, and education information and records of the child must be attached to the case plan and updated throughout the judicial review process:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the child’s health, mental health, and educational providers;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s grade level performance;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s school record;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assurances that the child’s placement takes into account proximity to the school in which the child is enrolled at the time of placement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the child’s immunizations;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s known medical history, including any known problems;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s medications, if any; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other relevant health, mental health, and education information concerning the child.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other requirement, if the child is in an out-of-home placement, the case plan must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the type of placement in which the child is to be living.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the parent’s visitation rights and obligations and the plan for sibling visitation if the child has siblings and is separated from them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When appropriate, for a child who is 13 years of age or older, a written description of the programs and services that will help the child prepare for the transition from foster care to independent living.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A discussion of the safety and the appropriateness of the child’s placement, which placement is intended to be safe, and the least restrictive and the most family-like setting available consistent with the best interest and special needs of the child and in as close proximity as possible to the child’s home.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2006-86.</History></Section>