<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.814" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Oaths, records, and confidential information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge, clerks or deputy clerks, and authorized agents of the department shall each have the power to administer oaths and affirmations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall make and keep records of all cases brought before it pursuant to this part and shall preserve the records of proceedings under this part pursuant to the Florida Rules of Judicial Administration. Records of cases where orders were entered permanently depriving a parent of the custody of a child shall be preserved permanently.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk shall keep all court records required by this part separate from other records of the circuit court. All court records required by this part shall not be open to inspection by the public. All records shall be inspected only upon order of the court by persons deemed by the court to have a proper interest therein, except that, custodians of the child and their attorneys, law enforcement agencies, and the department and its designees shall always have the right to inspect and copy any official record pertaining to the child. The court may permit authorized representatives of recognized organizations compiling statistics for proper purposes to inspect and make abstracts from official records, under whatever conditions upon their use and disposition the court may deem proper, and may punish by contempt proceedings any violation of those conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All information obtained pursuant to this part in the discharge of official duty by any judge, employee of the court, authorized agent of the department, or law enforcement agent shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and shall not be disclosed to anyone other than the authorized personnel of the court, the department and its designees, law enforcement agents, and others entitled under this part to receive that information, except upon order of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All orders of the court entered pursuant to this part shall be in writing and signed by the judge, except that the clerk or deputy clerk may sign a summons or notice to appear.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court record of proceedings under this part shall be admissible in evidence in any other civil or criminal proceeding, except that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records of proceedings under this part forming a part of the record on appeal shall be used in the appellate court in the manner hereinafter provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records necessary therefor shall be admissible in evidence in any case in which a person is being tried upon a charge of having committed perjury.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final order entered pursuant to an adjudicatory hearing is admissible in evidence in any subsequent civil proceeding relating to placement of, access to, parental time with, adoption of, or parental rights and responsibilities for the same child or a sibling of that child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence admitted in any proceeding under this part may be admissible in evidence when offered by any party in a subsequent civil proceeding relating to placement of, access to, parental time with, adoption of, or parental rights and responsibilities for the same child or a sibling of that child if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice is given to the opposing party or opposing party’s counsel of the intent to offer the evidence and a copy of such evidence is delivered to the opposing party or opposing party’s counsel; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The evidence is otherwise admissible in the subsequent civil proceeding.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Final orders, records, and evidence in any proceeding under this part which are subsequently admitted in evidence pursuant to subsection (6) remain subject to subsections (3) and (4).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 14, ch. 90-360; s. 17, ch. 96-406; s. 3, ch. 97-226; s. 96, ch. 98-403; s. 49, ch. 99-193; s. 6, ch. 2005-239.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.471.</Text></Note></Section>