<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0039.307" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports of child-on-child sexual abuse.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving a report alleging juvenile sexual abuse as defined in s. 39.01(7), the department shall assist the family in receiving appropriate services to address the allegations of the report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, contracted sheriff’s office providing protective investigation services, or contracted case management personnel responsible for providing services, at a minimum, shall adhere to the following procedures:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the response to a report alleging juvenile sexual abuse behavior shall be explained to the caregiver.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the response shall be explained in a manner consistent with legislative purpose and intent provided in this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and office telephone number of the person responding shall be provided to the caregiver of the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior and the victim’s caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The possible consequences of the department’s response, including outcomes and services, shall be explained to the caregiver of the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior and the victim’s caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The caregiver of the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior and the victim’s caregiver shall be involved to the fullest extent possible in determining the nature of the sexual behavior concerns and the nature of any problem or risk to other children.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessment of risk and the perceived treatment needs of the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior, the victim, and respective caregivers shall be conducted by the district staff, the child protection team of the Department of Health, and other providers under contract with the department to provide services to the caregiver of the alleged offender, the victim, and the victim’s caregiver.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessment shall be conducted in a manner that is sensitive to the social, economic, and cultural environment of the family.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If necessary, the child protection team of the Department of Health shall conduct a physical examination of the victim, which is sufficient to meet forensic requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on the information obtained from the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior, his or her caregiver, the victim, and the victim’s caregiver, an assessment of service and treatment needs must be completed and, if needed, a case plan developed within 30 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall classify the outcome of the report as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report closed. Services were not offered because the department determined that there was no basis for intervention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services accepted by alleged juvenile sexual offender. Services were offered to the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior and accepted by the caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report closed. Services were offered to the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior, but were rejected by the caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notification to law enforcement. The risk to the victim’s safety and well-being cannot be reduced by the provision of services or the caregiver rejected services, and notification of the alleged delinquent act or violation of law to the appropriate law enforcement agency was initiated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services accepted by victim. Services were offered to the victim and accepted by the caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report closed. Services were offered to the victim but were rejected by the caregiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If services have been accepted by the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior, the victim, and respective caregivers, the department shall designate a case manager and develop a specific case plan.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the plan, the caregiver shall indicate its acceptance of the plan in writing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case manager shall periodically review the progress toward achieving the objectives of the plan in order to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make adjustments to the plan or take additional action as provided in this part; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the case if indicated by successful or substantial achievement of the objectives of the plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services provided to the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior, the victim, and respective caregivers or family must be voluntary and of necessary duration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the family or caregiver of the alleged juvenile sexual offender or child who has exhibited inappropriate sexual behavior fails to adequately participate or allow for the adequate participation of the child in the services or treatment delineated in the case plan, the case manager may recommend that the department:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Close the case;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the case to mediation or arbitration, if available; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the appropriate law enforcement agency of failure to comply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time, as a result of additional information, findings of facts, or changing conditions, the department may pursue a child protective investigation as provided in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to develop rules and other policy directives necessary to implement the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 95-266; s. 50, ch. 95-267; s. 13, ch. 97-98; s. 9, ch. 98-137; s. 45, ch. 98-403; s. 4, ch. 2003-127; s. 7, ch. 2008-245; s. 8, ch. 2012-178.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 415.50171.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>