<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.811" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of disposition; order of disposition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that the grounds for termination of parental rights have not been established by clear and convincing evidence, the court shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If grounds for dependency have been established, adjudicate or readjudicate the child dependent and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter an order placing or continuing the child in out-of-home care under a case plan; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter an order returning the child to the parent or parents. The court shall retain jurisdiction over a child returned to the parent or parents for a period of 6 months, but, at that time, based on a report of the social service agency and any other relevant factors, the court shall make a determination as to whether its jurisdiction shall continue or be terminated.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If grounds for dependency have not been established, dismiss the petition.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is in the custody of the department and the court finds that the grounds for termination of parental rights have been established by clear and convincing evidence, the court shall, by order, place the child in the custody of the department for the purpose of adoption.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is in the custody of one parent and the court finds that the grounds for termination of parental rights have been established for the remaining parent by clear and convincing evidence, the court shall enter an order terminating the rights of the parent for whom the grounds have been established and placing the child in the custody of the remaining parent, granting that parent sole parental responsibility for the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is neither in the custody of the department nor in the custody of a parent and the court finds that the grounds for termination of parental rights have been established for either or both parents, the court shall enter an order terminating parental rights for the parent or parents for whom the grounds for termination have been established and placing the child with the department or an appropriate legal custodian. If the parental rights of both parents have been terminated, or if the parental rights of only one parent have been terminated and the court makes specific findings based on evidence presented that placement with the remaining parent is likely to be harmful to the child, the court may order that the child be placed with a legal custodian other than the department after hearing evidence of the suitability of the intended placement. Suitability of the intended placement includes the fitness and capabilities of the proposed legal custodian to function as the primary caregiver for a particular child; and the compatibility of the child with the home in which the child is intended to be placed. If the court orders that a child be placed with a legal custodian under this subsection, the court shall appoint a legal custodian as the guardian for the child as provided in s. 744.3021 or s. 39.621. The court may modify the order placing the child in the custody of the legal custodian and revoke the guardianship established under s. 744.3021 or another relationship if the court subsequently finds the placement to be no longer in the best interest of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court terminates parental rights, the court shall enter a written order of disposition briefly stating the facts upon which its decision to terminate the parental rights is made. An order of termination of parental rights, whether based on parental consent or after notice served as prescribed in this part, permanently deprives the parents of any right to the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parental rights of one parent may be severed without severing the parental rights of the other parent only under the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child has only one surviving parent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the identity of a prospective parent has been established as unknown after sworn testimony;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the parent whose rights are being terminated became a parent through a single-parent adoption;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the protection of the child demands termination of the rights of a single parent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the parent whose rights are being terminated meets any of the criteria specified in s. 39.806(1)(d) and (f)-(l).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The termination of parental rights does not affect the rights of grandparents unless the court finds that continued visitation is not in the best interests of the child or that such visitation would interfere with the permanency goals for the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court terminates parental rights, it may, as appropriate, order that the parents, siblings, or relatives of the parent whose rights are terminated be allowed to maintain some communication or contact with the child pending adoption if the best interests of the child support this continued communication or contact, except as provided in paragraph (a). If the court orders such continued communication or contact, which may include, but is not limited to, visits, letters, and cards or telephone calls, the nature and frequency of the communication or contact must be set forth in written order and may be reviewed upon motion of any party, or, for purposes of this subsection, an identified prospective adoptive parent. If a child is placed for adoption, the nature and frequency of the communication or contact must be reviewed by the court at the time the child is placed for adoption.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court terminates parental rights, it shall, in its order of disposition, provide for a hearing, to be scheduled no later than 30 days after the date of disposition, in which the department shall provide to the court an amended case plan that identifies the permanency goal for the child. Reasonable efforts must be made to place the child in a timely manner in accordance with the permanency plan and to complete whatever steps are necessary to finalize the permanent placement of the child. Thereafter, until the adoption of the child is finalized or the child reaches the age of 18 years, whichever occurs first, the court shall hold hearings at 6-month intervals to review the progress being made toward permanency for the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After termination of parental rights, the court shall retain jurisdiction over any child for whom custody is given to a social service agency until the child is adopted. The court shall review the status of the child’s placement and the progress being made toward permanent adoptive placement. As part of this continuing jurisdiction, for good cause shown by the guardian ad litem for the child, the court may review the appropriateness of the adoptive placement of the child.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 34, ch. 88-337; s. 21, ch. 90-306; s. 73, ch. 91-45; s. 39, ch. 94-164; s. 2, ch. 97-226; s. 1, ch. 98-50; s. 93, ch. 98-403; s. 48, ch. 99-193; s. 37, ch. 2000-139; s. 4, ch. 2001-3; s. 27, ch. 2006-86; s. 28, ch. 2008-245.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.469.</Text></Note></Section>