<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.6013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Case plan amendments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the case plan has been developed under s. 39.6011, the tasks and services agreed upon in the plan may not be changed or altered in any way except as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan may be amended at any time in order to change the goal of the plan, employ the use of concurrent planning, add or remove tasks the parent must complete to substantially comply with the plan, provide appropriate services for the child, and update the child’s health, mental health, and education records required by s. 39.6012.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan may be amended upon approval of the court if all parties are in agreement regarding the amendments to the plan and the amended plan is signed by all parties and submitted to the court with a memorandum of explanation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan may be amended by the court or upon motion of any party at any hearing to change the goal of the plan, employ the use of concurrent planning, or add or remove tasks the parent must complete in order to substantially comply with the plan if there is a preponderance of evidence demonstrating the need for the amendment. The need to amend the case plan may be based on information discovered or circumstances arising after the approval of the case plan for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A previously unaddressed condition that, without services, may prevent the child from safely returning to the home or may prevent the child from safely remaining in the home;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s need for permanency, taking into consideration the child’s age and developmental needs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of a party to substantially comply with a task in the original case plan, including the ineffectiveness of a previously offered service; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An error or oversight in the case plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan may be amended by the court or upon motion of any party at any hearing to provide appropriate services to the child if there is competent evidence demonstrating the need for the amendment. The reason for amending the case plan may be based on information discovered or circumstances arising after the approval of the case plan regarding the provision of safe and proper care to the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case plan is deemed amended as to the child’s health, mental health, and education records required by s. 39.6012 when the child’s updated health and education records are filed by the department under s. 39.701(8)(a).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amendments must include service interventions that are the least intrusive into the life of the parent and child, must focus on clearly defined objectives, and must provide the most efficient path to quick reunification or permanent placement given the circumstances of the case and the child’s need for safe and proper care. A copy of the amended plan must be immediately given to the persons identified in s. 39.6011(6)(b).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2006-86; s. 3, ch. 2007-5; s. 12, ch. 2009-43.</History></Section>