<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adjudicatory hearing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a hearing on a petition for termination of parental rights, the court shall consider the elements required for termination. Each of these elements must be established by clear and convincing evidence before the petition is granted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adjudicatory hearing must be held within 45 days after the advisory hearing, but reasonable continuances for the purpose of investigation, discovery, or procuring counsel or witnesses may, when necessary, be granted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adjudicatory hearing must be conducted by the judge without a jury, applying the rules of evidence in use in civil cases and adjourning the case from time to time as necessary. For purposes of the adjudicatory hearing, to avoid unnecessary duplication of expense, the judge may consider in-court testimony previously given at any properly noticed hearing, without regard to the availability or unavailability of the witness at the time of the actual adjudicatory hearing, if the recorded testimony itself is made available to the judge. Consideration of such testimony does not preclude the witness being subpoenaed to answer supplemental questions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All hearings involving termination of parental rights are confidential and closed to the public. Hearings involving more than one child may be held simultaneously when the children involved are related to each other or were involved in the same case. The child and the parents may be examined separately and apart from each other.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall enter a written order with the findings of fact and conclusions of law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 19, ch. 90-306; ss. 8, 10, ch. 92-158; s. 38, ch. 94-164; s. 91, ch. 98-403.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.467.</Text></Note></Section>