<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.812" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Postdisposition relief; petition for adoption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department is given custody of a child for subsequent adoption in accordance with this chapter, the department may place the child with an agency as defined in s. 63.032, with a child-caring agency registered under s. 409.176, or in a family home for prospective subsequent adoption. The department may thereafter become a party to any proceeding for the legal adoption of the child and appear in any court where the adoption proceeding is pending and consent to the adoption, and that consent alone shall in all cases be sufficient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any subsequent adoption proceeding, the parents are not entitled to notice of the proceeding and are not entitled to knowledge at any time after the order terminating parental rights is entered of the whereabouts of the child or of the identity or location of any person having the custody of or having adopted the child, except as provided by order of the court pursuant to this chapter or chapter 63. In any habeas corpus or other proceeding involving the child brought by any parent of the child, an agent or contract provider of the department may not be compelled to divulge that information, but may be compelled to produce the child before a court of competent jurisdiction if the child is still subject to the guardianship of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The entry of the custody order to the department does not entitle the department to guardianship of the estate or property of the child, but the department shall be the guardian of the person of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall retain jurisdiction over any child placed in the custody of the department until the child is adopted. After custody of a child for subsequent adoption has been given to the department, the court has jurisdiction for the purpose of reviewing the status of the child and the progress being made toward permanent adoptive placement. As part of this continuing jurisdiction, for good cause shown by the guardian ad litem for the child, the court may review the appropriateness of the adoptive placement of the child. When a licensed foster parent or court-ordered custodian has applied to adopt a child who has resided with the foster parent or custodian for at least 6 months and who has previously been permanently committed to the legal custody of the department and the department does not grant the application to adopt, the department may not, in the absence of a prior court order authorizing it to do so, remove the child from the foster home or custodian, except when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is probable cause to believe that the child is at imminent risk of abuse or neglect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty days have expired following written notice to the foster parent or custodian of the denial of the application to adopt, within which period no formal challenge of the department’s decision has been filed; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foster parent or custodian agrees to the child’s removal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition for adoption must be filed in the division of the circuit court which entered the judgment terminating parental rights, unless a motion for change of venue is granted pursuant to s. 47.122. A copy of the consent executed by the department must be attached to the petition, unless waived pursuant to s. 63.062(7). The petition must be accompanied by a statement, signed by the prospective adoptive parents, acknowledging receipt of all information required to be disclosed under s. 63.085 and a form provided by the department which details the social and medical history of the child and each parent and includes the social security number and date of birth for each parent, if such information is available or readily obtainable. The prospective adoptive parents may not file a petition for adoption until the judgment terminating parental rights becomes final. An adoption proceeding under this subsection is governed by chapter 63.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 41, ch. 94-164; s. 14, ch. 95-228; s. 94, ch. 98-403; s. 5, ch. 2001-3; s. 1, ch. 2004-389; s. 1, ch. 2008-151.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.47.</Text></Note></Section>