<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.827" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hearing for appointment of a guardian advocate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a petition for appointment of a guardian advocate has been filed with the circuit court, the hearing shall be held within 14 days unless all parties agree to a continuance. If a child is in need of necessary medical treatment as defined in s. 39.01, s. 984.03, or s. 985.03, the court shall hold a hearing within 24 hours.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the hearing, the parents have the right to be present, to present testimony, to call and cross-examine witnesses, to be represented by counsel at their own expense, and to object to the appointment of the guardian advocate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The hearing shall be conducted by the judge without a jury, applying the rules of evidence in use in civil cases. In a hearing on a petition for appointment of a guardian advocate, the moving party shall prove all the elements in s. 39.828 by a preponderance of the evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The hearing under this section shall remain confidential and closed to the public. The clerk shall keep all court records required by this part separate from other records of the circuit court. All court records required by this part shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). All records shall be inspected only upon order of the court by persons deemed by the court to have a proper interest therein, except that a child and the parents or custodians of the child and their attorneys and the department and its designees shall always have the right to inspect and copy any official record pertaining to the child. The court may permit authorized representatives of recognized organizations compiling statistics for proper purposes to inspect and make abstracts from official records, under whatever conditions upon their use and disposition the court may deem proper, and may punish by contempt proceedings any violation of those conditions. All information obtained pursuant to this part in the discharge of official duty by any judge, employee of the court, or authorized agent of the department shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and shall not be disclosed to anyone other than the authorized personnel of the court or the department and its designees, except upon order of the court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 89-345; s. 19, ch. 91-71; s. 274, ch. 96-406; s. 44, ch. 98-280; s. 108, ch. 98-403.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 415.5086.</Text></Note></Section>