<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0039.0134" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointed counsel; compensation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If counsel is entitled to receive compensation for representation pursuant to a court appointment in a dependency proceeding or a termination of parental rights proceeding pursuant to this chapter, compensation shall be paid in accordance with s. 27.5304. The state may acquire and enforce a lien upon court-ordered payment of attorney’s fees and costs in the same manner prescribed in s. 938.29.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent whose child is dependent, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or whose parental rights are terminated and who has received the assistance of the office of criminal conflict and civil regional counsel, or any other court-appointed attorney, or who has received due process services after being found indigent for costs, shall be liable for payment of the assessed application fee under s. 57.082, together with reasonable attorney’s fees and costs as determined by the court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If reasonable attorney’s fees or costs are assessed, the court, at its discretion, may make payment of the fees or costs part of any case plan in dependency proceedings. However, a case plan may not remain open for the sole issue of payment of attorney’s fees or costs. At the court’s discretion, a lien upon court-ordered payment of attorney’s fees and costs may be ordered by the court and enforced in the same manner prescribed in s. 938.29.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the court shall transfer monthly all attorney’s fees and costs collected under this subsection to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Indigent Civil Defense Trust Fund, to be used as appropriated by the Legislature and consistent with s. 27.511.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 84-311; s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 28, ch. 98-403; s. 9, ch. 99-193; s. 57, ch. 2003-402; s. 36, ch. 2004-265; s. 19, ch. 2010-162.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 39.415, 39.474.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>