<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0039.905" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Domestic violence centers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Domestic violence centers certified under this part must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a facility which will serve as a center to receive and house persons who are victims of domestic violence. For the purpose of this part, minor children and other dependents of a victim, when such dependents are partly or wholly dependent on the victim for support or services, may be sheltered with the victim in a domestic violence center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive the annual written endorsement of local law enforcement agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide minimum services that include, but are not limited to, information and referral services, counseling and case management services, temporary emergency shelter for more than 24 hours, a 24-hour hotline, training for law enforcement personnel, assessment and appropriate referral of resident children, and educational services for community awareness relative to the incidence of domestic violence, the prevention of such violence, and the services available for persons engaged in or subject to domestic violence. If a 24-hour hotline, professional training, or community education is already provided by a certified domestic violence center within its designated service area, the department may exempt such certification requirements for a new center serving the same service area in order to avoid duplication of services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in the provision of orientation and training programs developed for law enforcement officers, social workers, and other professionals and paraprofessionals who work with domestic violence victims to better enable such persons to deal effectively with incidents of domestic violence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain a board of directors composed of at least three citizens, one of whom must be a member of a local, municipal, or county law enforcement agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with rules adopted pursuant to this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File with the coalition a list of the names of the domestic violence advocates who are employed or who volunteer at the domestic violence center who may claim a privilege under s. 90.5036 to refuse to disclose a confidential communication between a victim of domestic violence and the advocate regarding the domestic violence inflicted upon the victim. The list must include the title of the position held by the advocate whose name is listed and a description of the duties of that position. A domestic violence center must file amendments to this list as necessary.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate local need and ability to sustain operations through a history of 18 consecutive months’ operation as a domestic violence center, including 12 months’ operation of an emergency shelter as provided in paragraph (c), and a business plan which addresses future operations and funding of future operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its center is a new center applying for certification, demonstrate that the services provided address a need identified in the most current statewide needs assessment approved by the department. If the center applying for initial certification proposes providing services in an area that has an existing certified domestic violence center, the center applying for initial certification must demonstrate the unmet need in that service area and describe its efforts to avoid duplication of services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that there is failure by a center to comply with the requirements established under this part or with the rules adopted pursuant thereto, the department may deny, suspend, or revoke the certification of the center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual certificate automatically expires on June 30 of each state fiscal year unless the certification is temporarily extended to allow the center to implement a corrective action plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domestic violence centers shall establish procedures pursuant to which persons subject to domestic violence may seek services from these centers voluntarily.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Domestic violence centers may be established throughout the state when private, local, state, or federal funds are available and a need is demonstrated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to receive state funds, a center must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain certification pursuant to this part. However, the issuance of a certificate does not obligate the coalition to provide funding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive at least 25 percent of its funding from one or more local, municipal, or county sources, public or private. Contributions in kind, whether materials, commodities, transportation, office space, other types of facilities, or personal services, may be evaluated and counted as part of the required local funding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds collected and appropriated to the domestic violence program for certified domestic violence centers shall be distributed annually according to an allocation formula approved by the department. In developing the formula, the factors of population, rural characteristics, geographical area, and the incidence of domestic violence shall be considered.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between the coalition and a certified domestic violence center shall contain provisions ensuring the availability and geographic accessibility of services throughout the service area. For this purpose, a center may distribute funds through subcontracts or to center satellites, if such arrangements and any subcontracts are approved by the coalition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the required services are exempted from certification by the department under this section, the center may not receive funding from the coalition for those services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-281; s. 4, ch. 79-402; s. 2, ch. 82-135; s. 4, ch. 82-192; s. 3, ch. 84-128; s. 5, ch. 84-343; s. 32, ch. 94-134; s. 32, ch. 94-135; ss. 3, 8, ch. 95-187; s. 117, ch. 98-403; s. 2, ch. 2003-11; s. 5, ch. 2012-147.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 409.605; s. 415.605.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>