<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.6231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permanent placement with a fit and willing relative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a court finds that reunification or adoption are not in the best interests of a child, the court may place the child with a fit and willing relative as a permanency option if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child has been in the placement for at least the preceding 6 months;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The relative has made a commitment to provide for the child until the child reaches the age of majority and to prepare the child for adulthood and independence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The relative is suitable and able to provide a safe and permanent home for the child; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The relative agrees to give notice of any change in his or her residence or the residence of the child by filing a written document with the clerk of court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the guardian ad litem shall provide the court with a recommended list and description of services needed by the child and the family in order to ensure the permanency of the placement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In its written order placing the child with a fit and willing relative, the court shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">List the circumstances or reasons why reunification is not possible by referring to specific findings of fact made in its order adjudicating the child dependent or by making separate findings of fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State the reasons why permanent placement with a fit and willing relative is being established instead of adoption;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the frequency and nature of visitation or contact between the child and his or her parents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the frequency and nature of visitation or contact between the child and his or her grandparents, under s. 39.509;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the frequency and nature of visitation or contact between the child and his or her siblings; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that the relative not return the child to the physical care and custody of the person from whom the child was removed without the approval of the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall give the relative a separate order establishing his or her authority to care for the child and providing other information the court deems proper which can be provided to entities and individuals who are not parties to the proceeding as necessary, notwithstanding the confidentiality of s. 39.202.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall continue to supervise the placement with the relative until further court order. The court shall continue to review the placement at least once every 6 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each party to the proceeding must be advised by the department and the court that placement with a fit and willing relative does not preclude the possibility of the child returning to the custody of the parent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall continue to conduct permanency hearings in order to reevaluate the possibility of adoption or permanent guardianship of the child.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2006-86.</History></Section>