<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.808" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advisory hearing; pretrial status conference.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advisory hearing on the petition to terminate parental rights must be held as soon as possible after all parties have been served with a copy of the petition and a notice of the date, time, and place of the advisory hearing for the petition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the hearing the court shall inform the parties of their rights under s. 39.807, shall appoint counsel for the parties in accordance with legal requirements, and shall appoint a guardian ad litem to represent the interests of the child if one has not already been appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall set a date for an adjudicatory hearing to be held within 45 days after the advisory hearing, unless all of the necessary parties agree to some other hearing date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advisory hearing is not required if a petition is filed seeking an adjudication for termination of parental rights based on a voluntary surrender of parental rights. Adjudicatory hearings for petitions for voluntary termination must be held within 21 days after the filing of the petition. Notice of the use of this subsection must be filed with the court at the same time as the filing of the petition to terminate parental rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 10 days before the adjudicatory hearing on a petition for involuntary termination of parental rights, the court shall conduct a pretrial status conference to determine the order in which each party may present witnesses or evidence, the order in which cross-examination and argument shall occur, and any other matters that may aid in the conduct of the adjudicatory hearing to prevent any undue delay in the conduct of the adjudicatory hearing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 87-289; s. 33, ch. 88-337; s. 18, ch. 90-306; s. 37, ch. 94-164; s. 90, ch. 98-403; s. 47, ch. 99-193.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.466.</Text></Note></Section>