<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.3035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Child advocacy centers; standards; state funding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to become eligible for a full membership in the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., a child advocacy center in this state shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a private, nonprofit incorporated agency or a governmental entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a child protection team, or by written agreement incorporate the participation and services of a child protection team, with established community protocols which meet all of the requirements of the National Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a neutral, child-focused facility where joint department and law enforcement interviews take place with children in appropriate cases of suspected child sexual abuse or physical abuse. All multidisciplinary agencies shall have a place to interact with the child as investigative or treatment needs require.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a minimum designated staff that is supervised and approved by the local board of directors or governmental entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a multidisciplinary case review team that meets on a regularly scheduled basis or as the caseload of the community requires. The team shall consist of representatives from the Office of the State Attorney, the department, the child protection team, mental health services, law enforcement, and the child advocacy center staff. Medical personnel and a victim’s advocate may be part of the team.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide case tracking of child abuse cases seen through the center. A center shall also collect data on the number of child abuse cases seen at the center, by sex, race, age, and other relevant data; the number of cases referred for prosecution; and the number of cases referred for mental health therapy. Case records shall be subject to the confidentiality provisions of s. 39.202.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide referrals for medical exams and mental health therapy. The center shall provide followup on cases referred for mental health therapy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide training for various disciplines in the community that deal with child abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have an interagency commitment, in writing, covering those aspects of agency participation in a multidisciplinary approach to the handling of child sexual abuse and serious physical abuse cases.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide assurance that child advocacy center employees and volunteers at the center are trained and screened in accordance with s. 39.001(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child advocacy center within this state may not receive the funds generated pursuant to s. 938.10, state or federal funds administered by a state agency, or any other funds appropriated by the Legislature unless all of the standards of subsection (1) are met and the screening requirement of subsection (2) is met. The Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., shall be responsible for tracking and documenting compliance with subsections (1) and (2) for any of the funds it administers to member child advocacy centers.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds for the specific purpose of funding children’s advocacy centers shall be appropriated to the Department of Children and Family Services from funds collected from the additional court cost imposed in cases of certain crimes against minors under s. 938.10. Funds shall be disbursed to the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., as established under this section, for the purpose of providing community-based services that augment, but do not duplicate, services provided by state agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., shall retain 10 percent of all revenues collected to be used to match local contributions, at a rate not to exceed an equal match, in communities establishing children’s advocacy centers. The board of directors may use up to 5 percent of the remaining funds to support the activities of the network office and must develop funding criteria and an allocation methodology that ensures an equitable distribution of remaining funds among network participants. The criteria and methodologies must take into account factors that include, but need not be limited to, the center’s accreditation status with respect to the National Children’s Alliance, the number of clients served, and the population of the area being served by the children’s advocacy center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the end of each fiscal year, each children’s advocacy center receiving revenue as provided in this section must provide a report to the board of directors of the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., which reflects center expenditures, all sources of revenue received, and outputs that have been standardized and agreed upon by network members and the board of directors, such as the number of clients served, client demographic information, and number and types of services provided. The Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., must compile reports from the centers and provide a report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives in August of each year beginning in 2005.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 98-403; s. 16, ch. 99-193; s. 37, ch. 2004-265; s. 6, ch. 2006-1; s. 5, ch. 2008-16.</History></Section>