<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0039.402" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Placement in a shelter.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless ordered by the court under this chapter, a child taken into custody shall not be placed in a shelter prior to a court hearing unless there is probable cause to believe that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child has been abused, neglected, or abandoned, or is suffering from or is in imminent danger of illness or injury as a result of abuse, neglect, or abandonment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent or legal custodian of the child has materially violated a condition of placement imposed by the court; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child has no parent, legal custodian, or responsible adult relative immediately known and available to provide supervision and care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child taken into custody may be placed or continued in a shelter only if one or more of the criteria in subsection (1) applies and the court has made a specific finding of fact regarding the necessity for removal of the child from the home and has made a determination that the provision of appropriate and available services will not eliminate the need for placement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a child is taken into custody, the department shall immediately notify the parents or legal custodians, shall provide the parents or legal custodians with a statement setting forth a summary of procedures involved in dependency cases, and shall notify them of their right to obtain their own attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines that placement in a shelter is necessary under subsections (1) and (2), the authorized agent of the department shall authorize placement of the child in a shelter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents or legal custodians of the child shall be given such notice as best ensures their actual knowledge of the date, time, and location of the shelter hearing. If the parents or legal custodians are outside the jurisdiction of the court, are not known, or cannot be located or refuse or evade service, they shall be given such notice as best ensures their actual knowledge of the date, time, and location of the shelter hearing. The person providing or attempting to provide notice to the parents or legal custodians shall, if the parents or legal custodians are not present at the hearing, advise the court either in person or by sworn affidavit, of the attempts made to provide notice and the results of those attempts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents or legal custodians shall be given written notice that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They will be given an opportunity to be heard and to present evidence at the shelter hearing; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They have the right to be represented by counsel, and, if indigent, the parents have the right to be represented by appointed counsel, at the shelter hearing and at each subsequent hearing or proceeding, pursuant to the procedures set forth in s. 39.013. If the parents or legal custodians appear for the shelter hearing without legal counsel, then, at their request, the shelter hearing may be continued up to 72 hours to enable the parents or legal custodians to consult legal counsel. If a continuance is requested by the parents or legal custodians, the child shall be continued in shelter care for the length of the continuance, if granted by the court.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court, or the county court if previously designated by the chief judge of the circuit court for such purpose, shall hold the shelter hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shelter petition filed with the court must address each condition required to be determined by the court in paragraphs (8)(a), (b), (d), and (h).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may not be removed from the home or continued out of the home pending disposition if, with the provision of appropriate and available early intervention or preventive services, including services provided in the home, the child could safely remain at home. If the child’s safety and well-being are in danger, the child shall be removed from danger and continue to be removed until the danger has passed. If the child has been removed from the home and the reasons for his or her removal have been remedied, the child may be returned to the home. If the court finds that the prevention or reunification efforts of the department will allow the child to remain safely at home, the court shall allow the child to remain in the home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may not be held in a shelter longer than 24 hours unless an order so directing is entered by the court after a shelter hearing. In the interval until the shelter hearing is held, the decision to place the child in a shelter or release the child from a shelter lies with the protective investigator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents or legal custodians of the child shall be given such notice as best ensures their actual knowledge of the time and place of the shelter hearing. The failure to provide notice to a party or participant does not invalidate an order placing a child in a shelter if the court finds that the petitioner has made a good faith effort to provide such notice. The court shall require the parents or legal custodians present at the hearing to provide to the court on the record the names, addresses, and relationships of all parents, prospective parents, and next of kin of the child, so far as are known.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, the court shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a guardian ad litem to represent the best interest of the child, unless the court finds that such representation is unnecessary;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform the parents or legal custodians of their right to counsel to represent them at the shelter hearing and at each subsequent hearing or proceeding, and the right of the parents to appointed counsel, pursuant to the procedures set forth in s. 39.013; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give the parents or legal custodians an opportunity to be heard and to present evidence.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, in order to continue the child in shelter care:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must establish probable cause that reasonable grounds for removal exist and that the provision of appropriate and available services will not eliminate the need for placement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court must determine that additional time is necessary, which may not exceed 72 hours, in which to obtain and review documents pertaining to the family in order to appropriately determine the risk to the child during which time the child shall remain in the department’s custody, if so ordered by the court.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, the department shall provide the court copies of any available law enforcement, medical, or other professional reports, and shall also provide copies of abuse hotline reports pursuant to state and federal confidentiality requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, the department shall inform the court of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any identified current or previous case plans negotiated in any district with the parents or caregivers under this chapter and problems associated with compliance;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any adjudication of the parents or caregivers of delinquency;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any past or current injunction for protection from domestic violence; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the child’s places of residence during the prior 12 months.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, each party shall provide to the court a permanent mailing address. The court shall advise each party that this address will be used by the court and the petitioner for notice purposes unless and until the party notifies the court and the petitioner in writing of a new mailing address.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order for placement of a child in shelter care must identify the parties present at the hearing and must contain written findings:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That placement in shelter care is necessary based on the criteria in subsections (1) and (2).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That placement in shelter care is in the best interest of the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That continuation of the child in the home is contrary to the welfare of the child because the home situation presents a substantial and immediate danger to the child’s physical, mental, or emotional health or safety which cannot be mitigated by the provision of preventive services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That based upon the allegations of the petition for placement in shelter care, there is probable cause to believe that the child is dependent or that the court needs additional time, which may not exceed 72 hours, in which to obtain and review documents pertaining to the family in order to appropriately determine the risk to the child.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the department has made reasonable efforts to prevent or eliminate the need for removal of the child from the home. A finding of reasonable effort by the department to prevent or eliminate the need for removal may be made and the department is deemed to have made reasonable efforts to prevent or eliminate the need for removal if:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first contact of the department with the family occurs during an emergency;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appraisal of the home situation by the department indicates that the home situation presents a substantial and immediate danger to the child’s physical, mental, or emotional health or safety which cannot be mitigated by the provision of preventive services;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child cannot safely remain at home, either because there are no preventive services that can ensure the health and safety of the child or because, even with appropriate and available services being provided, the health and safety of the child cannot be ensured; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent or legal custodian is alleged to have committed any of the acts listed as grounds for expedited termination of parental rights in s. 39.806(1)(f)-(i).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the court notified the parents, relatives that are providing out-of-home care for the child, or legal custodians of the time, date, and location of the next dependency hearing and of the importance of the active participation of the parents, relatives that are providing out-of-home care for the child, or legal custodians in all proceedings and hearings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the court notified the parents or legal custodians of their right to counsel to represent them at the shelter hearing and at each subsequent hearing or proceeding, and the right of the parents to appointed counsel, pursuant to the procedures set forth in s. 39.013.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the court notified relatives who are providing out-of-home care for a child as a result of the shelter petition being granted that they have the right to attend all subsequent hearings, to submit reports to the court, and to speak to the court regarding the child, if they so desire.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any shelter hearing, the department shall provide to the court a recommendation for scheduled contact between the child and parents, if appropriate. The court shall determine visitation rights absent a clear and convincing showing that visitation is not in the best interest of the child. Any order for visitation or other contact must conform to the provisions of s. 39.0139. If visitation is ordered but will not commence within 72 hours of the shelter hearing, the department shall provide justification to the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shelter hearing order shall contain a written determination as to whether the department has made a reasonable effort to prevent or eliminate the need for removal or continued removal of the child from the home. This determination must include a description of which specific services, if available, could prevent or eliminate the need for removal or continued removal from the home and the date by which the services are expected to become available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If services are not available to prevent or eliminate the need for removal or continued removal of the child from the home, the written determination must also contain an explanation describing why the services are not available for the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department has not made an effort to prevent or eliminate the need for removal, the court shall order the department to provide appropriate and available services to ensure the protection of the child in the home when the services are necessary for the child’s health and safety.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a child is placed in a shelter pursuant to a court order following a shelter hearing, the court shall require in the shelter hearing order that the parents of the child, or the guardian of the child’s estate, if possessed of assets which under law may be disbursed for the care, support, and maintenance of the child, to pay, to the department or institution having custody of the child, fees as established by the department. When the order affects the guardianship estate, a certified copy of the order shall be delivered to the judge having jurisdiction of the guardianship estate. The shelter order shall also require the parents to provide to the department and any other state agency or party designated by the court, within 28 days after entry of the shelter order, the financial information necessary to accurately calculate child support pursuant to s. 61.30.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall request that the parents consent to provide access to the child’s medical records and provide information to the court, the department or its contract agencies, and any guardian ad litem or attorney for the child. If a parent is unavailable or unable to consent or withholds consent and the court determines access to the records and information is necessary to provide services to the child, the court shall issue an order granting access. The court may also order the parents to provide all known medical information to the department and to any others granted access under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall request that the parents consent to provide access to the child’s educational records and provide information to the court, the department or its contract agencies, and any guardian ad litem or attorney for the child. If a parent is unavailable or unable to consent or withholds consent and the court determines access to the records and information is necessary to provide services to the child, the court shall issue an order granting access.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may appoint a surrogate parent or may refer the child to the district school superintendent for appointment of a surrogate parent if the child has or is suspected of having a disability and the parent is unavailable pursuant to s. 39.0016(3)(b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the shelter hearing is conducted by a judge other than the juvenile court judge, the juvenile court judge shall hold a shelter review on the status of the child within 2 working days after the shelter hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may not be held in a shelter under an order so directing for more than 60 days without an adjudication of dependency. A child may not be held in a shelter for more than 30 days after the entry of an order of adjudication unless an order of disposition has been entered by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limitations in this section do not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Periods of delay resulting from a continuance granted at the request or with the consent of the child’s counsel or the child’s guardian ad litem, if one has been appointed by the court, or, if the child is of sufficient capacity to express reasonable consent, at the request or with the consent of the child’s attorney or the child’s guardian ad litem, if one has been appointed by the court, and the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Periods of delay resulting from a continuance granted at the request of any party, if the continuance is granted:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because of an unavailability of evidence material to the case when the requesting party has exercised due diligence to obtain such evidence and there are substantial grounds to believe that such evidence will be available within 30 days. However, if the requesting party is not prepared to proceed within 30 days, any other party, inclusive of the parent or legal custodian, may move for issuance of an order to show cause or the court on its own motion may impose appropriate sanctions, which may include dismissal of the petition.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To allow the requesting party additional time to prepare the case and additional time is justified because of an exceptional circumstance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable periods of delay necessary to accomplish notice of the hearing to the child’s parents or legal custodians; however, the petitioner shall continue regular efforts to provide notice to the parents or legal custodians during such periods of delay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable periods of delay resulting from a continuance granted at the request of the parent or legal custodian of a subject child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the foregoing, continuances and extensions of time are limited to the number of days absolutely necessary to complete a necessary task in order to preserve the rights of a party or the best interests of a child. Time is of the essence for the best interests of dependent children in conducting dependency proceedings in accordance with the time limitations set forth in this chapter. Time limitations are a right of the child which may not be waived, extended, or continued at the request of any party in advance of the particular circumstances or need arising upon which delay of the proceedings may be warranted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continuances or extensions of time may not total more than 60 days for all parties within any 12-month period during proceedings under this chapter. A continuance or extension beyond the 60 days may be granted only for extraordinary circumstances necessary to preserve the constitutional rights of a party or when substantial evidence demonstrates that the child’s best interests will be affirmatively harmed without the granting of a continuance or extension of time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, at the conclusion of the shelter hearing, shall make available to parents or legal custodians seeking voluntary services, any referral information necessary for participation in such identified services. The parents’ or legal custodians’ participation in the services shall not be considered an admission or other acknowledgment of the allegations in the shelter petition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of a shelter hearing, the court shall notify all parties in writing of the next scheduled hearing to review the shelter placement. The hearing shall be held no later than 30 days after placement of the child in shelter status, in conjunction with the arraignment hearing, and at such times as are otherwise provided by law or determined by the court to be necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the shelter hearing, the court shall inquire of the parent whether the parent has relatives who might be considered as a placement for the child. The parent shall provide to the court and all parties identification and location information regarding the relatives. The court shall advise the parent that the parent has a continuing duty to inform the department of any relative who should be considered for placement of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall advise the parents that, if the parents fail to substantially comply with the case plan, their parental rights may be terminated and that the child’s out-of-home placement may become permanent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 78-414; s. 13, ch. 80-290; s. 6, ch. 84-311; s. 5, ch. 85-80; s. 82, ch. 86-220; s. 5, ch. 87-133; s. 5, ch. 87-289; s. 12, ch. 88-337; s. 1, ch. 90-167; s. 7, ch. 90-208; s. 5, ch. 90-306; s. 3, ch. 92-158; s. 3, ch. 92-170; s. 7, ch. 92-287; s. 4, ch. 94-164; s. 58, ch. 94-209; s. 7, ch. 95-228; s. 3, ch. 97-96; s. 3, ch. 97-276; s. 58, ch. 98-403; s. 12, ch. 99-168; s. 23, ch. 99-193; s. 19, ch. 2000-139; s. 6, ch. 2000-151; s. 7, ch. 2000-217; s. 2, ch. 2001-68; s. 2, ch. 2002-216; s. 1, ch. 2005-65; s. 10, ch. 2006-86; s. 2, ch. 2007-109; s. 3, ch. 2009-35; s. 7, ch. 2009-43.</History></Section>