<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Change of interest and address.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner shall furnish the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles notice of the transfer of all or any part of his or her interest in a vessel registered or titled in this state pursuant to this chapter or of the destruction or abandonment of such vessel, within 30 days thereof, on a form prescribed by the department. Such transfer, destruction, or abandonment shall terminate the certificate for such vessel, except that in the case of a transfer of a part interest which does not affect the owner’s right to operate such vessel, such transfer shall not terminate the certificate. The department shall provide the form for such notice and shall attach the form to every vessel title issued or reissued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder of a certificate of registration shall notify the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or the county tax collector within 30 days, if his or her address no longer conforms to the address appearing on the certificate and shall, as a part of such notification, furnish the department or such county tax collector with the new address. The department shall provide in its rules and regulations for the surrender of the certificate bearing the former address and its replacement with a certificate bearing the new address or for the alteration of an outstanding certificate to show the new address of the holder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-399; s. 1, ch. 65-361; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 74-327; s. 6, ch. 84-184; s. 453, ch. 95-148; s. 53, ch. 95-333; s. 19, ch. 99-289; s. 4, ch. 2006-309; s. 46, ch. 2007-5.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.101; s. 327.19.</Text></Note></Section>