<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemption of vessels and outboard motors from personal property tax; temporary certificate of registration; vessel registration certificate fee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every vessel registered as provided herein, and outboard motor capable of propelling any such vessel, shall be exempt from any personal property tax and in lieu thereof shall pay a vessel registration certificate fee. A certificate of registration shall be issued for any documented vessel, the owner of which has paid the registration certificate fee, but no state registration number shall be issued to such vessel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary certificate of registration may be issued to a vessel for use in the following cases:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner has made application to the United States Coast Guard for documentation and has paid the applicable registration certificate fee pursuant to s. 328.72(1). A temporary certificate of registration shall only be issued upon proof that all applicable state sales taxes have been paid and that the application for documentation is on file with the United States Coast Guard. Any reregistration of such a vessel without the submission of the vessel’s documentation papers shall require written verification from the United States Coast Guard as to the current status of the application for the vessel’s documentation. Upon receipt of the vessel’s documentation papers, the owner shall bring them to the agent issuing the temporary certificate for official recording of information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An out-of-state resident, subject to registration in this state, who must secure ownership documentation from the home state, and is unable to submit an out-of-state title because it is being held by an out-of-state lienholder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 8, ch. 74-327; s. 25, ch. 79-334; s. 77, ch. 82-226; s. 7, ch. 84-184; s. 2, ch. 85-252; s. 59, ch. 96-413; s. 54, ch. 99-248; s. 23, ch. 99-289.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.64; s. 327.23.</Text></Note></Section>