<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vessel registration number.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each vessel that is operated, used, or stored on the waters of this state must display a commercial or recreational Florida registration number, unless it is:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel operated, used, and stored exclusively on private lakes and ponds;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel owned by the United States Government;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel used exclusively as a ship’s lifeboat;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A non-motor-powered vessel less than 16 feet in length or a non-motor-powered canoe, kayak, racing shell, or rowing scull, regardless of length;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federally documented vessel;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel already covered by a registration number in full force and effect which has been awarded to it pursuant to a federally approved numbering system of another state or by the United States Coast Guard in a state without a federally approved numbering system, if the vessel has not been within this state for a period in excess of 90 consecutive days;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel operating under a valid temporary certificate of number;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vessel from a country other than the United States temporarily using the waters of this state; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An undocumented vessel used exclusively for racing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-399; ss. 2, 3, ch. 61-511; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 52, ch. 95-333; s. 56, ch. 96-413; s. 15, ch. 99-289; s. 27, ch. 2000-362; s. 3, ch. 2008-106; s. 24, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.131; s. 327.15.</Text></Note></Section>