<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duplicate certificate of title.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may issue a duplicate certificate of title upon application by the person entitled to hold such a certificate if the department is satisfied that the original certificate has been lost, destroyed, or mutilated. The department shall charge a fee of $6 for issuing a duplicate certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the fee imposed by subsection (1), the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall charge a fee of $5 for expedited service in issuing a duplicate certificate of title. Application for such expedited service may be made by mail or in person. The department shall issue each certificate of title applied for under this subsection within 5 working days after receipt of a proper application or shall refund the additional $5 fee upon written request by the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, following the issuance of an original, duplicate, or corrected certificate of title by the department, the certificate is lost in transit and is not delivered to the addressee, the owner of the vessel or the holder of a lien thereon may, within 180 days after the date of issuance of the title, apply to the department for reissuance of the certificate of title. An additional fee may not be charged for reissuance under this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall implement a system to verify that the application is signed by a person authorized to receive a duplicate title certificate under this section if the address shown on the application is different from the address shown for the applicant on the records of the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 67-586; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 13, ch. 74-327; s. 14, ch. 84-184; s. 2, ch. 87-291; s. 59, ch. 95-333; s. 63, ch. 96-413; s. 59, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.79.</Text></Note></Section>