<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance in duplicate; delivery; liens and encumbrances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall assign a number to each certificate of title and shall issue each certificate of title and each corrected certificate in duplicate. The database record shall serve as the duplicate title certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorized person must sign the original certificate of title and each corrected certificate and, if there are no liens or encumbrances on the vessel, as shown in the records of the department or as shown in the application, must deliver the certificate to the applicant or to another person as directed by the applicant or person, agent, or attorney submitting the application. If there are one or more liens or encumbrances on the vessel, the department must deliver the certificate to the first lienholder as shown by department records. The department shall deliver to the first lienholder, along with the certificate, a form to be subsequently used by the lienholder as a satisfaction. If the application for certificate of title shows the name of a first lienholder which is different from the name of the first lienholder as shown by the records of the department, the certificate shall not be issued to any person until after the department notifies all parties who appear to hold a lien and the applicant for the certificate, in writing by certified mail. If the parties do not amicably resolve the conflict within 10 days after the date the notice was mailed, the department shall serve notice in writing by certified mail on all persons that appear to hold liens on that particular vessel, including the applicant for the certificate, to show cause within 15 days after the date the notice is mailed why it should not issue and deliver the certificate to the person indicated in the notice of lien filed by the lienholder whose name appears in the application as the first lienholder without showing any lien or liens as outstanding other than those appearing in the application or those filed subsequent to the filing of the application for the certificate of title. If, within the 15-day period, any person other than the lienholder shown in the application or a party filing a subsequent lien, in answer to the notice to show cause, appears in person or by a representative, or responds in writing, and files a written statement under oath that his or her lien on that particular vessel is still outstanding, the department shall not issue the certificate to anyone until after the conflict has been settled by the lien claimants involved or by a court of competent jurisdiction. If the conflict is not settled amicably within 10 days after the final date for filing an answer to the notice to show cause, the complaining party shall have 10 days to obtain a ruling, or a stay order, from a court of competent jurisdiction. If a ruling or stay order is not issued and served on the department within the 10-day period, the department shall issue the certificate showing no liens, except those shown in the application or thereafter filed, to the original applicant if there are no liens shown in the application and none are thereafter filed, or to the person indicated in the notice of lien filed by the lienholder whose name appears in the application as the first lienholder if there are liens shown in the application or thereafter filed. A duplicate certificate or corrected certificate must show only such lien or liens as were shown in the application and subsequently filed liens that may be outstanding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 328.15(11), the certificate of title shall be retained by the first lienholder. The first lienholder is entitled to retain the certificate until the first lien is satisfied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any requirements in this section or in s. 328.15 indicating that a lien on a vessel shall be noted on the face of the Florida certificate of title, if there are one or more liens or encumbrances on a vessel, the department shall electronically transmit the lien to the first lienholder and notify the first lienholder of any additional liens. Subsequent lien satisfactions shall be electronically transmitted to the department and must include the name and address of the person or entity satisfying the lien. When electronic transmission of liens and lien satisfactions are used, the issuance of a certificate of title may be waived until the last lien is satisfied and a clear certificate of title is issued to the owner of the vessel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a vessel, upon which a lien has been filed with the department or noted upon a certificate of title for a period of 5 years, may apply to the department in writing for such lien to be removed from the department files or from the certificate of title. The application must be accompanied by evidence satisfactory to the department that the applicant has notified the lienholder by certified mail, not less than 20 days prior to the date of the application, of his or her intention to apply to the department for removal of the lien. Ten days after receipt of the application, the department may remove the lien from its files or from the certificate of title, as the case may be, if no statement in writing protesting removal of the lien is received by the department from the lienholder within the 10-day period. However, if the lienholder files with the department, within the 10-day period, a written statement that the lien is still outstanding, the department may not remove the lien until the lienholder presents a satisfaction of lien to the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 66, ch. 96-413; s. 42, ch. 97-300; s. 61, ch. 99-248; s. 72, ch. 2001-61; s. 68, ch. 2012-181.</History></Section>