<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special manufacturers’ and dealers’ number.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of a vessel used for demonstration, sales promotional, or testing purposes by a manufacturer or dealer shall be omitted from the certificate of registration. In lieu of the description, the word “manufacturer” or “dealer,” as appropriate, shall be plainly marked on the certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer or dealer shall have the number awarded printed upon or attached to a removable sign or signs to be temporarily but firmly mounted upon or attached to the vessel being demonstrated, promoted, or tested so long as the display meets the requirements of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer registration shall not be issued to a manufacturer or a dealer pursuant to this chapter unless he or she provides to the county tax collector a copy of his or her current sales tax certificate of registration, if such certificate is required, from the Department of Revenue and a copy of his or her current commercial or occupational business license if such license is required by the local governmental entity in which the manufacturer or dealer operates a vessel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manufacturer or dealer shall not use or authorize the use of any vessel registered pursuant to this section for other than demonstration, sales promotional, or testing purposes. Such vessel shall not be used for any commercial or other use not specifically authorized by this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-399; s. 1, ch. 65-361; s. 6, ch. 84-184; s. 451, ch. 95-148; s. 13, ch. 99-289.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 371.071; s. 327.13.</Text></Note></Section>