<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0328.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration; duties of tax collectors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax collectors in the counties of the state, as authorized agents of the department, shall issue registration certificates and vessel numbers and decals to applicants, subject to the requirements of law and in accordance with rules of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each tax collector shall keep a full and complete record and account of all vessel decals or other properties received by him or her from the department or from any other source and shall make prompt remittance of moneys collected by him or her at the times and in the manner prescribed by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fee of 50 cents shall be charged in addition to the fees required under s. 328.72 on every vessel decal registration sold to cover the cost of the Florida Real Time Vehicle Information System. The fees collected under this section shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and shall be used to fund that system and may be used to fund the general operations of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding chapter 116, every county officer within this state authorized to collect funds provided for in this chapter shall pay all sums officially received by the officer into the State Treasury no later than 5 working days after the close of the business day in which the officer received the funds. Payment by county officers to the state shall be made by means of electronic funds transfer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 99-248; s. 51, ch. 2000-152; s. 43, ch. 2000-313; s. 16, ch. 2002-235.</History></Section>