<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0531.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit for commercially operated or tested weights or measures instrument or devices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A weights and measures instrument or device may not operate or be used for commercial purposes, as defined by department rule, within this state without a valid commercial use permit issued by the department, unless exempted as provided in s. 531.61. Such permit applies only to the specific instrument or device for which the permit was issued. However, the department may allow such permit to be applicable to a replacement for the original instrument or device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If ownership of an instrument or device for which a permit has been issued changes and the instrument or device:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remains in the same location, the permit transfers to the new owner and remains in effect until its original expiration date. Within 30 days after the change in ownership, the new owner shall notify the department of the change and provide the pertinent information regarding the change in ownership and an updated replacement permit shall be issued if needed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moves to a new location, the permit automatically expires and a new permit must be issued which will expire 1 year following the date of issuance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weights and measures instruments or devices that are not used commercially may be tested by the department under this chapter only if they are permitted and appropriate fees paid as prescribed by this section and adopted rules.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 33, 40, ch. 2009-66.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed July 1, 2014, by s. 40, ch. 2009-66.</Text></Note></Section>