<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0531.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special police powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to the enforcement of this chapter and rules pursuant thereto, the department is:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Empowered to seize, for use as evidence, without formal warrant, any incorrect or unapproved weight, measure, package, or commodity found to be used, retained, offered, or exposed for sale, or sold in violation of the provisions of this chapter or rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized to enter any commercial premises during normal business hours for the purpose of performing its duties.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that such premises, or part thereof, are not open to the public, the representative of the department shall first present his or her credentials before seeking entry thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person refusing authorized entry is in violation of this chapter and shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083. Such fine shall not be construed to be an elected alternative negating the authority to enter the establishment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that such entry is denied, the representative of the department may apply for a search warrant from any person authorized to issue the same.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On probable cause of violation of this chapter, empowered to stop any commercial vehicle, and the representative of the department may, after presentment of his or her credentials, inspect the contents, require that the person in charge of that vehicle produce any documents in that person’s possession concerning the contents, and require him or her to proceed with the vehicle to some specified place for inspection. Any person refusing such inspection or failing to comply with any proper instructions is in violation of this chapter and shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083. Such fine shall not be construed to be an elected alternative negating the authority to stop the vehicle, inspect the contents, or order that it be taken to a specified place.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Empowered to issue stop-use, hold, and removal orders with respect to any weights and measures commercially used, and stop-sale, hold, and removal orders with respect to any packaged commodities or bulk commodities kept or offered or exposed for sale.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 1A, ch. 72-101; s. 729, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>