<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0531.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Weights and measures” means all weights and measures of every kind, instruments, and devices for weighing and measuring, and any appliance and accessories associated with any or all such instruments and devices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Weight” in connection with any commodity means net weight.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Correct” in connection with weights and measures means conformance to all applicable requirements of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Primary standards” means the physical standards of the state which serve as the legal reference from which all other standards, weights, and measures are derived.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secondary standards” means the physical standards which are traceable to the primary standards through comparisons, using acceptable laboratory procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” includes both plural and singular, as the case demands, and includes individuals, partnerships, corporations, companies, societies, and associations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sale from bulk” means the sale of commodities when the quantity is determined at the time of sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Package” means any container or wrapping in which any commodity is enclosed for use in the delivery or display of that commodity to purchasers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-101.</History></Section>