<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4655" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Involuntary outpatient placement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CRITERIA FOR INVOLUNTARY OUTPATIENT PLACEMENT.<EmDash />A person may be ordered to involuntary outpatient placement upon a finding of the court that by clear and convincing evidence:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is 18 years of age or older;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a mental illness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is unlikely to survive safely in the community without supervision, based on a clinical determination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a history of lack of compliance with treatment for mental illness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least twice within the immediately preceding 36 months been involuntarily admitted to a receiving or treatment facility as defined in s. 394.455, or has received mental health services in a forensic or correctional facility. The 36-month period does not include any period during which the person was admitted or incarcerated; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaged in one or more acts of serious violent behavior toward self or others, or attempts at serious bodily harm to himself or herself or others, within the preceding 36 months;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is, as a result of his or her mental illness, unlikely to voluntarily participate in the recommended treatment plan and either he or she has refused voluntary placement for treatment after sufficient and conscientious explanation and disclosure of the purpose of placement for treatment or he or she is unable to determine for himself or herself whether placement is necessary;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In view of the person’s treatment history and current behavior, the person is in need of involuntary outpatient placement in order to prevent a relapse or deterioration that would be likely to result in serious bodily harm to himself or herself or others, or a substantial harm to his or her well-being as set forth in s. 394.463(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is likely that the person will benefit from involuntary outpatient placement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All available, less restrictive alternatives that would offer an opportunity for improvement of his or her condition have been judged to be inappropriate or unavailable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVOLUNTARY OUTPATIENT PLACEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A patient who is being recommended for involuntary outpatient placement by the administrator of the receiving facility where the patient has been examined may be retained by the facility after adherence to the notice procedures provided in s. 394.4599. The recommendation must be supported by the opinion of a psychiatrist and the second opinion of a clinical psychologist or another psychiatrist, both of whom have personally examined the patient within the preceding 72 hours, that the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement are met. However, in a county having a population of fewer than 50,000, if the administrator certifies that a psychiatrist or clinical psychologist is not available to provide the second opinion, the second opinion may be provided by a licensed physician who has postgraduate training and experience in diagnosis and treatment of mental and nervous disorders or by a psychiatric nurse. Any second opinion authorized in this subparagraph may be conducted through a face-to-face examination, in person or by electronic means. Such recommendation must be entered on an involuntary outpatient placement certificate that authorizes the receiving facility to retain the patient pending completion of a hearing. The certificate shall be made a part of the patient’s clinical record.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the patient has been stabilized and no longer meets the criteria for involuntary examination pursuant to s. 394.463(1), the patient must be released from the receiving facility while awaiting the hearing for involuntary outpatient placement. Before filing a petition for involuntary outpatient treatment, the administrator of a receiving facility or a designated department representative must identify the service provider that will have primary responsibility for service provision under an order for involuntary outpatient placement, unless the person is otherwise participating in outpatient psychiatric treatment and is not in need of public financing for that treatment, in which case the individual, if eligible, may be ordered to involuntary treatment pursuant to the existing psychiatric treatment relationship.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service provider shall prepare a written proposed treatment plan in consultation with the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, for the court’s consideration for inclusion in the involuntary outpatient placement order. The service provider shall also provide a copy of the proposed treatment plan to the patient and the administrator of the receiving facility. The treatment plan must specify the nature and extent of the patient’s mental illness, address the reduction of symptoms that necessitate involuntary outpatient placement, and include measurable goals and objectives for the services and treatment that are provided to treat the person’s mental illness and assist the person in living and functioning in the community or to prevent a relapse or deterioration. Service providers may select and supervise other individuals to implement specific aspects of the treatment plan. The services in the treatment plan must be deemed clinically appropriate by a physician, clinical psychologist, psychiatric nurse, mental health counselor, marriage and family therapist, or clinical social worker who consults with, or is employed or contracted by, the service provider. The service provider must certify to the court in the proposed treatment plan whether sufficient services for improvement and stabilization are currently available and whether the service provider agrees to provide those services. If the service provider certifies that the services in the proposed treatment plan are not available, the petitioner may not file the petition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a patient in involuntary inpatient placement meets the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement, the administrator of the treatment facility may, before the expiration of the period during which the treatment facility is authorized to retain the patient, recommend involuntary outpatient placement. The recommendation must be supported by the opinion of a psychiatrist and the second opinion of a clinical psychologist or another psychiatrist, both of whom have personally examined the patient within the preceding 72 hours, that the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement are met. However, in a county having a population of fewer than 50,000, if the administrator certifies that a psychiatrist or clinical psychologist is not available to provide the second opinion, the second opinion may be provided by a licensed physician who has postgraduate training and experience in diagnosis and treatment of mental and nervous disorders or by a psychiatric nurse. Any second opinion authorized in this subparagraph may be conducted through a face-to-face examination, in person or by electronic means. Such recommendation must be entered on an involuntary outpatient placement certificate, and the certificate must be made a part of the patient’s clinical record.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator of the treatment facility shall provide a copy of the involuntary outpatient placement certificate and a copy of the state mental health discharge form to a department representative in the county where the patient will be residing. For persons who are leaving a state mental health treatment facility, the petition for involuntary outpatient placement must be filed in the county where the patient will be residing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service provider that will have primary responsibility for service provision shall be identified by the designated department representative prior to the order for involuntary outpatient placement and must, prior to filing a petition for involuntary outpatient placement, certify to the court whether the services recommended in the patient’s discharge plan are available in the local community and whether the service provider agrees to provide those services. The service provider must develop with the patient, or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, a treatment or service plan that addresses the needs identified in the discharge plan. The plan must be deemed to be clinically appropriate by a physician, clinical psychologist, psychiatric nurse, mental health counselor, marriage and family therapist, or clinical social worker, as defined in this chapter, who consults with, or is employed or contracted by, the service provider.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the service provider certifies that the services in the proposed treatment or service plan are not available, the petitioner may not file the petition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PETITION FOR INVOLUNTARY OUTPATIENT PLACEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for involuntary outpatient placement may be filed by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator of a receiving facility; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator of a treatment facility.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each required criterion for involuntary outpatient placement must be alleged and substantiated in the petition for involuntary outpatient placement. A copy of the certificate recommending involuntary outpatient placement completed by a qualified professional specified in subsection (2) must be attached to the petition. A copy of the proposed treatment plan must be attached to the petition. Before the petition is filed, the service provider shall certify that the services in the proposed treatment plan are available. If the necessary services are not available in the patient’s local community to respond to the person’s individual needs, the petition may not be filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition for involuntary outpatient placement must be filed in the county where the patient is located, unless the patient is being placed from a state treatment facility, in which case the petition must be filed in the county where the patient will reside. When the petition has been filed, the clerk of the court shall provide copies of the petition and the proposed treatment plan to the department, the patient, the patient’s guardian or representative, the state attorney, and the public defender or the patient’s private counsel. A fee may not be charged for filing a petition under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPOINTMENT OF COUNSEL.<EmDash />Within 1 court working day after the filing of a petition for involuntary outpatient placement, the court shall appoint the public defender to represent the person who is the subject of the petition, unless the person is otherwise represented by counsel. The clerk of the court shall immediately notify the public defender of the appointment. The public defender shall represent the person until the petition is dismissed, the court order expires, or the patient is discharged from involuntary outpatient placement. An attorney who represents the patient shall have access to the patient, witnesses, and records relevant to the presentation of the patient’s case and shall represent the interests of the patient, regardless of the source of payment to the attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTINUANCE OF HEARING.<EmDash />The patient is entitled, with the concurrence of the patient’s counsel, to at least one continuance of the hearing. The continuance shall be for a period of up to 4 weeks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEARING ON INVOLUNTARY OUTPATIENT PLACEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall hold the hearing on involuntary outpatient placement within 5 working days after the filing of the petition, unless a continuance is granted. The hearing shall be held in the county where the petition is filed, shall be as convenient to the patient as is consistent with orderly procedure, and shall be conducted in physical settings not likely to be injurious to the patient’s condition. If the court finds that the patient’s attendance at the hearing is not consistent with the best interests of the patient and if the patient’s counsel does not object, the court may waive the presence of the patient from all or any portion of the hearing. The state attorney for the circuit in which the patient is located shall represent the state, rather than the petitioner, as the real party in interest in the proceeding.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may appoint a master to preside at the hearing. One of the professionals who executed the involuntary outpatient placement certificate shall be a witness. The patient and the patient’s guardian or representative shall be informed by the court of the right to an independent expert examination. If the patient cannot afford such an examination, the court shall provide for one. The independent expert’s report shall be confidential and not discoverable, unless the expert is to be called as a witness for the patient at the hearing. The court shall allow testimony from individuals, including family members, deemed by the court to be relevant under state law, regarding the person’s prior history and how that prior history relates to the person’s current condition. The testimony in the hearing must be given under oath, and the proceedings must be recorded. The patient may refuse to testify at the hearing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court concludes that the patient meets the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement pursuant to subsection (1), the court shall issue an order for involuntary outpatient placement. The court order shall be for a period of up to 6 months. The order must specify the nature and extent of the patient’s mental illness. The order of the court and the treatment plan shall be made part of the patient’s clinical record. The service provider shall discharge a patient from involuntary outpatient placement when the order expires or any time the patient no longer meets the criteria for involuntary placement. Upon discharge, the service provider shall send a certificate of discharge to the court.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may not order the department or the service provider to provide services if the program or service is not available in the patient’s local community, if there is no space available in the program or service for the patient, or if funding is not available for the program or service. A copy of the order must be sent to the Agency for Health Care Administration by the service provider within 1 working day after it is received from the court. After the placement order is issued, the service provider and the patient may modify provisions of the treatment plan. For any material modification of the treatment plan to which the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, does agree, the service provider shall send notice of the modification to the court. Any material modifications of the treatment plan which are contested by the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, must be approved or disapproved by the court consistent with subsection (2).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in the clinical judgment of a physician, the patient has failed or has refused to comply with the treatment ordered by the court, and, in the clinical judgment of the physician, efforts were made to solicit compliance and the patient may meet the criteria for involuntary examination, a person may be brought to a receiving facility pursuant to s. 394.463. If, after examination, the patient does not meet the criteria for involuntary inpatient placement pursuant to s. 394.467, the patient must be discharged from the receiving facility. The involuntary outpatient placement order shall remain in effect unless the service provider determines that the patient no longer meets the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement or until the order expires. The service provider must determine whether modifications should be made to the existing treatment plan and must attempt to continue to engage the patient in treatment. For any material modification of the treatment plan to which the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, does agree, the service provider shall send notice of the modification to the court. Any material modifications of the treatment plan which are contested by the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed, must be approved or disapproved by the court consistent with subsection (2).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, at any time before the conclusion of the initial hearing on involuntary outpatient placement, it appears to the court that the person does not meet the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement under this section but, instead, meets the criteria for involuntary inpatient placement, the court may order the person admitted for involuntary inpatient examination under s. 394.463. If the person instead meets the criteria for involuntary assessment, protective custody, or involuntary admission pursuant to s. 397.675, the court may order the person to be admitted for involuntary assessment for a period of 5 days pursuant to s. 397.6811. Thereafter, all proceedings shall be governed by chapter 397.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the hearing on involuntary outpatient placement, the court shall consider testimony and evidence regarding the patient’s competence to consent to treatment. If the court finds that the patient is incompetent to consent to treatment, it shall appoint a guardian advocate as provided in s. 394.4598. The guardian advocate shall be appointed or discharged in accordance with s. 394.4598.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator of the receiving facility or the designated department representative shall provide a copy of the court order and adequate documentation of a patient’s mental illness to the service provider for involuntary outpatient placement. Such documentation must include any advance directives made by the patient, a psychiatric evaluation of the patient, and any evaluations of the patient performed by a clinical psychologist or a clinical social worker.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROCEDURE FOR CONTINUED INVOLUNTARY OUTPATIENT PLACEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person continues to meet the criteria for involuntary outpatient placement, the service provider shall, before the expiration of the period during which the treatment is ordered for the person, file in the circuit court a petition for continued involuntary outpatient placement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existing involuntary outpatient placement order remains in effect until disposition on the petition for continued involuntary outpatient placement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate shall be attached to the petition which includes a statement from the person’s physician or clinical psychologist justifying the request, a brief description of the patient’s treatment during the time he or she was involuntarily placed, and an individualized plan of continued treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service provider shall develop the individualized plan of continued treatment in consultation with the patient or the patient’s guardian advocate, if appointed. When the petition has been filed, the clerk of the court shall provide copies of the certificate and the individualized plan of continued treatment to the department, the patient, the patient’s guardian advocate, the state attorney, and the patient’s private counsel or the public defender.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 1 court working day after the filing of a petition for continued involuntary outpatient placement, the court shall appoint the public defender to represent the person who is the subject of the petition, unless the person is otherwise represented by counsel. The clerk of the court shall immediately notify the public defender of such appointment. The public defender shall represent the person until the petition is dismissed or the court order expires or the patient is discharged from involuntary outpatient placement. Any attorney representing the patient shall have access to the patient, witnesses, and records relevant to the presentation of the patient’s case and shall represent the interests of the patient, regardless of the source of payment to the attorney.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearings on petitions for continued involuntary outpatient placement shall be before the circuit court. The court may appoint a master to preside at the hearing. The procedures for obtaining an order pursuant to this paragraph shall be in accordance with subsection (6), except that the time period included in paragraph (1)(e) is not applicable in determining the appropriateness of additional periods of involuntary outpatient placement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the hearing shall be provided as set forth in s. 394.4599. The patient and the patient’s attorney may agree to a period of continued outpatient placement without a court hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The same procedure shall be repeated before the expiration of each additional period the patient is placed in treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the patient has previously been found incompetent to consent to treatment, the court shall consider testimony and evidence regarding the patient’s competence. Section 394.4598 governs the discharge of the guardian advocate if the patient’s competency to consent to treatment has been restored.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2004-385; s. 3, ch. 2006-171; s. 4, ch. 2009-38.</History></Section>