<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.494" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General performance outcomes for the child and adolescent mental health treatment and support system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the child and adolescent mental health treatment and support system achieve the following performance outcomes within the target populations who are eligible for services:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stabilization or improvement of the emotional condition or behavior of the child or adolescent, as evidenced by resolving the presented problems and symptoms of the serious emotional disturbance recorded in the initial assessment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stabilization or improvement of the behavior or condition of the child or adolescent with respect to the family, so that the child or adolescent can function in the family with minimum appropriate supports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stabilization or improvement of the behavior or condition of the child or adolescent with respect to school, so that the child can function in the school with minimum appropriate supports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stabilization or improvement of the behavior or condition of the child or adolescent with respect to the way he or she interacts in the community, so that the child or adolescent can avoid behaviors that may be attributable to the emotional disturbance, such as substance abuse, unintended pregnancy, delinquency, sexually transmitted diseases, and other negative consequences.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually, pursuant to <Reference Number="1" />s. 216.0166, the department shall develop more specific performance outcomes and performance measures to assess the performance of the child and adolescent mental health treatment and support system in achieving the intent of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 98-5.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 61, ch. 2000-371.</Text></Note></Section>