<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4574" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department responsibilities for a mental health resident who resides in an assisted living facility that holds a limited mental health license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “mental health resident,” for purposes of this section, means an individual who receives social security disability income due to a mental disorder as determined by the Social Security Administration or receives supplemental security income due to a mental disorder as determined by the Social Security Administration and receives optional state supplementation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must ensure that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mental health resident has been assessed by a psychiatrist, clinical psychologist, clinical social worker, or psychiatric nurse, or an individual who is supervised by one of these professionals, and determined to be appropriate to reside in an assisted living facility. The documentation must be provided to the administrator of the facility within 30 days after the mental health resident has been admitted to the facility. An evaluation completed upon discharge from a state mental hospital meets the requirements of this subsection related to appropriateness for placement as a mental health resident if it was completed within 90 days prior to admission to the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cooperative agreement, as required in s. 429.075, is developed between the mental health care services provider that serves a mental health resident and the administrator of the assisted living facility with a limited mental health license in which the mental health resident is living. Any entity that provides Medicaid prepaid health plan services shall ensure the appropriate coordination of health care services with an assisted living facility in cases where a Medicaid recipient is both a member of the entity’s prepaid health plan and a resident of the assisted living facility. If the entity is at risk for Medicaid targeted case management and behavioral health services, the entity shall inform the assisted living facility of the procedures to follow should an emergent condition arise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The community living support plan, as defined in s. 429.02, has been prepared by a mental health resident and a mental health case manager of that resident in consultation with the administrator of the facility or the administrator’s designee. The plan must be provided to the administrator of the assisted living facility with a limited mental health license in which the mental health resident lives. The support plan and the agreement may be in one document.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assisted living facility with a limited mental health license is provided with documentation that the individual meets the definition of a mental health resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mental health services provider assigns a case manager to each mental health resident who lives in an assisted living facility with a limited mental health license. The case manager is responsible for coordinating the development of and implementation of the community living support plan defined in s. 429.02. The plan must be updated at least annually.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Children and Family Services, in consultation with the Agency for Health Care Administration, shall annually require each district administrator to develop, with community input, detailed plans that demonstrate how the district will ensure the provision of state-funded mental health and substance abuse treatment services to residents of assisted living facilities that hold a limited mental health license. These plans must be consistent with the substance abuse and mental health district plan developed pursuant to s. 394.75 and must address case management services; access to consumer-operated drop-in centers; access to services during evenings, weekends, and holidays; supervision of the clinical needs of the residents; and access to emergency psychiatric care.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 97-82; s. 23, ch. 98-80; s. 12, ch. 2000-349; s. 18, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>