<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.930" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority to adopt rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall adopt rules for:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures that must be followed by members of the multidisciplinary teams when assessing and evaluating persons subject to this part;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education and training requirements for members of the multidisciplinary teams and professionals who assess and evaluate persons under this part;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The criteria that must exist in order for a multidisciplinary team to recommend to a state attorney that a petition should be filed to involuntarily commit a person under this part. The criteria shall include, but are not limited to, whether:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a propensity to engage in future acts of sexual violence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person should be placed in a secure, residential facility; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person needs long-term treatment and care.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designation of secure facilities for sexually violent predators who are subject to involuntary commitment under this part;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The components of the basic treatment plan for all committed persons under this part;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The protocol to inform a person that he or she is being examined to determine whether he or she is a sexually violent predator under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 99-222; s. 82, ch. 2000-139.</History></Section>