<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4674" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plan and report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to develop a comprehensive plan for the deinstitutionalization of patients in a treatment facility who are over age 55 and do not meet the criteria for involuntary placement pursuant to s. 394.467. The plan shall include, but need not be limited to, the projected numbers of patients, the timetables for deinstitutionalization, and the specific actions to be taken to accomplish the deinstitutionalization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare and submit a semiannual report to the Legislature, until the conditions specified in subsection (1) are met, which shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status of compliance with the deinstitutionalization plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific efforts to stimulate alternative living and support resources outside the hospitals and all documentation of the success of these efforts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific efforts to facilitate the development and retention of daily living skills identified by the department as being necessary for living outside an institution and any evidence of the success of these efforts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific plans for new efforts to accomplish the deinstitutionalization of patients in this age group; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any evidence of involvement between the Mental Health Program Office and other program offices within the department and between the department and other state and private agencies and individuals to accomplish the deinstitutionalization of patients in this age group.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-293; s. 245, ch. 81-259; s. 6, ch. 81-290; s. 20, ch. 96-169; s. 49, ch. 2000-139.</History></Section>