<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.495" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Child and adolescent mental health system of care; programs and services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish, within available resources, an array of services to meet the individualized service and treatment needs of children and adolescents who are members of the target populations specified in s. 394.493, and of their families. It is the intent of the Legislature that a child or adolescent may not be admitted to a state mental health facility and such a facility may not be included within the array of services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The array of services must include assessment services that provide a professional interpretation of the nature of the problems of the child or adolescent and his or her family; family issues that may impact the problems; additional factors that contribute to the problems; and the assets, strengths, and resources of the child or adolescent and his or her family. The assessment services to be provided shall be determined by the clinical needs of each child or adolescent. Assessment services include, but are not limited to, evaluation and screening in the following areas:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical and mental health for purposes of identifying medical and psychiatric problems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Psychological functioning, as determined through a battery of psychological tests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intelligence and academic achievement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social and behavioral functioning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Family functioning.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The assessment for academic achievement is the financial responsibility of the school district. The department shall cooperate with other state agencies and the school district to avoid duplicating assessment services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessments must be performed by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional as defined in s. 394.455(2), (4), (21), (23), or (24);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional licensed under chapter 491; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is under the direct supervision of a professional as defined in s. 394.455(2), (4), (21), (23), or (24) or a professional licensed under chapter 491.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall adopt by rule statewide standards for mental health assessments, which must be based on current relevant professional and accreditation standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The array of services may include, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevention services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home-based services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School-based services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Family therapy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Family support.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Respite services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Outpatient treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Day treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crisis stabilization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Therapeutic foster care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inpatient hospitalization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Case management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services for victims of sex offenses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transitional services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to enhance collaboration between agencies and to facilitate the provision of services by the child and adolescent mental health treatment and support system and the school district, the local child and adolescent mental health system of care shall include the local educational multiagency network for severely emotionally disturbed students specified in s. 1006.04.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 98-5; s. 981, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>