<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joint alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health service programs in two or more counties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to rules established by the department, any county within a service district shall have the same power to contract for alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health services as the department has under existing statutes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to carry out the intent of this part and to provide alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health services in accordance with the district plan, the counties within a service district may enter into agreements with each other for the establishment of joint service programs. The agreements may provide for the joint provision or operation of services and facilities or for the provision or operation of services and facilities by one participating county under contract with other participating counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a service district comprises two or more counties or portions thereof, it is the obligation of the planning council to submit to the governing bodies, prior to the budget submission date of each governing body, an estimate of the proportionate share of costs of alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health services proposed to be borne by each such governing body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county desiring to withdraw from a joint program may submit to the district administrator a resolution requesting withdrawal therefrom together with a plan for the equitable adjustment and division of the assets, property, debts, and obligations, if any, of the joint program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 70-109; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 8, ch. 76-221; s. 15, ch. 84-285.</History></Section>