<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0394.913" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice to state attorney and multidisciplinary team of release of sexually violent predator; establishing multidisciplinary teams; information to be provided to multidisciplinary teams.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency with jurisdiction over a person who has been convicted of a sexually violent offense shall give written notice to the multidisciplinary team, and a copy to the state attorney of the circuit where that person was last convicted of a sexually violent offense. If the person has never been convicted of a sexually violent offense in this state but has been convicted of a sexually violent offense in another state or in federal court, the agency with jurisdiction shall give written notice to the multidisciplinary team and a copy to the state attorney of the circuit where the person was last convicted of any offense in this state. If the person is being confined in this state pursuant to interstate compact and has a prior or current conviction for a sexually violent offense, the agency with jurisdiction shall give written notice to the multidisciplinary team and a copy to the state attorney of the circuit where the person plans to reside upon release or, if no residence in this state is planned, the state attorney in the circuit where the facility from which the person to be released is located. Except as provided in s. 394.9135, the written notice must be given:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 545 days prior to the anticipated release from total confinement of a person serving a sentence in the custody of the Department of Corrections, except that in the case of persons who are totally confined for a period of less than 545 days, written notice must be given as soon as practicable;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 180 days prior to the anticipated release from residential commitment of a person committed to the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice, except that in the case of persons who are committed to low or moderate risk, written notice must be given as soon as practicable; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 180 days prior to the anticipated hearing regarding possible release of a person committed to the custody of the department who has been found not guilty by reason of insanity or mental incapacity of a sexually violent offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency having jurisdiction shall provide the multidisciplinary team with the following information:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s name; identifying characteristics; anticipated future residence; the type of supervision the person will receive in the community, if any; and the person’s offense history;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s criminal history, including police reports, victim statements, presentence investigation reports, postsentence investigation reports, if available, and any other documents containing facts of the person’s criminal incidents or indicating whether the criminal incidents included sexual acts or were sexually motivated;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mental health, mental status, and medical records, including all clinical records and notes concerning the person;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of institutional adjustment and any treatment received and, in the case of an adjudicated delinquent committed to the Department of Juvenile Justice, copies of the most recent performance plan and performance summary; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person was returned to custody after a period of supervision, documentation of adjustment during supervision and any treatment received.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary or his or her designee shall establish a multidisciplinary team or teams.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each team shall include, but is not limited to, two licensed psychiatrists or psychologists or one licensed psychiatrist and one licensed psychologist. The multidisciplinary team shall assess and evaluate each person referred to the team. The assessment and evaluation shall include a review of the person’s institutional history and treatment record, if any, the person’s criminal background, and any other factor that is relevant to the determination of whether such person is a sexually violent predator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before recommending that a person meets the definition of a sexually violent predator, the person must be offered a personal interview. If the person agrees to participate in a personal interview, at least one member of the team who is a licensed psychiatrist or psychologist must conduct a personal interview of the person. If the person refuses to fully participate in a personal interview, the multidisciplinary team may proceed with its recommendation without a personal interview of the person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General’s Office shall serve as legal counsel to the multidisciplinary team.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 180 days after receiving notice, there shall be a written assessment as to whether the person meets the definition of a sexually violent predator and a written recommendation, which shall be provided to the state attorney. The written recommendation shall be provided by the Department of Children and Family Services and shall include the written report of the multidisciplinary team.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subparagraph 1., in the case of a person for whom the written assessment and recommendation has not been completed at least 365 days before his or her release from total confinement, the department shall prioritize the assessment of that person based upon the person’s release date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are not jurisdictional, and failure to comply with them in no way prevents the state attorney from proceeding against a person otherwise subject to the provisions of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 98-64; s. 6, ch. 99-222; s. 81, ch. 2000-139; s. 1, ch. 2002-59; s. 1, ch. 2007-241; s. 1, ch. 2012-79.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 916.33.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>