<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.90" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection; right of entry; records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in accordance with s. 408.811, and the department may enter and inspect at any time a licensed facility to determine whether the facility is in compliance with this chapter, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the agency may enter and inspect any premises that it has probable cause to suspect may be operating as an unlicensed crisis stabilization unit or residential treatment facility; however, such entry and inspection shall be made only with the permission of the person in charge of such premises or pursuant to warrant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any application for licensure under this chapter constitutes full permission for the department and the agency to enter and inspect the premises of the applicant or licensee at any time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of monitoring and investigation, the department and the Agency for Health Care Administration shall have access to the clinical records of any client of a licensee or designated facility, the provisions of s. 394.4615 to the contrary notwithstanding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall schedule periodic inspections of licensees so as to minimize the cost to the licensees and the disruption of the licensees’ programs. This subsection shall not be construed to limit the authority of the department and the agency to inspect the facilities of a licensee at any time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee shall maintain as public information, available to any person upon request, copies of all reports of inspections of the licensee filed with or issued by any governmental agency during the preceding 5-year period. The licensee shall furnish a copy of the most recent inspection report of the agency to any person upon payment of a reasonable charge for copying.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall accept, in lieu of its own inspections for licensure, the survey or inspection of an accrediting organization, if the provider is accredited according to the provisions of s. 394.741 and the agency receives the report of the accrediting organization.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 11, ch. 85-167; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 47, ch. 93-39; s. 28, ch. 96-169; s. 65, ch. 97-100; s. 32, ch. 98-171; s. 3, ch. 2001-171; s. 5, ch. 2001-191; s. 34, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>