<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.496" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service planning.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the service planning process:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Focus on individualized treatment and the service needs of the child or adolescent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Concentrate on the service needs of the family and individual family members of the child’s or adolescent’s family.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involve appropriate family members and pertinent community-based health, education, and social agencies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principals of the service planning process shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist the family and other caregivers in developing and implementing a workable services plan for treating the mental health problems of the child or adolescent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use all available resources in the community, particularly informal support services, which will assist in carrying out the goals and objectives of the services plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the child or adolescent in the most normal environment possible, as close to home as possible; and maintain the child in a stable school placement, which is consistent with the child’s or adolescent’s and other students’ need for safety, if the child is removed from home and placed in state custody.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure the ability and likelihood of family participation in the treatment of the child or adolescent, as well as enhancing family independence by building on family strengths and assets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services plan must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A behavioral description of the problem being addressed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the services or treatment to be provided to the child or adolescent and his or her family which address the identified problem, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The frequency and duration of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location at which the services or treatment are to be provided.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each accountable provider of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the measurable objectives of treatment, which, if met, will result in measurable improvements of the condition of the child or adolescent, as specified in s. 394.494.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For students who are served by exceptional student education, there must be consistency between the services prescribed in the service plan and the components of the individual education plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt by rule criteria for determining when a child or adolescent who receives mental health services under ss. 394.490-394.497 must have an individualized services plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional as defined in s. 394.455(2), (4), (21), (23), or (24) or a professional licensed under chapter 491 must be included among those persons developing the services plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services plan shall be developed in conference with the parent or legal guardian. If the parent or legal guardian believes that the services plan is inadequate, the parent or legal guardian may request that the department or its designee review and make recommended changes to the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services plan shall be reviewed at least every 90 days for programmatic and financial compliance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 98-5.</History></Section>