<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0394.4985" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Districtwide information and referral network; implementation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each service district of the Department of Children and Family Services shall develop a detailed implementation plan for a districtwide comprehensive child and adolescent mental health information and referral network to be operational by July 1, 1999. The plan must include an operating budget that demonstrates cost efficiencies and identifies funding sources for the district information and referral network. The district shall use existing district information and referral providers if, in the development of the plan, it is concluded that these providers would deliver information and referral services in a more efficient and effective manner when compared to other alternatives. The district information and referral network must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resource file that contains information about the child and adolescent mental health services as described in s. 394.495, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Type of program;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hours of service;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ages of persons served;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program description;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligibility requirements; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information about private providers and professionals in the community who serve children and adolescents with an emotional disturbance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A system to document requests for services which are received through the network referral process, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of calls by type of service requested;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ages of the children and adolescents for whom services are requested; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Type of referral made by the network.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability to share client information with the appropriate community agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In planning the information and referral network, the district shall consider the establishment of a 24-hour toll-free telephone number, staffed at all times, for parents and other persons to call for information that concerns child and adolescent mental health services and a community public service campaign to inform the public about information and referral services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 98-5; s. 101, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>