<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0394.917" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination; commitment procedure; mistrials; housing; counsel and costs in indigent appellate cases.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court or jury shall determine by clear and convincing evidence whether the person is a sexually violent predator. If the determination is made by a jury, the verdict must be unanimous. If the jury is unable to reach a unanimous verdict, the court must declare a mistrial and poll the jury. If a majority of the jury would find the person is a sexually violent predator, the state attorney may refile the petition and proceed according to the provisions of this part. Any retrial must occur within 90 days after the previous trial, unless the subsequent proceeding is continued in accordance with s. 394.916(2). The determination that a person is a sexually violent predator may be appealed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court or jury determines that the person is a sexually violent predator, upon the expiration of the incarcerative portion of all criminal sentences and disposition of any detainers, the person shall be committed to the custody of the Department of Children and Family Services for control, care, and treatment until such time as the person’s mental abnormality or personality disorder has so changed that it is safe for the person to be at large. At all times, persons who are detained or committed under this part shall be kept in a secure facility segregated from patients of the department who are not detained or committed under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public defender of the circuit in which a person was determined to be a sexually violent predator shall be appointed to represent the person on appeal. That public defender may request the public defender who handles criminal appeals for the circuit to represent the person on appeal in the manner provided in s. 27.51(4). If the public defender is unable to represent the person on appeal due to a conflict, the court shall appoint other counsel, who shall be compensated at a rate not less than that provided for appointed counsel in criminal cases. Filing fees for indigent appeals under this act are waived. Costs and fees related to such appeals, including the amounts paid for records, transcripts, and compensation of appointed counsel, shall be authorized by the trial court and paid from state funds that are appropriated for such purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 98-64; s. 12, ch. 99-222; s. 2, ch. 2002-59; s. 43, ch. 2004-5; s. 3, ch. 2012-79.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 916.37.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>