<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State and district substance abuse and mental health plans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every 3 years, beginning in 2001, the department, in consultation with the Medicaid program in the Agency for Health Care Administration, shall prepare a state master plan for the delivery and financing of a system of publicly funded, community-based substance abuse and mental health services throughout the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial plan must include an assessment of the clinical practice guidelines and standards for community-based mental health and substance abuse services delivered by persons or agencies under contract with the Department of Children and Family Services. The assessment must include an inventory of current clinical guidelines and standards used by persons and agencies under contract with the department, and by nationally recognized accreditation organizations, to address the quality of care and must specify additional clinical practice standards and guidelines for new or existing services and programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan must propose changes in department policy or statutory revisions to strengthen the quality of mental health and substance abuse treatment and support services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan must identify strategies for meeting the treatment and support needs of children, adolescents, adults, and older adults who have, or are at risk of having, mental, emotional, or substance abuse problems as defined in this chapter or chapter 397.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan must include input from persons who represent local communities; local government entities that contribute funds to the local substance abuse and mental health treatment systems; consumers of publicly funded substance abuse and mental health services, and their families; and stakeholders interested in mental health and substance abuse services. The plan must describe the means by which this local input occurred. The plan shall be updated annually.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan must include statewide policies and planning parameters that will be used by the <Reference Number="1" />health and human services boards in preparing the district substance abuse and mental health plans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district plans shall be one component of the state master plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state master plan shall also include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposal for the development of a data system that will evaluate the effectiveness of programs and services provided to clients of the substance abuse and mental health service system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposal to resolve the funding discrepancies between districts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A methodology for the allocation of resources available from federal, state, and local sources and a description of the current level of funding available from each source.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the statewide priorities for clients and services, and each district’s priorities for clients and services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for methods of enhancing local participation in the planning, organization, and financing of substance abuse and mental health services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the current methods of contracting for services, an assessment of the efficiency of these methods in providing accountability for contracted funds, and recommendations for improvements to the system of contracting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for improving access to services by clients and their families.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guidelines and formats for the development of district plans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for future directions for the substance abuse and mental health service delivery system.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A schedule, format, and procedure for development and review of the state master plan shall be adopted by the department by June of each year. The plan and annual updates must be submitted to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1 of each year, beginning January 1, 2001.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district <Reference Number="1" />health and human services board shall prepare an integrated district substance abuse and mental health plan. The plan shall be prepared and updated on a schedule established by the <Reference Number="2" />Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Program Office. The plan shall reflect the needs and program priorities established by the department and the needs of the district established under ss. 394.674 and 394.675. The plan must list in order of priority the mental health and the substance abuse treatment needs of the district and must rank each program separately. The plan shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the total amount of money available in the district for mental health and substance abuse services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of each service that will be purchased with state funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the amount of money allocated for each service identified in the plan as being purchased with state funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the total funds allocated to each provider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the total funds allocated to each provider by type of service to be purchased with state funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Input from community-based persons, organizations, and agencies interested in substance abuse and mental health treatment services; local government entities that contribute funds to the public substance abuse and mental health treatment systems; and consumers of publicly funded substance abuse and mental health services, and their family members. The plan must describe the means by which this local input occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The plan shall be submitted by the district <Reference Number="1" />board to the district administrator and to the governing bodies for review, comment, and approval.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district plan shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the publicly funded, community-based substance abuse and mental health system of care, and identify statutorily defined populations, their service needs, and the resources available and required to meet their needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the means for meeting the needs of the district’s eligible clients, specified in ss. 394.674 and 394.675, for substance abuse and mental health services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a process for coordinating the delivery of services within a community-based system of care to eligible clients. Such process must involve service providers, clients, and other stakeholders. The process must also provide a means by which providers will coordinate and cooperate to strengthen linkages, achieve maximum integration of services, foster efficiencies in service delivery and administration, and designate responsibility for outcomes for eligible clients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a projection of district program and fiscal needs for the next fiscal year, provide for the orderly and economical development of needed services, and indicate priorities and resources for each population served, performance outcomes, and anticipated expenditures and revenues.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include a summary budget request for the total district substance abuse and mental health program, which must include the funding priorities established by the district planning process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a basis for the district legislative budget request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include a policy and procedure for allocation of funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include a procedure for securing local matching funds. Such a procedure shall be developed in consultation with governing bodies and service providers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the integration of substance abuse and mental health services with the other departmental programs and with the criminal justice, juvenile justice, child protection, school, and health care systems within the district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a plan for the coordination of services in such manner as to ensure effectiveness and avoid duplication, fragmentation of services, and unnecessary expenditures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for continuity of client care between state treatment facilities and community programs to assure that discharge planning results in the rapid application for all benefits for which a client is eligible, including Medicaid coverage for persons leaving state treatment facilities and returning to community-based programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the most appropriate and economical use of all existing public and private agencies and personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the fullest possible and most appropriate participation by existing programs; state hospitals and other hospitals; city, county, and state health and family service agencies; drug abuse and alcoholism programs; probation departments; physicians; psychologists; social workers; marriage and family therapists; mental health counselors; clinical social workers; public health nurses; school systems; and all other public and private agencies and personnel that are required to, or may agree to, participate in the plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include an inventory of all public and private substance abuse and mental health resources within the district, including consumer advocacy groups and self-help groups known to the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district plan shall address how substance abuse and mental health services will be provided and how a system of care for target populations will be provided given the resources available in the service district. The plan must include provisions for maximizing client access to the most recently developed psychiatric medications approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration, for developing independent housing units through participation in the Section 811 program operated by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, for developing supported employment services through the Division of Vocational Rehabilitation of the Department of Education, for providing treatment services to persons with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse problems which are integrated across treatment systems, and for providing services to adults who have a serious mental illness, as defined in s. 394.67, and who reside in assisted living facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district plan shall provide the means by which the needs of the population groups specified pursuant to s. 394.674 will be addressed in the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In developing the district plan, optimum use shall be made of any federal, state, and local funds that may be available for substance abuse and mental health service planning. However, the department must provide these services within legislative appropriations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district <Reference Number="1" />health and human services board shall establish a subcommittee to prepare the portion of the district plan relating to children and adolescents. The subcommittee shall include representative membership of any committee organized or established by the district to review placement of children and adolescents in residential treatment programs. The <Reference Number="1" />board shall establish a subcommittee to prepare the portion of the district plan which relates to adult mental health and substance abuse. The subcommittee must include representatives from the community who have an interest in mental health and substance abuse treatment for adults.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All departments of state government and all local public agencies shall cooperate with officials to assist them in service planning. Each district administrator shall, upon request and the availability of staff, provide consultative services to the local agency directors and governing bodies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district administrator shall ensure that the district plan:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conforms to the priorities in the state plan, the requirements of this part, and the standards adopted under this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensures that the most effective and economical use will be made of available public and private substance abuse and mental health resources in the service district; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has adequate provisions made for review and evaluation of the services provided in the service district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district administrator shall require such modifications in the district plan as he or she deems necessary to bring the plan into conformance with the provisions of this part. If the district <Reference Number="1" />board and the district administrator cannot agree on the plan, including the projected budget, the issues under dispute shall be submitted directly to the secretary of the department for immediate resolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each governing body that provides local funds has the authority to require necessary modification to only that portion of the district plan which affects substance abuse and mental health programs and services within the jurisdiction of that governing body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district administrator shall report annually to the district <Reference Number="1" />board the status of funding for priorities established in the district plan. Each report must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the district plan priorities that were included in the district legislative budget request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the district plan priorities that were included in the departmental budget request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the programs and services included in the district plan priorities that were appropriated funds by the Legislature in the legislative session that preceded the report.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 70-109; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 10, ch. 76-221; s. 2, ch. 77-372; s. 4, ch. 82-223; s. 17, ch. 84-285; s. 18, ch. 88-398; s. 60, ch. 91-221; s. 6, ch. 92-174; s. 13, ch. 93-200; s. 7, ch. 93-267; s. 722, ch. 95-148; s. 51, ch. 2000-139; s. 11, ch. 2000-349; s. 20, ch. 2002-22.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health and human services boards were abolished by s. 2, ch. 2000-139, which substantially reworded s. 20.19.</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 2, ch. 2000-139, amended s. 20.19, relating to the structure of the Department of Children and Family Services; separate program offices are established for mental health and for substance abuse.</Text></Note></Section>