<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4685" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of patients among facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRANSFER BETWEEN PUBLIC FACILITIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A patient who has been admitted to a public receiving facility, or the family member, guardian, or guardian advocate of such patient, may request the transfer of the patient to another public receiving facility. A patient who has been admitted to a public treatment facility, or the family member, guardian, or guardian advocate of such patient, may request the transfer of the patient to another public treatment facility. Depending on the medical treatment or mental health treatment needs of the patient and the availability of appropriate facility resources, the patient may be transferred at the discretion of the department. If the department approves the transfer of an involuntary patient, notice according to the provisions of s. 394.4599 shall be given prior to the transfer by the transferring facility. The department shall respond to the request for transfer within 2 working days after receipt of the request by the facility administrator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When required by the medical treatment or mental health treatment needs of the patient or the efficient utilization of a public receiving or public treatment facility, a patient may be transferred from one receiving facility to another, or one treatment facility to another, at the department’s discretion, or, with the express and informed consent of the patient or the patient’s guardian or guardian advocate, to a facility in another state. Notice according to the provisions of s. 394.4599 shall be given prior to the transfer by the transferring facility. If prior notice is not possible, notice of the transfer shall be provided as soon as practicable after the transfer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRANSFER FROM PUBLIC TO PRIVATE FACILITIES.<EmDash />A patient who has been admitted to a public receiving or public treatment facility and has requested, either personally or through his or her guardian or guardian advocate, and is able to pay for treatment in a private facility shall be transferred at the patient’s expense to a private facility upon acceptance of the patient by the private facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRANSFER FROM PRIVATE TO PUBLIC FACILITIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A patient or the patient’s guardian or guardian advocate may request the transfer of the patient from a private to a public facility, and the patient may be so transferred upon acceptance of the patient by the public facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private facility may request the transfer of a patient from the facility to a public facility, and the patient may be so transferred upon acceptance of the patient by the public facility. The cost of such transfer shall be the responsibility of the transferring facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public facility must respond to a request for the transfer of a patient within 2 working days after receipt of the request.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRANSFER BETWEEN PRIVATE FACILITIES.<EmDash />A patient in a private facility or the patient’s guardian or guardian advocate may request the transfer of the patient to another private facility at any time, and the patient shall be transferred upon acceptance of the patient by the facility to which transfer is sought.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 96-169.</History></Section>