<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0394.875" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Crisis stabilization units, residential treatment facilities, and residential treatment centers for children and adolescents; authorized services; license required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of a crisis stabilization unit is to stabilize and redirect a client to the most appropriate and least restrictive community setting available, consistent with the client’s needs. Crisis stabilization units may screen, assess, and admit for stabilization persons who present themselves to the unit and persons who are brought to the unit under s. 394.463. Clients may be provided 24-hour observation, medication prescribed by a physician or psychiatrist, and other appropriate services. Crisis stabilization units shall provide services regardless of the client’s ability to pay and shall be limited in size to a maximum of 30 beds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of a residential treatment facility is to be a part of a comprehensive treatment program for mentally ill individuals in a community-based residential setting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of a residential treatment center for children and adolescents is to provide mental health assessment and treatment services pursuant to ss. 394.491, 394.495, and 394.496 to children and adolescents who meet the target population criteria specified in s. 394.493(1)(a), (b), or (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to implement a demonstration project in circuit 18 to test the impact of expanding beds authorized in crisis stabilization units from 30 to 50 beds. Specifically, the department is directed to authorize existing public or private crisis stabilization units in circuit 18 to expand bed capacity to a maximum of 50 beds and to assess the impact such expansion would have on the availability of crisis stabilization services to clients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure under ss. 394.455-394.903 and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to ss. 394.455-394.903. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate a crisis stabilization unit, a residential treatment facility, or a residential treatment center for children and adolescents, or to act as a crisis stabilization unit, a residential treatment facility, or a residential treatment center for children and adolescents in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from licensure as required in ss. 394.455-394.903:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homes for special services licensed under chapter 400.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nursing homes licensed under chapter 400.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comprehensive transitional education programs licensed under s. 393.067.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, may establish multiple license classifications for residential treatment facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may not issue a license to a crisis stabilization unit unless the unit receives state mental health funds and is affiliated with a designated public receiving facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may issue a license for a crisis stabilization unit or short-term residential treatment facility, certifying the number of authorized beds for such facility as indicated by existing need and available appropriations. The agency may disapprove an application for such a license if it determines that a facility should not be licensed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. Any facility operating beds in excess of those authorized by the agency shall, upon demand of the agency, reduce the number of beds to the authorized number, forfeit its license, or provide evidence of a license issued pursuant to chapter 395 for the excess beds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A children’s crisis stabilization unit which does not exceed 20 licensed beds and which provides separate facilities or a distinct part of a facility, separate staffing, and treatment exclusively for minors may be located on the same premises as a crisis stabilization unit serving adults. The department, in consultation with the agency, shall adopt rules governing facility construction, staffing and licensure requirements, and the operation of such units for minors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, must adopt rules governing a residential treatment center for children and adolescents which specify licensure standards for: admission; length of stay; program and staffing; discharge and discharge planning; treatment planning; seclusion, restraints, and time-out; rights of patients under s. 394.459; use of psychotropic medications; and standards for the operation of such centers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (6), crisis stabilization units may not exceed their licensed capacity by more than 10 percent, nor may they exceed their licensed capacity for more than 3 consecutive working days or for more than 7 days in 1 month.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, any facility licensed under former chapter 396 and chapter 397 for detoxification, residential level I care, and outpatient treatment may elect to license concurrently all of the beds at such facility both for that purpose and as a long-term residential treatment facility pursuant to this section, if all of the following conditions are met:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensure application is received by the department prior to January 1, 1993.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On January 1, 1993, the facility was licensed under former chapter 396 and chapter 397 as a facility for detoxification, residential level I care, and outpatient treatment of substance abuse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facility restricted its practice to the treatment of law enforcement personnel for a period of at least 12 months beginning after January 1, 1992.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of beds to be licensed under this chapter is equal to or less than the number of beds licensed under former chapter 396 and chapter 397 as of January 1, 1993.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee agrees in writing to a condition placed upon the license that the facility will limit its treatment exclusively to law enforcement personnel and their immediate families who are seeking admission on a voluntary basis and who are exhibiting symptoms of posttraumatic stress disorder or other mental health problems, including drug or alcohol abuse, which are directly related to law enforcement work and which are amenable to verbal treatment therapies; the licensee agrees to coordinate the provision of appropriate postresidential care for discharged individuals; and the licensee further agrees in writing that a failure to meet any condition specified in this paragraph shall constitute grounds for a revocation of the facility’s license as a residential treatment facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee agrees that the facility will meet all licensure requirements for a residential treatment facility, including minimum standards for compliance with lifesafety requirements, except those licensure requirements which are in express conflict with the conditions and other provisions specified in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee agrees that the conditions stated in this subsection must be agreed to in writing by any person acquiring the facility by any means.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any facility licensed under this subsection is not required to provide any services to any persons except those included in the specified conditions of licensure, and is exempt from any requirements related to the 60-day or greater average length of stay imposed on community-based residential treatment facilities otherwise licensed under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 85-167; s. 1, ch. 90-251; s. 249, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 9, ch. 93-247; ss. 27, 71, ch. 98-171; s. 4, ch. 2000-265; ss. 65, 154, ch. 2000-349; s. 25, ch. 2001-53; s. 26, ch. 2001-62; s. 2, ch. 2001-67; s. 148, ch. 2001-277; s. 42, ch. 2004-267; s. 29, ch. 2007-230; s. 77, ch. 2010-5; s. 1, ch. 2011-234.</History>
</Section>