<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.499" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Integrated children’s crisis stabilization unit/juvenile addictions receiving facility services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2001, the Department of Children and Family Services, in consultation with the Agency for Health Care Administration, is authorized to establish children’s behavioral crisis unit demonstration models in Collier, Lee, and Sarasota Counties. As a result of the recommendations regarding expansion of the demonstration models contained in the evaluation report of December 31, 2003, the department, in cooperation with the agency, may expand the demonstration models to other areas in the state after July 1, 2005. The children’s behavioral crisis unit demonstration models will integrate children’s mental health crisis stabilization units with substance abuse juvenile addictions receiving facility services, to provide emergency mental health and substance abuse services that are integrated within facilities licensed and designated by the agency for children under 18 years of age who meet criteria for admission or examination under this section. The services shall be designated as “integrated children’s crisis stabilization unit/juvenile addictions receiving facility services,” shall be licensed by the agency as children’s crisis stabilization units, and shall meet all licensure requirements for crisis stabilization units. The department, in cooperation with the agency, shall develop standards that address eligibility criteria; clinical procedures; staffing requirements; operational, administrative, and financing requirements; and investigation of complaints for such integrated facility services. Standards that are implemented specific to substance abuse services shall meet or exceed existing standards for addictions receiving facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children eligible to receive integrated children’s crisis stabilization unit/juvenile addictions receiving facility services include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 18 years of age for whom voluntary application is made by his or her guardian, if such person is found to show evidence of mental illness and to be suitable for treatment pursuant to s. 394.4625. A person under 18 years of age may be admitted for integrated facility services only after a hearing to verify that the consent to admission is voluntary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 18 years of age who may be taken to a receiving facility for involuntary examination, if there is reason to believe that he or she is mentally ill and because of his or her mental illness, pursuant to s. 394.463:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has refused voluntary examination after conscientious explanation and disclosure of the purpose of the examination; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is unable to determine for himself or herself whether examination is necessary; and</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without care or treatment is likely to suffer from neglect or refuse to care for himself or herself; such neglect or refusal poses a real and present threat of substantial harm to his or her well-being; and it is not apparent that such harm may be avoided through the help of willing family members or friends or the provision of other services; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a substantial likelihood that without care or treatment he or she will cause serious bodily harm to himself or herself or others in the near future, as evidenced by recent behavior.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 18 years of age who wishes to enter treatment for substance abuse and applies to a service provider for voluntary admission, pursuant to s. 397.601.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 18 years of age who meets the criteria for involuntary admission because there is good faith reason to believe the person is substance abuse impaired pursuant to s. 397.675 and, because of such impairment:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has lost the power of self-control with respect to substance use; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has inflicted, or threatened or attempted to inflict, or unless admitted is likely to inflict, physical harm on himself or herself or another; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in need of substance abuse services and, by reason of substance abuse impairment, his or her judgment has been so impaired that the person is incapable of appreciating his or her need for such services and of making a rational decision in regard thereto; however, mere refusal to receive such services does not constitute evidence of lack of judgment with respect to his or her need for such services.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 18 years of age who meets the criteria for examination or admission under paragraph (b) or paragraph (d) and has a coexisting mental health and substance abuse disorder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in cooperation with the agency, is authorized to adopt rules regarding standards and procedures for integrated children’s crisis stabilization unit/juvenile addictions receiving facility services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2001-171; s. 1, ch. 2001-191; s. 55, ch. 2005-2; s. 1, ch. 2005-55.</History></Section>