<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.912" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency with jurisdiction” means the agency that releases, upon lawful order or authority, a person who is serving a sentence in the custody of the Department of Corrections, a person who was adjudicated delinquent and is committed to the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice, or a person who was involuntarily committed to the custody of the Department of Children and Family Services upon an adjudication of not guilty by reason of insanity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Convicted of a sexually violent offense” means a person who has been:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjudicated guilty of a sexually violent offense after a trial, guilty plea, or plea of nolo contendere;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjudicated not guilty by reason of insanity of a sexually violent offense; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjudicated delinquent of a sexually violent offense after a trial, guilty plea, or plea of nolo contendere.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Likely to engage in acts of sexual violence” means the person’s propensity to commit acts of sexual violence is of such a degree as to pose a menace to the health and safety of others.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental abnormality” means a mental condition affecting a person’s emotional or volitional capacity which predisposes the person to commit sexually violent offenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual 18 years of age or older who is a potential or actual subject of proceedings under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the secretary of the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexually motivated” means that one of the purposes for which the defendant committed the crime was for sexual gratification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexually violent offense” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Murder of a human being while engaged in sexual battery in violation of s. 782.04(1)(a)2.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kidnapping of a child under the age of 13 and, in the course of that offense, committing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lewd, lascivious, or indecent assault or act upon or in the presence of the child;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing the offense of false imprisonment upon a child under the age of 13 and, in the course of that offense, committing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lewd, lascivious, or indecent assault or act upon or in the presence of the child;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery in violation of s. 794.011;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lewd, lascivious, or indecent assault or act upon or in presence of the child in violation of s. 800.04 or s. 847.0135(5);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An attempt, criminal solicitation, or conspiracy, in violation of s. 777.04, of a sexually violent offense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conviction for a felony offense in effect at any time before October 1, 1998, which is comparable to a sexually violent offense under paragraphs (a)-(f) or any federal conviction or conviction in another state for a felony offense that in this state would be a sexually violent offense; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any criminal act that, either at the time of sentencing for the offense or subsequently during civil commitment proceedings under this part, has been determined beyond a reasonable doubt to have been sexually motivated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexually violent predator” means any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted of a sexually violent offense; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suffers from a mental abnormality or personality disorder that makes the person likely to engage in acts of sexual violence if not confined in a secure facility for long-term control, care, and treatment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Total confinement” means that the person is currently being held in any physically secure facility being operated or contractually operated for the Department of Corrections, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the Department of Children and Family Services. A person shall also be deemed to be in total confinement for applicability of provisions under this part if the person is serving an incarcerative sentence under the custody of the Department of Corrections or the Department of Juvenile Justice and is being held in any other secure facility for any reason.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-64; s. 5, ch. 99-222; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 11, ch. 2008-172.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 916.32.</Text></Note></Section>