<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4599" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VOLUNTARY PATIENTS.<EmDash />Notice of a voluntary patient’s admission shall only be given at the request of the patient, except that in an emergency, notice shall be given as determined by the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVOLUNTARY PATIENTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever notice is required to be given under this part, such notice shall be given to the patient and the patient’s guardian, guardian advocate, attorney, and representative.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When notice is required to be given to a patient, it shall be given both orally and in writing, in the language and terminology that the patient can understand, and, if needed, the facility shall provide an interpreter for the patient.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice to a patient’s guardian, guardian advocate, attorney, and representative shall be given by United States mail and by registered or certified mail with the receipts attached to the patient’s clinical record. Hand delivery by a facility employee may be used as an alternative, with delivery documented in the clinical record. If notice is given by a state attorney or an attorney for the department, a certificate of service shall be sufficient to document service.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A receiving facility shall give prompt notice of the whereabouts of a patient who is being involuntarily held for examination, by telephone or in person within 24 hours after the patient’s arrival at the facility, unless the patient requests that no notification be made. Contact attempts shall be documented in the patient’s clinical record and shall begin as soon as reasonably possible after the patient’s arrival. Notice that a patient is being admitted as an involuntary patient shall be given to the Florida local advocacy council no later than the next working day after the patient is admitted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written notice of the filing of the petition for involuntary placement must contain the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice that the petition has been filed with the circuit court in the county in which the patient is hospitalized and the address of such court.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice that the office of the public defender has been appointed to represent the patient in the proceeding, if the patient is not otherwise represented by counsel.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date, time, and place of the hearing and the name of each examining expert and every other person expected to testify in support of continued detention.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice that the patient, the patient’s guardian or representative, or the administrator may apply for a change of venue for the convenience of the parties or witnesses or because of the condition of the patient.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice that the patient is entitled to an independent expert examination and, if the patient cannot afford such an examination, that the court will provide for one.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A treatment facility shall provide notice of a patient’s involuntary admission on the next regular working day after the patient’s arrival at the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a patient is to be transferred from one facility to another, notice shall be given by the facility where the patient is located prior to the transfer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 96-169; s. 13, ch. 2000-263.</History></Section>