<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.4612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Integrated adult mental health crisis stabilization and addictions receiving facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration, in consultation with the Department of Children and Family Services, may license facilities that integrate services provided in an adult mental health crisis stabilization unit with services provided in an adult addictions receiving facility. Such a facility shall be licensed by the agency as an adult crisis stabilization unit under part IV and must meet all licensure requirements for crisis stabilization units providing integrated services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An integrated mental health crisis stabilization unit and addictions receiving facility may provide services under this section to adults who are 18 years of age or older and who fall into one or more of the following categories:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult meeting the requirements for voluntary admission for mental health treatment under s. 394.4625.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult meeting the criteria for involuntary examination for mental illness under s. 394.463.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult qualifying for voluntary admission for substance abuse treatment under s. 397.601.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult meeting the criteria for involuntary admission for substance abuse impairment under s. 397.675.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the agency, shall adopt by rule standards that address eligibility criteria; clinical procedures; staffing requirements; operational, administrative, and financing requirements; and the investigation of complaints.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2009-44.</History></Section>