<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0394.457" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation and administration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATION.<EmDash />The Department of Children and Family Services is designated the “Mental Health Authority” of Florida. The department and the Agency for Health Care Administration shall exercise executive and administrative supervision over all mental health facilities, programs, and services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT.<EmDash />The department is responsible for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The planning, evaluation, and implementation of a complete and comprehensive statewide program of mental health, including community services, receiving and treatment facilities, child services, research, and training as authorized and approved by the Legislature, based on the annual program budget of the department. The department is also responsible for the coordination of efforts with other departments and divisions of the state government, county and municipal governments, and private agencies concerned with and providing mental health services. It is responsible for establishing standards, providing technical assistance, and exercising supervision of mental health programs of, and the treatment of patients at, community facilities, other facilities for persons who have a mental illness, and any agency or facility providing services to patients pursuant to this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publication and distribution of an information handbook to facilitate understanding of this part, the policies and procedures involved in the implementation of this part, and the responsibilities of the various providers of services under this part. It shall stimulate research by public and private agencies, institutions of higher learning, and hospitals in the interest of the elimination and amelioration of mental illness.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWER TO CONTRACT.<EmDash />The department may contract to provide, and be provided with, services and facilities in order to carry out its responsibilities under this part with the following agencies: public and private hospitals; receiving and treatment facilities; clinics; laboratories; departments, divisions, and other units of state government; the state colleges and universities; the community colleges; private colleges and universities; counties, municipalities, and any other governmental unit, including facilities of the United States Government; and any other public or private entity which provides or needs facilities or services. Baker Act funds for community inpatient, crisis stabilization, short-term residential treatment, and screening services must be allocated to each county pursuant to the department’s funding allocation methodology. Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 287.057(3)(f), contracts for community-based Baker Act services for inpatient, crisis stabilization, short-term residential treatment, and screening provided under this part, other than those with other units of government, to be provided for the department must be awarded using competitive sealed bids when the county commission of the county receiving the services makes a request to the department’s district office by January 15 of the contracting year. The district shall not enter into a competitively bid contract under this provision if such action will result in increases of state or local expenditures for Baker Act services within the district. Contracts for these Baker Act services using competitive sealed bids will be effective for 3 years. The department shall adopt rules establishing minimum standards for such contracted services and facilities and shall make periodic audits and inspections to assure that the contracted services are provided and meet the standards of the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION FOR AND ACCEPTANCE OF GIFTS AND GRANTS.<EmDash />The department may apply for and accept any funds, grants, gifts, or services made available to it by any agency or department of the Federal Government or any other public or private agency or individual in aid of mental health programs. All such moneys shall be deposited in the State Treasury and shall be disbursed as provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing forms and procedures relating to the rights and privileges of patients seeking mental health treatment from facilities under this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules necessary for the implementation and administration of the provisions of this part, and a program subject to the provisions of this part shall not be permitted to operate unless rules designed to ensure the protection of the health, safety, and welfare of the patients treated through such program have been adopted. Rules adopted under this subsection must include provisions governing the use of restraint and seclusion which are consistent with recognized best practices and professional judgment; prohibit inherently dangerous restraint or seclusion procedures; establish limitations on the use and duration of restraint and seclusion; establish measures to ensure the safety of program participants and staff during an incident of restraint or seclusion; establish procedures for staff to follow before, during, and after incidents of restraint or seclusion; establish professional qualifications of and training for staff who may order or be engaged in the use of restraint or seclusion; and establish mandatory reporting, data collection, and data dissemination procedures and requirements. Rules adopted under this subsection must require that each instance of the use of restraint or seclusion be documented in the record of the patient.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing minimum standards for services provided by a mental health overlay program or a mobile crisis response service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERSONNEL.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, by rule, establish minimum standards of education and experience for professional and technical personnel employed in mental health programs, including members of a mobile crisis response service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall design and distribute appropriate materials for the orientation and training of persons actively engaged in implementing the provisions of this part relating to the involuntary examination and placement of persons who are believed to have a mental illness.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PAYMENT FOR CARE OF PATIENTS.<EmDash />Fees and fee collections for patients in state-owned, state-operated, or state-supported treatment facilities shall be according to s. 402.33.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 57-317; s. 1, ch. 59-222; s. 1, ch. 65-13; s. 3, ch. 65-22; s. 1, ch. 65-145; s. 1, ch. 67-334; ss. 11, 19, 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 71-131; s. 70, ch. 72-221; s. 2, ch. 72-396; s. 2, ch. 73-133; s. 25, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 74-233; s. 200, ch. 77-147; s. 19, ch. 78-95; s. 3, ch. 78-332; s. 3, ch. 79-298; s. 6, ch. 82-212; s. 4, ch. 84-285; s. 12, ch. 85-54; s. 11, ch. 87-238; s. 2, ch. 90-225; s. 28, ch. 90-347; s. 7, ch. 91-33; s. 22, ch. 91-57; s. 89, ch. 91-221; s. 2, ch. 91-249; s. 11, ch. 93-156; s. 19, ch. 94-134; s. 19, ch. 94-135; s. 15, ch. 95-152; s. 37, ch. 95-228; s. 124, ch. 95-418; s. 3, ch. 96-169; s. 8, ch. 96-268; s. 209, ch. 96-406; s. 123, ch. 96-410; s. 97, ch. 99-8; s. 13, ch. 2001-278; s. 34, ch. 2002-207; s. 1, ch. 2006-29; s. 38, ch. 2006-227; s. 29, ch. 2010-151.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 965.01(3), s. 402.10.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>