<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.66" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent with respect to substance abuse and mental health services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that a recovery and resiliency-based substance abuse and mental health system is implemented by the department and its state-funded mental health providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that mental illness and substance abuse impairment are diseases that are responsive to medical and psychological interventions and management that integrate treatment, rehabilitative, and support services to achieve recovery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and improve the mental health of the citizens of the state by making substance abuse and mental health treatment and support services available to those persons who are most in need and least able to pay, through a community-based system of care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involve local citizens in the planning of substance abuse and mental health services in their communities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the department and the Agency for Health Care Administration work cooperatively in planning and designing comprehensive community-based substance abuse and mental health programs that focus on the individual needs of persons served.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that all activities of the Department of Children and Family Services and the Agency for Health Care Administration, and their respective contract providers, involved in the delivery of substance abuse and mental health treatment and prevention services are coordinated and integrated with other local systems and groups, public and private, such as juvenile justice, criminal justice, child protection, and public health organizations; school districts; and local groups or organizations that focus on services to older adults.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide access to crisis services to all residents of the state with priority of attention being given to individuals exhibiting symptoms of acute mental illness or substance abuse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that services provided to persons with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse problems be integrated across treatment systems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure continuity of care, consistent with minimum standards, for persons who are released from a state treatment facility into the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure continuity of care, consistent with minimum standards, for persons with serious and persistent mental illnesses who are released from a state correctional facility into the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide accountability for service provision through statewide standards for treatment and support services, and statewide standards for management, monitoring, and reporting of information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include substance abuse and mental health services as a component of the integrated service delivery system of the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the districts of the department are the focal point of all substance abuse and mental health planning activities, including budget submissions, grant applications, contracts, and other arrangements that can be effected at the district level.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organize and finance community substance abuse and mental health services in local communities throughout the state through locally administered service delivery programs that are based on client outcomes, are programmatically effective, and are financially efficient, and that maximize the involvement of local citizens.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote best practices and the highest quality of care in contracted alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health services through achievement of national accreditation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the state agencies licensing and monitoring contracted providers perform in the most cost-efficient and effective manner with limited duplication and disruption to organizations providing services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 70-109; s. 30, ch. 75-48; s. 1, ch. 76-221; s. 11, ch. 84-285; s. 101, ch. 99-8; s. 1, ch. 99-396; s. 5, ch. 2000-349; s. 1, ch. 2001-171; s. 3, ch. 2001-191; s. 2, ch. 2006-50.</History></Section>