<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0394.461" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designation of receiving and treatment facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to designate and monitor receiving facilities and treatment facilities and may suspend or withdraw such designation for failure to comply with this part and rules adopted under this part. Unless designated by the department, facilities are not permitted to hold or treat involuntary patients under this part.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECEIVING FACILITY.<EmDash />The department may designate any community facility as a receiving facility. Any other facility within the state, including a private facility or a federal facility, may be so designated by the department, provided that such designation is agreed to by the governing body or authority of the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TREATMENT FACILITY.<EmDash />The department may designate any state-owned, state-operated, or state-supported facility as a state treatment facility. A civil patient shall not be admitted to a state treatment facility without previously undergoing a transfer evaluation. Before a court hearing for involuntary placement in a state treatment facility, the court shall receive and consider the information documented in the transfer evaluation. Any other facility, including a private facility or a federal facility, may be designated as a treatment facility by the department, provided that such designation is agreed to by the appropriate governing body or authority of the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRIVATE FACILITIES.<EmDash />Private facilities designated as receiving and treatment facilities by the department may provide examination and treatment of involuntary patients, as well as voluntary patients, and are subject to all the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility designated as a public receiving or treatment facility under this section shall report to the department on an annual basis the following data, unless these data are currently being submitted to the Agency for Health Care Administration:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of licensed beds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of contract days.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of admissions by payor class and diagnoses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of bed days by payor class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Average length of stay by payor class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total revenues by payor class.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, “payor class” means Medicare, Medicare HMO, Medicaid, Medicaid HMO, private-pay health insurance, private-pay health maintenance organization, private preferred provider organization, the Department of Children and Family Services, other government programs, self-pay patients, and charity care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The data required under this subsection shall be submitted to the department no later than 90 days following the end of the facility’s fiscal year. A facility designated as a public receiving or treatment facility shall submit its initial report for the 6-month period ending June 30, 2008.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue an annual report based on the data required pursuant to this subsection. The report shall include individual facilities’ data, as well as statewide totals. The report shall be submitted to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The department shall adopt rules relating to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures and criteria for receiving and evaluating facility applications for designation, which may include onsite facility inspection and evaluation of an applicant’s licensing status and performance history, as well as consideration of local service needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimum standards consistent with this part that a facility must meet and maintain in order to be designated as a receiving or treatment facility and procedures for monitoring continued adherence to such standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for receiving complaints against a designated facility and for initiating inspections and investigations of facilities alleged to have violated the provisions of this part or rules adopted under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures and criteria for the suspension or withdrawal of designation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 71-131; s. 3, ch. 72-396; s. 5, ch. 73-133; s. 1, ch. 77-90; s. 203, ch. 77-147; s. 6, ch. 79-298; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-384; s. 9, ch. 82-212; s. 7, ch. 84-285; s. 42, ch. 85-167; s. 707, ch. 95-148; s. 13, ch. 96-169; s. 1, ch. 2007-169.</History></Section>