<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0364.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Schedules of rates, tolls, rentals, and charges; filing; public inspection.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every telecommunications company shall publish through electronic or physical media schedules showing the rates, tolls, rentals, and charges of that company for service to be offered within the state. The commission shall have no jurisdiction over the content or form or format of such published schedules. A telecommunications company may, as an option, file the published schedules with the commission or publish its schedules through other reasonably publicly accessible means, including on a website. A telecommunications company that does not file its schedules with the commission shall inform its customers where a customer may view the telecommunications company’s schedules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not prohibit a telecommunications company from:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entering into contracts establishing rates, tolls, rentals, and charges that differ from its published schedules or offering services that are not included in its published schedules; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meeting competitive offerings in a specific geographic market or to a specific customer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to the rates, terms, and conditions established pursuant to 47 U.S.C. ss. 251 and 252.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 6525, 1913; RGS 4396; CGL 6360; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 4, 32, ch. 80-36; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 7, ch. 89-163; ss. 7, 48, 49, ch. 90-244; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 2009-226; s. 10, ch. 2011-36.</History>
</Section>