<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Madison County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Madison County are as follows: Beginning at the point where the west boundary line of lot number one hundred forty-three of fifteenth district Georgia fractions intersects with the Georgia state line and run thence due south along the west boundary line of lots numbers one hundred forty-three and one hundred eighty to the southwest corner of lot one hundred eighty; thence easterly along the south line of lot number one hundred eighty to the east line of section twenty-seven, township three north, range seven east; thence due south to the southeast corner of section ten, township two north, range seven east; thence due west to the southwest corner of said section ten; thence due south to the southeast corner of section sixteen, township two north, range seven east; thence due west to the southwest corner of said section sixteen; thence due south to the southeast corner of section twenty, township two north, range seven east; thence due west to the southwest corner of section nineteen, township two north, range seven east; thence due south to the southeast corner of section twenty-five, township two north, range six east; thence due west to the southwest corner of section twenty-six, township two north, range six east; thence due south to the southwest corner of section thirty-five, township two north, range six east; thence due west to the thread of the Big Aucilla river; thence southerly along the thread of said river to the middle line of township two south, range five east, or the north boundary line of Taylor County; thence east, concurrent with the north boundary line of Taylor County, on said middle township line to the range line dividing ranges eight and nine east; thence south on said range line to the township line dividing townships two and three south; thence east on said township line to the range line dividing ranges nine and ten east, or the northwest corner of Lafayette County; thence east, concurrent with the north boundary line of Lafayette County, on said township line to the thread of the Suwannee River; thence north and easterly, concurrent with the west boundary line of Suwannee County, along the thread of said Suwannee River to where it joins the thread of the Withlacoochee River; thence northerly, concurrent with the west boundary line of Hamilton County, along the thread of the said Withlacoochee River to the boundary line between the States of Georgia and Florida; thence west along said boundary line to the place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Dec. 26, 1827; s. 11, Nov. 23, 1828; s. 1, Feb. 5, 1844; s. 1, ch. 806, 1856; RS 24; GS 22; RGS 24; s. 1, ch. 9361, 1923; CGL 26.</History></Section>