<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.54" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Putnam County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Putnam County are as follows: Beginning at a point on the south side of the Oklawaha River at low watermark where the range line dividing ranges twenty-four and twenty-five east, township eleven south, crosses said river; thence south on said range line to where same intersects the township line dividing townships eleven and twelve south; thence east on said township line to where same intersects the section line dividing sections two and three, township twelve south, range twenty-five east; thence south on said section line and other section lines to the southwest corner of section twenty-three of said township twelve south, range twenty-five east; thence east on the section line dividing sections twenty-three and twenty-six and other sections to the range line dividing ranges twenty-five and twenty-six east; thence south on said range line to the southwest corner of section seven, township thirteen south, range twenty-six east; thence east on the south boundary of said section seven and other sections to the west shore of Lake George; thence southwardly along the shore of Lake George to the mouth of Sulphur Spring; thence to a point on Lake George south of the Spanish Grant, known as the Acosta Grant of land, and on the northern boundary of Volusia County; thence in a direct line and along the northern boundary of Volusia County to the most southern part of Crescent Lake; thence along said northern boundary of Volusia County, following the southeast shore of Crescent Lake, to the mouth of Haw Creek and the boundary of Flagler County; thence westerly and then northwardly along the boundary of Flagler County through the middle of Crescent Lake crossing Bear Island on a line easterly of and parallel to the west line of section nineteen, township twelve south, range twenty-eight east, said line being 10,280 feet easterly, measured at right angles from said west line of section nineteen, which line crosses approximately in the center of Bear Island, then continuing north and westerly through the middle of Crescent Lake, to the range line dividing ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east; thence north on said range line to its intersection with Deep Creek; thence west along the center of Deep Creek to the mouth thereof; thence due west to the west margin of the main channel of the St. Johns River; thence northerly along the west margin of the main channel of said river to the intersection of the south boundary line of township seven south with said river; thence west on said township line to its intersection with the north margin of the Bellamy or federal road leading from St. Augustine to Tallahassee; thence south and westerly along the north margin of said road to the point of intersection with such margin of a northerly extension of the east boundary line of Hillcrest on the Lake, a subdivision, as same appears of record in Plat Book 2, page 52, Public Records of Clay County; thence south along the east boundary line of such subdivision to the southeast corner of such subdivision; thence west along the south boundary line of such subdivision to a point intersecting the north margin of the Bellamy Road; thence south and westerly along the north margin of said road to where same intersects the north boundary of section seventeen, township nine south, range twenty-three east; thence west on the section line between sections eight and seventeen, seven and eighteen, township nine south, range twenty-three east, to the southeast corner of said section seven; thence continue west on the section line between sections twelve and thirteen, township nine south, range twenty-two east to Santa Fe Lake; thence in a southeasterly direction to a point on the range line dividing ranges twenty-two and twenty-three east where said range line is intersected by the Bellamy Road; thence south on said range line to where the same intersects the thread of Orange Creek; thence westerly along the thread of said creek to the intersection of same with the Oklawaha River; thence westerly along the south bank of said river at low watermark to the place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 280, 1849; s. 1, ch. 923, s. 3, ch. 1039, 1859; s. 1, ch. 2068, 1875; s. 1, ch. 3469, 1883; s. 1, ch. 3767, 1887; RS 36; GS 34; s. 1, ch. 5978, 1909; RGS 37; s. 1, ch. 12489, 1927; CGL 39; s. 2, ch. 59-488; s. 2, ch. 84-211.</History></Section>