<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0007.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Glades County.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Glades County are as follows: Beginning at the northwest corner of township forty south, range twenty-eight east; thence east on township line dividing townships thirty-nine and forty south to the southeast corner of township thirty-nine south, range thirty east; thence north on range line dividing ranges thirty and thirty-one east, to the northwest corner of township thirty-nine south, range thirty-one east; thence east on township line dividing townships thirty-eight and thirty-nine south, to the northeast corner of township thirty-nine south, range thirty-one east; thence north on range line dividing ranges thirty-one and thirty-two east, to the northwest corner of township thirty-eight south, range thirty-two east; thence east on township line dividing townships thirty-seven and thirty-eight south, to the intersection of the same with the Kissimmee River, and the western boundary of Okeechobee County; thence southerly along the thread of the Kissimmee River and the western boundary of Okeechobee County, to the mouth of said Kissimmee River; thence in a southerly direction in a straight course to the southeast corner of section twenty-five, being the northeast corner of section thirty-six, township forty south, range thirty-four east; thence southwesterly in a straight course to a point two miles east of the range line between ranges thirty-three and thirty-four east, on the line between townships forty-two and forty-three south; thence west on the township line dividing townships forty-two and forty-three south, to the southwest corner of section thirty-three, township forty-two south, range twenty-nine east; thence north on the section line to the northwest corner of said section thirty-three; thence west to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of section thirty-one, township forty-two south, range twenty-nine east; thence south on the half section line to the township line dividing townships forty-two and forty-three south; thence west on said township line dividing townships forty-two and forty-three south to the southwest corner of township forty-two south, range twenty-eight east; thence north on the range line dividing ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east, concurrent with the eastern boundary of Charlotte County, to the place of beginning.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 3770, 1887; s. 1, ch. 8513, 1921; s. 1, ch. 10596, 1925; CGL 61; s. 1, ch. 18568, 1937; s. 1, ch. 63-200.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 63-391, enlarged the boundaries of Hendry County to include the territory listed in the second paragraph of s. 7.26. Section 2, ch. 63-391, which was compiled as the third paragraph of s. 7.26, provides that the deletion of territory from Glades County and addition to Hendry County “shall not affect the computation of taxes on or from gasoline made pursuant to law.” Chapter 63-391 did not amend s. 7.22 pertaining to Glades County to revise the property description for that county.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>