<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pinellas County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Pinellas County are as follows: Beginning at a point where the line dividing townships twenty-six and twenty-seven south if projected in a westerly direction intersects with the western boundary of the jurisdictional waters of the State of Florida in the Gulf of Mexico; thence east on said line to the northeast corner of section one in township twenty-seven south, range sixteen east; thence south to the shore of old Tampa Bay; thence in a southerly direction through the middle waters of old Tampa Bay and Tampa Bay, to a point in Tampa Bay due east of the north shore of Mullet Key; thence due west to a point due north of a point 100 yards due east from the easternmost point of Mullet Key; thence in a line 100 yards from the shoreline around the southern portion of Mullet Key to a point 100 yards west of the northernmost shore of Mullet Key; thence west to a point where such line intersects the western boundary of the jurisdictional waters of the State of Florida in the Gulf of Mexico and northward, including the waters of said gulf within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to point of beginning; provided however that nothing herein contained shall now or at any time hereafter in any manner whatsoever repeal, amend, change or disturb in any manner whatsoever the apportionment, allotment, allocation, basis of computation, or other formula wherein and whereby the participation in the gas tax by both counties hereto under and by virtue of ss. 206.41 and 206.47 or any law hereafter enacted, is changed so that Hillsborough County would receive a lesser amount and Pinellas County would receive a greater amount of such gas funds or tax by reason of the change of the boundary line herein authorized.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 6247, 1911; RGS 50; CGL 52; s. 1, ch. 19058, 1939; s. 1, ch. 67-601; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-995.</History></Section>