<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duval County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Duval County are as follows: Beginning at the mouth of the Nassau River; thence up the thread of the main stream of said river to the run of Thomas Swamp; thence up the run of said swamp to where same would intersect the prolongation of a line drawn from the southwest corner of township one north, of range twenty-five east, to the southwest corner of township two south, of range twenty-three east; thence on said last-mentioned line in a southwesterly direction to where its extension would intersect the range line dividing ranges twenty-two and twenty-three east; thence south on said range line, concurrent with the Baker County line, to the dividing line between townships three and four south; thence east on said township line, concurrent with the north boundary of Clay County, to its intersection with the easterly limited access right-of-way line of U.S. 17, said point being located south 88°33′33″ west 2.37 feet of the southwest corner of Lot 12, Block 11 of Island View Subdivision, according to the plat thereof recorded in Plat Book 6, page 10, Public Records of Duval County, Florida; thence, along the limited access boundary of State Road 9-A, north 08°45′26″ east 119.74 feet; thence north 38°21′40″ east 165.23 feet; thence north 49°31′32″ east 101.97 feet, thence north 64°29′41″ east 145.12 feet; thence north 83°23′50″ east 290.48 feet to the beginning of a curve concave to the south and having a radius of 22,768.31 feet; thence, from a tangent bearing of south 89°51′51″ east, run easterly 1,466.89 feet along said curve through a central angle of 03°41′29″ to the end of said curve; thence south 86°10′22″ east 891.45 feet; thence south 86°49′27″ east 228.51 feet; thence north 87°54′15″ east 816.30 feet, thence south 86°49′27″ east, to the west margin of the main channel of the St. Johns River; thence southerly along the west margin of the main channel of said river, concurrent with the east boundary of Clay County, to a point where a line drawn due west from the mouth of Julington Creek would intersect said western margin of the main channel of the St. Johns River; thence, concurrent with the north boundary of St. Johns County, due east to the mouth of Julington Creek; thence along the thread of said Julington Creek to the south bank of Durbin Creek; thence eastwardly along the south bank of said Durbin Creek to a point where the range line dividing ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east intersects said south bank; thence south on said range line to the southwest corner of township four south, range twenty-eight east; thence east on the township line dividing townships four and five south to the southeast corner of township four south, range twenty-eight east; thence north on twenty-nine east to a point where an extension of the section line between sections eight and seventeen and sections nine and sixteen, township three south, range twenty-nine east, would intersect said section line; thence east on said section line to the Atlantic Ocean; thence northward along the Atlantic coast, including the waters of said ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to the point of beginning. Excluding from Duval County the following described parcel of land. Begin at the intersection of the north line of township four south with the easterly right-of-way line of State Road 21, also known as Blanding Boulevard, said east right-of-way line bearing north 00°02′42″ west; thence north 52°48′22″ east 2,239.0 feet; thence north 40°33′35″ west 301.54 feet; thence north 24°10′22″ east 40.18 feet to an intersection with the southerly limited access right-of-way line of State Road 9-A, also known as Interstate 295; thence along the southerly and easterly right-of-way line of said State Road 9-A the following 6 courses; thence south 66°10′44″ east 1,883.20 feet to the point of curvature of a curve concave northerly and having a radius of 5,879.578 feet; thence southeasterly 2,592.53 feet along and around said curve through a central angle of 25°15′50″ to the point of tangency of said curve; thence north 88°33′33″ east 3,540.04 feet; thence south 78°13′41″ east 219.09 feet; thence south 61°03′20″ east 233.15 feet; thence south 52°38′29″ east 379.68 feet to an intersection with the northerly line of said township four south; thence departing said right-of-way line, run thence west along said north line of township four south to the point of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Aug. 12, 1822; s. 7, Dec. 29, 1824; s. 5, Nov. 23, 1828; s. 1, ch. 920, 1859; s. 1, ch. 1039, 1859; s. 1, ch. 1185, 1861; s. 1, ch. 2068, 1875; RS 33; GS 31; RGS 33; CGL 35; s. 2, ch. 76-17; s. 2, ch. 80-9.</History></Section>