<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0007.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Palm Beach County.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Palm Beach County are as follows: Beginning on the east boundary of Florida at a point where the south boundary of township forty-seven south, of range forty-three east, produced easterly would intersect the same; thence westerly on said township line to its intersection with the axis or center line of the Hillsborough State Drainage Canal as at present located and constructed; thence westerly along the center line of said canal to its intersection with the range line dividing ranges forty and forty-one east; thence south on the range line dividing ranges forty and forty-one, township forty-seven south, to the northeast corner of section twenty-five of township forty-seven south, range forty east; thence due west on the north boundary of the sections numbered from twenty-five to thirty, inclusive, of townships forty-seven south, ranges thirty-seven to forty east, inclusive, as the same have been surveyed or may hereafter be surveyed by the authority of the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, to the northwest corner of section thirty, township forty-seven south, range thirty-seven east; thence continuing due west to the range line between ranges thirty-four and thirty-five east, and the east boundary of Hendry County; thence north on said range line, concurrent with the east boundary of Hendry County, to the south shore of Lake Okeechobee; thence continuing north on said range line to the northeast corner of section thirty-six, township forty south, range thirty-four east; thence easterly parallel to and one mile north from the township line dividing townships forty and forty-one south to where the south boundary of section twenty-six, township forty south, range thirty-seven east intersects the normal water level on the boundary of Lake Okeechobee; thence east on the south boundary line of said section twenty-six and other sections across ranges thirty-seven, thirty-eight and thirty-nine, forty, forty-one and forty-two east, to the east line of section twenty-eight, township forty south, range forty-two east; thence north on said east section line to the north line of said section twenty-eight; thence east on the section line between sections twenty-two and twenty-seven of township forty south, range forty-two east, and other sections to the waters of the Atlantic Ocean; thence easterly to the eastern boundary of Florida; thence southward along the coast, including the waters of the Atlantic Ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to the place of beginning.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 5970, 1909; s. 1, ch. 6934, 1915; s. 1, ch. 7401, 1917; RGS 59; s. 1, ch. 10090, 1925; s. 1, ch. 10180, 1925; s. 1, ch. 10596, 1925; CGL 65, 73; s. 5, ch. 63-200; ss. 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 2007-222.</History>
</Section>