<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Leon County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Leon County are as follows: Beginning at a point where the range line between ranges two and three east leaves the Wakulla line at the northeast corner of Wakulla County, and the southeast corner of section twenty-five, township two south, range two east; thence north on said range line to the base parallel; thence in a direction northeast to the point where sections twenty-one, twenty-eight and twenty-nine of township one north, range three east, corner; thence north to where the township line between townships one and two north of range three east, is intersected; thence east on said line to the waters of the Miccosukee; thence up Lake Miccosukee to the south boundary line of township three north, range three east; thence on said township line to the line of section thirty-four in said township three; thence due north on the east line of section thirty-four and other sections in said township to the Georgia line; thence west along the Georgia line to where same intersects the thread of the stream of the Ochlockonee River; thence, concurrent with the east boundary line of Gadsden County, southerly along the thread of the stream of the said Ochlockonee River to where the north boundary line of section sixteen in township one south, range four west, intersects said thread of the stream of said Ochlockonee River; thence west to the west bank of said Ochlockonee River; thence southerly along the west bank of the Ochlockonee River to a point where same is intersected by the north line of section twenty, township one south, range four west; thence, concurrent with the east boundary line of Liberty County, southerly along the west bank of said Ochlockonee River to a point where same is intersected by the middle township line of township two south; thence east, concurrent with the north boundary line of Wakulla County, on said middle township line across ranges five, four, three, two, one, west and range one east, to the railroad leading from Tallahassee to St. Marks; thence south along said railroad two sections to the south boundary of section twenty-eight, township two south, range one east; thence east on said south boundary and the south boundary of other sections across ranges one and two east, to the place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, Dec. 29, 1824; s. 14, Nov. 23, 1828; Nov. 14, 1829; ss. 1, 2, Feb. 13, 1831; s. 1, ch. 288, 1849; s. 1, ch. 414, 1851; s. 1, ch. 3176, 1879; s. 1, ch. 3304, 1881; RS 21; GS 19; RGS 21; CGL 23; s. 1, ch. 16436, 1933.</History></Section>