<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Columbia County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Columbia County are as follows: Beginning at the mouth of the Ichetucknee River where it enters the Santa Fe River; thence up the thread of the said Ichetucknee River to Ichetucknee Spring; thence north on the range line dividing ranges fifteen and sixteen east to the section line dividing sections one and twelve and sections two and eleven, township six south, range fifteen east; thence west on said section line to the southwest corner of section two, township six south, range fifteen east; thence north on the section line dividing sections two and three, township six south, range fifteen east, across townships six, five, four, three, and two south, to the thread of the Suwannee River; thence northeast up the thread of said river to the Georgia line; thence along said line to the range line dividing ranges eighteen and nineteen east; thence south on said range line to Olustee Creek; thence southerly down the thread of said creek to the Santa Fe River; thence southwesterly and northwesterly down the thread of said river to its southernmost intersection with the east line of section two, township seven south, range seventeen east; thence south along the east line of said section two to the northeast corner of section eleven, township seven south, range seventeen east; thence south along the east line of said section eleven to the northeast corner of government lot four in said section eleven; thence west along the north line of said government lot four to its northwest corner; thence south along the west line of said government lot four to its southwest corner; thence west along the north line of section fourteen, township seven south, range seventeen east to the northwest corner of said section fourteen; thence south along the west line of said section fourteen to its southwest corner; thence east along the south line of said section fourteen to the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence south and west along the thread of the Santa Fe River to the point of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Feb. 4, 1832; s. 3, ch. 895, 1858; s. 1, ch. 1048, 1859; s. 1, ch. 1391, 1863; s. 1, ch. 3948, 1889; RS 29; GS 27; s. 1, ch. 5979, 1909; RGS 29; CGL 31; s. 3, ch. 28312, 1953.</History></Section>