<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Marion County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Marion County are as follows: Beginning in the thread of the Withlacoochee River, at the range line dividing ranges seventeen and eighteen east; thence north to the township line dividing townships fourteen and fifteen south; thence east on said township line to the middle of township fourteen south, range nineteen east; thence north to the line dividing townships eleven and twelve south; thence east on said township line to Orange Lake; thence down said lake along its southern margin to Orange Creek; thence northerly and easterly down the thread of said creek to its junction with the Oklawaha River; thence northeasterly down the south side of the Oklawaha River at low-water mark to a point on the south side of the Oklawaha River at low-water mark, where the range line dividing ranges twenty-four and twenty-five east in township eleven south, crosses said river; thence south on said range line to where it intersects the township line dividing townships eleven and twelve south; thence east on said township line to where it intersects the section line dividing sections two and three, in township twelve south, of range twenty-five east; thence south on said section line and other section lines to the southwest corner of section twenty-three of said township twelve south, of range twenty-five east; thence east on the section line dividing sections twenty-three and twenty-six and other section lines to the range line dividing ranges twenty-five and twenty-six east; thence south on said range line to the southwest corner of section seven, township thirteen south, range twenty-six east; thence east on the section line dividing sections seven and eighteen, township thirteen south, range twenty-six east, and other section lines to the west shore of Lake George; thence southwardly along the shore of Lake George to the mouth of Sulphur Spring; thence along the western bank of Lake George until it arrives at range line dividing ranges twenty-six and twenty-seven east; thence south on said range line to township line dividing townships seventeen and eighteen south; thence due west on the said township line to the thread of the Withlacoochee River; thence northwesterly down the thread of said last mentioned river to the place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Mar. 14, 1844; s. 1, ch. 106, 1846; s. 1, ch. 548, 1853; s. 1, ch. 923, 1859; s. 1, ch. 3060, 1877; s. 1, ch. 3767, 1887; RS 39; GS 37; RGS 40; CGL 42.</History></Section>