<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alachua County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Alachua County are as follows: Begin where the range line between ranges sixteen and seventeen east intersects the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence run south on said range line to the southwest corner of section seven, township eleven south, range seventeen east; thence run east along the south line of sections seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven and twelve to the northwest corner of section eighteen, township eleven south, range eighteen east; thence run south along the west line of sections eighteen, nineteen, thirty and thirty-one, township eleven south, range eighteen east to southwest corner of said section thirty-one; thence run east along south line of sections thirty-one, thirty-two, thirty-three and thirty-four to southeast corner of section thirty-four, township eleven south, range eighteen east outside of Arredonda Grant; thence run north along east line of said section thirty-four to southwest corner of section thirty-four, township eleven south, range eighteen east inside said grant; thence run east along the township line between townships eleven and twelve, south, to its intersection with the west margin of Orange Lake; thence following the western and southern margin of Orange Lake to its intersection with the range line between range twenty-two and twenty-three east; thence run north along said range line to where same is intersected by the north and east margin of Santa Fe Lake; thence run north following the east margin of said Santa Fe Lake to its westernmost intersection with a line which is the prolongation of the north line of McManus Subdivision as per plat book “A”, page 117 of the public records of Alachua County; thence west along the north line of said subdivision to its intersection with the east line of government lot three of section twenty-one, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence north along said east line to the southeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section twenty-one; thence north along the line between the east half and the west half of the northwest quarter of said section twenty-one to the north line of said section twenty-one; thence west along the north line of said section twenty-one to the southeast corner of section seventeen, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the southeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence west to the southwest corner of the east half of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the northwest corner of the east half of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence west to the southwest corner of the northwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the half-mile corner of the south line of section eight, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the east half of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of said section eight; thence north to the northwest corner of the east half of the northeast quarter of the northwest quarter of said section eight; thence north to the northeast corner of the west half of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of section five, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said section five; thence north along the west line of said section five to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section six, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section six; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section six; thence west along the north line of said section six to the northwest corner of said section six; thence north along the east line of section one, township eight south, range twenty-one east to the southeast corner of section thirty-six, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north along the east line of said section thirty-six to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said section thirty-six; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said section thirty-six; thence north along the west line of said section thirty-six to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence northerly and westerly along the thread of the Santa Fe River to its intersection with the east line of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of section thirty-three, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section thirty-three; thence west to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section thirty-two, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section thirty-two; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section thirty-one, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section thirty-one; thence west to the half-mile corner of the south line of section thirty, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north on the quarter section line of said section thirty to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence southerly and westerly along the thread of said Santa Fe River to its intersection with the south line of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of section twenty-eight, township seven south, range twenty east; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty-eight; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty-eight; thence west to the northwest corner of said section twenty-eight; thence north along the east line of section twenty, township seven south, range twenty east to the southeast corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty; thence west on the quarter section line of said section twenty to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence northerly and westerly along the thread of the Santa Fe River to its southernmost intersection with the east line of section two, township seven south, range seventeen east; thence run south along the east line of said section two to the northeast corner of section eleven, township seven south, range seventeen east; thence run south along the east line of said section eleven to the northeast corner of government lot four in said section eleven; thence run west to the northwest corner of said government lot four; thence run south along west line of said government lot four to the southwest corner of said government lot four; thence run west along the south line of said section eleven to the northwest corner of section fourteen, township seven south, range seventeen east; thence run south along the west line of said section fourteen to the southwest corner of said section fourteen; thence run east along south line of said section fourteen to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence run southerly and westerly along the thread of said river to the point of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, Dec. 29, 1824; s. 3, Nov. 23, 1828; s. 1, Feb. 10, 1835; s. 1, ch. 106, 1846; s. 1, ch. 923, 1859; s. 1, ch. 1765, 1870; RS 38; GS 36; s. 1, ch. 6243, 1911; s. 1, ch. 6509, 1913; RGS 39; s. 1, ch. 11371, 1925 CGL 41; s. 1, ch. 28312, 1953.</History></Section>