<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">St. Johns County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of St. Johns County are as follows: Beginning at a point on the Atlantic coast, at a point where the section line between ten and fifteen, in township three south of range twenty-nine east, intersects the said Atlantic coast; thence west on the said section line to a point where said section line would intersect the range line between ranges twenty-eight and twenty-nine east; thence south on said range line to a point where said range line intersects the township line between townships four and five south; thence west on the township line between townships four and five south, in range twenty-eight east, to a point where said township line intersects the range line between ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east; thence north on said range line to where the same intersects Durbin Creek; thence along the south bank of Durbin Creek to Julington Creek; thence along the thread of Julington Creek to the mouth thereof; thence due west to the west margin of the main channel of the St. Johns River and boundary line of Clay County; thence southwardly along the west margin of the main channel of said river and boundaries of Clay and Putnam Counties to a point due west of the mouth of Deep Creek; thence due east to the mouth of Deep Creek; thence up the center of Deep Creek to the point of intersection of Deep Creek with the range lines between ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east; thence south on said range line to a point where the south boundary line of section eighteen, in township ten south, range twenty-eight east, intersects said range line; thence east on said section line to the range line between ranges twenty-nine and thirty east; thence north on said range line to the middle of Pellicer’s Creek; thence easterly on an imaginary line down the middle of said creek to the mouth of said creek; thence northeasterly on an imaginary line extending from the mouth of Pellicer’s Creek to a point on the extension of township line between townships nine and ten south, range thirty-one east and immediately north of Summer Haven on the Atlantic coast; thence northwardly along said Atlantic coast, including the waters of the Atlantic Ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Ord. July 21, 1821; s. 1, Aug. 12, 1822; s. 9, Dec. 29, 1824; s. 1, ch. 289, 1848; s. 1, ch. 2068, 1875; RS 35; GS 33; s. 1, ch. 5730, 1907; s. 1, ch. 7399, 1917; RGS 35; CGL 37.</History></Section>