<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Flagler County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Flagler County are as follows: Beginning on the township line between townships nine and ten south at a point directly north of Summer Haven; thence southwesterly to the mouth of Pellicer’s Creek; thence westerly along the middle of Pellicer’s Creek to a point where said creek intersects the range line between ranges twenty-nine and thirty east; thence south on said range line to the southeast corner of section thirteen, township ten south, range twenty-nine east; thence west on the south boundary of said section thirteen and other sections to the range line between ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east; thence south on said range line to the township line between townships eleven and twelve south; thence south and easterly through the middle of Crescent Lake crossing Bear Island on a line easterly of and parallel to the west line of section nineteen, township twelve south, range twenty-eight east, said line being ten thousand two hundred eighty feet easterly, measured at right angles from said west line of section nineteen, which line crosses approximately in the center of Bear Island, then continuing south and easterly through the middle of said lake to the mouth of Haw Creek; thence due east to a point where said creek is intersected by the range line between ranges twenty-eight and twenty-nine east; thence south on said range line to the southwest corner of section nineteen, township fourteen south, range twenty-nine east; thence east on the south line of said section nineteen and other sections to the southeast corner of section twenty-two, township fourteen south, range thirty-one east; thence north on the east line of said section twenty-two and other sections to the township line between townships twelve and thirteen south; thence east on said township line to a point where same is intersected by the King’s Road; thence northerly along said King’s Road to a point where the line dividing the Bulow and Ormond Grants intersects said road; thence along the said line between the said two grants in a northeasterly direction across Bulow Creek; thence following a continuance of this line, being the line dividing the lots seven and eight of the subdivision of the Bulow Grant, to the intersection with the Haulover or Smith Creek; thence along said Haulover or Smith Creek to the intersection of the line running east between sections thirty and thirty-one, and twenty-nine and thirty-two, township twelve south, range thirty-two east; thence along said line to the Atlantic Coast; thence northerly along the shore of the Atlantic Ocean, including the waters of said ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to the point of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7399, 1917; RGS 36; CGL 38; s. 1, ch. 59-488.</History></Section>