<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bradford County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county lines of Bradford County are as follows: Beginning at a point where the thread of New River intersects the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence northeasterly concurrent with the east boundary of Union County following the meanderings of the said New River to where same is intersected by the middle township line of township four south, range twenty-two east; thence east on said middle township line to the range line between ranges twenty-two and twenty-three east; thence south on said range line to the southeast corner of section twelve, township nine south, range twenty-two east; thence west on the section line between section twelve and thirteen, township nine south, range twenty-two east to Santa Fe Lake; thence northwesterly following the northeast shore of Santa Fe Lake to its westernmost intersection with a line which is the prolongation of the north line of McManus Subdivision as per plat book “A,” page 117 of the public records of Alachua County; thence west along the north line of said subdivision to its intersection with the east line of government lot three of section twenty-one, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence north along said east line to the southeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section twenty-one; thence north along the lines between the east half and the west half of the northwest quarter of said section twenty-one to the north line of said section twenty-one; thence west along the north line of said section twenty-one to the southeast corner of section seventeen, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the southeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence west to the southwest corner of the east half of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the northwest corner of the east half of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence west to the southwest corner of the northwest quarter of the northeast quarter of said section seventeen; thence north to the half-mile corner on the south line of section eight, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the east half of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of said section eight; thence north to the northwest corner of the east half of the northeast quarter of the northwest quarter of said section eight; thence north to the northeast corner of the west half of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of section five, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said section five; thence north along the west line of said section five to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section six, township eight south, range twenty-two east; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section six; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section six; thence west along the north line of said section six to the northwest corner of said section six; thence north along the east line of section one, township eight south, range twenty-one east to the southeast corner of section thirty-six, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north along the east line of said section thirty-six to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of said section thirty-six; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of said section thirty-six; thence north along the west line of said section thirty-six to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence northerly and westerly along the thread of the Santa Fe River to its intersection with the east line of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of section thirty-three, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section thirty-three; thence west to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section thirty-two, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of said section thirty-two; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section thirty-one, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of said section thirty-one; thence west to the half-mile corner on the south line of section thirty, township seven south, range twenty-one east; thence north on the quarter section line of said section thirty to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence southerly and westerly along the thread of said Santa Fe River to its intersection with the south line of the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter of section twenty-eight, township seven south, range twenty east; thence west to the southwest corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty-eight; thence north to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty-eight; thence west to the northwest corner of said section twenty-eight; thence north along the east line of section twenty, township seven south, range twenty east to the southeast corner of the northeast quarter of said section twenty; thence west on the quarter section line of said section twenty to its intersection with the thread of the Santa Fe River; thence northerly and westerly along the thread of said Santa Fe River to the point of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, Mar. 15, 1844; s. 3, ch. 895, 1858; s. 1, ch. 1039, 1859; s. 1, ch. 1185, 1861; s. 1, ch. 1300, 1861; s. 1, ch. 1765, 1870; RS 30; GS 28; RGS 20; s. 1, ch. 8516, 1921; CGL 32; s. 2, ch. 28312, 1953.</History></Section>