<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0007.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hendry County.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Hendry County are as follows: Beginning where the north line of township forty-three south, intersects the range line between ranges twenty-seven and twenty-eight east, at the line between Charlotte and Glades Counties; thence south on said range line to the north line of township forty-six south; thence east on the north line of township forty-six south, to the east line of range thirty east; thence south on said east line of range thirty east, to the north line of township forty-nine south; thence east on said north line of township forty-nine south, to the east line of range thirty-four east, and the west boundary of Broward County; thence north on said east line of range thirty-four east, concurrent with the west boundary of Broward and Palm Beach Counties, to where said east line intersects the south shore of Lake Okeechobee; thence due north on said east line of range thirty-four east, to the northeast corner of section thirty-six, township forty south, range thirty-four east; thence southwesterly in a straight course to a point two miles east of the range line between ranges thirty-three and thirty-four east, on the line between townships forty-two and forty-three south; thence west on the north line of township forty-three south, to the southwest corner of section thirty-three, township forty-two south, range twenty-nine east; thence north on the west line of said section thirty-three to the northwest corner of said section thirty-three; thence west on the north boundary line of sections thirty-two and thirty-one of township forty-two south, range twenty-nine east, to the northwest corner of the northeast quarter of section thirty-one in said township and range; thence south on the middle section line of said section thirty-one to the north line of township forty-three south; thence west on said township line to the place of beginning.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The existing boundaries of Hendry County are hereby enlarged and extended so as to comprise and include the following described additional territory: Begin on the county line between Hendry and Glades County, on the south line of Section 36, Township 42 South, Range 29 East, at a point 2572.81 feet westerly of the southeast corner of said Section 36, thence from a tangent bearing of north 73 °20′59″ East run northeasterly along a curve concaved to the southeast having a radius of 1196.28 feet through a central angle of 16°37′14″ for a distance of 347.02 feet to the end of curve; thence North 89°58′13″ East 2230.64 feet to east line of Section 36, Township 42 South, Range 29 East; thence North 89°58′13″ East 2563.80 feet; thence North 89°55′43″ East 1170.63 feet; thence North 89°57′23″ East 3029.37 feet; thence North 89°54′53″ East 3900.00 feet; thence North 89°56′53″ East 4114.17 feet; thence North 89°55′53″ East 2612.89 feet; thence North 89°54′08″ East 6272.94 feet; thence North 89°52′53″ East 3411.00 feet; thence South 89°45′26″ East 2789.00 feet; thence South 89°47′46″ East 700.00 feet; thence South 89°45′26″ East 1300.00 feet; thence South 89°53′26″ East 95.20 feet to the east line of Section 36, Township 42 South, Range 30 East, at a point 5259.75 feet south of the northeast corner of said Section 36; thence continue South 89°53′26″ East 3340.50 feet; thence South 89°56′11″ East 4664.30 feet; thence South 89°57′11″ East 1500.00 feet; thence South 89°59′31″ East 2000.00 feet; thence South 89°57′11″ East 1064.05 feet; thence South 89°58′11″ East 2493.95 feet; thence North 89°53′49″ East 4142.00 feet; thence North 89°55′09″ East 2234.94 feet to the east line of Section 34, Township 42 South, Range 31 East, at a point 5229.50 feet South of the northeast corner of said Section 34; thence continue North 89°55′09″ East 5.38 feet; thence South 89°43′31″ East 3859.68 feet; thence South 89°41′51″ East 1390.84 feet to the west line of Section 36, Township 42 South, Range 31 East, at a point 5251.30 feet south of the northwest corner of said Section 36; thence continue South 89°41′51″ East 5083.59 feet to beginning of curve concaved to the southwest having a radius of 1196.28 feet and a central angle of 18°05′19″; thence southeasterly along said curve a distance of 377.67 feet to its intersection with the south line of Section 36, Township 42 South, Range 31 East on the county line between Glades and Hendry Counties.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Such deletion from Glades County and addition to Hendry County shall not affect the computation of taxes on or from gasoline made pursuant to law.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 9360, 1923; s. 1, ch. 10090, 1925; CGL 72, 73; s. 1, ch. 18568, 1937; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 2, ch. 63-200; ss. 1, 2, ch. 63-391.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1, ch. 63-391, enlarged the boundaries of Hendry County to include the territory listed in the second paragraph of s. 7.26. Section 2, ch. 63-391, which was compiled as the third paragraph of s. 7.26, provides that the deletion of territory from Glades County and addition to Hendry County “shall not affect the computation of taxes on or from gasoline made pursuant to law.” Chapter 63-391 did not amend s. 7.22 pertaining to Glades County to revise the property description for that county.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>