<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.35" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lake County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Lake County are as follows: Beginning at the intersection of the range line dividing ranges twenty-three and twenty-four east with the township line dividing townships twenty-four and twenty-five south; thence east on said township line to the range line dividing ranges twenty-four and twenty-five east; thence north on said range line to the section line dividing sections thirty and thirty-one, in township twenty-four south, range twenty-five east; thence east on the north line of sections thirty-one, thirty-two, thirty-three and thirty-four in said township twenty-four south, range twenty-five east, to the northeast corner of said section thirty-four; thence south on the east line of said section thirty-four to the township line dividing townships twenty-four and twenty-five south; thence east on said township line to the range line dividing ranges twenty-six and twenty-seven east; thence north to the south shore of Lake Apopka; thence north across the waters of Lake Apopka, taking in all islands and peninsulas along the west shore of said lake to the north shore of Lake Apopka where it is intersected by the range line dividing ranges twenty-six and twenty-seven east; thence north on said range line to the township line dividing townships nineteen and twenty south; thence east on said township line to the Wekiva River; thence north along the thread of the said Wekiva River to the St. Johns River; thence in a northerly and northwesterly direction through the thread of the St. Johns River to the southwest shore of Lake George; thence north along the west shore of Lake George to the range line dividing ranges twenty-six and twenty-seven east; thence south on said range line to the township line dividing townships seventeen and eighteen south; thence west on the said township line to the range line dividing ranges twenty-three and twenty-four east; thence south on the said range line to the place of beginning; and all of township twenty south, of range twenty-seven east, bounded on the south and east by the waters of Lake Beauclaire, shall be and are declared to be a part of the territory of Lake County.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 3771, 1887; s. 1, ch. 3944, 1889; s. 1, ch. 4066, 1891; RS 42; GS 40; RGS 44; CGL 46.</History></Section>