<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0007.67" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Washington County.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Washington County are as follows: Beginning on the Choctawhatchee River on the line dividing townships four and five north; thence east on said township line to northwest corner of section four in township four north, thence east on said township line to northwest corner of section four in township four north, range fifteen west; thence south one mile on section line to the southwest corner of section four, township four north, range fifteen west; thence east one mile to southeast corner of section four, township four north, range fifteen west; thence south on section lines two miles to the southwest corner of section fifteen, township four north, range fifteen west; thence east on section lines to Holmes Creek; thence northward along the thread of Holmes Creek to a point where said creek intersects with section line running east and west between sections thirteen and twenty-four, fourteen and twenty-three in township five north, range fourteen west; thence east on said section line to the northeast corner of section twenty-four, township five north, range thirteen west; thence south on range line between ranges twelve and thirteen west to where said range line intersects with township line between townships four and five north; thence east on said township line to the southeast corner of section thirty-three, township five north, range twelve west; thence south on the section line to southwest corner of section fifteen, township two north, range twelve west; thence west on the section line to the southwest corner of section eighteen, township two north, range twelve west; thence south on the range line between ranges twelve and thirteen west to the meridian base line; thence west on the base line to the thread of Pine Log Creek in range sixteen west; thence down the thread of said creek into the Choctawhatchee River to the thread of said river; thence up the thread of said river to the place of beginning.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, Dec. 9, 1825; s. 2, Oct. 29, 1828; s. 1, ch. 108, 1847; s. 2, ch. 180, 1847; s. 1, ch. 1950, 1873; s. 1, ch. 3258, 1881; RS 15; s. 1, ch. 4236, 1893; s. 1, ch. 4577, 1897; GS 13; s. 1, ch. 6505, 1913; ss. 1, 2, ch. 6935, 1915; RGS 14; CGL 16.</History></Section>