<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0007.43" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Martin County.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The boundary lines of Martin County are as follows: Beginning at the northwest corner of township thirty-eight south, range thirty-seven east; thence east, concurrent with the south boundary line of St. Lucie County, to the southwest corner of section thirty-one, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east; thence north on the west line of said section thirty-one and other sections to the northwest corner of section eighteen, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east; thence east on the north line of said section eighteen and other sections to the waters of the Atlantic Ocean; thence easterly to the eastern boundary of the State of Florida; thence southward along the coast, including the waters of the Atlantic Ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to the south line of section twenty, township forty south, range forty-three east, produced easterly; thence west on the south line of said section twenty, and other sections, to the southwest corner of section twenty-two, township forty south, range forty-two east; thence south on the east line of section twenty-eight, township forty south, range forty-two east, to the southeast corner of said section twenty-eight; thence west on the south line of said section twenty-eight and other sections to the east shore of Lake Okeechobee; thence continue west in a straight course to the northeast corner of section thirty-six, township forty south, range thirty-four east, being the southwest corner of section thirty, township forty south, range thirty-five east; thence northeasterly in a straight course to the line of normal water level on the boundary of Lake Okeechobee at its intersection with the line dividing ranges thirty-six and thirty-seven east, township thirty-eight south; thence north on said range line to the place of beginning.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 10180, 1925; CGL 77; s. 3, ch. 63-200; s. 1, ch. 2012-45.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 5, ch. 2012-45, provides that “[u]pon approval by a majority vote of those qualified electors residing in the area being transferred from St. Lucie County to Martin County as described in section 1 voting in a referendum to be held by the Board of County Commissioners of St. Lucie County and conducted by the Supervisor of Elections of St. Lucie County in conjunction with the next general, special, or other election to be held in St. Lucie County, in accordance with the provisions of law relating to elections currently in force, this act shall take effect July 1, 2013.” Contingent upon that approval, s. 1, ch. 2012-45, amended s. 7.43, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">7.43 Martin County.</Font><EmDash/>The boundary lines of Martin County are as follows: Beginning at the northwest corner of township thirty-eight south, range thirty-seven east; thence east, concurrent with the south boundary line of St. Lucie County, to the southwest corner of section thirty-one, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east; thence north on the west line of said section thirty-one and section thirty, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east, 6,459 feet to a point lying within the water body of the north fork of the St. Lucie River; thence departing said line within the north fork of the St. Lucie River a bearing direction (State Plane Coordinate System, Florida East Zone) of 41 degrees north, 4 minutes west, a distance of 6,155 feet, more or less, to a point lying within the water body of the north fork of the St. Lucie River; thence departing said point a bearing direction (State Plane Coordinate System, Florida East Zone) of 45 degrees north, 16 minutes east, a distance of 2,355 feet, more or less, to a point intersecting with the north shore of the north fork of the St. Lucie River and the west edge of the Howard Creek as concurrent with the City of Port St. Lucie municipal boundary limits; thence departing said intersecting shore and edge lines following along the City of Port St. Lucie municipal boundary line north along the west edge of Howard Creek to the south line of the northeast quarter of section twenty-four, township thirty-seven south, range forty east; thence east along said south line of the northeast quarter to the intersection of the east 924.15 feet of section twenty-four, township thirty-seven south, range forty east; thence north along said east 924.15-foot line of section twenty-four, township thirty-seven south, range forty east, to the intersection of the north line of the south 508.15 feet of the northeast quarter of section twenty-four, township thirty-seven south, range forty east; thence east along said south 508.15-foot line of the northeast quarter of said section twenty-four, township thirty-seven south, range forty east, to an intersection with the west line of township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east, also being the existing Martin County boundary line; thence north concurrent with the Martin County boundary line, along the west line of sections nineteen and eighteen, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east, to the northwest corner of section eighteen, township thirty-seven south, range forty-one east; thence east on the north line of said section eighteen and other sections to the waters of the Atlantic Ocean; thence easterly to the eastern boundary of the State of Florida; thence southward along the coast, including the waters of the Atlantic Ocean within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida, to the south line of section twenty, township forty south, range forty-three east, produced easterly; thence west on the south line of said section twenty, and other sections, to the southwest corner of section twenty-two, township forty south, range forty-two east; thence south on the east line of section twenty-eight, township forty south, range forty-two east, to the southeast corner of said section twenty-eight; thence west on the south line of said section twenty-eight and other sections to the east shore of Lake Okeechobee; thence continue west in a straight course to the northeast corner of section thirty-six, township forty south, range thirty-four east, being the southwest corner of section thirty, township forty south, range thirty-five east; thence northeasterly in a straight course to the line of normal water level on the boundary of Lake Okeechobee at its intersection with the line dividing ranges thirty-six and thirty-seven east, township thirty-eight south; thence north on said range line to the place of beginning.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 3, ch. 2012-45, provides that “[a]ll public roads, and the public rights-of-way associated therewith, lying within the limits of the lands being incorporated into Martin County as described in sections 1 and 2 are transferred from the jurisdiction of St. Lucie County to the jurisdiction of Martin County on the effective date of the change in county boundaries pursuant to this act.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 4, ch. 2012-45, provides that “[t]he governing bodies of St. Lucie County and Martin County shall enter into an interlocal agreement no later than May 1, 2013, which shall provide a financially feasible plan for transfer of services, personnel, and public infrastructure from St. Lucie County to Martin County. The agreement shall include compensation for the value of infrastructure investments by St. Lucie County in the transferred property minus depreciation, if any. Upon the effective date of this act, the total tax and assessment revenue that would have been generated in fiscal year 2013-2014 by all St. Lucie County taxing authorities levying taxes or assessments within the area transferred to Martin County less 10 percent shall be transmitted to St. Lucie County for distribution to the county and all other affected taxing authorities. Thereafter, through fiscal year 2022-2023, the tax and assessment revenue amount that would have been generated by all St. Lucie County taxing authorities levying taxes or assessments in the transferred area for fiscal year 2013-2014 shall serve as the base amount of tax and assessment revenue for further annual reductions of 10 percent of the base amount before annual distributions to the St. Lucie County through fiscal year 2022-2023. However, for any fiscal year through fiscal year 2022-2023 when the total taxes and assessments collected within the transferred area exceed the base amount by more than 3 percent, St. Lucie County shall receive the same percentage distribution from the tax and assessment revenue that exceeds the base amount by more than 3 percent as they will receive from the base amount. All distributions to St. Lucie County shall occur within 30 days after the beginning of each calendar year.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>