<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0525.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of department; inspections; unlawful acts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall inspect all measuring devices used in selling or distributing petroleum fuel at wholesale and retail.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall define, by rule, the tolerances to be allowed, in excess or deficiency, on all measuring devices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons who own or operate a petroleum fuel measuring device shall be responsible for ensuring accurate measure by the device within the tolerances defined by the rule. An appropriate security seal shall be placed on all measuring devices found to be giving accurate measure within the tolerances defined by the department in such a way that the metering adjustment cannot be changed without breaking the seal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any measuring device that is found to be operating outside the tolerances defined by the department shall be deemed inaccurate and the department, at its discretion, shall either:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give, in writing, the operator or owner of the measuring device a reasonable time to repair the measuring device; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Condemn or prohibit the further use of the measuring device by using an appropriate security seal to obstruct the mechanism so that it cannot be operated without breaking the seal. The measuring device shall not be operated in this state again without the written consent of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person to operate any measuring device that has been condemned or prohibited from further use by the department, without the written consent of the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person to install or operate a petroleum fuel measuring device in this state which gives short measure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to break, cut, or remove any seal applied by the department to a petroleum fuel measuring device or container. If it becomes necessary to repair and adjust a petroleum fuel measuring device during the absence of an inspector of the department, the seal on the meter adjustment may be broken by a person who is registered with the department as a meter mechanic. After repairs and adjustments have been made, the adjusting mechanism must immediately be resealed by the registered meter mechanic with a seal clasp bearing at least the name or initials of the registered mechanic. The registered mechanic shall immediately notify the department of this action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons and service agencies that repair or install petroleum fuel measuring devices must register with the department on forms provided by the department. Any registered person or agency that has installed a petroleum fuel measuring device must report the existence of the petroleum fuel measuring device to the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a vendor has a petroleum fuel measuring device installed by any person or agency that is not registered by the department, that owner must report the existence of the newly installed petroleum fuel measuring device to the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons and service agencies that adjust the accuracy of a petroleum fuel measuring device must use test measures that have been calibrated with standards traceable to the National Institute of Standards and Technology within 1 year prior to the date of the adjustment for volumes of less than 500 gallons and within 3 years before the date of the adjustment for volumes of 500 gallons or more.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 7905, 1919; s. 2, ch. 10134, 1925; CGL 3963, 8119, 8120, 8121, 8122; s. 1, ch. 21883, 1943; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 505, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 71-152; s. 72, ch. 92-291; s. 3, ch. 94-335; s. 1, ch. 98-38; s. 6, ch. 2007-232; s. 26, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>