<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.282" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pilot program for the transition to electronic and digital instructional materials.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A district school board may designate pilot program schools to implement the transition to instructional materials that are in an electronic or a digital format as defined in s. 1006.29(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A district school board may designate pilot program schools if the school district:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implements a local instructional improvement system pursuant to s. 1006.281 which enables district staff to plan, create, and manage professional development and to connect professional development with staff information and student performance, provides the ability to seamlessly connect the system to electronic and digital instructional materials and the instructional materials to student assessment data, and includes the minimum standards published by the Department of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requests only the electronic or digital format of the sample copies of instructional materials submitted pursuant to s. 1006.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses at least 50 percent of the pilot program school’s annual allocation from the district for the purchase of electronic or digital instructional materials included on the state-adopted list.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A school designated as a pilot program school by the school board is exempt from:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1006.40(2)(a), if the school provides comprehensive electronic or digital instructional materials to all students; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 1006.37.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By August 1 of each year, beginning in 2011, the school board must report to the Department of Education the school or schools in its district which have been designated as pilot program schools. The department shall publish the list of pilot program schools on the department’s Internet website. The report must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the pilot program school, the contact person and contact person information, and the grade or grades and associated course or courses included in the pilot program school.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the type of technological tool or tools that will be used to access the electronic or digital instructional materials included in the pilot program school, whether district-owned or student-owned.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The projected costs and funding sources, which must include cost savings or cost avoidances, associated with the pilot program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By September 1 of each year, beginning in 2012, each school board that has a designated pilot program school shall provide to the Department of Education, the Executive Office of the Governor, and the chairs of the appropriations committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives a review of the pilot program schools which must include, but need not be limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Successful practices;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average amount of online Internet time needed by a student to access and use the school’s electronic or digital instructional materials;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lessons learned;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The level of investment and cost-effectiveness; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impacts on student performance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 2011-55.</History>
</Section>