<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specified university publications; activities; trust funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the approval of the appropriate university, the Florida Law Review, the Florida State University Law Review, the Florida State University Journal of Land Use and Environmental Law, the University of Florida Journal of Law and Public Policy, and the Florida International Law Journal of the University of Florida are authorized to engage in the following activities relating to their respective publications, notwithstanding the contrary provision of any statute, rule, or regulation of the state or its subdivisions or agencies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grant of reprint rights relating to any or all issues of the Florida Law Review, the Florida State University Law Review, the Florida State University Journal of Land Use and Environmental Law, the University of Florida Journal of Law and Public Policy, or the Florida International Law Journal of the University of Florida, or any of the materials, articles, or ideas contained therein;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale for adequate consideration of any or all past or future stock and inventory of published issues of the Florida Law Review, the Florida State University Law Review, the Florida State University Journal of Land Use and Environmental Law, the University of Florida Journal of Law and Public Policy, or the Florida International Law Journal of the University of Florida, or portions thereof; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The retention of the proceeds obtained under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) together with all moneys received by the Florida Law Review or the Florida State University Law Review from current or future subscriptions, sale of individual issues, sale of advertising, binding service, royalties, donations, and all other sources except direct or indirect appropriations from the state, its subdivisions, or agencies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys retained by the Florida Law Review pursuant to this section shall be placed in a trust fund to be known as the Florida Law Review Trust Fund. Moneys retained by the Florida State University Law Review pursuant to this section shall be placed in a trust fund to be known as the Florida State University Law Review Trust Fund. Moneys retained by the Florida State University Journal of Land Use and Environmental Law pursuant to this section shall be placed in a trust fund to be known as the Florida State University Journal of Land Use and Environmental Law Trust Fund. Moneys retained by the University of Florida Journal of Law and Public Policy pursuant to this section shall be placed in a trust fund to be known as the University of Florida Journal of Law and Public Policy Trust Fund. Moneys retained by the Florida International Law Journal of the University of Florida pursuant to this section shall be placed in a trust fund to be known as the Florida International Law Journal of the University of Florida Trust Fund. Such trust funds shall be used to pay or supplement the payment of printing costs or other costs incident to the publication of the respective law reviews and law journals and shall be administered by the dean of each college of law or his or her faculty designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Printing of such publications shall be let upon contract to the lowest responsive bidder, in accordance with s. 283.33, except when the additional costs incurred in changing from the current printer to the new low bidder exceed the savings reflected in the bid prices. Such additional costs shall not exceed 10 percent of the lowest bid price.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 326, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>