<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">School resource officers and school safety officers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school boards may establish school resource officer programs, through a cooperative agreement with law enforcement agencies or in accordance with subsection (2).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School resource officers shall be certified law enforcement officers, as defined in s. 943.10(1), who are employed by a law enforcement agency as defined in s. 943.10(4). The powers and duties of a law enforcement officer shall continue throughout the employee’s tenure as a school resource officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School resource officers shall abide by district school board policies and shall consult with and coordinate activities through the school principal, but shall be responsible to the law enforcement agency in all matters relating to employment, subject to agreements between a district school board and a law enforcement agency. Activities conducted by the school resource officer which are part of the regular instructional program of the school shall be under the direction of the school principal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School safety officers shall be law enforcement officers, as defined in s. 943.10(1), certified under the provisions of chapter 943 and employed by either a law enforcement agency or by the district school board. If the officer is employed by the district school board, the district school board is the employing agency for purposes of chapter 943, and must comply with the provisions of that chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A district school board may commission one or more school safety officers for the protection and safety of school personnel, property, and students within the school district. The district school superintendent may recommend and the district school board may appoint one or more school safety officers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A school safety officer has and shall exercise the power to make arrests for violations of law on district school board property and to arrest persons, whether on or off such property, who violate any law on such property under the same conditions that deputy sheriffs are authorized to make arrests. A school safety officer has the authority to carry weapons when performing his or her official duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A district school board may enter into mutual aid agreements with one or more law enforcement agencies as provided in chapter 23. A school safety officer’s salary may be paid jointly by the district school board and the law enforcement agency, as mutually agreed to.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 282, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>