<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of instructional materials allocation; instructional materials, library books, and reference books; repair of books.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before July 1 each year, the commissioner shall certify to each district school superintendent the estimated allocation of state funds for instructional materials, computed pursuant to the provisions of s. 1011.67 for the ensuing fiscal year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board must purchase current instructional materials to provide each student with a major tool of instruction in core courses of the subject areas of mathematics, language arts, science, social studies, reading, and literature for kindergarten through grade 12. Such purchase must be made within the first 2 years after the effective date of the adoption cycle. For the 2012-2013 mathematics adoption, a district using a comprehensive mathematics instructional materials program adopted in the 2009-2010 adoption shall be deemed in compliance with this subsection if it provides each student with such additional state-adopted materials as may be necessary to align the previously adopted comprehensive program to common core standards and the other criteria of the 2012-2013 mathematics adoption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the 2015-2016 fiscal year, each district school board shall use at least 50 percent of the annual allocation for the purchase of digital or electronic instructional materials included on the state-adopted list, except as otherwise authorized in paragraphs (b) and (c). </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 50 percent of the annual allocation may be used for the purchase of instructional materials, including library and reference books and nonprint materials, not included on the state-adopted list and for the repair and renovation of textbooks and library books.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school boards may use 100 percent of that portion of the annual allocation designated for the purchase of instructional materials for kindergarten, and 75 percent of that portion of the annual allocation designated for the purchase of instructional materials for first grade, to purchase materials not on the state-adopted list.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds described in subsection (3) which district school boards may use to purchase materials not on the state-adopted list shall be used for the purchase of instructional materials or other items having intellectual content which assist in the instruction of a subject or course. These items may be available in bound, unbound, kit, or package form and may consist of hardbacked or softbacked textbooks, electronic content, replacements for items which were part of previously purchased instructional materials, consumables, learning laboratories, manipulatives, electronic media, computer courseware or software, and other commonly accepted instructional tools as prescribed by district school board rule. </Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall adopt rules, and each district school superintendent shall implement procedures, that will assure the maximum use by the students of the authorized instructional materials.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school boards may issue purchase orders subsequent to February 1 in an aggregate amount which does not exceed 20 percent of the current year’s allocation, and subsequent to April 1 in an aggregate amount which does not exceed 90 percent of the current year’s allocation, for the purpose of expediting the delivery of instructional materials which are to be paid for from the ensuing year’s allocation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any year in which the total instructional materials allocation for a school district has not been expended or obligated prior to June 30, the district school board shall carry forward the unobligated amount and shall add it to the next year’s allocation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 315, ch. 2002-387; s. 10, ch. 2009-3; s. 19, ch. 2009-59; s. 21, ch. 2010-154; s. 31, ch. 2011-55; s. 14, ch. 2012-133.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-133, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Digital Instructional Materials Work Group is created to plan and monitor the implementation of the transition to digital instructional materials as required in ss. 1006.29(3) and 1006.40(3)(a), Florida Statutes.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The Commissioner of Education, or his or her designee, shall serve as the ex officio, nonvoting executive director of the work group.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The work group shall be comprised of the following: one school district instructional technology expert, one school district instructional content expert with experience in digital learning initiatives, one representative from an institution of postsecondary education, one high school principal with experience in digital learning initiatives, one middle school principal with experience in digital learning initiatives, one business representative, and one parent.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) A member may not represent a company that has a business interest in education content or technology.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) The chair shall schedule and conduct the first meeting of the work group by October 1, 2012. The work group shall conduct a majority of its meetings virtually.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) The work group shall submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and State Board of Education by March 1, 2013. The report shall include an implementation plan for meeting the deadline of transition to digital instructional materials as provided in ss. 1006.29(3) and 1006.40(3)(a), Florida Statutes. The plan must specify options for the provision of access devices for students, options for providing content by subject area, provisions for training and professional development for preservice and inservice teachers, and a detailed review of options for funding, including the reprioritization of existing resources and recommendations for new funding.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>