<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Production and dissemination of educational materials and products by department.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational materials and products developed by or under the direction of the department, through research and development or other efforts, including those subject to copyright, patent, or trademark, shall be made available for use by teachers, students, administrators, and other appropriate persons in the state system of education at the earliest practicable date and in the most economical and efficient manner possible.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To accomplish this objective, the department may publish, produce, or have produced educational materials and products and make them readily available for appropriate use in the state system of education. The department may charge an amount adequate to cover the essential cost of producing and disseminating such materials and products in the state system of education and may sell copies for educational use to private schools in the state and to the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All proceeds from the sale of educational materials and products shall be remitted to the Chief Financial Officer and shall be kept in a separate fund to be known as the “Educational Media and Technology Trust Fund” and, when properly budgeted as approved by the Legislature and the Executive Office of the Governor, used to pay the cost of producing and disseminating educational materials and products.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cases in which the educational materials or products are of such nature, or the circumstances are such, that it is not practicable or feasible for the department to produce or have produced materials and products so developed, it may, after review and approval by the Department of State, license, lease, assign, sell, or otherwise give written consent to any person, firm or corporation for the manufacture or use thereof, on a royalty basis, or for such other consideration as the department finds proper and in the best interest of the state. The department shall protect educational materials and products against improper or unlawful use or infringement and enforce the collection of any sums due for the manufacture or use thereof by any other party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not enter into the business of producing or publishing instructional materials for general use in classrooms.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 314, ch. 2002-387; s. 1953, ch. 2003-261; s. 30, ch. 2011-55.</History>
</Section>