<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Guidance services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall annually submit a district guidance report to the Commissioner of Education by June 30.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guidance report shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examination of student access to guidance counselors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Degree to which a district has adopted or implemented a guidance model program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of the information and training available to guidance counselors and career specialists to advise students on areas of critical need, labor market trends, and technical training requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Progress toward incorporation of best practices for advisement as identified by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consideration of alternative guidance systems or ideas, including, but not limited to, a teacher-advisor model, mentoring, partnerships with the business community, web-based delivery, and parental involvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken to provide information to students for the school-to-work transition pursuant to s. 1006.02.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guidance plan for the district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide resources to district school boards that may assist districts in preparing the annual guidance report. The resources shall include, but are not limited to, materials relating to guidance model programs, training available through the department for career guidance, adopted best practices, alternative guidance systems or ideas, and a model district guidance plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2004-357.</History></Section>