<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.59" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Historically Black College and University Library Improvement Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to enhance the quality of the libraries at Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, Bethune-Cookman University, Edward Waters College, and Florida Memorial University.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Historically Black College and University Library Improvement Program to be administered by the Department of Education. The primary objectives of the program shall be to increase each library’s holdings by 500 to 1,000 books per year, to increase library use by students and faculty, and to enhance the professional growth of librarians by providing inservice training. At least 50 percent of library acquisitions shall be in the humanities, with the balance to be in all other disciplines. It is the intent of the Legislature to provide general revenue funds each year to support this program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each institution shall submit to the State Board of Education a plan for enhancing its library through the following activities:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each institution shall increase the number of volumes by purchasing replacement books and new titles. Funds shall not be used to purchase periodicals. The goal of these purchases is to meet the needs of students and faculty in disciplines that have recently been added to the curriculum, in traditional academic fields that have been expanded, or in academic fields in which rapid changes in technology result in accelerated obsolescence of related library holdings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A committee composed of librarians and faculty at each institution shall assess the adequacy of library holdings in all academic areas. The committee shall develop a list of resources that need to be replaced. Based on its assessment of the current collection, the committee shall develop a prioritized list of recommended acquisitions and shall submit such list to the college or university president.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 329, ch. 2002-387; s. 98, ch. 2009-21; s. 8, ch. 2010-155.</History>
</Section>