<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.71" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gender equity in intercollegiate athletics.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GENDER EQUITY PLAN.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution and state university shall develop a gender equity plan pursuant to s. 1000.05.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan shall include consideration of equity in sports offerings, participation, availability of facilities, scholarship offerings, and funds allocated for administration, recruitment, comparable coaching, publicity and promotion, and other support costs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall annually assess the progress of each Florida College System institution’s plan and advise the State Board of Education and the Legislature regarding compliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chancellor of the State University System shall annually assess the progress of each state university’s plan and advise the Board of Governors and the Legislature regarding compliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board of trustees of a Florida College System institution or state university shall annually evaluate the presidents on the extent to which the gender equity goals have been achieved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine the proper level of support for women’s athletic scholarships, an equity plan may determine, where appropriate, that support for women’s scholarships may be disproportionate to the support of scholarships for men.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a Florida College System institution is not in compliance with Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 and the Florida Educational Equity Act, the State Board of Education shall:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Declare the Florida College System institution ineligible for competitive state grants.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withhold funds sufficient to obtain compliance.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Florida College System institution shall remain ineligible and the funds shall not be paid until the Florida College System institution comes into compliance or the Commissioner of Education approves a plan for compliance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a state university is not in compliance with Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 and the Florida Educational Equity Act, the Board of Governors shall:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Declare the state university ineligible for competitive state grants.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withhold funds sufficient to obtain compliance.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The state university shall remain ineligible and the funds shall not be paid until the state university comes into compliance or the Board of Governors approves a plan for compliance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An equitable portion of all separate athletic fees shall be designated for women’s intercollegiate athletics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The level of funding and percentage share of support for women’s intercollegiate athletics for Florida College System institutions shall be determined by the State Board of Education. The level of funding and percentage share of support for women’s intercollegiate athletics for state universities shall be determined by the Board of Governors. The level of funding and percentage share attained in the 1980-1981 fiscal year shall be the minimum level and percentage maintained by each institution, except as the State Board of Education or the Board of Governors otherwise directs its respective institutions for the purpose of assuring equity. Consideration shall be given by the State Board of Education or the Board of Governors to emerging athletic programs at institutions which may not have the resources to secure external funds to provide athletic opportunities for women. It is the intent that the effect of any redistribution of funds among institutions shall not negate the requirements as set forth in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the above amount, an amount equal to the sales taxes collected from admission to athletic events sponsored by a state university shall be retained and utilized by each university to support women’s athletics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION.<EmDash />The State Board of Education shall assure equal opportunity for female athletes at Florida College System institutions and establish:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guidelines for reporting of intercollegiate athletics data concerning financial, program, and facilities information for review by the State Board of Education annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systematic audits for the evaluation of such data.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining and assuring equity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD OF GOVERNORS.<EmDash />The Board of Governors shall ensure equal opportunity for female athletes at state universities and establish:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guidelines for reporting of intercollegiate athletics data concerning financial, program, and facilities information for review by the Board of Governors annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systematic audits for the evaluation of such data.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining and ensuring equity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 341, ch. 2002-387; s. 110, ch. 2007-217; s. 86, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>