<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.70" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sponsorship of athletic activities similar to those for which scholarships offered; rulemaking.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a district school board sponsors an athletic activity or sport that is similar to a sport for which a Florida College System institution or state university offers an athletic scholarship, it must sponsor the athletic activity or sport for which a scholarship is offered. This section does not affect academic requirements for participation or prevent the districts or Florida College System institutions from sponsoring activities in addition to those for which scholarships are provided.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a Florida College System institution sponsors an athletic activity or sport that is similar to a sport for which a state university offers an athletic scholarship, it must sponsor the athletic activity or sport for which a scholarship is offered.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two athletic activities or sports that are similar may be offered simultaneously.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the level of participation is insufficient to warrant continuation of an athletic activity or sport, the school may offer an alternative athletic activity or sport.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules to administer this section, including rules that determine which athletic activities are similar to sports for which public postsecondary educational institutions offer scholarships.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 340, ch. 2002-387; s. 85, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>