<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Collections management for museums and galleries of state universities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State universities may enter into contracts or agreements with or without competitive bidding, as appropriate, for the restoration of objects of art, art history, or natural history in their collections or for the purchase of objects of art, art history, or natural history which are to be added to their collections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State universities may sell any art, art history, or natural history object in their museum or gallery collections if the university determines that it is no longer appropriate for the collection. The proceeds of the sale shall be deposited in the Acquisition, Restoration, and Conservation Trust Fund or other appropriate trust fund of the university. Each state university museum or gallery shall function entirely separate from every state university museum or gallery. State universities also may exchange any art, art history, or natural history object which the university museums or galleries judge is of equivalent or greater value to their museums or galleries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No employee, representative, or agent of a university shall receive a commission, fee, or financial benefit in connection with the sale or exchange of a work of art, art history, or natural history, nor may he or she be a business associate of any individual, firm, or organization involved in the sale or exchange.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each university may establish an Acquisition, Restoration, and Conservation Trust Fund or utilize an appropriate existing trust fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president of each university may delegate the following authority to the museum or gallery directors and governing bodies of the museums or galleries:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter into contracts for the restoration or purchase of art, art history, or natural history objects, with or without competitive bidding, as appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sell art, art history, or natural history objects in museum or gallery collections, the proceeds of which shall be deposited in the Acquisition, Restoration, and Conservation Trust Fund or other appropriate existing trust fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exchange art, art history, or natural history objects of equal or greater value with any other state university.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 328, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>