<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Educational multiagency services for students with severe emotional disturbance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intensive, integrated educational program; a continuum of mental health treatment services; and, when needed, residential services are necessary to enable students with severe emotional disturbance to develop appropriate behaviors and demonstrate academic and career education skills. The small incidence of severe emotional disturbance in the total school population requires multiagency programs to provide access to appropriate services for all students with severe emotional disturbance. District school boards should provide educational programs, and state departments and agencies administering children’s mental health funds should provide mental health treatment and residential services when needed, forming a multiagency network to provide support for students with severe emotional disturbance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program goals for each component of the multiagency network are to enable students with severe emotional disturbance to learn appropriate behaviors, reduce dependency, and fully participate in all aspects of school and community living; to develop individual programs for students with severe emotional disturbance, including necessary educational, residential, and mental health treatment services; to provide programs and services as close as possible to the student’s home in the least restrictive manner consistent with the student’s needs; and to integrate a wide range of services necessary to support students with severe emotional disturbance and their families.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may award grants to district school boards for statewide planning and development of the multiagency network for students with severe emotional disturbance. The educational services shall be provided in a manner consistent with the requirements of ss. 402.22 and 1003.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State departments and agencies may use appropriate funds for the multiagency network for students with severe emotional disturbance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 269, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>