<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide school safety hotline.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract with the Florida Sheriffs Association to establish and operate a statewide toll-free school safety hotline for the purpose of reporting incidents that affect the safety and well-being of the school’s population.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The toll-free school safety hotline is to be a conduit for any person to anonymously report activity that affects the safety and well-being of the school’s population.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There may not be an award or monetary benefit for reporting an incident through the toll-free school safety hotline.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The toll-free school safety hotline shall be operated in a manner that ensures that a designated school official is notified of a complaint received through the hotline if the complaint concerns that school. A complaint that concerns an actionable offense must be reported to the designated official within a reasonable time after the complaint is made. An actionable offense is an incident that could directly affect the safety or well-being of a person or property within a school.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a toll-free school safety hotline is established by contract with the Florida Sheriffs Association, the Florida Sheriffs Association shall produce a quarterly report that evaluates the incidents that have been reported to the hotline. This information may be used to evaluate future school safety educational needs and the need for prevention programs as the district school board considers necessary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 285, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>