<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1006.135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hazing at high schools with grades 9-12 prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “hazing” means any action or situation that recklessly or intentionally endangers the mental or physical health or safety of a student at a high school with grades 9 through 12 for purposes including, but not limited to, initiation or admission into or affiliation with any organization operating under the sanction of a high school with grades 9 through 12. “Hazing” includes, but is not limited to, pressuring or coercing the student into violating state or federal law, any brutality of a physical nature, such as whipping, beating, branding, exposure to the elements, forced consumption of any food, liquor, drug, or other substance, or other forced physical activity that could adversely affect the physical health or safety of the student, and also includes any activity that would subject the student to extreme mental stress, such as sleep deprivation, forced exclusion from social contact, forced conduct that could result in extreme embarrassment, or other forced activity that could adversely affect the mental health or dignity of the student. Hazing does not include customary athletic events or other similar contests or competitions or any activity or conduct that furthers a legal and legitimate objective.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits hazing, a third degree felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, when he or she intentionally or recklessly commits any act of hazing as defined in subsection (1) upon another person who is a member of or an applicant to any type of student organization and the hazing results in serious bodily injury or death of such other person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits hazing, a first degree misdemeanor, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, when he or she intentionally or recklessly commits any act of hazing as defined in subsection (1) upon another person who is a member of or an applicant to any type of student organization and the hazing creates a substantial risk of physical injury or death to such other person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of any sentence imposed pursuant to subsection (2) or subsection (3), the court shall order the defendant to attend and complete a 4-hour hazing education course and may also impose a condition of drug or alcohol probation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not a defense to a charge of hazing that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent of the victim had been obtained;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct or activity that resulted in the death or injury of a person was not part of an official organizational event or was not otherwise sanctioned or approved by the organization; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct or activity that resulted in death or injury of the person was not done as a condition of membership to an organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed to preclude prosecution for a more general offense resulting from the same criminal transaction or episode.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-146.</History></Section>