<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="1006.72">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing electronic library resources.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FINDINGS.<EmDash />The Legislature finds that the most cost-efficient and cost-effective means of licensing electronic library resources requires that Florida College System institutions and state universities collaborate with school districts and public libraries in the identification and acquisition of such resources needed by more than one sector.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROCESS TO IDENTIFY RESOURCES.<EmDash />Library staff from Florida College System institutions, state universities, school districts, and public libraries shall implement a process that annually identifies the electronic library resources for each of the core categories established in this section. To the extent possible, the Florida Virtual Campus and the Division of Library and Information Services within the Department of State shall jointly coordinate this annual process.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEWIDE CORE RESOURCES.<EmDash />For purposes of licensing electronic library resources of the Florida Electronic Library, library representatives from public libraries, school districts, Florida College System institutions, and state universities shall identify the statewide core resources that will be available to all students, teachers, and citizens of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POSTSECONDARY EDUCATION CORE RESOURCES.<EmDash />For purposes of licensing electronic library resources from funds appropriated to the Florida Virtual Campus, Florida College System institution and state university library staff shall identify the postsecondary education core resources that will be available to all public postsecondary education students.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOUR-YEAR DEGREE CORE RESOURCES.<EmDash />For purposes of licensing electronic library resources beyond the postsecondary education core resources by the Florida Virtual Campus from funds appropriated to the campus, state university library staff, in consultation with Florida College System institution library staff, shall identify the 4-year degree core resources that will be available to all 4-year degree-seeking students in the State University System and the Florida College System. The Florida Virtual Campus shall include in the negotiated pricing model any Florida College System institution interested in licensing a resource.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TWO-YEAR DEGREE CORE RESOURCES.<EmDash />For purposes of licensing electronic library resources beyond the postsecondary education core resources by the Florida Virtual Campus from funds appropriated to the campus, Florida College System institution library staff shall identify the 2-year degree core resources that will be available to all Florida College System institution students. The Florida Virtual Campus shall include in the negotiated pricing model any state university interested in licensing a resource.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORT.<EmDash />The chancellors and vice chancellors of the Florida College System and the State University System shall annually report to the Executive Office of the Governor and the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees the cost savings realized as a result of the collaborative licensing process identified in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2010-155; s. 87, ch. 2011-5; s. 7, ch. 2011-63; s. 13, ch. 2012-134.</History>
</Section>