<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1006.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Codes of conduct; disciplinary measures; authority to adopt rules or regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution may adopt, by rule, and each state university may adopt, by regulation, codes of conduct and appropriate penalties for violations of rules or regulations by students, to be administered by the institution. Such penalties, unless otherwise provided by law, may include: reprimand; restitution; fines; withholding of diplomas or transcripts pending compliance with rules or regulations, completion of any student judicial process or sanction, or payment of fines; restrictions on the use of or removal from campus facilities; community service; educational requirements; and the imposition of probation, suspension, dismissal, or expulsion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution may adopt, by rule, and each state university may adopt, by regulation, a code of conduct and appropriate penalties for violations of rules or regulations by student organizations, to be administered by the institution. Such penalties, unless otherwise provided by law, may include: reprimand; restitution; suspension, cancellation, or revocation of the registration or official recognition of a student organization; and restrictions on the use of, or removal from, campus facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sanctions authorized by such codes of conduct may be imposed only for acts or omissions in violation of rules or regulations adopted by the institution, including rules or regulations adopted under this section, rules of the State Board of Education, rules or regulations of the Board of Governors regarding the State University System, county and municipal ordinances, and the laws of this state, the United States, or any other state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution may establish and adopt, by rule, and each state university may establish and adopt, by regulation, codes of appropriate penalties for violations of rules or regulations governing student academic honesty. Such penalties, unless otherwise provided by law, may include: reprimand; reduction of grade; denial of academic credit; invalidation of university credit or of the degree based upon such credit; probation; suspension; dismissal; or expulsion. In addition to any other penalties that may be imposed, an individual may be denied admission or further registration, and the institution may invalidate academic credit for work done by a student and may invalidate or revoke the degree based upon such credit if it is determined that the student has made false, fraudulent, or incomplete statements in the application, residence affidavit, or accompanying documents or statements in connection with, or supplemental to, the application for admission to or graduation from the institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution shall adopt rules and each state university shall adopt regulations for the lawful discipline of any student who intentionally acts to impair, interfere with, or obstruct the orderly conduct, processes, and functions of the institution. Said rules or regulations may apply to acts conducted on or off campus when relevant to such orderly conduct, processes, and functions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 330, ch. 2002-387; s. 106, ch. 2007-217; s. 17, ch. 2010-78; s. 80, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>