<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0618.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bylaws.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each association incorporated under this chapter shall adopt for its government and management, a code of bylaws not inconsistent with the powers granted by this chapter. A majority vote of a quorum of the members or stockholders attending a meeting, of which notice of the proposed bylaws shall have been given, is sufficient to adopt or amend the bylaws. Each association, under its bylaws, may provide for any or all of the following matters:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time, place, and manner of calling and conducting its meetings, which meetings and meetings of its directors, may be held either within or without the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of stockholders or members constituting a quorum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of members or stockholders to vote by proxy or by mail or both; and the conditions, manner, form, and effects of such votes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of directors constituting a quorum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualifications, compensation, and duties and term of office of directors and officers; time of their election and the mode and manner of giving notice thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Penalties for violations of the bylaws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of entrance, organization, and membership fees, if any; the manner and method of collection of the same; and the purposes for which they may be used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount which each member or stockholder shall be required to pay annually or from time to time, if at all, to carry on the business of the association; the charge, if any, to be paid by each member or stockholder for services rendered by the association to him or her and the time of payment and the manner of collection; and the form of marketing contract between the association and its members or stockholders, which marketing contract shall be binding upon every member or stockholder, unless otherwise agreed upon in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and qualification of members or stockholders of the association and the conditions precedent to membership or ownership of common stock; the method, time, and manner of permitting members to withdraw or the holders of common stock to transfer their stock; the manner of assignment and transfer of the interest of members and of the shares of common stock; the condition upon which and time when membership of any member shall cease; the automatic suspension of the rights of a member when he or she ceases to be eligible to membership in the association; the mode, manner, and effect of the expulsion of a member; whether a member upon withdrawal, death, or expulsion shall have any interest in the property of the association, if organized without capital stock; the manner of determining the value of the property interest or the shares of common stock of retiring or expelled members, which interest or stock may be conclusively appraised by the board of directors of the association and purchased by the association at such value within 1 year after the date of such retirement or expulsion.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 9300, 1923; CGL 6475; s. 10, ch. 14675, 1931; s. 4, ch. 16879, 1935; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 108, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>