<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seed investigation and conciliation council; composition; purpose; meetings; duties; expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Agriculture shall appoint a seed investigation and conciliation council composed of seven members and seven alternate members, one member and one alternate to be appointed upon the recommendation of each of the following: the deans of extension and research, Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, University of Florida; president of the Florida Seedsmen and Garden Supply Association; president of the Florida Farm Bureau Federation; and the president of the Florida Fruit and Vegetable Association. The Commissioner of Agriculture shall appoint a representative and an alternate from the agriculture industry at large and from the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. Initially, three members and their alternates shall be appointed for 4-year terms and four members and their alternates shall be appointed for 2-year terms. Thereafter, members and alternates shall be appointed for 4-year terms. Each alternate member shall serve only in the absence of the member for whom she or he is an alternate. A vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. The council shall annually elect a chair from its membership. It shall be the duty of the chair to conduct all meetings and deliberations held by the council and to direct all other activities of the council. The department representative shall serve as secretary of the council. It shall be the duty of the secretary to keep accurate and correct records on all meetings and deliberations and perform other duties for the council as directed by the chair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the seed investigation and conciliation council is to assist farmers and agricultural seed dealers in determining the validity of complaints made by farmers against dealers and recommend cost damages resulting from the alleged failure of the seed to produce as represented by label on the seed package.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seed investigation and conciliation council may be called into session by the department or upon the direction of the chair to consider matters referred to it by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department refers to the seed investigation and conciliation council any complaint made by a farmer against a dealer, said council shall make a full and complete investigation of the matters complained of and at the conclusion of said investigation shall report its findings and make its recommendation of cost damages and file same with the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting its investigation the seed investigation and conciliation council or any representative, member, or members thereof authorized to examine the farmer on her or his farming operation of which she or he complains and the dealer on her or his packaging, labeling, and selling operation of the seed alleged to be faulty; to grow to production a representative sample of the alleged faulty seed through the facilities of the state, under the supervision of the department when such action is deemed to be necessary; to hold informal hearings at a time and place directed by the department or by the chair of the council upon reasonable notice to the farmer and the dealer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any investigation made by less than the whole membership of the council shall be by authority of a written directive by the department or by the chair, and such investigation shall be summarized in writing and considered by the council in reporting its findings and making its recommendation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the council shall receive no compensation for the performance of their duties hereunder, but the members of the council shall be reimbursed for travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061 when they attend a meeting or perform a service in conformity with the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 57-199; ss. 3, 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-1; ss. 4, 5, ch. 88-75; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 914, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>