<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, distribute for sale, offer for sale, expose for sale, handle for sale, or solicit orders for the purchase of any agricultural, vegetable, flower, or forest tree seed within this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the test to determine the percentage of germination required by s. 578.09 shall have been completed within a period of 7 months, exclusive of the calendar month in which the test was completed, immediately prior to sale, exposure for sale, offering for sale, or transportation, except for germination test for seed in hermetically sealed containers which is provided for in s. 578.28.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not labeled in accordance with the provisions of this law, or having false or misleading labeling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pertaining to which there has been a false or misleading advertisement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Containing noxious weed seeds subject to tolerances and methods of determination prescribed in the rules and regulations under this law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a seed license has been obtained in accordance with the provisions of this law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless such seed conforms to the definition of a “lot of seed.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person within this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To detach, deface, destroy, or use a second time any label or tag provided for in this law or in the rules and regulations made and promulgated hereunder or to alter or substitute seed in a manner that may defeat the purpose of this law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To disseminate any false or misleading advertisement concerning agricultural, vegetable, flower, or forest tree seed in any manner or by any means.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To hinder or obstruct in any way any authorized person in the performance of her or his duties under this law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to comply with a stop-sale order or seizure order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sell, distribute for sale, offer for sale, expose for sale, handle for sale, or solicit orders for the purchase of any agricultural, vegetable, flower, or forest tree seed labeled “certified seed,” “registered seed,” “foundation seed,” “breeder seed,” or similar terms, unless it has been produced and labeled under seal in compliance with the rules and regulations of any agency authorized by law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to keep a complete record, including a file sample which shall be retained for 1 year after seed is sold, of each lot of seed and to make available for inspection such records to the department or its duly authorized agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To use the name of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services or Florida State Seed Laboratory in connection with analysis tag, labeling advertisement, or sale of any seed in any manner whatsoever.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 20251, 1941; s. 4, ch. 21942, 1943; s. 4, ch. 22694, 1945; s. 6, ch. 57-199; s. 5, ch. 61-436; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 10, ch. 69-144; s. 13, ch. 96-407; s. 1186, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>