<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Forest tree seed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each container of forest tree seed which is sold, offered for sale, exposed for sale, or transported within this state for sowing purposes shall bear thereon or have attached thereto in a conspicuous place a plainly written or printed label or tag in the English language, giving the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all forest tree seed treated as defined in this law:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A word or statement indicating that the seed has been treated.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commonly accepted coined, chemical or abbreviated chemical (generic) name of the applied substance or description of the process used.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words “poison treated” in red letters at least <Fraction>1/4</Fraction>-inch type and a caution statement such as “Do not use for food, feed, or oil purposes.”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the seed has been treated with an inoculant, the date beyond which the inoculant is not to be considered effective (date of expiration).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all forest tree seed subject to this law:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Common name of the species of seed (and subspecies, if appropriate).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scientific name of the genus and species (and subspecies, if appropriate).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lot number or other lot identification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State of origin and forest tree seed collection zone in state if state is divided into zones.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purity as a percentage of pure seed by weight.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those species for which standard germination testing procedures are prescribed by the department, the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage germination exclusive of hard seed.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of hard seed, if present.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calendar month and year test was completed to determine such percentages.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of sub-subparagraphs 6.a., b., and c., above, the seed may be labeled “Test is in process, results will be supplied upon request.”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those species for which standard germination testing procedures have not been prescribed by the department, the calendar year in which the seed was collected.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person who labeled said seed or who sells, offers, or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information required by subsection (1) to be placed on labels attached to seed containers shall not be modified or denied in the labeling or on another label attached to the container. However, labeling of seed supplied under a contractual agreement may be by invoice accompanying the shipment or by an analysis tag attached to said invoice if each bag or other container is clearly identified by a lot number stenciled on the container or if the seed is in bulk. Each bag or container that is not so identified must carry complete labeling.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 69-144; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>