<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 578.13 shall not apply to any common carrier in respect to any seed transported or delivered for transportation in the ordinary course of its business as a carrier. Provided, that such carrier is not engaged in processing or merchandising seed subject to the provisions of this law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 578.09 and 578.13 do not apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seed or grain not intended for sowing or planting purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seed in storage in, consigned to or being transported to seed cleaning or processing establishments for cleaning or processing only. Any labeling or other representation which may be made with respect to the unclean seed shall be subject to this law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall be subject to the criminal penalties of this law for having sold, offered, exposed, or distributed for sale in this state any agricultural, vegetable, or forest tree seed which were incorrectly labeled or represented as to kind and variety or origin, which seed cannot be identified by examination thereof, unless she or he has failed to obtain an invoice or grower’s declaration giving kind and variety and origin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When seeds are sold from a duly labeled container and taken therefrom in the presence of the purchaser, the container in which such seeds are delivered to the purchaser will not be required to have a label or tag unless so requested by the purchaser. This, however, shall not relieve or exempt any seed dealer from any liability imposed by the Florida Seed Law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 19364, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(595); s. 5, ch. 20251, 1941; s. 5, ch. 21942, 1943; s. 5, ch. 22694, 1945; s. 2, ch. 26969, 1951; ss. 4, 9, ch. 57-199; s. 7, ch. 69-144; s. 911, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>