<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Label requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each container of agricultural, vegetable, or flower seed sold, offered for sale, exposed for sale, or distributed for sale within this state for sowing or planting purposes shall bear thereon or have attached thereto, in a conspicuous place, a label or labels containing all information required under this section, plainly written or printed in the English language, in Century type. All data pertaining to analysis shall appear on a single label. Language setting forth the requirements for filing and serving complaints as described in s. 578.26(1)(b) shall be included on the analysis label or be otherwise attached to the package, except for packages containing less than 1,000 seeds by count.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR TREATED SEED.<EmDash />For all agricultural, vegetable, or flower seed treated as defined in this chapter:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A word or statement indicating that the seed has been treated or description of process used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commonly accepted coined, chemical or abbreviated chemical (generic) name of the applied substance and the words “poison treated” in red letters, in not less than <Fraction>1/4</Fraction>-inch type.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A caution statement such as “Do not use for food, feed, or oil purposes.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rate of application or statement “Treated at manufacturer’s recommended rate.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the seed is treated with an inoculant, the date beyond which the inoculant is not to be considered effective (date of expiration).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AGRICULTURAL SEED.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commonly accepted name of kind and variety of each agricultural seed component in excess of 5 percent of the whole, and the percentage by weight of each in the order of its predominance. Where more than one component is required to be named, the word “mixture” or the word “mixed” shall be shown conspicuously on the label.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lot number or other lot identification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net weight or seed count.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Origin, if known; if unknown, that fact shall be stated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage by weight of all weed seed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and number per pound of each kind of restricted noxious weed seed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage by weight of other crop seed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage by weight of inert matter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each named agricultural seed:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of germination, exclusive of hard seed;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of hard seed when present, if desired; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The calendar month and year the test was completed to determine such percentages.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address of the person who labeled said seed or who sells, distributes, offers, or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR VEGETABLE SEED IN CONTAINERS OF 8 OUNCES OR MORE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name of kind and variety of seed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net weight or seed count.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lot number or other lot identification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of germination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calendar month and year the test was completed to determine such percentages.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address of the person who labeled said seed or who sells, distributes, offers or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seed which germinate less than the standard last established by the department the words “below standard,” in not less than 8-point type, must be printed or written in ink on the face of the tag, in addition to the other information required. Provided, that no seed marked “below standard” shall be sold which falls more than 20 percent below the standard for such seed which has been established by the department, as authorized by this law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and number of restricted noxious weed seed per pound.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR VEGETABLE SEED IN CONTAINERS OF LESS THAN 8 OUNCES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name of kind and variety of seed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address of person who labeled seed or who sells, distributes, offers, or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seed which germinate less than standard last established by the department, the additional information must be shown:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of germination, exclusive of hard seed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of hard seed when present, if desired.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calendar month and year the test was completed to determine such percentages.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words “below standard” in not less than 8-point type.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No seed marked “below standard” shall be sold which fall more than 20 percent below the established standard for such seed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR FLOWER SEED IN PACKETS PREPARED FOR USE IN HOME GARDENS OR HOUSEHOLD PLANTINGS OR FLOWER SEED IN PREPLANTED CONTAINERS, MATS, TAPES, OR OTHER PLANTING DEVICES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all kinds of flower seed:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the kind and variety or a statement of type and performance characteristics as prescribed in the rules and regulations promulgated under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The calendar month and year the seed was tested or the year for which the seed was packaged.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person who labeled said seed, or who sells, offers, or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seed of those kinds for which standard testing procedures are prescribed and which germinate less than the germination standard last established under the provisions of this chapter:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of germination exclusive of hard seed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words “below standard” in not less than 8-point type.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seed placed in a germination medium, mat, tape, or other device in such a way as to make it difficult to determine the quantity of seed without removing the seed from the medium, mat, tape, or device, a statement to indicate the minimum number of seed in the container.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR FLOWER SEED IN CONTAINERS OTHER THAN PACKETS PREPARED FOR USE IN HOME FLOWER GARDENS OR HOUSEHOLD PLANTINGS AND OTHER THAN PREPLANTED CONTAINERS, MATS, TAPES, OR OTHER PLANTING DEVICES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the kind and variety or a statement of type and performance characteristics as prescribed in rules and regulations promulgated under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lot number or other lot identification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The calendar month and year that the seed were tested or the year for which the seed were packaged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person who labeled said seed or who sells, offers, or exposes said seed for sale within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those kinds of seed for which standard testing procedures are prescribed:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage germination exclusive of hard seed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of hard seed, if present.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those seeds which germinate less than the standard last established by the department, the words “below standard” in not less than 8-point type must be printed or written in ink on the face of the tag.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT TO PRESCRIBE UNIFORM ANALYSIS TAG.<EmDash />The department shall have the authority to prescribe a uniform analysis tag required by this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 19364, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(594); s. 3, ch. 20251, 1941; ss. 3, 13, ch. 21942, 1943; ss. 3, 12, ch. 22694, 1945; ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 26926, 1951; s. 3, ch. 57-199; s. 3, ch. 61-436; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 69-144; s. 1, ch. 88-75; s. 6, ch. 93-29.</History></Section>