<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0578.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complaint, investigation, hearings, findings, and recommendation prerequisite to legal action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any farmer is damaged by the failure of agricultural, vegetable, flower, or forest tree seed to produce or perform as represented by the label attached to the seed as required by s. 578.09, as a prerequisite to her or his right to maintain a legal action against the dealer from whom the seed was purchased, the farmer shall make a sworn complaint against the dealer alleging damages sustained. The complaint shall be filed with the department, and a copy of the complaint shall be served by the department on the dealer by certified mail, within such time as to permit inspection of the crops, plants, or trees by the seed investigation and conciliation council or its representatives and by the dealer from whom the seed was purchased.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Language setting forth the requirement for filing and serving the complaint shall be legibly typed or printed on the analysis label or be attached to the package containing the seed at the time of purchase by the farmer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonrefundable filing fee of $100 shall be paid to the department with each complaint filed. However, the complainant may recover the filing fee cost from the dealer upon the recommendation of the seed investigation and conciliation council.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after receipt of a copy of the complaint, the dealer shall file with the department her or his answer to the complaint and serve a copy of the answer on the farmer by certified mail. Upon receipt of the findings and recommendation of the arbitration council, the department shall transmit them to the farmer and to the dealer by certified mail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall refer the complaint and the answer thereto to the seed investigation and conciliation council provided in s. 578.27 for investigation, informal hearing, findings, and recommendation on the matters complained of.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each party shall be allowed to present its side of the dispute at an informal hearing before the seed investigation and conciliation council. Attorneys may be present at the hearing to confer with their clients. However, no attorney may participate directly in the proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearings, including the deliberations of the seed investigation and conciliation council, shall be open to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after completion of a hearing, the seed investigation and conciliation council shall transmit its findings and recommendations to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Upon receipt of the findings and recommendation of the seed investigation and conciliation council, the department shall transmit them to the farmer and to the dealer by certified mail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide administrative support for the seed investigation and conciliation council and shall adopt rules to govern investigations and hearings. A copy of the rules shall be mailed to each party, upon receipt of a complaint by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 26814, 1951; s. 7, ch. 57-199; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 13, ch. 69-144; s. 1, ch. 83-95; s. 3, ch. 85-62; s. 5, ch. 87-386; s. 3, ch. 88-75; s. 26, ch. 92-143; s. 913, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>