<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.520" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inconvenient forum.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of this state which has jurisdiction under this part to make a child custody determination may decline to exercise its jurisdiction at any time if it determines that it is an inconvenient forum under the circumstances and that a court of another state is a more appropriate forum. The issue of inconvenient forum may be raised upon motion of a party, the court’s own motion, or request of another court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before determining whether it is an inconvenient forum, a court of this state shall consider whether it is appropriate for a court of another state to exercise jurisdiction. For this purpose, the court shall allow the parties to submit information and shall consider all relevant factors, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether domestic violence has occurred and is likely to continue in the future and which state could best protect the parties and the child;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The length of time the child has resided outside this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The distance between the court in this state and the court in the state that would assume jurisdiction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The relative financial circumstances of the parties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agreement of the parties as to which state should assume jurisdiction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and location of the evidence required to resolve the pending litigation, including testimony of the child;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the court of each state to decide the issue expeditiously and the procedures necessary to present the evidence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The familiarity of the court of each state with the facts and issues in the pending litigation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a court of this state determines that it is an inconvenient forum and that a court of another state is a more appropriate forum, it shall stay the proceedings upon condition that a child custody proceeding be promptly commenced in another designated state and may impose any other condition the court considers just and proper.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of this state may decline to exercise its jurisdiction under this part if a child custody determination is incidental to an action for divorce or another proceeding while still retaining jurisdiction over the divorce or other proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-65.</History></Section>