<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Equitable distribution of marital assets and liabilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding for dissolution of marriage, in addition to all other remedies available to a court to do equity between the parties, or in a proceeding for disposition of assets following a dissolution of marriage by a court which lacked jurisdiction over the absent spouse or lacked jurisdiction to dispose of the assets, the court shall set apart to each spouse that spouse’s nonmarital assets and liabilities, and in distributing the marital assets and liabilities between the parties, the court must begin with the premise that the distribution should be equal, unless there is a justification for an unequal distribution based on all relevant factors, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contribution to the marriage by each spouse, including contributions to the care and education of the children and services as homemaker.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The economic circumstances of the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of the marriage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interruption of personal careers or educational opportunities of either party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contribution of one spouse to the personal career or educational opportunity of the other spouse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The desirability of retaining any asset, including an interest in a business, corporation, or professional practice, intact and free from any claim or interference by the other party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contribution of each spouse to the acquisition, enhancement, and production of income or the improvement of, or the incurring of liabilities to, both the marital assets and the nonmarital assets of the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The desirability of retaining the marital home as a residence for any dependent child of the marriage, or any other party, when it would be equitable to do so, it is in the best interest of the child or that party, and it is financially feasible for the parties to maintain the residence until the child is emancipated or until exclusive possession is otherwise terminated by a court of competent jurisdiction. In making this determination, the court shall first determine if it would be in the best interest of the dependent child to remain in the marital home; and, if not, whether other equities would be served by giving any other party exclusive use and possession of the marital home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The intentional dissipation, waste, depletion, or destruction of marital assets after the filing of the petition or within 2 years prior to the filing of the petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other factors necessary to do equity and justice between the parties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court awards a cash payment for the purpose of equitable distribution of marital assets, to be paid in full or in installments, the full amount ordered shall vest when the judgment is awarded and the award shall not terminate upon remarriage or death of either party, unless otherwise agreed to by the parties, but shall be treated as a debt owed from the obligor or the obligor’s estate to the obligee or the obligee’s estate, unless otherwise agreed to by the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any contested dissolution action wherein a stipulation and agreement has not been entered and filed, any distribution of marital assets or marital liabilities shall be supported by factual findings in the judgment or order based on competent substantial evidence with reference to the factors enumerated in subsection (1). The distribution of all marital assets and marital liabilities, whether equal or unequal, shall include specific written findings of fact as to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clear identification of nonmarital assets and ownership interests;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of marital assets, including the individual valuation of significant assets, and designation of which spouse shall be entitled to each asset;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of the marital liabilities and designation of which spouse shall be responsible for each liability;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other findings necessary to advise the parties or the reviewing court of the trial court’s rationale for the distribution of marital assets and allocation of liabilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judgment distributing assets shall have the effect of a duly executed instrument of conveyance, transfer, release, or acquisition which is recorded in the county where the property is located when the judgment, or a certified copy of the judgment, is recorded in the official records of the county in which the property is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds good cause that there should be an interim partial distribution during the pendency of a dissolution action, the court may enter an interim order that shall identify and value the marital and nonmarital assets and liabilities made the subject of the sworn motion, set apart those nonmarital assets and liabilities, and provide for a partial distribution of those marital assets and liabilities. An interim order may be entered at any time after the date the dissolution of marriage is filed and served and before the final distribution of marital and nonmarital assets and marital and nonmarital liabilities.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such an interim order shall be entered only upon good cause shown and upon sworn motion establishing specific factual basis for the motion. The motion may be filed by either party and shall demonstrate good cause why the matter should not be deferred until the final hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall specifically take into account and give appropriate credit for any partial distribution of marital assets or liabilities in its final allocation of marital assets or liabilities. Further, the court shall make specific findings in any interim order under this section that any partial distribution will not cause inequity or prejudice to either party as to either party’s claims for support or attorney’s fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interim order partially distributing marital assets or liabilities as provided in this subsection shall be pursuant to and comport with the factors in subsections (1) and (3) as such factors pertain to the assets or liabilities made the subject of the sworn motion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “good cause” means extraordinary circumstances that require an interim partial distribution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marital assets and liabilities” include:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assets acquired and liabilities incurred during the marriage, individually by either spouse or jointly by them.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enhancement in value and appreciation of nonmarital assets resulting either from the efforts of either party during the marriage or from the contribution to or expenditure thereon of marital funds or other forms of marital assets, or both.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interspousal gifts during the marriage.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All vested and nonvested benefits, rights, and funds accrued during the marriage in retirement, pension, profit-sharing, annuity, deferred compensation, and insurance plans and programs.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All real property held by the parties as tenants by the entireties, whether acquired prior to or during the marriage, shall be presumed to be a marital asset. If, in any case, a party makes a claim to the contrary, the burden of proof shall be on the party asserting the claim that the subject property, or some portion thereof, is nonmarital.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All personal property titled jointly by the parties as tenants by the entireties, whether acquired prior to or during the marriage, shall be presumed to be a marital asset. In the event a party makes a claim to the contrary, the burden of proof shall be on the party asserting the claim that the subject property, or some portion thereof, is nonmarital.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The burden of proof to overcome the gift presumption shall be by clear and convincing evidence.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonmarital assets and liabilities” include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assets acquired and liabilities incurred by either party prior to the marriage, and assets acquired and liabilities incurred in exchange for such assets and liabilities;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assets acquired separately by either party by noninterspousal gift, bequest, devise, or descent, and assets acquired in exchange for such assets;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All income derived from nonmarital assets during the marriage unless the income was treated, used, or relied upon by the parties as a marital asset;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assets and liabilities excluded from marital assets and liabilities by valid written agreement of the parties, and assets acquired and liabilities incurred in exchange for such assets and liabilities; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any liability incurred by forgery or unauthorized signature of one spouse signing the name of the other spouse. Any such liability shall be a nonmarital liability only of the party having committed the forgery or having affixed the unauthorized signature. In determining an award of attorney’s fees and costs pursuant to s. 61.16, the court may consider forgery or an unauthorized signature by a party and may make a separate award for attorney’s fees and costs occasioned by the forgery or unauthorized signature. This subparagraph does not apply to any forged or unauthorized signature that was subsequently ratified by the other spouse.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cut-off date for determining assets and liabilities to be identified or classified as marital assets and liabilities is the earliest of the date the parties enter into a valid separation agreement, such other date as may be expressly established by such agreement, or the date of the filing of a petition for dissolution of marriage. The date for determining value of assets and the amount of liabilities identified or classified as marital is the date or dates as the judge determines is just and equitable under the circumstances. Different assets may be valued as of different dates, as, in the judge’s discretion, the circumstances require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All assets acquired and liabilities incurred by either spouse subsequent to the date of the marriage and not specifically established as nonmarital assets or liabilities are presumed to be marital assets and liabilities. Such presumption is overcome by a showing that the assets and liabilities are nonmarital assets and liabilities. The presumption is only for evidentiary purposes in the dissolution proceeding and does not vest title. Title to disputed assets shall vest only by the judgment of a court. This section does not require the joinder of spouses in the conveyance, transfer, or hypothecation of a spouse’s individual property; affect the laws of descent and distribution; or establish community property in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may provide for equitable distribution of the marital assets and liabilities without regard to alimony for either party. After the determination of an equitable distribution of the marital assets and liabilities, the court shall consider whether a judgment for alimony shall be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do equity between the parties, the court may, in lieu of or to supplement, facilitate, or effectuate the equitable division of marital assets and liabilities, order a monetary payment in a lump sum or in installments paid over a fixed period of time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special equity is abolished. All claims formerly identified as special equity, and all special equity calculations, are abolished and shall be asserted either as a claim for unequal distribution of marital property and resolved by the factors set forth in subsection (1) or as a claim of enhancement in value or appreciation of nonmarital property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-98; s. 2, ch. 91-246; s. 3, ch. 93-188; s. 1, ch. 94-204; s. 1, ch. 96-305; s. 1, ch. 2002-244; s. 1, ch. 2008-46.</History></Section>