<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.122" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Parenting plan recommendation; presumption of psychologist’s good faith; prerequisite to parent’s filing suit; award of fees, costs, reimbursement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A psychologist who has been appointed by the court to develop a parenting plan recommendation in a dissolution of marriage, a case of domestic violence, or a paternity matter involving the relationship of a child and a parent, including time-sharing of children, is presumed to be acting in good faith if the psychologist’s recommendation has been reached under standards that a reasonable psychologist would use to develop a parenting plan recommendation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An administrative complaint against a court-appointed psychologist which relates to a parenting plan recommendation conducted by the psychologist may not be filed anonymously. The individual who files an administrative complaint must include in the complaint his or her name, address, and telephone number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent who desires to file a legal action against a court-appointed psychologist who has acted in good faith in developing a parenting plan recommendation must petition the judge who presided over the dissolution of marriage, case of domestic violence, or paternity matter involving the relationship of a child and a parent, including time-sharing of children, to appoint another psychologist. Upon the parent’s showing of good cause, the court shall appoint another psychologist. The court shall determine who is responsible for all court costs and attorney’s fees associated with making such an appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a legal action, whether it be a civil action, a criminal action, or an administrative proceeding, is filed against a court-appointed psychologist in a dissolution of marriage, case of domestic violence, or paternity matter involving the relationship of a child and a parent, including time-sharing of children, the claimant is responsible for all reasonable costs and reasonable attorney’s fees associated with the action for both parties if the psychologist is held not liable. If the psychologist is held liable in civil court, the psychologist must pay all reasonable costs and reasonable attorney’s fees for the claimant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-112; s. 7, ch. 2008-61; s. 4, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>