<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.079" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Premarital agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “Uniform Premarital Agreement Act” and this section applies only to proceedings under the Florida Family Law Rules of Procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Premarital agreement” means an agreement between prospective spouses made in contemplation of marriage and to be effective upon marriage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” includes, but is not limited to, an interest, present or future, legal or equitable, vested or contingent, in real or personal property, tangible or intangible, including income and earnings, both active and passive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FORMALITIES.<EmDash />A premarital agreement must be in writing and signed by both parties. It is enforceable without consideration other than the marriage itself.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parties to a premarital agreement may contract with respect to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and obligations of each of the parties in any of the property of either or both of them whenever and wherever acquired or located;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to buy, sell, use, transfer, exchange, abandon, lease, consume, expend, assign, create a security interest in, mortgage, encumber, dispose of, or otherwise manage and control property;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disposition of property upon separation, marital dissolution, death, or the occurrence or nonoccurrence of any other event;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment, modification, waiver, or elimination of spousal support;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making of a will, trust, or other arrangement to carry out the provisions of the agreement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ownership rights in and disposition of the death benefit from a life insurance policy;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The choice of law governing the construction of the agreement; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other matter, including their personal rights and obligations, not in violation of either the public policy of this state or a law imposing a criminal penalty.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of a child to support may not be adversely affected by a premarital agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EFFECT OF MARRIAGE.<EmDash />A premarital agreement becomes effective upon marriage of the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AMENDMENT; REVOCATION OR ABANDONMENT.<EmDash />After marriage, a premarital agreement may be amended, revoked, or abandoned only by a written agreement signed by the parties. The amended agreement, revocation, or abandonment is enforceable without consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ENFORCEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A premarital agreement is not enforceable in an action proceeding under the Florida Family Law Rules of Procedure if the party against whom enforcement is sought proves that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party did not execute the agreement voluntarily;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement was the product of fraud, duress, coercion, or overreaching; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement was unconscionable when it was executed and, before execution of the agreement, that party:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was not provided a fair and reasonable disclosure of the property or financial obligations of the other party;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Did not voluntarily and expressly waive, in writing, any right to disclosure of the property or financial obligations of the other party beyond the disclosure provided; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Did not have, or reasonably could not have had, an adequate knowledge of the property or financial obligations of the other party.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a provision of a premarital agreement modifies or eliminates spousal support and that modification or elimination causes one party to the agreement to be eligible for support under a program of public assistance at the time of separation or marital dissolution, a court, notwithstanding the terms of the agreement, may require the other party to provide support to the extent necessary to avoid that eligibility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An issue of unconscionability of a premarital agreement shall be decided by the court as a matter of law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ENFORCEMENT; VOID MARRIAGE.<EmDash />If a marriage is determined to be void, an agreement that would otherwise have been a premarital agreement is enforceable only to the extent necessary to avoid an inequitable result.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS.<EmDash />Any statute of limitations applicable to an action asserting a claim for relief under a premarital agreement is tolled during the marriage of the parties to the agreement. However, equitable defenses limiting the time for enforcement, including laches and estoppel, are available to either party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION TO PROBATE CODE.<EmDash />This section does not alter the construction, interpretation, or required formalities of, or the rights or obligations under, agreements between spouses under s. 732.701 or s. 732.702.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-171.</History></Section>