<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alimony and child support; additional method for enforcing orders and judgments; costs, expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order or judgment for the payment of alimony or child support or either entered by any court of this state may be enforced by another chancery court in this state in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person to whom such alimony or child support is payable or for whose benefit it is payable may procure a certified copy of the order or judgment and file it with a complaint for enforcement in the circuit court for the county in which the person resides or in the county where the person charged with the payment of the alimony or child support resides or is found.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the pleadings seek a change in the amount of the alimony or child support money, the court has jurisdiction to adjudicate the application and change the order or judgment. In such event the clerk of the circuit court in which the order is entered changing the original order or judgment shall transmit a certified copy thereof to the court of original jurisdiction, and the new order shall be recorded and filed in the original action and become a part thereof. If the pleadings ask for a modification of the order or judgment, the court may determine that the action should be tried by the court entering the original order or judgment and shall then transfer the action to that court for determination as a part of the original action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of a case certified under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act under this section shall grant to the registering court jurisdiction to address only those issues allowed and reimbursable under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court in which such an action is brought has jurisdiction to award costs and expenses as are equitable, including the cost of certifying and recording the judgment entered in the action in the court of original jurisdiction and reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The entry of a judgment for arrearages for child support, alimony, or attorney’s fees and costs does not preclude a subsequent contempt proceeding or certification of a IV-D case for intercept, by the United States Internal Revenue Service, for failure of an obligor to pay the child support, alimony, attorney’s fees, or costs for which the judgment was entered.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 28187, 1953; s. 16, ch. 67-254; s. 18, ch. 71-241; s. 125, ch. 86-220; s. 7, ch. 92-138.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 65.18.</Text></Note></Section>