<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Social investigation and recommendations regarding a parenting plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action where the parenting plan is at issue because the parents are unable to agree, the court may order a social investigation and study concerning all pertinent details relating to the child and each parent when such an investigation has not been done and the study therefrom provided to the court by the parties or when the court determines that the investigation and study that have been done are insufficient. The agency, staff, or person conducting the investigation and study ordered by the court pursuant to this section shall furnish the court and all parties of record in the proceeding a written study containing recommendations, including a written statement of facts found in the social investigation on which the recommendations are based. The court may consider the information contained in the study in making a decision on the parenting plan, and the technical rules of evidence do not exclude the study from consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A social investigation and study, when ordered by the court, shall be conducted by qualified staff of the court; a child-placing agency licensed pursuant to s. 409.175; a psychologist licensed pursuant to chapter 490; or a clinical social worker, marriage and family therapist, or mental health counselor licensed pursuant to chapter 491. If a certification of indigence based on an affidavit filed with the court pursuant to s. 57.081 is provided by an adult party to the proceeding and the court does not have qualified staff to perform the investigation and study, the court may request that the Department of Children and Family Services conduct the investigation and study.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as to persons who obtain certification of indigence as specified in subsection (2), for whom no costs are incurred, the parents involved in a proceeding to determine a parenting plan where the court has ordered the performance of a social investigation and study are responsible for paying the costs of the investigation and study. Upon submitting the study to the court, the agency, staff, or person performing the study shall include a bill for services, which shall be taxed and ordered paid as costs in the proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-186; s. 16, ch. 67-254; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 12, ch. 77-147; s. 27, ch. 77-433; s. 1, ch. 86-101; s. 1, ch. 89-38; s. 4, ch. 99-8; s. 14, ch. 2008-61; s. 6, ch. 2009-180.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 65.21.</Text></Note></Section>