<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.077" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of entitlement to setoffs or credits upon sale of marital home.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party is not entitled to any credits or setoffs upon the sale of the marital home unless the parties’ settlement agreement, final judgment of dissolution of marriage, or final judgment equitably distributing assets or debts specifically provides that certain credits or setoffs are allowed or given at the time of the sale. In the absence of a settlement agreement involving the marital home, the court shall consider the following factors before determining the issue of credits or setoffs in its final judgment:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether exclusive use and possession of the marital home is being awarded, and the basis for the award;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether alimony is being awarded to the party in possession and whether the alimony is being awarded to cover, in part or otherwise, the mortgage and taxes and other expenses of and in connection with the marital home;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether child support is being awarded to the party in possession and whether the child support is being awarded to cover, in part or otherwise, the mortgage and taxes and other expenses of and in connection with the marital home;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value to the party in possession of the use and occupancy of the marital home;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of the loss of use and occupancy of the marital home to the party out of possession;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which party will be entitled to claim the mortgage interest payments, real property tax payments, and related payments in connection with the marital home as tax deductions for federal income tax purposes;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether one or both parties will experience a capital gains taxable event as a result of the sale of the marital home; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other factor necessary to bring about equity and justice between the parties.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-249.</History></Section>