<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.514" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Initial child custody jurisdiction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 61.517, a court of this state has jurisdiction to make an initial child custody determination only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This state is the home state of the child on the date of the commencement of the proceeding, or was the home state of the child within 6 months before the commencement of the proceeding and the child is absent from this state but a parent or person acting as a parent continues to live in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of another state does not have jurisdiction under paragraph (a), or a court of the home state of the child has declined to exercise jurisdiction on the grounds that this state is the more appropriate forum under s. 61.520 or s. 61.521, and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child and the child’s parents, or the child and at least one parent or a person acting as a parent, have a significant connection with this state other than mere physical presence; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substantial evidence is available in this state concerning the child’s care, protection, training, and personal relationships;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All courts having jurisdiction under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) have declined to exercise jurisdiction on the grounds that a court of this state is the more appropriate forum to determine the custody of the child under s. 61.520 or s. 61.521; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court of any other state would have jurisdiction under the criteria specified in paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) is the exclusive jurisdictional basis for making a child custody determination by a court of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical presence of, or personal jurisdiction over, a party or a child is not necessary or sufficient to make a child custody determination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-65.</History></Section>