<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.531" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Expedited enforcement of child custody determination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition under ss. 61.524-61.540 must be verified. Certified copies of all orders sought to be enforced and of any order confirming registration must be attached to the petition. A copy of a certified copy of an order may be attached instead of the original.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for enforcement of a child custody determination must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the court that issued the determination identified the jurisdictional basis it relied upon in exercising jurisdiction and, if so, specify the basis;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the determination for which enforcement is sought has been vacated, stayed, or modified by a court whose decision must be enforced under this part and, if so, identify the court, the case number, and the nature of the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether any proceeding has been commenced that could affect the current proceeding, including proceedings relating to domestic violence, protective orders, termination of parental rights, and adoptions and, if so, identify the court, the case number, and the nature of the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present physical address of the child and the respondent, if known;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether relief in addition to the immediate physical custody of the child and attorney’s fees is sought, including a request for assistance from law enforcement officers and, if so, the relief sought; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child custody determination has been registered and confirmed under s. 61.528, the date and place of registration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a petition, the court shall issue an order directing the respondent to appear in person with or without the child at a hearing and may enter any order necessary to ensure the safety of the parties and the child. The hearing must be held on the next judicial day after service of the order unless that date is impossible. In that event, the court shall hold the hearing on the first judicial day possible. The court may extend the date of the hearing at the request of the petitioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order issued under subsection (3) must state the time and place of the hearing and advise the respondent that at the hearing the court will order that the petitioner may take immediate physical custody of the child and the payment of fees, costs, and expenses under s. 61.535 and may schedule a hearing to determine whether further relief is appropriate, unless the respondent appears and establishes that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child custody determination has not been registered and confirmed under s. 61.528 and that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuing court did not have jurisdiction under ss. 61.514-61.523;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child custody determination for which enforcement is sought has been vacated, stayed, or modified by a court of a state having jurisdiction to do so under ss. 61.514-61.523; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The respondent was entitled to notice, but notice was not given in accordance with the standards of s. 61.509 in the proceedings before the court that issued the order for which enforcement is sought; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child custody determination for which enforcement is sought was registered and confirmed under s. 61.528, but has been vacated, stayed, or modified by a court of a state having jurisdiction to do so under ss. 61.514-61.523.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-65.</History></Section>