<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.1827" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identifying information concerning applicants for and recipients of child support services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information that reveals the identity of applicants for or recipients of child support services, including the name, address, and telephone number of such persons, held by a non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement agency is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a) of Art. I of the State Constitution. The use or disclosure of such information by the non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement agency is limited to the purposes directly connected with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any investigation, prosecution, or criminal or civil proceeding connected with the administration of any non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement program;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mandatory disclosure of identifying and location information as provided in s. 61.13(7) by the non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement agency when providing non-Title IV-D services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mandatory disclosure of information as required by ss. 409.2577, 61.181, 61.1825, and 61.1826 and Title IV-D of the Social Security Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure to an authorized person, as defined in 45 C.F.R. s. 303.15, for purposes of enforcing any state or federal law with respect to the unlawful taking or restraint of a child or making or enforcing a parenting plan. As used in this paragraph, the term “authorized person” includes a parent with whom the child does not currently reside, unless a court has entered an order under s. 741.30, s. 741.31, or s. 784.046.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement agency shall not disclose information that identifies by name and address an applicant for or recipient of child support services or the whereabouts of such party or child to another person against whom a protective order with respect to the former party or the child has been entered if the county agency has reason to believe that the release of information to such person could result in physical or emotional harm to the party or the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “non-Title IV-D county child support enforcement agency” means a department, division, or other agency of a county government which is operated by the county, excluding local depositories pursuant to s. 61.181 operated by the clerk of the court, to provide child support enforcement and depository services to county residents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-131; s. 10, ch. 2005-239; s. 1, ch. 2006-156; s. 13, ch. 2008-61.</History></Section>