<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.521" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction declined by reason of conduct.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 61.517 or by other law of this state, if a court of this state has jurisdiction under this part because a person seeking to invoke its jurisdiction has engaged in unjustifiable conduct, the court shall decline to exercise its jurisdiction unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents and all persons acting as parents have acquiesced in the exercise of jurisdiction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of the state otherwise having jurisdiction under ss. 61.514-61.516 determines that this state is a more appropriate forum under s. 61.520; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court of any other state would have jurisdiction under the criteria specified in ss. 61.514-61.516.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a court of this state declines to exercise its jurisdiction under subsection (1), it may fashion an appropriate remedy to ensure the safety of the child and prevent a repetition of the unjustifiable conduct, including staying the proceeding until a child custody proceeding is commenced in a court having jurisdiction under ss. 61.514-61.516.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a court dismisses a petition or stays a proceeding because it declines to exercise its jurisdiction under subsection (1), it shall assess against the party seeking to invoke its jurisdiction necessary and reasonable expenses, including costs, communication expenses, attorney’s fees, investigative fees, expenses for witnesses, travel expenses, and expenses for child care during the course of the proceedings, unless the party from whom fees are sought establishes that the assessment would be clearly inappropriate. The court may not assess fees, costs, or expenses against this state unless authorized by law other than this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-65.</History></Section>