<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.13016" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension of driver’s licenses and motor vehicle registrations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver’s license and motor vehicle registration of a support obligor who is delinquent in payment or who has failed to comply with subpoenas or a similar order to appear or show cause relating to paternity or support proceedings may be suspended. When an obligor is 15 days delinquent making a payment in support or failure to comply with a subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or similar order in IV-D cases, the Title IV-D agency may provide notice to the obligor of the delinquency or failure to comply with a subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or similar order and the intent to suspend by regular United States mail that is posted to the obligor’s last address of record with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles. When an obligor is 15 days delinquent in making a payment in support in non-IV-D cases, and upon the request of the obligee, the depository or the clerk of the court must provide notice to the obligor of the delinquency and the intent to suspend by regular United States mail that is posted to the obligor’s last address of record with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles. In either case, the notice must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms of the order creating the support obligation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The period of the delinquency and the total amount of the delinquency as of the date of the notice or describe the subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or other similar order which has not been complied with;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That notification will be given to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to suspend the obligor’s driver’s license and motor vehicle registration unless, within 20 days after the date the notice is mailed, the obligor:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays the delinquency in full and any other costs and fees accrued between the date of the notice and the date the delinquency is paid;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enters into a written agreement for payment with the obligee in non-IV-D cases or with the Title IV-D agency in IV-D cases; or in IV-D cases, complies with a subpoena or order to appear, order to show cause, or a similar order; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Files a petition with the circuit court to contest the delinquency action; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays any applicable delinquency fees.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the obligor in non-IV-D cases enters into a written agreement for payment before the expiration of the 20-day period, the obligor must provide a copy of the signed written agreement to the depository or the clerk of the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon petition filed by the obligor in the circuit court within 20 days after the mailing date of the notice, the court may, in its discretion, direct the department to issue a license for driving privileges restricted to business purposes only, as defined by s. 322.271, if the person is otherwise qualified for such a license. As a condition for the court to exercise its discretion under this subsection, the obligor must agree to a schedule of payment on any child support arrearages and to maintain current child support obligations. If the obligor fails to comply with the schedule of payment, the court shall direct the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to suspend the obligor’s driver’s license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor must serve a copy of the petition on the Title IV-D agency in IV-D cases or on the depository or the clerk of the court in non-IV-D cases. When an obligor timely files a petition to set aside a suspension, the court must hear the matter within 15 days after the petition is filed. The court must enter an order resolving the matter within 10 days after the hearing, and a copy of the order must be served on the parties. The timely filing of a petition under this subsection stays the intent to suspend until the entry of a court order resolving the matter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor does not, within 20 days after the mailing date on the notice, pay the delinquency, enter into a payment agreement, comply with the subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or other similar order, or file a motion to contest, the Title IV-D agency in IV-D cases, or the depository or clerk of the court in non-IV-D cases, shall file the notice with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and request the suspension of the obligor’s driver’s license and motor vehicle registration in accordance with s. 322.058.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor may, within 20 days after the mailing date on the notice of delinquency or noncompliance and intent to suspend, file in the circuit court a petition to contest the notice of delinquency or noncompliance and intent to suspend on the ground of mistake of fact regarding the existence of a delinquency or the identity of the obligor. The obligor must serve a copy of the petition on the Title IV-D agency in IV-D cases or depository or clerk of the court in non-IV-D cases. When an obligor timely files a petition to contest, the court must hear the matter within 15 days after the petition is filed. The court must enter an order resolving the matter within 10 days after the hearing, and a copy of the order must be served on the parties. The timely filing of a petition to contest stays the notice of delinquency and intent to suspend until the entry of a court order resolving the matter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedures prescribed in this section and s. 322.058 may be used to enforce compliance with an order to appear for genetic testing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-222; s. 6, ch. 97-96; s. 5, ch. 97-170; s. 1, ch. 97-206; s. 4, ch. 99-375; s. 7, ch. 2001-158; s. 3, ch. 2005-39; s. 1, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>