<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.076" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distribution of retirement plans upon dissolution of marriage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All vested and nonvested benefits, rights, and funds accrued during the marriage in retirement, pension, profit-sharing, annuity, deferred compensation, and insurance plans and programs are marital assets subject to equitable distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the parties were married for at least 10 years, during which at least one of the parties who was a member of the federal uniformed services performed at least 10 years of creditable service, and if the division of marital property includes a division of uniformed services retired or retainer pay, the final judgment shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to identify the member of the uniformed services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification that the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act was observed if the decree was issued while the member was on active duty and was not represented in court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specification of the amount of retired or retainer pay to be distributed pursuant to the order, expressed in dollars or as a percentage of the disposable retired or retainer pay.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order which provides for distribution of retired or retainer pay from the federal uniformed services shall not provide for payment from this source more frequently than monthly and shall not require the payor to vary normal pay and disbursement cycles for retired or retainer pay in order to comply with the order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 88-98; s. 5, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>