<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.513" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation between courts; preservation of records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of this state may request the appropriate court of another state to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold an evidentiary hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order a person to produce or give evidence pursuant to the laws of that state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order that an evaluation be made with respect to the custody of a child involved in a pending proceeding pursuant to the laws of the state where the proceeding is pending;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forward to the court of this state a certified copy of the transcript of the record of the hearing, the evidence otherwise presented, and any evaluation prepared in compliance with the request; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order a party to a child custody proceeding or any person having physical custody of the child to appear in the proceeding with or without the child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of a court of another state, a court of this state may hold a hearing or enter an order described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Travel and other necessary and reasonable expenses incurred under subsections (1) and (2) may be assessed against the parties according to the laws of this state if the court has personal jurisdiction over the party against whom these expenses are being assessed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of this state shall preserve the pleadings, orders, decrees, records of hearings, evaluations, and other pertinent records with respect to a child custody proceeding until the child attains 18 years of age. Upon appropriate request by a court or law enforcement official of another state, the court shall forward a certified copy of these records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-65.</History></Section>