<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0061.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Depository for alimony transactions, support, maintenance, and support payments; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office of the clerk of the court shall operate a depository unless the depository is otherwise created by special act of the Legislature or unless, prior to June 1, 1985, a different entity was established to perform such functions. The department shall, no later than July 1, 1998, extend participation in the federal child support cost reimbursement program to the central depository in each county, to the maximum extent possible under existing federal law. The depository shall receive reimbursement for services provided under a cooperative agreement with the department pursuant to s. 61.1826. Each depository shall participate in the State Disbursement Unit and shall implement all statutory and contractual duties imposed on the State Disbursement Unit. Each depository shall receive from and transmit to the State Disbursement Unit required data through the Clerk of Court Child Support Enforcement Collection System. Payments on non-Title IV-D cases without income deduction orders shall not be sent to the State Disbursement Unit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request by the department, the depository created pursuant to paragraph (a) shall establish an account for the receipt and disbursement of support payments for Title IV-D interstate cases. The department shall provide a copy of the other state’s order with the request, and the depository shall advise the department of the account number in writing within 4 business days after receipt of the request.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payments not required to be processed through the State Disbursement Unit, the depository shall impose and collect a fee on each payment made for receiving, recording, reporting, disbursing, monitoring, or handling alimony or child support payments as required under this section. For non-Title IV-D cases required to be processed by the State Disbursement Unit pursuant to this chapter, the State Disbursement Unit shall, on each payment received, collect a fee, and shall transmit to the depository in which the case is located 40 percent of such service charge for the depository’s administration, management, and maintenance of such case. If a payment is made to the State Disbursement Unit which is not accompanied by the required fee, the State Disbursement Unit shall not deduct any moneys from the support payment for payment of the fee. The fee shall be a flat fee based, to the extent practicable, upon estimated reasonable costs of operation. The fee shall be reduced in any case in which the fixed fee results in a charge to any party of an amount greater than 3 percent of the amount of any support payment made in satisfaction of the amount which the party is obligated to pay, except that no fee shall be less than $1 nor more than $5 per payment made. The fee shall be considered by the court in determining the amount of support that the obligor is, or may be, required to pay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee imposed in paragraph (a) shall be increased to 4 percent of the support payments which the party is obligated to pay, except that no fee shall be more than $5.25. The fee shall be considered by the court in determining the amount of support that the obligor is, or may be, required to pay. Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 145.022, 75 percent of the additional revenues generated by this paragraph shall be remitted monthly to the Clerk of the Court Child Support Enforcement Collection System Trust Fund administered by the department as provided in subparagraph 2. These funds shall be used exclusively for the development, implementation, and operation of the Clerk of the Court Child Support Enforcement Collection System to be operated by the depositories, including the automation of civil case information necessary for the State Case Registry. The department shall contract with the Florida Association of Court Clerks and the depositories to design, establish, operate, upgrade, and maintain the automation of the depositories to include, but not be limited to, the provision of online electronic transfer of information to the IV-D agency as otherwise required by this chapter. The department’s obligation to fund the automation of the depositories is limited to the state share of funds available in the Clerk of the Court Child Support Enforcement Collection System Trust Fund. Each depository created under this section shall fully participate in the Clerk of the Court Child Support Enforcement Collection System and transmit data in a readable format as required by the contract between the Florida Association of Court Clerks and the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys to be remitted to the department by the depository shall be done daily by electronic funds transfer and calculated as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each support payment of less than $33, 18.75 cents.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each support payment between $33 and $140, an amount equal to 18.75 percent of the fee charged.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each support payment in excess of $140, 18.75 cents.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees established by this section shall be set forth and included in every order of support entered by a court of this state which requires payment to be made into the depository.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payments not required to be processed through the State Disbursement Unit, the depository shall collect and distribute all support payments paid into the depository to the appropriate party. On or after July 1, 1998, if a payment is made on a Title IV-D case which is not accompanied by the required transaction fee, the depository shall not deduct any moneys from the support payment for payment of the fee. Nonpayment of the required fee shall be considered a delinquency, and when the total of fees and costs which are due but not paid exceeds $50, the judgment by operation of law process set forth in s. 61.14(6)(a) shall become applicable and operational. As part of its collection and distribution functions, the depository shall maintain records listing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor’s name, address, social security number, place of employment, and any other sources of income.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligee’s name, address, and social security number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of support due as provided in the court order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The schedule of payment as provided in the court order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actual amount of each support payment received, the date of receipt, the amount disbursed, and the recipient of the disbursement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unpaid balance of any arrearage due as provided in the court order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other records as necessary to comply with federal reporting requirements.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository may require a payor or obligor to complete an information form, which shall request the following about the payor or obligor who provides payment by check:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full name, address, and home phone number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driver’s license number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social security number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name, address, and business phone number of obligor’s employer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date of birth.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weight and height.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as may be required by the State Attorney if prosecution for an insufficient check becomes necessary.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the depository requests such information, and a payor or obligor does not comply, the depository may refuse to accept personal checks from the payor or obligor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parties using the depository for support payments shall inform the depository of changes in their names or addresses. An obligor shall, additionally, notify the depository of all changes in employment or sources of income, including the payor’s name and address, and changes in the amounts of income received. Notification of all changes shall be made in writing to the depository within 7 days of a change.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When time-sharing of a child is relinquished by a parent who is entitled to receive child support moneys from the depository to the custody of a licensed or registered long-term care child agency, that agency may request from the court an order directing child support payments that would otherwise be distributed to the parent be distributed to the agency for the period of time that the child is with the agency. Thereafter, payments shall be distributed to the agency as if the agency were the parent until further order of the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository shall provide to the IV-D agency, at least once a month, a listing of IV-D accounts which identifies all delinquent accounts, the period of delinquency, and total amount of delinquency. The list shall be in alphabetical order by name of obligor, shall include the obligee’s name and case number, and shall be provided at no cost to the IV-D agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository shall accept a support payment tendered in the form of a check drawn on the account of a payor or obligor, unless the payor or obligor has previously remitted a check which was returned to the depository due to lack of sufficient funds in the account. If the payor or obligor has had a check returned for this reason, the depository shall accept payment by cash, cashier’s check, or money order, or may accept a check upon deposit by the payor or obligor of an amount equal to 1 month’s payment. Upon payment by cash, cashier’s check, or money order, the depository shall disburse the proceeds to the obligee within 2 working days. Payments drawn by check on the account of a payor or obligor shall be disbursed within 4 working days. Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 28.243, the administrator of the depository shall not be personally liable if the check tendered by the payor or obligor is not paid by the bank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified copies of payment records maintained by a depository shall without further proof be admitted into evidence in any legal proceeding in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository shall provide to the Title IV-D agency the date provided by a payor, as required in s. 61.1301, for each payment received and forwarded to the agency. If no date is provided by the payor, the depository shall provide the date of receipt by the depository and shall report to the Title IV-D agency those payors who fail to provide the date the deduction was made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before July 1, 1994, the depository shall provide information required by this chapter to be transmitted to the Title IV-D agency by online electronic transmission pursuant to rules promulgated by the Title IV-D agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the increase in fees as provided by paragraph (2)(b) expires or is otherwise terminated, the depository shall not be required to provide the Title IV-D agency the date provided by a payor as required by s. 61.1301.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with the requirements of this section shall be included as part of the annual county audit required pursuant to s. 218.39.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-112; s. 1, ch. 75-148; s. 4, ch. 84-110; s. 5, ch. 85-178; s. 126, ch. 86-220; s. 1, ch. 87-358; s. 24, ch. 88-176; s. 3, ch. 89-183; s. 9, ch. 92-138; s. 14, ch. 93-208; s. 2, ch. 96-190; s. 5, ch. 96-305; s. 8, ch. 97-170; ss. 10, 42, ch. 98-397; s. 1, ch. 99-5; s. 6, ch. 99-375; s. 9, ch. 2000-158; s. 12, ch. 2001-158; s. 4, ch. 2002-173; s. 74, ch. 2003-402; s. 51, ch. 2004-265; s. 4, ch. 2004-305; s. 5, ch. 2004-334; s. 12, ch. 2008-61.</History></Section>