<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0551.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License fee; tax rate; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE FEE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon submission of the initial application for a slot machine license and annually thereafter, on the anniversary date of the issuance of the initial license, the licensee must pay to the division a nonrefundable license fee of $3 million for the succeeding 12 months of licensure. In the 2010-2011 fiscal year, the licensee must pay the division a nonrefundable license fee of $2.5 million for the succeeding 12 months of licensure. In the 2011-2012 fiscal year and for every fiscal year thereafter, the licensee must pay the division a nonrefundable license fee of $2 million for the succeeding 12 months of licensure. The license fee shall be deposited into the Pari-mutuel Wagering Trust Fund of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation to be used by the division and the Department of Law Enforcement for investigations, regulation of slot machine gaming, and enforcement of slot machine gaming provisions under this chapter. These payments shall be accounted for separately from taxes or fees paid pursuant to the provisions of chapter 550.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to January 1, 2007, the division shall evaluate the license fee and shall make recommendations to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives regarding the optimum level of slot machine license fees in order to adequately support the slot machine regulatory program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TAX ON SLOT MACHINE REVENUES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax rate on slot machine revenues at each facility shall be 35 percent. If, during any state fiscal year, the aggregate amount of tax paid to the state by all slot machine licensees in Broward and Miami-Dade Counties is less than the aggregate amount of tax paid to the state by all slot machine licensees in the 2008-2009 fiscal year, each slot machine licensee shall pay to the state within 45 days after the end of the state fiscal year a surcharge equal to its pro rata share of an amount equal to the difference between the aggregate amount of tax paid to the state by all slot machine licensees in the 2008-2009 fiscal year and the amount of tax paid during the fiscal year. Each licensee’s pro rata share shall be an amount determined by dividing the number 1 by the number of facilities licensed to operate slot machines during the applicable fiscal year, regardless of whether the facility is operating such machines.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The slot machine revenue tax imposed by this section shall be paid to the division for deposit into the Pari-mutuel Wagering Trust Fund for immediate transfer by the Chief Financial Officer for deposit into the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund of the Department of Education. Any interest earnings on the tax revenues shall also be transferred to the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds transferred to the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund under paragraph (b) shall be used to supplement public education funding statewide.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If necessary to comply with any covenant established pursuant to s. 1013.68(4), s. 1013.70(1), or s. 1013.737(3), funds transferred to the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund under paragraph (b) shall first be available to pay debt service on lottery bonds issued to fund school construction in the event lottery revenues are insufficient for such purpose or to satisfy debt service reserve requirements established in connection with lottery bonds. Moneys available pursuant to this subparagraph are subject to annual appropriation by the Legislature.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PAYMENT AND DISPOSITION OF TAXES.<EmDash />Payment for the tax on slot machine revenues imposed by this section shall be paid to the division. The division shall deposit these sums with the Chief Financial Officer, to the credit of the Pari-mutuel Wagering Trust Fund. The slot machine licensee shall remit to the division payment for the tax on slot machine revenues. Such payments shall be remitted by 3 p.m. Wednesday of each week for taxes imposed and collected for the preceding week ending on Sunday. Beginning on July 1, 2012, the slot machine licensee shall remit to the division payment for the tax on slot machine revenues by 3 p.m. on the 5th day of each calendar month for taxes imposed and collected for the preceding calendar month. If the 5th day of the calendar month falls on a weekend, payments shall be remitted by 3 p.m. the first Monday following the weekend. The slot machine licensee shall file a report under oath by the 5th day of each calendar month for all taxes remitted during the preceding calendar month. Such payments shall be accompanied by a report under oath showing all slot machine gaming activities for the preceding calendar month and such other information as may be prescribed by the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TO PAY TAX; PENALTIES.<EmDash />A slot machine licensee who fails to make tax payments as required under this section is subject to an administrative penalty of up to $10,000 for each day the tax payment is not remitted. All administrative penalties imposed and collected shall be deposited into the Pari-mutuel Wagering Trust Fund of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation. If any slot machine licensee fails to pay penalties imposed by order of the division under this subsection, the division may suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the license of the slot machine licensee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUBMISSION OF FUNDS.<EmDash />The division may require slot machine licensees to remit taxes, fees, fines, and assessments by electronic funds transfer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-362; s. 1, ch. 2006-27; s. 1, ch. 2007-59; s. 5, ch. 2007-252; s. 21, ch. 2009-170; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-29.</History>
</Section>