<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0551.104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License to conduct slot machine gaming.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application and a finding by the division after investigation that the application is complete and the applicant is qualified and payment of the initial license fee, the division may issue a license to conduct slot machine gaming in the designated slot machine gaming area of the eligible facility. Once licensed, slot machine gaming may be conducted subject to the requirements of this chapter and rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application may be approved by the division only after the voters of the county where the applicant’s facility is located have authorized by referendum slot machines within pari-mutuel facilities in that county as specified in s. 23, Art. X of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A slot machine license may be issued only to a licensed pari-mutuel permitholder, and slot machine gaming may be conducted only at the eligible facility at which the permitholder is authorized under its valid pari-mutuel wagering permit to conduct pari-mutuel wagering activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of licensure and to maintain continued authority for the conduct of slot machine gaming, the slot machine licensee shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continue to be in compliance with this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continue to be in compliance with chapter 550, where applicable, and maintain the pari-mutuel permit and license in good standing pursuant to the provisions of chapter 550. Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law and in order to expedite the operation of slot machines at eligible facilities, any eligible facility shall be entitled within 60 days after the effective date of this act to amend its 2006-2007 pari-mutuel wagering operating license issued by the division under ss. 550.0115 and 550.01215. The division shall issue a new license to the eligible facility to effectuate any approved change.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct no fewer than a full schedule of live racing or games as defined in s. 550.002(11). A permitholder’s responsibility to conduct such number of live races or games shall be reduced by the number of races or games that could not be conducted due to the direct result of fire, war, hurricane, or other disaster or event beyond the control of the permitholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of any changes relating to the pari-mutuel permit by the division, be responsible for providing appropriate current and accurate documentation on a timely basis to the division in order to continue the slot machine license in good standing. Changes in ownership or interest of a slot machine license of 5 percent or more of the stock or other evidence of ownership or equity in the slot machine license or any parent corporation or other business entity that in any way owns or controls the slot machine license shall be approved by the division prior to such change, unless the owner is an existing holder of that license who was previously approved by the division. Changes in ownership or interest of a slot machine license of less than 5 percent, unless such change results in a cumulative total of 5 percent or more, shall be reported to the division within 20 days after the change. The division may then conduct an investigation to ensure that the license is properly updated to show the change in ownership or interest. No reporting is required if the person is holding 5 percent or less equity or securities of a corporate owner of the slot machine licensee that has its securities registered pursuant to s. 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, 15 U.S.C. ss. 78a-78kk, and if such corporation or entity files with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission the reports required by s. 13 of that act or if the securities of the corporation or entity are regularly traded on an established securities market in the United States. A change in ownership or interest of less than 5 percent which results in a cumulative ownership or interest of 5 percent or more shall be approved by the division prior to such change unless the owner is an existing holder of the license who was previously approved by the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the division and the Department of Law Enforcement unrestricted access to and right of inspection of facilities of a slot machine licensee in which any activity relative to the conduct of slot machine gaming is conducted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the facilities-based computer system that the licensee will use for operational and accounting functions of the slot machine facility is specifically structured to facilitate regulatory oversight. The facilities-based computer system shall be designed to provide the division and the Department of Law Enforcement with the ability to monitor, at any time on a real-time basis, the wagering patterns, payouts, tax collection, and such other operations as necessary to determine whether the facility is in compliance with statutory provisions and rules adopted by the division for the regulation and control of slot machine gaming. The division and the Department of Law Enforcement shall have complete and continuous access to this system. Such access shall include the ability of either the division or the Department of Law Enforcement to suspend play immediately on particular slot machines if monitoring of the system indicates possible tampering or manipulation of those slot machines or the ability to suspend play immediately of the entire operation if the tampering or manipulation is of the computer system itself. The computer system shall be reviewed and approved by the division to ensure necessary access, security, and functionality. The division may adopt rules to provide for the approval process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that each slot machine is protected from manipulation or tampering to affect the random probabilities of winning plays. The division or the Department of Law Enforcement shall have the authority to suspend play upon reasonable suspicion of any manipulation or tampering. When play has been suspended on any slot machine, the division or the Department of Law Enforcement may examine any slot machine to determine whether the machine has been tampered with or manipulated and whether the machine should be returned to operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a security plan, including the facilities’ floor plan, the locations of security cameras, and a listing of all security equipment that is capable of observing and electronically recording activities being conducted in the facilities of the slot machine licensee. The security plan must meet the minimum security requirements as determined by the division under s. 551.103(1)(i) and be implemented prior to operation of slot machine gaming. The slot machine licensee’s facilities must adhere to the security plan at all times. Any changes to the security plan must be submitted by the licensee to the division prior to implementation. The division shall furnish copies of the security plan and changes in the plan to the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create and file with the division a written policy for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creating opportunities to purchase from vendors in this state, including minority vendors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creating opportunities for employment of residents of this state, including minority residents.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring opportunities for construction services from minority contractors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring that opportunities for employment are offered on an equal, nondiscriminatory basis.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training for employees on responsible gaming and working with a compulsive or addictive gambling prevention program to further its purposes as provided for in s. 551.118.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The implementation of a drug-testing program that includes, but is not limited to, requiring each employee to sign an agreement that he or she understands that the slot machine facility is a drug-free workplace.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The slot machine licensee shall use the Internet-based job-listing system of the Department of Economic Opportunity in advertising employment opportunities. Beginning in June 2007, each slot machine licensee shall provide an annual report to the division containing information indicating compliance with this paragraph in regard to minority persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the payout percentage of a slot machine gaming facility is at least 85 percent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A slot machine license is not transferable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A slot machine licensee shall keep and maintain permanent daily records of its slot machine operation and shall maintain such records for a period of not less than 5 years. These records must include all financial transactions and contain sufficient detail to determine compliance with the requirements of this chapter. All records shall be available for audit and inspection by the division, the Department of Law Enforcement, or other law enforcement agencies during the licensee’s regular business hours.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A slot machine licensee shall file with the division a monthly report containing the required records of such slot machine operation. The required reports shall be submitted on forms prescribed by the division and shall be due at the same time as the monthly pari-mutuel reports are due to the division, and the reports shall be deemed public records once filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A slot machine licensee shall file with the division an audit of the receipt and distribution of all slot machine revenues provided by an independent certified public accountant verifying compliance with all financial and auditing provisions of this chapter and the associated rules adopted under this chapter. The audit must include verification of compliance with all statutes and rules regarding all required records of slot machine operations. Such audit shall be filed within 60 days after the completion of the permitholder’s pari-mutuel meet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may share any information with the Department of Law Enforcement, any other law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over slot machine gaming or pari-mutuel activities, or any other state or federal law enforcement agency the division or the Department of Law Enforcement deems appropriate. Any law enforcement agency having jurisdiction over slot machine gaming or pari-mutuel activities may share any information obtained or developed by it with the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No slot machine license or renewal thereof shall be issued to an applicant holding a permit under chapter 550 to conduct pari-mutuel wagering meets of thoroughbred racing unless the applicant has on file with the division a binding written agreement between the applicant and the Florida Horsemen’s Benevolent and Protective Association, Inc., governing the payment of purses on live thoroughbred races conducted at the licensee’s pari-mutuel facility. In addition, no slot machine license or renewal thereof shall be issued to such an applicant unless the applicant has on file with the division a binding written agreement between the applicant and the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, Inc., governing the payment of breeders’, stallion, and special racing awards on live thoroughbred races conducted at the licensee’s pari-mutuel facility. The agreement governing purses and the agreement governing awards may direct the payment of such purses and awards from revenues generated by any wagering or gaming the applicant is authorized to conduct under Florida law. All purses and awards shall be subject to the terms of chapter 550. All sums for breeders’, stallion, and special racing awards shall be remitted monthly to the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, Inc., for the payment of awards subject to the administrative fee authorized in s. 550.2625(3).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No slot machine license or renewal thereof shall be issued to an applicant holding a permit under chapter 550 to conduct pari-mutuel wagering meets of quarter horse racing unless the applicant has on file with the division a binding written agreement between the applicant and the Florida Quarter Horse Racing Association or the association representing a majority of the horse owners and trainers at the applicant’s eligible facility, governing the payment of purses on live quarter horse races conducted at the licensee’s pari-mutuel facility. The agreement governing purses may direct the payment of such purses from revenues generated by any wagering or gaming the applicant is authorized to conduct under Florida law. All purses shall be subject to the terms of chapter 550.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall suspend a slot machine license if one or more of the agreements required under paragraph (a) are terminated or otherwise cease to operate or if the division determines that the licensee is materially failing to comply with the terms of such an agreement. Any such suspension shall take place in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agreement required under paragraph (a) cannot be reached prior to the initial issuance of the slot machine license, either party may request arbitration or, in the case of a renewal, if an agreement required under paragraph (a) is not in place 120 days prior to the scheduled expiration date of the slot machine license, the applicant shall immediately ask the American Arbitration Association to furnish a list of 11 arbitrators, each of whom shall have at least 5 years of commercial arbitration experience and no financial interest in or prior relationship with any of the parties or their affiliated or related entities or principals. Each required party to the agreement shall select a single arbitrator from the list provided by the American Arbitration Association within 10 days of receipt, and the individuals so selected shall choose one additional arbitrator from the list within the next 10 days.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agreement required under paragraph (a) is not in place 60 days after the request under subparagraph 1. in the case of an initial slot machine license or, in the case of a renewal, 60 days prior to the scheduled expiration date of the slot machine license, the matter shall be immediately submitted to mandatory binding arbitration to resolve the disagreement between the parties. The three arbitrators selected pursuant to subparagraph 1. shall constitute the panel that shall arbitrate the dispute between the parties pursuant to the American Arbitration Association Commercial Arbitration Rules and chapter 682.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of the proceedings, which shall be no later than 90 days after the request under subparagraph 1. in the case of an initial slot machine license or, in the case of a renewal, 30 days prior to the scheduled expiration date of the slot machine license, the arbitration panel shall present to the parties a proposed agreement that the majority of the panel believes equitably balances the rights, interests, obligations, and reasonable expectations of the parties. The parties shall immediately enter into such agreement, which shall satisfy the requirements of paragraph (a) and permit issuance of the pending annual slot machine license or renewal. The agreement produced by the arbitration panel under this subparagraph shall be effective until the last day of the license or renewal period or until the parties enter into a different agreement. Each party shall pay its respective costs of arbitration and shall pay one-half of the costs of the arbitration panel, unless the parties otherwise agree. If the agreement produced by the arbitration panel under this subparagraph remains in place 120 days prior to the scheduled issuance of the next annual license renewal, then the arbitration process established in this paragraph will begin again.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that neither of the agreements required under subparagraph (a)1. or the agreement required under subparagraph (a)2. are in place by the deadlines established in this paragraph, arbitration regarding each agreement will proceed independently, with separate lists of arbitrators, arbitration panels, arbitration proceedings, and resulting agreements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to the agreements required under paragraph (a) governing the payment of purses, the arbitration and resulting agreement called for under this paragraph shall be limited to the payment of purses from slot machine revenues only.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any provision of this subsection or its application to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the invalidity does not affect other provisions or applications of this subsection or chapter which can be given effect without the invalid provision or application, and to this end the provisions of this subsection are severable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-362; s. 3, ch. 2007-252; s. 20, ch. 2009-170; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-29; s. 409, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>