<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0784.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Felony battery; domestic battery by strangulation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits felony battery if he or she:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actually and intentionally touches or strikes another person against the will of the other; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causes great bodily harm, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits domestic battery by strangulation if the person knowingly and intentionally, against the will of another, impedes the normal breathing or circulation of the blood of a family or household member or of a person with whom he or she is in a dating relationship, so as to create a risk of or cause great bodily harm by applying pressure on the throat or neck of the other person or by blocking the nose or mouth of the other person. This paragraph does not apply to any act of medical diagnosis, treatment, or prescription which is authorized under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Family or household member” has the same meaning as in s. 741.28.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dating relationship” means a continuing and significant relationship of a romantic or intimate nature.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits felony battery or domestic battery by strangulation commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-183; s. 1, ch. 2007-133.</History></Section>