<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0784.074" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assault or battery on sexually violent predators detention or commitment facility staff; reclassification of offenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person is charged with committing an assault or aggravated assault or a battery or aggravated battery upon a staff member of a sexually violent predators detention or commitment facility as defined in part V of chapter 394, while the staff member is engaged in the lawful performance of his or her duties and when the person committing the offense knows or has reason to know the identity or employment of the victim, the offense for which the person is charged shall be reclassified as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of aggravated battery, from a felony of the second degree to a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an aggravated assault, from a felony of the third degree to a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of battery, from a misdemeanor of the first degree to a felony of the third degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of assault, from a misdemeanor of the second degree to a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, a staff member of the facilities listed includes persons employed by the Department of Children and Family Services, persons employed at facilities licensed by the Department of Children and Family Services, and persons employed at facilities operated under a contract with the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-244; s. 116, ch. 2002-1.</History></Section>