<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0784.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assault or battery on persons 65 years of age or older; reclassification of offenses; minimum sentence.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is convicted of an aggravated assault or aggravated battery upon a person 65 years of age or older shall be sentenced to a minimum term of imprisonment of 3 years and fined not more than $10,000 and shall also be ordered by the sentencing judge to make restitution to the victim of such offense and to perform up to 500 hours of community service work. Restitution and community service work shall be in addition to any fine or sentence which may be imposed and shall not be in lieu thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person is charged with committing an assault or aggravated assault or a battery or aggravated battery upon a person 65 years of age or older, regardless of whether he or she knows or has reason to know the age of the victim, the offense for which the person is charged shall be reclassified as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of aggravated battery, from a felony of the second degree to a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of aggravated assault, from a felony of the third degree to a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of battery, from a misdemeanor of the first degree to a felony of the third degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of assault, from a misdemeanor of the second degree to a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 948.01, adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence shall not be suspended, deferred, or withheld.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-327; s. 1, ch. 92-50; s. 18, ch. 93-406; s. 1200, ch. 97-102; s. 19, ch. 97-194; s. 5, ch. 99-188; s. 1, ch. 2002-208.</History></Section>