<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0011.51" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability is authorized to examine all entities and records listed in s. 11.45(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of an examination, the designated representative of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall discuss the examination with the official whose office is examined and submit to that official the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability’s preliminary findings. If the official is not available for receipt of the preliminary findings, clearly designated as such, delivery thereof is presumed to be made when it is delivered to his or her office. Whenever necessary, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability may request the official to submit his or her written statement of explanation or rebuttal within 15 days after the receipt of the findings. If the response time is not requested to be within 15 days, the official shall submit his or her response within 30 days after receipt of the preliminary findings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 18 months after the release of a report of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, the agencies that are the subject of that report shall provide data and other information that describes with specificity what the agencies have done to respond to the recommendations contained in the report. The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability may verify the data and information provided by the agencies. If the data and information provided by the agencies are deemed sufficient and accurate, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall report to the Legislative Auditing Committee and to the legislative standing committees concerned with the subject areas of the audit. The report shall include a summary of the agencies’ responses, the evaluation of those responses, and any recommendations deemed to be appropriate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work papers held by the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability which relate to an authorized project or a research product are exempt from s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. The exemption applies to work papers held by the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability before, on, or after the effective date of the exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 90-110; s. 16, ch. 94-249; s. 30, ch. 96-318; s. 1, ch. 96-380; s. 6, ch. 2001-86; s. 17, ch. 2001-266; s. 3, ch. 2004-305; s. 14, ch. 2011-34; s. 1, ch. 2011-35.</History>
</Section>