<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.62" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative review of proposed regulation of unregulated functions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Sunrise Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That no profession or occupation be subject to regulation by the state unless the regulation is necessary to protect the public health, safety, or welfare from significant and discernible harm or damage and that the police power of the state be exercised only to the extent necessary for that purpose; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That no profession or occupation be regulated by the state in a manner that unnecessarily restricts entry into the practice of the profession or occupation or adversely affects the availability of the professional or occupational services to the public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether to regulate a profession or occupation, the Legislature shall consider the following factors:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the unregulated practice of the profession or occupation will substantially harm or endanger the public health, safety, or welfare, and whether the potential for harm is recognizable and not remote;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the practice of the profession or occupation requires specialized skill or training, and whether that skill or training is readily measurable or quantifiable so that examination or training requirements would reasonably assure initial and continuing professional or occupational ability;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the regulation will have an unreasonable effect on job creation or job retention in the state or will place unreasonable restrictions on the ability of individuals who seek to practice or who are practicing a given profession or occupation to find employment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the public is or can be effectively protected by other means; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the overall cost-effectiveness and economic impact of the proposed regulation, including the indirect costs to consumers, will be favorable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proponents of legislation that provides for the regulation of a profession or occupation not already expressly subject to state regulation shall provide, upon request, the following information in writing to the state agency that is proposed to have jurisdiction over the regulation and to the legislative committees to which the legislation is referred:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of individuals or businesses that would be subject to the regulation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each association that represents members of the profession or occupation, together with a copy of its codes of ethics or conduct;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of the nature and extent of the harm to the public caused by the unregulated practice of the profession or occupation, including a description of any complaints that have been lodged against persons who have practiced the profession or occupation in this state during the preceding 3 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of states that regulate the profession or occupation, and the dates of enactment of each law providing for such regulation and a copy of each law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list and description of state and federal laws that have been enacted to protect the public with respect to the profession or occupation and a statement of the reasons why these laws have not proven adequate to protect the public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the voluntary efforts made by members of the profession or occupation to protect the public and a statement of the reasons why these efforts are not adequate to protect the public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of any federal legislation mandating regulation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of the reasons why other types of less restrictive regulation would not effectively protect the public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost, availability, and appropriateness of training and examination requirements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of regulation, including the indirect cost to consumers, and the method proposed to finance the regulation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost imposed on applicants or practitioners or on employers of applicants or practitioners as a result of the regulation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The details of any previous efforts in this state to implement regulation of the profession or occupation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information the agency or the committee considers relevant to the analysis of the proposed legislation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall provide the Legislature with information concerning the effect of proposed legislation that provides for new regulation of a profession or occupation regarding:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The departmental resources necessary to implement and enforce the proposed regulation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The technical sufficiency of the proposal for regulation, including its consistency with the regulation of other professions and occupations under existing law; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, any alternatives to the proposed regulation which may result in a less restrictive or more cost-effective regulatory scheme.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When making a recommendation concerning proposed legislation providing for new regulation of a profession or occupation, a legislative committee shall determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the regulation is justified based on the criteria specified in subsection (3), the information submitted pursuant to request under subsection (4), and the information provided under subsection (5);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The least restrictive and most cost-effective regulatory scheme that will adequately protect the public; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The technical sufficiency of the proposed legislation, including its consistency with the regulation of other professions and occupations under existing law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 94-218; s. 133, ch. 99-251.</History></Section>