<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0011.249" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commissioners to the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall appoint, subject to confirmation by the Senate, three commissioners to the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws. Such appointed commissioners, together with any residents of the state who because of long service in the cause of the uniformity of state legislation shall have been elected life members from this state of the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws, shall constitute Florida’s representatives to the national conference.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners shall examine the subjects of marriage and dissolution of marriage, insolvency, form of notarial certificates, descent and distribution of property, acknowledgment of deeds, execution and probate of wills, and other subjects; ascertain the best means to effect assimilation and uniformity in the laws of the state, and cooperate and advise with similar commissions appointed for a like purpose in other states of the union; and, if wise and practicable, draft uniform laws to be submitted for the approval and adoption of the several states, and devise and recommend such other course of action as shall best accomplish the purposes of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said appointed commissioners shall serve for 4 years. All commissioners and the associate member shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coordinator of the Office of Legislative Services shall designate an appropriate legislative employee to serve as an associate member and secretary to the Florida commissioners to the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws. He or she shall prepare and sign all vouchers authorized by law and keep such records as directed by the commissioners.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 4447, 1895; GS 66; RGS 77; CGL 93; s. 1, ch. 61-42; s. 19, ch. 63-400; s. 2, ch. 67-472; ss. 1, 29, 30, ch. 69-52; s. 12, ch. 72-178; s. 1, ch. 73-300; s. 1, ch. 77-85; s. 1, ch. 88-70; s. 30, ch. 95-147; s. 18, ch. 98-136; s. 10, ch. 2010-102.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 11.01; s. 13.10.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>