<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.9005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Government Efficiency Task Force.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Government Efficiency Task Force. The task force shall convene no later than January 2007, and each 4th year thereafter. The task force shall be composed of 15 members. Five members shall be appointed by the President of the Senate, five members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and five members shall be appointed by the Governor. The task force shall be composed of members of the Legislature and representatives from the private and public sectors, as designated by the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Governor. Each member shall serve at the pleasure of the officer who appointed the member. A vacancy on the task force shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. The terms of the members shall be for 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The task force shall elect a chair from among its members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The task force shall meet as necessary, but at least quarterly, at the call of the chair and at the time and place designated by him or her. The task force may conduct its meetings through teleconferences or other similar means.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the task force are entitled to receive reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses pursuant to s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The task force shall develop recommendations for improving governmental operations and reducing costs. Staff to assist the task force in performing its duties shall be assigned by the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Governor. The task force shall consider reports issued by the Auditor General, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, and agency inspectors general in developing its recommendations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The task force shall complete its work within 1 year and submit its recommendations to the chairperson and vice chairperson of the Legislative Budget Commission, the Governor, and the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court. The task force may submit all or part of its recommendations at any time during the year, but a final report summarizing its recommendations must be submitted at the completion of its work.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2006-119.</History></Section>