<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.2423" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Laws or statutes not repealed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No special or local statute, or statute, local, limited or special in its nature, shall be repealed by the Florida Statutes, now or hereafter adopted, and, for the purpose of this saving from repeal any statute of the following classes shall be taken to be included in such exception, namely:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statutes for or concerning only a certain county or certain designated counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statute for, or concerning or operative in only a portion of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statute for or concerning only a certain municipal corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statute for or concerning only a designated individual corporation or corporations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statute incorporating a designated individual corporation, or making a grant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statute of such limited or local application as makes its inclusion in a general statute impracticable or undesirable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Road designation laws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Severability section in any law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act of the Legislature declaring a trust fund to be exempt from termination pursuant to s. 19(f), Art. III of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foregoing enumeration of classes of statutes not repealed shall not be construed to imply a repeal of other statutes which are local, limited or special in their nature.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 20719, 1941; s. 3, ch. 22000, 1943; s. 3, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 3, ch. 24337, 1947; s. 3, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 3, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 3, ch. 27991, 1953; s. 3, ch. 59-1; s. 3, ch. 77-104; s. 5, ch. 99-205; s. 4, ch. 99-243.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 16.21.</Text></Note></Section>