<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0011.0455" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electronic filing of compensation reports and other information.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “electronic filing system” means an Internet system for recording and reporting lobbying compensation and other required information by reporting period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each lobbying firm that is required to file reports with the Office of Legislative Services pursuant to s. 11.045 must file such reports with the office by means of the office’s electronic filing system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report filed pursuant to this section must be completed and filed through the electronic filing system not later than 11:59 p.m. of the day designated in s. 11.045. A report not filed by 11:59 p.m. of the day designated is a late-filed report and is subject to the penalties under s. 11.045(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each report filed pursuant to this section is deemed to meet the certification requirements of s. 11.045(3)(a)4., and as such subjects the person responsible for filing and the lobbying firm to the provisions of s. 11.045(7) and (8). Persons given a secure sign-on to the electronic filing system are responsible for protecting it from disclosure and are responsible for all filings using such credentials, unless they have notified the office that their credentials have been compromised.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The electronic filing system developed by the office must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be based on access by means of the Internet.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be accessible by anyone with Internet access using standard web-browsing software.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for direct entry of compensation report information as well as upload of such information from software authorized by the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a method that prevents unauthorized access to electronic filing system functions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each house of the Legislature shall provide by rule, or may provide by a joint rule adopted by both houses, procedures to implement and administer this section, including, but not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alternate filing procedures in case the office’s electronic filing system is not operable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance of an electronic receipt to the person submitting the report indicating and verifying the date and time that the report was filed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each house of the Legislature shall provide by rule that the office make all the data filed available on the Internet in an easily understood and accessible format. The Internet website must also include, but not be limited to, the names and business addresses of lobbyists, lobbying firms, and principals, the affiliations between lobbyists and principals, and the classification system designated and identified by each principal pursuant to s. 11.045(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2005-359; s. 2, ch. 2012-51.</History>
</Section>