<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Auditor General.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General appointed in this section is the auditor that is required by s. 2, Art. III of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General shall be appointed to office to serve at the pleasure of the Legislature, by a majority vote of the members of the Legislative Auditing Committee, subject to confirmation by both houses of the Legislature. At the time of her or his appointment, the Auditor General shall have been certified under the Public Accountancy Law in this state for a period of at least 10 years and shall have had not less than 10 years’ experience in an accounting or auditing related field. Vacancies in the office shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To carry out her or his duties the Auditor General shall make all spending decisions within the annual operating budget approved by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. The Auditor General shall employ qualified persons necessary for the efficient operation of the Auditor General’s office and shall fix their duties and compensation and, with the approval of the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, shall adopt and administer a uniform personnel, job classification, and pay plan for such employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall be employed as a financial auditor who does not possess the qualifications to take the examination for a certificate as certified public accountant under the laws of this state, and no person shall be employed or retained as legal adviser, on either a full-time or a part-time basis, who is not a member of The Florida Bar.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General, before entering upon the duties of the office, shall take and subscribe the oath of office required of state officers by the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appointment of the Auditor General may be terminated at any time by a majority vote of both houses of the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The headquarters of the Auditor General shall be at the state capital, but to facilitate auditing and to eliminate unnecessary traveling the Auditor General may establish field offices located outside the state capital. The Auditor General shall be provided with adequate quarters to carry out the position’s functions in the state capital and in other areas of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All payrolls and vouchers for the operations of the Auditor General’s office shall be submitted to the Chief Financial Officer and, if found to be correct, payments shall be issued therefor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General may make and enforce reasonable rules and regulations necessary to facilitate audits which she or he is authorized to perform.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No officer or salaried employee of the Office of the Auditor General shall serve as the representative of any political party or on any executive committee or other governing body thereof; serve as an executive, officer, or employee of any political party committee, organization, or association; or be engaged on behalf of any candidate for public office in the solicitation of votes or other activities in behalf of such candidacy. Neither the Auditor General nor any employee of the Auditor General may become a candidate for election to public office unless she or he first resigns from office or employment. No officer or salaried employee of the Auditor General shall actively engage in any other business or profession or be otherwise employed without the prior written permission of the Auditor General.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 11.25(1) and 11.26 shall not apply to the Auditor General.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 67-470; s. 3, ch. 69-82; s. 1, ch. 86-217; s. 1, ch. 91-162; s. 1, ch. 94-322; s. 1308, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 95-395; s. 24, ch. 96-318; s. 1, ch. 97-2; s. 71, ch. 97-190; s. 1, ch. 99-4; s. 2, ch. 99-333; s. 14, ch. 2001-266; s. 6, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 11.183.</Text></Note></Section>