<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proof of publication of notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affidavit of proof of publication of such notice of intention to apply therefor, may be made, in substantially the following general form, but such form shall not be exclusive:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Before the undersigned authority personally appeared <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, who on oath does solemnly swear (or affirm) that she or he has knowledge of the matters stated herein; that a notice stating the substance of a contemplated law or proposed bill relating to</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(here identify bill)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">has been published at least 30 days prior to this date, by being printed in the issues of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(here state day, month and year of issue or issues)</Directions> of the <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, a newspaper or newspapers published in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County or Counties, Florida (or) there being no newspaper, by being posted for at least 30 days prior to this date at three public places in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County or Counties, one of which places was at the courthouse of said county or counties, where the matter or thing to be affected by the contemplated law is situated; that a copy of the notice that has been published as aforesaid and also this affidavit of proof of publication are attached to the proposed bill or contemplated law, and such copy of the notice so attached is by reference made a part of this affidavit. 
<HorizontalRule Type="Full" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such affidavit of proof of publication shall be attached to the contemplated law when it is introduced into the Legislature. A true copy of the notice published or posted shall also be attached to the bill when introduced, but it shall not be necessary to enter said published or posted notice, or proof thereof, in the journals. The fact that such notice was established in the Legislature shall in every case be recited upon the journals of the Senate and of the House of Representatives, and the notice published and affidavit of publication thereof shall accompany the bill throughout the Legislature and be preserved as a part thereof in the Department of State.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 3708, 1887; RS 67; GS 68; RGS 79; CGL 95; s. 1, ch. 13791, 1929; s. 1, ch. 21635, 1943; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 95-147; s. 11, ch. 98-246.</History></Section>