<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0011.47" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; failure to make a proper audit or examination; making a false report; failure to produce documents or information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All officers whose respective offices the Auditor General or the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability is authorized to audit or examine shall enter into their public records sufficient information for proper audit or examination, and shall make the same available to the Auditor General or the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability on demand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The willful failure or refusal of the Auditor General, director of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, or any staff employed by the Auditor General or the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability to make a proper audit or examination in line with his or her duty, the willful making of a false report as to any audit or examination, or the willful failure or refusal to report a shortage or misappropriation of funds or property shall be cause for removal from such office or employment, and the Auditor General, the director of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability, or a staff member shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully fails or refuses to furnish or produce any book, record, paper, document, data, or sufficient information necessary to a proper audit or examination which the Auditor General or the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability is by law authorized to perform shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer who willfully fails or refuses to furnish or produce any book, record, paper, document, data, or sufficient information necessary to a proper audit or examination which the Auditor General or the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability is by law authorized to perform, shall be subject to removal from office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 69-82; s. 9, ch. 71-136; s. 22, ch. 95-147; s. 27, ch. 96-318; s. 16, ch. 2001-266.</History></Section>