<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Oversight of the commission; long-range policy planning; plans, reports, and recommendations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall exercise oversight of the activities of the commission to the extent necessary to facilitate the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate efficient and cost-effective regulation, the commission and the department, where appropriate, shall develop and implement a long-range policy planning and monitoring process to include recommendations specific to the commission. Included in the plan shall be specific recommendations regarding performance standards and measurable outcomes for the commission. Such process shall include estimates of revenues, expenditures, cash balances, and performance statistics for the commission. The period covered shall not be less than 5 years. The commission, with assistance from the department, shall develop the long-range plan which must be approved by the Governor. The department shall monitor compliance with the approved long-range plan and shall assist the commission in annually updating the plan for approval by the Governor. The department shall provide concise management reports to the commission and the Governor quarterly. As part of the review process, the department shall evaluate:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the commission is operating efficiently and effectively and if there is need for assistance to help the commission in ensuring cost-effective regulation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How and why pugilistic exhibitions and contests are regulated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether there is a need to continue regulation, and to what degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not licensee and consumer protection is adequate, and how it can be improved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether unlicensed activity is adequately enforced.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such plans should include conclusions and recommendations on these and other issues as appropriate. Such plans shall be provided to the Governor and the Legislature by November 1 of each year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 115, ch. 99-251.</History></Section>