<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension or revocation of license or permit by commission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may suspend or revoke a license or permit if the commission finds that the licensee or permittee:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is guilty of violating this chapter or the rules of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has committed fraud or deceit in securing any license or permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted of, has pleaded guilty to, has entered a plea of nolo contendere to, or has been found guilty of a crime involving moral turpitude in any jurisdiction within 10 years preceding the suspension or revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is guilty of unprofessional or unethical conduct.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made a misstatement of a material fact, fraudulently concealed a material fact, or induced or aided another person in misstating or concealing any material fact in any application or other proceeding under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to account for or pay over moneys belonging to others which have come into her or his possession in connection with a match.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to furnish to the proper party a copy of any contract or statement required by this chapter or has breached such a contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has paid or agreed to pay any money or article of value to any licensee or permittee for soliciting or for business secured or for rendering any service or the doing of any of the acts forbidden by this chapter and the rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has loaned her or his license or permit to another person or has borrowed or used the license or permit of another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has employed a person who does not hold a license or permit as required by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to maintain in force the bond required by this chapter or has failed to deposit with the commission the required cash, check, or securities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been disciplined by the Florida State Boxing Commission or similar agency or body of any jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to pay a fine imposed under this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 777, ch. 97-103; s. 130, ch. 99-251.</History></Section>