<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.043" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Weights and classes, limitations; gloves.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish classes of participants based upon weights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish by rule the acceptable difference in weight between participants; however, the maximum difference in weight in boxing matches shall not exceed 12 pounds, except matches in the cruiserweight and heavyweight classes and exhibitions held solely for training purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish by rule the appropriate weight of gloves to be used in each boxing match; however, all participants in boxing matches shall wear gloves weighing not less than 8 ounces each and participants in mixed martial arts matches shall wear gloves weighing 4 to 8 ounces each. Participants shall wear such protective devices as the commission deems necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participants in a match shall be weighed on the same scale at a time and place to be determined by the commission or a commission representative. The weigh-in shall be conducted in the presence of the opponent of the participant and a commission representative. If a participant fails to arrive at the weigh-in at the scheduled time and place, the opponent of the late-arriving participant will be permitted to be weighed without the late-arriving participant present. The participant who arrived at the weigh-in on time shall not lose his or her right of observing the weighing in of his or her opponent. The weigh-in shall occur no sooner than 4 p.m. on the day preceding the date of the program of matches or at such other time as designated by the commission or commission representative.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 6, ch. 88-365; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 123, ch. 99-251; s. 12, ch. 2002-172.</History></Section>