<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida State Boxing Commission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida State Boxing Commission is created and is assigned to the Department of Business and Professional Regulation for administrative and fiscal accountability purposes only. The Florida State Boxing Commission shall consist of five members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. One member must be a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459, who must maintain an unencumbered license in good standing, and who must, at the time of her or his appointment, have practiced medicine for at least 5 years. Upon the expiration of the term of a commissioner, the Governor shall appoint a successor to serve for a 4-year term. A commissioner whose term has expired shall continue to serve on the commission until such time as a replacement is appointed. If a vacancy on the commission occurs prior to the expiration of the term, it shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida State Boxing Commission, as created by subsection (1), shall administer the provisions of this chapter. The commission has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter and to implement each of the duties and responsibilities conferred upon the commission, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of an ethical code of conduct for commissioners, commission staff, and commission officials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facility and safety requirements relating to the ring, floor plan and apron seating, emergency medical equipment and services, and other equipment and services necessary for the conduct of a program of matches.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements regarding a participant’s apparel, bandages, handwraps, gloves, mouthpiece, and appearance during a match.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements relating to a manager’s participation, presence, and conduct during a match.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duties and responsibilities of all licensees under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for hearings and resolution of disputes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifications for appointment of referees and judges.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifications for and appointment of chief inspectors and inspectors and duties and responsibilities of chief inspectors and inspectors with respect to oversight and coordination of activities for each program of matches regulated under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation and duties of a knockdown timekeeper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Setting fee and reimbursement schedules for referees and other officials appointed by the commission or the representative of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of criteria for approval, disapproval, suspension of approval, and revocation of approval of amateur sanctioning organizations for amateur boxing, kickboxing, and mixed martial arts held in this state, including, but not limited to, the health and safety standards the organizations use before, during, and after the matches to ensure the health, safety, and well-being of the amateurs participating in the matches, including the qualifications and numbers of health care personnel required to be present, the qualifications required for referees, and other requirements relating to the health, safety, and well-being of the amateurs participating in the matches. The commission may adopt by rule, or incorporate by reference into rule, the health and safety standards of USA Boxing as the minimum health and safety standards for an amateur boxing sanctioning organization, the health and safety standards of the International Sport Kickboxing Association as the minimum health and safety standards for an amateur kickboxing sanctioning organization, and the minimum health and safety standards for an amateur mixed martial arts sanctioning organization. The commission shall review its rules for necessary revision at least every 2 years and may adopt by rule, or incorporate by reference into rule, the then-existing current health and safety standards of USA Boxing and the International Sport Kickboxing Association. The commission may adopt emergency rules to administer this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall maintain an office in Tallahassee. At the first meeting of the commission after June 1 of each year, the commission shall select a chair and a vice chair from among its membership. Three members shall constitute a quorum and the concurrence of at least three members is necessary for official commission action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three consecutive unexcused absences or absences constituting 50 percent or more of the commission’s meetings within any 12-month period shall cause the commission membership of the member in question to become void, and the position shall be considered vacant. The commission shall, by rule, define unexcused absences.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each commission member shall be accountable to the Governor for the proper performance of duties as a member of the commission. The Governor shall cause to be investigated any complaint or unfavorable report received by the Governor or the department concerning an action of the commission or any member and shall take appropriate action thereon. The Governor may remove from office any member for malfeasance, unethical conduct, misfeasance, neglect of duty, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to or being found guilty of a felony.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the commission shall be compensated at the rate of $50 for each day she or he attends a commission meeting and shall be reimbursed for other expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall be authorized to join and participate in the activities of the Association of Boxing Commissions (ABC).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide all legal and investigative services necessary to implement this chapter. The department may adopt rules as provided in ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to carry out its duties under this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 1, ch. 85-21; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 205, ch. 94-218; s. 762, ch. 97-103; s. 183, ch. 98-200; s. 113, ch. 99-251; s. 2, ch. 2002-172; s. 3, ch. 2004-69; s. 49, ch. 2009-195.</History></Section>