<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Control of contracts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules governing the form and content of contracts executed in this state between managers and participants. All such contracts shall be in writing and shall contain all provisions specifically worded as required by rules of the commission. Contracts that do not contain all provisions specifically worded as required by rules of the commission shall be deemed to contain such provisions. A copy of all such contracts must be filed with the commission within 7 days after execution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract between a manager and a participant shall contain provisions governing its duration, division of the participant’s purses, and any minimum sum guaranteed annually to the participant by the manager. Each contract shall provide that it is automatically terminated if the license of either party is revoked by the commission or if the manager fails to renew her or his license within 30 days after its expiration date. If the license of either party is suspended, the contract is not binding upon the other party during the period of suspension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may require that each contract contain language authorizing the Florida State Boxing Commission to withhold any or all of any manager’s share of a purse in the event of a contractual dispute as to entitlement to any portion of a purse. The commission may establish rules governing the manner of resolution of such dispute. In addition, if the commission deems it appropriate, the commission is hereby authorized to implead interested parties over any disputed funds into the appropriate circuit court for resolution of the dispute prior to release of all or any part of the funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract subject to this section shall contain the following clause: “This agreement is subject to the provisions of chapter 548, Florida Statutes, and to the rules of the Florida State Boxing Commission and to any future amendments of either.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 11, ch. 88-365; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 769, ch. 97-103; s. 126, ch. 99-251; s. 15, ch. 2002-172.</History></Section>