<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Promoters and foreign copromoters; bonds or other security.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any license is issued or renewed to a promoter or foreign copromoter and before any permit is issued to a promoter or foreign copromoter, she or he must file a surety bond with the commission in such reasonable amount, but not less than $15,000, as the commission determines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All bonds must be upon forms approved and supplied by the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sufficiency of any surety is subject to approval of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surety bond must be conditioned upon the faithful performance by the promoter or foreign copromoter of her or his obligations under this chapter and upon the fulfillment of her or his contracts with any other licensees under this chapter. However, the aggregate annual liability of the surety for all obligations and fees may not exceed the amount of the bond.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of a surety bond, the promoter or foreign copromoter may deposit with the commission cash or a certified check, in an equivalent amount and subject to the same conditions as the bond. Such security may not be returned to the promoter until 1 year after the date on which it was deposited with the commission unless a surety bond is substituted for it. If no claim against the deposit is outstanding, it shall be returned to the depositor 1 year after the date it was deposited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recovery may be made against any bond, cash, or other security in the same manner as penalties are recoverable at law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 763, ch. 97-103; s. 119, ch. 99-251.</History></Section>