<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0548.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payments to state; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A promoter holding a match shall, within 72 hours after the match, file with the commission a written report which includes the number of tickets sold, the amount of gross receipts, and any other facts the commission may require. For the purposes of this chapter, total gross receipts include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gross price charged for the sale or lease of broadcasting, television, and motion picture rights without any deductions for commissions, brokerage fees, distribution fees, advertising, or other expenses or charges;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The portion of the receipts from the sale of souvenirs, programs, and other concessions received by the promoter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The face value of all tickets sold and complimentary tickets issued, provided, or given; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The face value of any seat or seating issued, provided, or given in exchange for advertising, sponsorships, or anything of value to the promotion of an event.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the rights to telecast a match or matches held in this state under the supervision of the Florida State Boxing Commission are in whole owned by, sold to, acquired by, or held by any person who intends to or subsequently sells or, in some other manner, extends such rights in part to another, such person is deemed to be a promoter and must be licensed as such in this state. Such person shall, within 72 hours after the sale, transfer, or extension of such rights in whole or in part, file with the commission a written report that includes the number of tickets sold, the amount of gross receipts, and any other facts the commission may require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A concessionaire shall, within 72 hours after the match, file with the commission a written report that includes the number of tickets sold, the amount of gross receipts, and any other facts the commission may require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any written report required to be filed with the commission under this section shall be postmarked within 72 hours after the conclusion of the match, and an additional 5 days shall be allowed for mailing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written report shall be accompanied by a tax payment in the amount of 5 percent of the total gross receipts exclusive of any federal taxes, except that the tax payment derived from the gross price charged for the sale or lease of broadcasting, television, and motion picture rights shall not exceed $40,000 for any single event.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any promoter who willfully makes a false and fraudulent report under this section is guilty of perjury and, upon conviction, is subject to punishment as provided by law. Such penalty shall be in addition to any other penalties imposed by this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any promoter who willfully fails, neglects, or refuses to make a report or to pay the taxes as prescribed or who refuses to allow the commission to examine the books, papers, and records of any promotion is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-246; s. 3, ch. 85-21; s. 141, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 18, ch. 2002-172.</History></Section>